<topic>
  <!-- topic 1 -->
  <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-darwin-theory-of-evolution</id>
  <results>
    <!-- article 1 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85029094/1863-06-27/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Darwin+Origin+Species</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1863‐1898: Darwinism is occasionally discussed in newspapers. Scientists begin to lecture on Darwin’s evolution theory, mainly to the scientific community.</time>
      <text>
        The Origin of Species.
        Of late yeais men of science and oth
        ers hive wrangled much over Mr. Dar
        win's work on The Origin of Species."
        In most of the English and American
        reviews his treatise lms been Muverely
        criticised, as having an infidel tendency;
        not on account of (lie facts therein giv
        en, but the conclusion of ihe author.
        He appears to liavo been very generally
        rnLsunilerstood, judging from a most in
        teresting little woik just insued by D.
        Appleton Jc Co., this city, beim: the
        publictiou of six lectures delivered to
        woikiugmen, by Thomas II. Huxley, F.
        R. S., Professor of Natural History in
        the School of Mines, London. Broadly
        slated, the subject of these lectures
        consists of an inquiry into the oiii'in of
        species and a discussion on the causes
        of the phenomena in organic naiure.
        The meaning of organic uature is
        something that grows, lias life and le
        productive powers. It is exemplified
        in tliu seed of a plan: in contradistinc
        tion to n grain of sand. Organic nature
        embraces the vegetable and animal
        kingdom, as entirely distinct in tunc
        tions from loeke, fluids, and what chem
        ists call "elementary matter." Ani
        mals and plants are divided by natural
        ists into gioups,and these into kitijidoms,
        sub-kingdoms,jirovinces, cl.tsses.orders,
        families, genera and species- it was
        once very generally believed (and many
        person entertain such views still) that
        there vras'such a thing s spontaneous
        generation that is, mere eiemeiitiiry
        malter, such as pure water or mineral
        dust exposed in favorab'e positions, to
        light aud heat, would bring forth vege
        tation and nnimalcula spontaneously
        Hence it has been asserted that, if there
        is such phncomena as the spon.atieous
        generation of life, according to the "de
        velopment theory" of torao uiituralists
        and the -views of Mr. Darwin on the
        origin of species, man may have been
        developed from the lowest forms of
        spontaneous generation. If Mich views
        were founded on facts in na'ural history,
        pantheism, viz that "God is nature
        and naiure is God," would bo suppos
        ed upon a very firm foundation.
        Mr. Darwin doos not discuss the
        question of tpontaneous gonerati -n at
        all, and science completely silences
        pantheism. Every organism commen
        ces existence in an gg-eell or seed, and
        each seed is believed to lie been
        specially created, with special functions
        and powers of reproduction, as stated
        in th Scriptures. Al. Pasteur, a dis
        tinguished French chemists, has lately
        made a great number of carefully con
        ducted experiments to lest the theory
        of hpomaneous generation. The result
        of hi labors rfcem to be conclusive
        againt the theoij; no such propert) as
        spontaneous crfc&amp;'iou belongs to ele
        mentary matter acted upon by thw forces
        of nature. An old and bitterly dispu
        ted question thus appear now to be
        settled scientifically.
        Another miestion of much dispute
        seems lo bs settled bv Mr. Darwin; tints
        the Caucasian, the Malay, and the Ae
        gto, according to his facts, are varieties
        ol xpecieis and way alMiave descended
        fiom a single pair, as set forth in the
        Scriptures. On the other Hand, t'ror.
        Agassiz and others believe that they
        have descended from difieicnt original
        pairs, jind thus j.ley would really bo
        liffeient orders. Vu 1793. a new v.rie-
        tj of sheep was produced by Sethi
        Wright of Massachusetts, lie nau a
        flock! the members of which were pe-
        cia 'lT K",ed w"'' t,ie P0Ws;r of JumP"'o
        fauces nd thus tormenting the pro
        prietor a.-J bis neighbors. In one ac
        cidental buck lamb, which had very
        short bowed K, die acute mind of
        Sell. Wright saw remedy for his
        troublesome fance-junT"'1 b)' cr8
        ful breeding be at last ,"btnned an en
        tire flock of long-bodied 8l'",;!ef;
        sheep, called the "otter tirei?". .,r01"
        this singhi buck, which could no"-Jnip
        a foot-rail. Various species of
        do-'saml pigeons have.ueen in me s.i".
        muniier. In structure they are differ
        ent frcm others of the same gtnus. Hut
        pyycologically they are identical. 'J heie
        is a well defined limit to organic varie
        ties in animals.
        1'wo eiiuroly different
        races mav mix; but their progeny, as in
        t i I'm.
        the case ol mules, uecoiuc siumv.
        feasor Huxley states tliat iheie is no
        icliable exception to this law.
        The rapid powers of pi odiictionjn
        lauts from a single specimen, is set
        forth by Prof. Huxley as follows:
        -Suppose the habitable part of the globe
        to be 51,000,000 square miles, and the
        climate and soil equal over that space,
        it may be entirely covered in nine years
        from the product of a s.ngle plant bear
        inefif'T seeds, each plant lequinngone
        foot of' soil for support." It is hardly
        conceivable that the whole statcu ava i
        bl .urfaco of the earth could be stock
        ed in about nine yar fiom a single
        plant, yet tho fiu-es deinorstrato such
        a possibility. Scientific American.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 2 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1871-01-21/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Darwin+Darwinism+evolution+Origin+Species+species</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1863‐1898: Darwinism is occasionally discussed in newspapers. Scientists begin to lecture on Darwin’s evolution theory, mainly to the scientific community.</time>
      <text>
        MAX A.H IMmOTXD Arjs.
        Tbe Laat Resatt t Darwinians.
        Mr. CoaUi HoDiai Oabwix, the eminent
        natural!., and author of The Origin of Species,"
        has Just published In England hi laat and groateat
        work, Th4 IXttfnt of Jan, which tbe Appletons
        hire tn rjrsii, and will issue la a few days, Th
        work, we nnderstand, ha created a profound sen
        atloa.ln England, where the first edition was sold
        la a day, and will undoubtedly, when It appear, be
        received here with equal Interest.
        Brosdly expressed, Darwinism Is the attempt to
        account for the present and past diversities of life
        on our globe by means of continuous development,
        without the Intervention of special creative flat at
        tbe orlglo or each distinct species. It Is well known
        tint lo tbe hand of breeder useful peculiarities In
        kalmsj aro DerpeloaUl by pairing thoie which
        ahow such peculiarities. Our present Improved
        breeds of long-horned snd short-horned cattle, rsca
        horses, merino sheep, snd the countless varieties of
        pigeons, til developed from a alnglo stock the rock
        pigeon demonstrate that lhase pecnllirltles may
        not only be perpetuated, hut Increased largely, If
        not Indefinitely. Thla process Is known a ttttctltm,
        and Is used by man exclusively for his own benefit.
        Mr. Dsrwln extends this procedure to Nature, with
        an Important change tn 11 object. Man car. only
        soled vlsibte characteristic! Mature, on .the con
        trary, Is contlnuslly scrutlnlxlng the tcAoni being,
        and ts continually stamping with approval those
        variations which aro useful to tbe orgsnlsm. This
        principle works altogether by mean of life aad
        death tbe latter being tbe penalty of a failure to
        meet successfully the circumstance In which a being
        is placed, be those circumstance physical or vital,
        enemloaor force in a word, "the condition of
        existence."
        An lUustratton given by Prof. Haxlsy will serv
        to fix this la th mind: "lathe woods of florid
        there sro many plgs.tond very curiously, they are
        all black. I'rof. Wyman, many year ago, asked
        some of the reople why tbey had no white pigs, and
        was Informed there wan a root In the wooda (called
        pilot root), of which. If the tcAlfs pig eat, their
        hoofs cricked and tbey died, while it did not hart
        the Uocl pigs at all." This weeding out on the ono
        side, and preservation on tbe other, I what Is meant
        by natural n'.tctlun.
        In the introduction to his new work. The Descent
        of Man," Mr. Darwin quotea, with evident sstlsfae
        tlon, the remark made by tbe eminent naturalist
        Carl Vogt In hla addiess a President of the National
        Institution of Geneva, In ISC, that "nobody la Eu
        rope at lout now vantured to maintain the doctrlno
        of the Independent creation of species" a state
        ment rather broader, wo fancy, than the fact will
        warrant, though It Is no doubt true that a large
        number of naturallsta hare accepted the theory of
        Darwinism, snd admit thst species aro tbe modi
        fled dcicendants of other species. Mr. Darwin him
        self,, however, says that those who accept Ms theory
        are mostly tbe younger race, and "of the older and
        honored chiefs ln natural science, msny unfortunately
        are still opposed to evolution In every form." He men
        tions as among the eminent naturallsta who have
        ndootud his view Wallace, Itaxley, Lyell, and Lub
        bock In England, and In Germany, Duckner, Itolle,
        and Hackel. An Italian phlloevpl er, Dr. l'rancesco,
        al-omilntalns tbe same views ln n work published
        In 1PC9, under Ihe significant ttl'e ot "Man, made In
        the Image of God, wo also made In the Image of
        Ibe Ape."
        The following extracts, from advance sheets of
        Mr. Darwin's new book, will snfncteully Indicate Ha
        acope aud character:
        As soon ss pome ancient member In the great
        series of the Prtm-itos time, owing lu a cianre In
        its manner of procuring snbaistence. or to a cb.in,e
        In the conditions of Its native countrr, to lite some,
        whst loss on trees and more on tho ground. Its mso
        ucr of progression would bate ben modified ami
        In this care It would have had tn become cither moro
        strictly quadrupedal or bipedal lliboona frequent
        hilly and rocky distilcls. and only from nrcriiy
        climb np high trees: and they bate acquired almost
        tlM gilt of a dog. Man alone haa become a bipod
        und we can, I think, partly see how ho has come to
        Miami his erect sttltuJe, wbtca forms one of the
        most coniplcnom dttlcrences between lilm and bis
        nearest allies, Man could not have attained bis
        present dominsnt position In tbe world without tho
        uae of I li bands, which are so admirably adapted to
        act tn obedience to bis will. As Sir C. Bell lusUts,
        the head supplies all loatrnmenta, and by Its cor
        respondence with the Intellect gives him universal
        antiunion, jiat me nanus and arms couh! hardly
        have becomo pericct enough to hate manufactured
        wcapous, or to liavehurlod atones and rpvarswitu
        a true aim, aa long ns thex were habitually
        used for locumolloi, and for supporting Ihe whole
        aetghtof tlio body, or as long as tlie) were cape
        Ci.'Ht wall adapted, as previously remarked, for
        rliin.sliig trees, fitch rough treatment would nlru
        havo U'lnted tho sense of touch, on w Inch their dull
        csle use rge)y depeiute. from these causes alone
        II would tn.ve been an advantage to aim to hate be
        come a ld''.': but, for mint actions, It Is atn.ost
        necary tl at a"'"' arms and the whol npper part
        of the bodj should be free: and he mint for this end
        atiind flriiiij on his C-it. lo gain this gicat advan
        tage, tho fret hue I.e. 'ii rei dered fl.t and the great
        toe peculiarly mod I lied, though this has entailed llie
        !om ol the power of piVeualun. It accords with
        lue principlt of the divlilui. ot pb)slulotlcsl labor,
        which prevails throughout v.ie animal kingdom,
        that, nsili bauds became pcrfm'ed 'or prehension,
        the leet should hate become er'i cted for support
        and locoinulion. With Koine savage, however, tho
        foot has not alt 'grther lott Us ire!ien.' power, as
        shown bv thoir manner of climbing tre,-1" uud of
        using them lu other ways,
        ooeoo
        lu regard to bo.llly slxa or strength, we do not
        know whether msn is descended irom some cuai
        parstttelr small species, like the ehlmptnije, oi
        Irom one ns pnwer'ut as tho gorilla and, theroture,
        we cannot say whether manliss become lamer and
        aironger. or smaller and weaker. In comp.irlon
        with his progenitors. We ehcu'd, howoer, bear In
        mind that nn unimal posienlng great :trongth,
        and ferocity, and which, like tho coritla, eoufri do
        fend iti-cif from all cnemtea, would probably, (hou'ih
        not nrceasaillr, hale lallc t to becouio sociil and
        this would moat creetnjllr hato checked tho ac
        quirement by man of bit hlt.ier mental qualities
        such as smpulby aud tho lova of hla feliow-croi
        lures. Hence II mitht tune been an Immense ad
        T'ntage to man to have sprung frum sowiu comparu
        Wici -.Tk creature
        Tho slim: corporeal strength of mm, bis little
        speed, hla w. ii.t ol natural we..pn, Ac. aro moro
        than counterbahnced, Uratly by hi ininliectual
        powers, throueli w ln.-'i he haa, while still remain
        ing In a barbaroas statu, funned lor hlmaelf wea
        pon, tools, Ai i ud re. olid' by lis social qnall
        ties, w hich leal lilm to give ntd tu hts Idlow men.
        uud to receive It lu leturn. No ountry In the
        world abounds In a greater degree with dangerous
        beasis than Southern Africa; uo country presents
        mucfoaifu. physical hardahlps than tho arctic m
        glona; yet one of the puniest races, namely, the
        lluaht-icn, matnUilii themselves In touthcrn Vrlca
        ts do tbe dwarfed Luiuimsux tu the arctic region''
        Ihe early progenitors of man wer- no doubt 1 .1
        fenor in Intellect, uud probably In soc al dia.,it
        tiou, tothelowet existing sststcsj but it li quite
        concelrabls that they might liato existed, ur iien
        fl.iuris.ul, If, llio they grad.iall, lost their bmte
        like poweis, i-ueti ns cllmlliiig Uvea, .W, Ihei at He
        tame time adanced In Inleileil. Hut grintiiii Hut
        the progenitors of uunwero lar more liolple.i and
        iieuiiceiess man nj extsluig savages, If itu-r had
        mhabitid somo warm comment, or Urge island
        juch vi Australia, or stv Citrines., or Borneo (the
        latter t.laud beliur nuw teua ted by tho orans). tbey
        would not lute becnexposcd to any special danger
        In aa .rea as hrge as Sue ol those islan i, the com
        iclulon bi-iween tilbe and trihii would huve been
        sufllcienl, utidir favorable cciidlllons, tu hae ram-d
        man, throueli the siiiv,ol of the fltteat, ionium a
        with tlo liibeiltid ellecls of habit, to hli presuit
        bih position lu tl e organic fcale.
        aaaaa
        At the period and ll.ice, whenever und where
        eier II mi) b..to been, wheu man first Ion his hairy
        coieilng, ue probably Inbaolted a hot eounirj j und
        this would hae hem latorublo lor a Iiiulieruus
        diet, ou which, Ju Iglni: fnmi u alugy, hu subsisted
        We ate lar frum knuwluj how hugngolt Wuj wheii
        man lint diverged Irom tl.c Catarhlnc itooks but thla
        may haio otcurred at an .-rodi as remotu .is Ihe
        l.ucehe .-ilod f. r Iho hUhcr opes hud dlvi-r.-e I
        from the luwer nj e as early as the Upper Miocene
        period, us .howii by the ealsieuce of Ibellnn
        I'llbeius. are also qullo linuraut at how rapid
        u lute orgonliinis, whether hiith or lov lu the seile
        mat under favurablo circumstances be nv.diuVd
        We know, however, that aolllu have n tallied the
        same lurmduilng an euui uious lup.e ul time. I rom
        hat we see going on under d imoiic..tiotn, we
        learn thai within the eainu period some uf Iho ci
        d s endatita of iho same hkcics may bo not ut all
        changed, some a little, und sumo i.ieatl) cbauge 1.
        i bus It may have buen with man, who Ins undei
        gotie a great omouut ul iiiodiiUatlon In certain
        characters In compaiiauu Willi tho higher apes.
        It will bo seen ut a glanro that these views are ut
        direct variance with Ciirltlianlty, at least as com
        monly understood. Thoy Ignore ultoiethcr tho
        spliltual part of man, and regard htm simply as au
        unloial. They Ignore nlo the existence, or at lean
        lie active exl.tenco ot tie Creater.wiio, althoush Ho
        may at the louioto beginning hate created the geitm
        ficm which everyihlug haa been doieloped, Is yet
        repreientcd as having abdicated his functions, and
        turned over Iho universe lo the benlOccut control ol
        Nuture.by whoso luceasant agency, through the prlu
        clplo ol natural selection, cverylhlnj la accom
        plished, Mr. Darwin, like the rest of Ms atheistic ichool,
        evidently rejects with contempt tlie Idea of a spirit
        ul God who creates and sustaina the universe. He
        would probably say thero la no proof of his tilst
        euce. And yet lie coolly assumes tho existence ol
        a supremo and beneficent power which be culls Ns
        tare, and assigns to It the uctlve and Inlolll.eut
        control of tho unlverso What proof haa he ot tho
        eililcuce cf this mysterious aud lucouiprebcnilblo
        mt-igMJJtjajM jijii i i xutv
        powerf His "Nstare Is a supernatural and aa
        Incessantly active a the God whom he reject, but
        whoso powers and attribute he ascribes to her. HI
        theory would be relieved of much of Its odlonsnee
        If his shallow tod vulgar theological prejudices had
        not prompted him to substitute this purely and.
        ful "Nature" for the true and living Ood, whose
        rmldacbMUfand theologian I Justly regard.,
        ed u performing Ihe functions and exeielslng tba
        beneficent and (elective power which Mr. Darwin
        needlessly ascribes to his Imaginary "Nature,"
        Apart, however, Irom hla theological heresies, w
        think Mr, Dsrwln Is mistaken In supposing that hla
        theories have become eeitlod principles of natural sci
        ence. They are la vogue Jast now, It Is true, and,
        aro attracting universal attention, and commandlag
        a good deal of enthusiastic aeient. But so ditto
        kindred theories of hts grandfather, Dr. Eroamoa 1
        Darwin, which aro sow utterly neglected and for. V
        gol.'on. And so also did the transmutation llioorlea
        of Lamarck, of whom Mr. Darwin la only a follow-'
        er, and whose crude and Inaccurate conclusion
        were greatly admired until they wer exploded bjr
        the authority of Cuvier.
        Mr. Darwin write with an sir of great candot
        snd Ingenuousness. Bui the critical reader wlllaooa
        perceive what M, Flourenr, the Tcrpetaal Secretary
        ot the French Academy of Sciences, long ago point,
        ed out, that he cites only author who confirm hit
        opinion that he glide over difficulties, and dwell
        stron.ly oa fscts which no one denies, hut which
        prove little or nothing: that he continually takes for
        granted what lie cannot prove and that, ln short,
        hi whole argument la little better than a string ol
        assumptions. The array of fact, whlc'i hs hi,
        culled and manipulated with to much car to prove
        bis theory of development, prove bo each Ihlagr,
        Any Intelligent Hwedenborgiin, for Inilaace, wonldi
        readily furnish for thoir explanation a theory tnach.
        more plausible lean taaa of Mr. Darwin, and at tba
        same tlmo la strict accordance with Christian doc
        trine. He-haa not been able to find In the whola
        range of natural science one atngla proof of tb de
        velopment of one species from another. Neither natu-
        ral liiitory nor geology afford th (lightest Ince of a, 1
        kangaroo producing a monkey, or of a monitey do- W
        veloplng Into a man. Even hi principle of natural A
        selection, on which hi whole elaborate slructura
        depends. Is obviously fsnclful and arbltnry whea
        carried to tb extent which he gives It.
        Dot notwithstanding these defect, Mr. Darwin'
        new book Is a most Important and valuable contrl- fe
        butlon to knowledge. The questions he raises endr
        tbe view he maintains cannot be shirked by either
        science or religion. They .must be met and an
        swered, accepted or exploded. They are the vital
        question of the age, snd we do not object to their
        discussion. We do not sccept Mr. Dsrwln'a theo.
        riea, and do not see that be hi made any real pro
        gress towsrd establishing them by substantial and
        lodlspulable proof. But he ta clearly entitle J to
        patient and fair bearing, aa a man of great ability,
        vast and varied research, and unexceptionable
        courtesy of manner.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 3 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1871-03-18/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Darwin+Origin+Species</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1863‐1898: Darwinism is occasionally discussed in newspapers. Scientists begin to lecture on Darwin’s evolution theory, mainly to the scientific community.</time>
      <text>
        The Descent OT Mun.
        lt ie now more than ten years 'since tbe
        world of science was startled "by the appear
        anccQfilr.^Darwin's "Origin ol Species.
        Bat profound and widespread as bin "been
        the agitation created by the announcement
        of the hypothesis of "Natural. Selection," as
        familiar to men's ears as is the name of the
        "Darwinian Theory,0 thetis are yet many
        who through lack of leisure or inclination to
        pursue the subject, nave not yet a definite
        ideR of what the theory actually is. Let us
        briefly explain. All animals and plants tend
        to increase with enormous rapidity. In the
        case of the slowest breeders, if there were no
        canses at work to iuterfere-with .the rate of
        their increase, the earth would be speecttJy
        over populated. Hence to maintain a Just
        equilibrium there prevails' throughout the
        organic world a continued and prodigious
        slaughter. In the struggle for existence, in
        the competition for subsistence, the strong
        flourish at the expense pf the weak. The.
        feeble and less favored individuals* which
        constitute the majority, succumlfand perish,
        while they.who are best endowed with the
        cionrities which tit them for success in t-e
        strife, survive, and transmit their superior
        organization to their descendants". Tilts ie
        the doctrine of Natural Selection; "the sur?
        vival of tile fltfest," of those best adapted to*?
        Lae conditions In which they live. Now if j,
        the circumstances of their environment re?
        mained constant., there would be no .altera?
        tion of species. But the fact exists that
        there is everywhere an incessant change in
        tbe conditions of the soil aud the atmos?
        phere, and in the influences of beat and
        moisture. To conform to these changes
        there must be a consequent continual varia?
        tion in the constitution and characteristics
        of plants and animals. The members of
        each species are,- therefore, constantly vary?
        ing-those dwelling in oue locality ever de?
        veloping new and needed capacities, and
        those in* a different situation acquiring di?
        verse enes, according to their necessity
        until finally, in the course of many genera?
        tions, the change has become .so great that
        distinct species ure recognized, or, in other
        words, the protjess of the evolution of- one
        species from another has been effected. The
        theory, in.its .full significance, is that all
        present species of animals-sprang from lower
        and ruder forms, and that evey man himself
        is the ultimate result ol this evolution and
        process of selection.
        lu his lately published work, "The De
        "scent Of Mun," of which we have as yet but
        the first volume. Mr. Darwin does not pro?
        ject anything ubsolutely Bew regarding the
        origin of species, tint'occupies himsely chiefly
        with an application bf the theory of evolu?
        tion to the case of maa. In the opening
        chapters lu} bringa forward o^crowd of in?
        teresting facts Lo-ehow the points of. resem?
        blance between man and the lower animals
        in physical structure and mental powers.
        The mass of evidence tends to prove that the
        intellectual faculties of man and the loweri
        animals do not differ in kind, although im?
        measurably, in degree. The distance be?
        tween the intelligence of man abd the high?
        est .Mirna] is not, aecqrding~to"Kc. .Darwin,
        so great as that between the coccus' qr
        scale insect and the ant, two species which,
        beion? to the sam? class.
        '?Plie female -coccus, while younjr, attaches
        itself by its probocls to a plant; sucks the sap,
        but never moves again;-ts i.-rtUlzed and lays
        egiw; and this ls its whole history. On the-J
        other hand, ants communicate Information to
        each other, and -several unite tor the same
        work, or games of play. They recognize their
        fellowvants alter months of absence. They
        build great edifioes, keep them clean, close the
        doors ?bthe evening^ and post 8?nj^J^-^a?y j
        collect (bod for*the communtty,ijtod when an
        'object, ?io largejor entrance, ie brought taine
        nest, th|y enligge t%dbori ??3 aftei*wairtt
        build it up again. They gp oat to battle In
        regular bands, and freely sacrifice their Uves
        ferr the common need." They emigrate inao~J
        ^oordance with a preconcerted plan.. They cap?
        ture slaves. They keep aphides as milch
        1 cows. They move the eggs of their aphlaesl?s
        well as their own eggs and cocoons, "into warm
        parts of the nest, tn order that they may be
        quickly "hatched, besffles performing endless
        similar feats of intelligence. "On the. whole,
        the' dlfference in mental power between an ant
        and a coccus ls immense; yet rib one has ever
        dreamed ol placing them in distinct, classes,
        [.much less in distinct kingdoms. No doubt
        this interval labridged over by the intermedi?
        ate mental .powers of many other insects; and
        this is not the case" with, mari and .the higher
        apes. "But we have every reason to believe
        that breaks In the series are the result bf many
        forms having become-extlnct."
        The most expert anatomists agree that in
        all parts of his organization mau diners less
        "from the higher apes than- these do from the,
        lo**er members of the same group. In re*
        viewing the testimony which his evlderice'af
        fords, Mr. Darwin advances the hypalbesiB
        that mau ?as deaceodedIrom the progenitor
        of the"Catarhine or Old World group of mon?
        keys, ada that bis birthplace was either in
        Europe or ?frica. Startling and revolting j
        to-the pride as is this conclusion witb regard
        to the origin of man, lt ts reached by follow?
        ing a chain of facts incontestable direct?
        ness arid ingenuity,
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 4 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026844/1874-02-06/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Darwin+Darwinism+origin+species</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1863‐1898: Darwinism is occasionally discussed in newspapers. Scientists begin to lecture on Darwin’s evolution theory, mainly to the scientific community.</time>
      <text>
        DARWINISM.
        WHAT IS DARWINISM 1
        Many ol tho ideas which aro current in
        regard to it aro exceedingly crude and
        vague. Aud this again has affected the
        reception with which it meets nt the
        bauds ui' dilleront persons. Some have
        hastily embraced it, who, il they had fully
        comprehended its ualure would al
        least have hesitated before tbey subscribed
        themselves amongst its adhereuls.
        To some it has been a sort of btle noir,
        concerning which lltey have been disposed
        to manifest a ioolish alarm. If
        they only understood what it is they
        would not be afraid to march np to it aud
        boldly examine it. Many an object seen
        In the darkness of a fog or of the approaching
        night has been taken tor u terrible
        monster. When confronted it may be
        nothing very formidable.
        avujuu viumsai.
        Darwinism la a form ol what iu modern
        scientltlc add theological parlance la called
        tvolutiQuism. The following quolallon
        trom a living author probably would be
        accepted by Ibo parties ranged on either
        side ol these questlqps, as substantially a
        correct statement of the doctrine in its j
        widestI'otm: "Tlioddctrine of Evolution
        -known also as the Law Scheme, and the
        Development Hypothesis, in its ripest
        torm, is that all things wo perceive, including
        what are called spiritual phenomena,
        have come Itom the simplest beginnings,
        solely by means ol Buch forces
        and laws as belong lo matter, buppose
        all matter expanded into one great cloud
        ol atoms. Then these atoms, by virtue of
        properties inherent in lltemwlm, would, in
        course of time,come together into worlds,
        into astronomic systems, into the vegetable
        and animal kingdoms, and even into
        that great spiritual realm which ia the
        chief wonder and glory of Nature."
        Tho above is a statement of the doctrine
        of evolutionism In general. But as
        applied to the different Isolds it has taken
        Uireo principal lorms. The general
        theory M a stem which separates into
        these aa its branohes. The first is the
        AVrtiJar Hflolhuit. It deals with the
        mftWlnt* nf wnrlrio Afwiwffnar tr?
        Ironditfon ol the universe at the moat
        remote time in the past to which science
        c&amp;u penetrate was thai of matter in a highly
        attenuated and widely diffused state.
        It is often spoken of a* star-dust or firemlst.
        This matter had in it all tho forces
        and properties which now belong to it,
        and, under their operation elono and in
        accordance with them, the sun and
        moon and stars wcro evolved, and
        took their places in (be order of
        the heavens. The sejond lorrn of
        evolutionism it Sponiaiuoue Generation.
        It deals with the origin tit llle. According
        to it, llto, instead of being something
        which is Introduced ab alra even at its
        tint appearance in the world, is the result
        ol the peculiar arrangement ol the atoms
        ol water. Huxley, lor example, teaches
        that "the matter of lite is composed of
        ordinary matter, differing Irom it only in
        the mumer.ia which its atoms are aggregated.
        The third lorm which evolutionism
        assumes is Darmniim, as it is
        properly called, or the traiumutaUon of
        ycut. It deals with plants and animals.
        It undertakes to show that all plants and
        animals, Including man, came, by the operation
        alone ot oertain natural laws,
        from ono or a lew species, which were introduce
        by creation, or by spontaneous
        generation into the world at? period ?o
        remote that we cannot with any distincthob
        ho back to it.j
        For the Kks ol clearness it has asemed
        proper thnsto Mate the general doctrine
        ol evolutionism and the branches Into
        which it divides. Still It ii not true that
        became a man accepts one of its forms be
        most alto recctve the other. In fact inch
        Isnottfeeoise. For instance Dsrwin diflers
        with Huxley aa to the origin of life.
        Darwin believes that the Almighty
        breathed life in the beginning in bis supposed
        progenitor or progenitors ol the
        whole animal and Testable kingdoms.
        Bat Huxley traces life to the forces which
        ho supposes to belong eiMntially to the
        original particles of matter.
        TDK NAHK Or DABWIIUSU.
        The writer Intends in wj)at he may present
        in these articles, to confine himself to
        Darwinism proper. It is populate known
        by this name because oT the prominence
        of Professor Charlca Darwin of England
        in connection with it. He first expounded
        his theory In an essay published In 1859
        on the "Origin of species by Means of Natural
        Selection." nis work was soon
        translated Into all the leading European
        languages. It made a profound popular
        ltnpresaiqn, and has been sold by thousands
        ol copies. In It ho confined the application
        of his theory to animals and
        plants, and passed by man. About two
        and a half years ago, however, ho published
        another work called ."The Descent
        of Man, and Selection in Relation to Sex,"
        in which he in the most unequivocal manner
        applies his doctrine to the human
        race, la the same line are his "Animals
        and Plants under Domestication," and i
        "The Expression of the Emotions in Man
        and Animals." While the prominence of
        Darwin In connection with tUs tbeory
        has been such that it is called after him,
        he is not alone in its adoption. The num- j
        bcr ol persons who can fairly claim h j
        place in the ranks of scientific men and i
        who have received it is much .smaller
        both in Europe and America than many
        of the lees learned would suppose. Still
        there are enough of them to command
        serious attention. A. K. Wallace prdponnded
        the hypothesis about the same
        time with Darwin, and stillisanadvocatsi
        ol It though with some limitations. Herbert
        Spenct'r In hia "Principles of Biology"
        eargerly endorse* it and uses It for
        the purposes of his system ot philosophy.
        Others whose names are lesa familiar to
        th? general public could alio be mentioned
        a3 its adherents.
        the two great u? of darwinism.
        Tho general hypothesis ol Darwinism
        la that all plants and animals, including
        man, came from one or a few species by
        tho operation of certain natural laws. Of
        these laws, it is held that there are two.
        The first Is called Natural Selection Tho
        word Kchction Id this phase is calculated
        to convey to the mind of the uninitiated
        the idea that the plant or animal concerned
        exercises some choice In the matter.
        But the word natural is used to qualify
        it, for the purpose ot guarding against
        such a construction. The whole phase
        indicates a process from, which everything
        amounting to an intelligent choice
        of the end attained is excluded. This law
        may bo better understood by its other
        name of the Survival of the Filtat When
        plants and animals greatly multiply, as
        they ever tend to do, there is a struggle
        lor existence. In that struggle the strongest,
        that Is those which are best adapted
        to the circumstances, survive and the
        weaker perish. And aa a consequence
        those species which are the strongest are
        perpetuated, and the peculiarities in
        which their strength lies are developed
        until they become new species. By this
        process of a few primordial germs the
        plants and animals of our era ot the world
        have been in the Ispse of ages produced.
        The other of the laws is oalled Sexual
        Selection. It is supposed to come into exercise
        along with natural selection in the
        origin of animals and of man." 80 prominent
        is it held to bo in this sphere that
        tha ..-I 41 r
        tuu vvuoiuciaviuu Ul ll MUUUpiCB lUtCC*
        fourths of the work of Darwin on the J
        "Descent ol Man." It is there treated as
        a corner stone with which the whole edi- J
        fice stands or falls. To it we as men are t!
        supposed to owe our power of song and 8
        our hairlessneaa ot body and much that
        distinguishes us from the beasts. To it
        also he attributes the rise and conserve- lion
        of the various races of the human t
        species.
        Under.the head ol sexual selection, Dar- r
        win includes two distinct processes. One1
        ol these applies to the male, and the e
        other to the female. The mate, who is j
        endowed with superior strength and activity,
        drives away rivals and thereby
        succeeds in perpetuating and still further 1
        developing tho peculiarities by which he ii
        is distinguished. This, however, is sub- c
        stattially the same thing in its operation t
        as natural selection and may be so treat-
        ed in the discussion. The process as to j
        the female is a practical preference for u
        certain males on account of some such
        quality as beauty of form, or color, or a
        odor, or voice. In mating she chooses c
        them because ol these things, and thereby a
        perpetuates and still further develnpis
        them, until as a result new species arise
        TUB OIliaiN OP MAN. t
        By the operation ol these principles all J
        plants and animals are supposed to have
        been derived from ono or more primor- 1
        dial germs. Any complete discussion ol
        Darwinism therefore must range over the r
        whole field of organic existences. But
        by the application of the hypothesis to I
        man the subject is brought directly home
        to ourselves as a raco. The following ia 8
        the conclusion to which Darwin comes. 1
        It is stated in his own language: "We
        thus learu that man is descended from a
        hairy quadruped, furnished with a tail,
        and pointed cars, probably arboreal in its
        habits, and an inhabitant of the Old
        World. This creature, if its whole struc- 8
        turo bad been examined by a naturalist,
        would have been classed among the quod-
        rumana, a* surely as would the common
        and still more ancient marsulllal anima',
        and this through a long line of diversified
        lorms, either from some reptile-like or
        some amphibian-like creature, and this
        again Irom some fish-like animal Id the 8
        dim obscurity or the past we can see that
        tho early progenitor ol all the vertebrata j
        must have been an aquatic animal provld-
        ed with branchia, with the twoiexeannit- S
        cd in tho same individual, and with the J
        mostilmportantjorgansof the body (such t
        as the brain and heart) imperfectly devel-
        oped. This animal seems to have been J
        more like the larvae of our existing ma-
        fine ascidtana than any other known
        form. By the same general process our
        Si12?.lual P?wera fid general moral
        disposition have been undeveloped aocording
        to this theory.
        ,THK QUESTION AT ISSUE.
        Soch ist fair statement of Darwinism J
        and its fundamental principles. In de- S
        elding for or against its truth, the query I
        Is not whether any tuch principles at nat- J
        ural selection and sexual selection obtain o
        in nature. This is not denied by any
        competent ludge. One great service of
        Darwinism is that it bat so distinctly
        hrnntrht Ant thn ftrti w tV tkJ.
        principles. Bat the question U whether c
        tho origin of species is to bo traced to the
        operation of these laws; and especially
        whether by their operation nan has teen
        developed more nearly frbra an ape and
        more remotely from tho lowest terms ol
        animal existence? Are we In body, mind,
        and soul the Qflipring of the beasts, from
        whom We are still sot separated by any
        essential difference of nature? Tho response
        of the writer will be an unequivocal
        negative.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 5 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085523/1907-03-13/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=creation+Darwin+fittest+Spencer+survival</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1900: Darwin’s theory of evolution gains national acceptance and his intellectual pursuits are credited for “progressing the country.” His theories are even used in advertisements to promote furniture sales.</time>
      <text>
        EVOLUTION
        Dr. Ganvllle Lowther.
        About 50 years ago Charles Dar-
        Iwln, the world's greatest naturalist
        and Herbert Spencer, the world's
        greatest philosopher, announced
        their belief In the theory of evolu
        jtlon as an explanation of the order
        of the universe. It startled chrls
        tlans and was opposed with a logic
        learning, eloquence and wit per
        haps unequaled by any discussions
        of the past. It was an age when
        the rack, the gibbet, the cross and
        any other form of physical punish
        ment for opinion's sake had passed
        away, and the appeal was made to
        reason. After fifty years of the most
        careful scrutiny, the severest crit
        icisms, the most eloquent and learn
        ed discussions, by the best scholars
        on both sides, it has won Its way intc
        literature, college text books, lec
        tures, -sermons and the thought of
        the masses, so that but few who lay
        Just claim to scholarship deny the
        truth of its claims and the effort
        now is to harmonize the facts of na
        ture and the experiences of life with
        j its teachings. The evolutionists
        1 themselves are not agreed as to their
        i theories. It is true of them as
        diaries Darwin taught of the strug
        i gles of the various forms of life on
        j the earth for existence, "The strug
        i gle is greatest among the individ
        uals of the same kind; because they
        subsisting on the same food and liv
        ing under the same conditions, come
        ilnto more direct contact and there
        fore direct conflict, with each other
        for the same things." This is true
        of the various denominations of the
        I Christian church. It has been ob
        served in a majority of cases where
        there is in any city or country a
        sharp competition or rivalry between
        denominations of Christians, that
        I those most alike were the greatest
        rivals. So it has been with the ad
        Jvocates of evolution. They have dl
        jvided into three schools of thought
        iviz: Atheistic, who eliminated God
        from the idea of the universe, Deis
        tic, who believe in God, believe that
        He created all things and that evo
        lution was His mode of operation
        but believe that after calling the
        primary substances Into being, and
        placing them under certain laws, He
        left them to work out their destiny
        without interference of guidance;
        Thelstlc, who believe in God, be
        lieve that all material things are
        expressions of His life, energy and
        thought, that He is In them and
        clothes Himself with them and that
        their movements under what we call
        natural law are His modes of oper
        ation. It is this theory of evolu
        tion that we will in a series of ar
        ticles discuss. We do not care to
        discuss the Atheistic nor the Dels
        tic, but to set forth the arguments
        that are generally relied on for he
        support of evolution in general and
        then for Theistic evolution. I
        The arguments used for the sup
        port of evolution are from the var
        ious branches of science. They come
        from the generally accepted facts
        classified under the general heads
        of biology, geology, embryology,
        eoology, astronomy, physiology, an
        thropology, bibliology, history and
        sociology.
        The principal laws In operation
        jare (1) all life struggles for expres
        sion. (2) There is In all forms of
        I life a struggle for existence. (3)
        In the struggle for existence there
        will be the survival of the fittest; in
        other words, the survival of the best
        'adapted to Its environments.
        In the survival of the fitest, the sur
        vlval of the unfit Is Impossible. This
        occurs because there is not room
        or food for all that comes Into being
        and only that which ls best adapted
        Ito the conditions of life can live
        (5) The above facts are responsible
        for what we call nature's law of
        selection and rejection. (6) In all
        the individuals of any species there
        is a tendency to variation. This var
        iation is often in size as in case
        where one Is better fed than anoth
        er. It may be in color, as is some
        times seen the nature of the food Is
        changed. It Is seen ln the thick
        ness of the skin or the color of the
        hair as a result of climate. There
        are also changes of texture .chemi
        cal changes in blood, sap and juices
        of the body on account of soil, water
        and the mental states of animals
        These and other facts, It is argued
        make evolution possible. Tbe ques
        tion then arises, is it probable? In
        the answer to this question may be
        found the evidences from nature as
        seen ln the various fields of invest!
        gat ion. in the phenomena of the un
        Iverse.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 6 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1882-04-22/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Darwin+Darwinism+origin+species</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1882: Darwin dies.</time>
      <text>
        THE DEATH OF DAKWIX.
        Ill* I.He and Works.
        Charles R. Darwin, whose death was announced
        yesterday, was born In Shrewsbury England.
        February 12th, 1809, where he received the
        el?n e its of his education at the local grammar
        school. Mr. Darwin went iu 1S35 to the University
        of Edinburgh, whence, afler two years of
        study, he went to Christ's College. Cambridge.
        At the latter place he took his degree In 1831,
        and the same year volunteered as naturalist
        aboard the Bea-le In its exploring expedition
        nr&lt;>und the world. The publication in
        1839 of an account of his discoveries
        in natural history and geology while on this
        voyage was the beginning of a career
        ol authorship extending through forty-three
        years. A large number of books and papers
        "from his pen on scientific subjects had appeared
        when. in 1859. his fainons work on '-Origin of
        Species by Means of Natural Selection" was
        published. In it Mr. Darwin attempted to
        account for the diverse forms of life on the
        globe on a theory of continuous development
        from simpler structures,without the intervention
        of special creative flats at the origin of each
        species. Large deductions were drawn by
        others frmn the principles laid down, and
        "Dfir.vini.sm" became the subject or hot
        debate. A catalogue of the literature of
        Darwinism contains 86 octave pasres of the
        titles of books and 312 names of authors. In
        1871 appeared ''The Descent of Man, and
        Selection In Kelation to Sex*" a work complementary
        to that on the origin of species. In 1
        this work it was sought to prove that man is
        descended from a lower order of animal?"from
        a hairy quadru|>ed. furnished with a tail and
        Krinted ears, probably arboreal in its habits."
        r. Darwin is not, however, authority for the
        doctrine that man is descended from the monkey.
        so often credited to him. Nor can he be
        considered the father of the doctrine of evolution,
        though he was one of Its principal supporters.
        Iu this, as in other fields, the Greeks
        had anticipated modern thought. The first to
        torin a distinct hypothesis of evolution in modern
        times was Lamarck, a Frenchman, who In
        1809 published his views, and Mr. Herbert
        Spencer was the first to systematize it into a
        philosophy of general application. Mr. Darwin
        was famous for his habit of patient and careful
        investigation, and with little turn for speculation,
        confined himself to his studies iu natural
        history and zoology.
        WHAT DARWINISM IS.
        Reducing the conception to the greatest possible
        precision, Herbert Spencer defines evolu
        tion as a change froin the homogeneous to the
        heterogenec us, from the general to the special^
        from the indefinite and simple to the definite
        and complex. On this hypothesis, the universe
        as it now exist is the result of an almost infinite
        series of chances, "relat ed to and dej enient
        upon each other, as successive steps, or rather
        irrowths. constituting a progress analogous to
        the unfolding or evolving of the parts of a
        growing organism." This process of development
        is considered to be "traceable in the formation
        ut'tiie worlds in space, in the multiplication
        of the types and species of plant3 and animals
        on the globe, in the origination and diverity
        of languages, literature, arts and sciences,
        and in all the changes of human institutions
        and society." In biology, as at present
        employed, evolution is a general name tor "the
        history of the steps by which any living being
        has acquired the morphological and the physiological
        characters which distinguish it.
        No exception is* at this time, known to the
        general law. established upon an immense multitude
        of direct'observations, that every living
        thing is evolved frotn a particle of matter in
        which no trace of the distinctive characters of
        the adult form of that living thing is dlseernable."
        The doctriue of evolution, however, is
        not identical with Darwinism, a term which
        came iuto current use with the publication of
        Mr. Darwin's "The Origin of Species" and
        "The Descent of Man
        Darwinism Is one of the attempts to explain
        the law or manner of evolution, finding the
        cause of the differentiation of species to lie in
        the struggle of the organism to adapt itself to
        the constantly altering conditions of its environment.
        These conditions of external life act
        on plants and animals in their natural state
        with an effect analogous to that by which artificial
        cultivation or breeding by man can change
        and improve the characteristics of the different
        domestic plants and animals. This process of
        the operation of natural circumstances, by
        which those varieties or individuals best adapted
        to their surroundings of climate, station, character
        of soil, food-supply and the number and
        kind of living being competing in the "struggle
        for existence." are preserved ihe longest in life,
        was called by Mr. Darwin "natural selection."
        But he not only saw that the constant battle for
        life going on among living creatures must be a
        "winnowing and improving process, those least
        adapted to the situation giving way before
        those better adapted; it was his merit to
        discover that natural selection is capable of projntciiig
        fitness between organisms and their circumstanccs.
        and of discerning the importance
        of the consequences that follow." Fromthe almost
        general admission of naturalists that natural
        selection was potent in the production of
        varieties in species, Mr. Darwin went further,
        aud held that one species sprang from anoth?r
        "bv al one continued process of slow variation
        and natural selection."
        DARWIN'S THEORY OF EVOLUTION.
        The article on "Evolution" in the Encyclopaedia
        Brltannica, written by Professor Huxley and
        James Sully, has the following regarding Mr.
        Darwin:
        The honor of working out this theory of evolution
        on a substantial basis of fact belontrs to
        England. Of the writers who have achieved this
        result Mr. Darwin deserves the first notice.
        Though modestly confining himself to the problem
        of accounting for the evolution of the higher
        organic forms out of the lower. Mr. Darwin has
        done much to further the idea of a gradual evolution
        of the physical world. The philosophical
        significance of* the hypothesis of natural selection,
        especially associated with Mr. Darwin, is
        due. as Professor Uehnholtz points out, to the
        fact that it Introduces a strictly mechanical conception
        in order to accouut for those intricate
        arrangements known as organic adaptations
        which had before been conceived only in ateleological
        manner..By viewing adaptations as conditions
        of self-preservation Mr. Darwin is able to
        explain how it is that the seemingly purposeful
        abounds in organic nature. In so doing he has
        done much to eliminate the teleological method
        from biology. It is true that in his conception
        of seemiugly spontaneous variations and of correlations
        of growth he leaves room for the old
        manner of viewing organic developments as controlled
        by some internal organizing principle.
        Yet his theory, as a whole, is clearly a heavy
        blow to the teleological method.
        Again. Mr. Darwin has trreatlv extended th?
        scope of mechanical Interpretation by making
        intelligible, apart firora the co-operation of intelligent
        purpose, the genesis of the organic
        world as a harmonious system ot distinct
        groups, a unity in variety, having certain wellmarked
        typical affinities. How greatly this arrangement
        lias helped to support the idea ot an
        ideal plan, we have had occasion to observe.
        Mr. Darwin, in his doctrine of the organic world
        as a survival, refers this appearance of systematic
        plan to perfectly natural causes, and in so
        doing he gives new meaning to the ancient
        theory that the harmony of the world arises out
        of discord. Once more," Mr. Darwin's hypothesis
        is of wide philosophic interest, since it'helps to
        support the idea of a perfect gradation in the
        progress of things. The variations which he
        postulates are alight, If not infinitesimal. and
        only effect a sensible functional dr morphological
        change after they have been frequently repeated
        and accumulated by heredity.
        Mr. Darwin's later work, in which he applies
        his theory of the origin ot species to man, is a
        valuable contribution to a naturalistic conception
        of human development. The mind of man
        in Its lowest stages of development is here
        brought into close Juxtaposition to the animal
        mind, and the upward progress of man is viewed
        as effected by natural causes, chief among which
        Is the action of natural selection. Mr. Darwin
        does not inquire into the exact way in which
        the mental and the bodily are connected. He
        simply assumes tiiat, just as the bodily organism
        is capable of varying in an indefinite number of
        wavs. so may the mental faculties vary indei
        finitely in correspondence with certain physical
        changes. la this way he seeks to account for
        all the higher mental powers, as the use of
        language and reason, the sentiment of beauty
        j and conscience.
        Finally, Mr. Darwin seeks to give a practical
        and ethical turn to his doctrine. He appears to
        make the end of evolution the conscious end of
        man's action, since he defines the general good
        as "the rearing of the greatest number of Individuals
        in lull health and vigor, and with all
        their faculties perfect, under the conditions to
        which they are subject." Further, In his view
        of the future of the race, Mr. Darwin leans to
        the idea that the natural process which has
        effected man's first progress must continue to be
        an Important factor in evolution, and that consequently,
        it is not well to check the scope of
        this process by undue restraints of population
        and a charitable preservation of the incompetent.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 7 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028272/1898-08-24/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Darwin+fittest+Fittest+Herbert+Spencer+Survival+survival+survive+survived</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1898: Firebrand preacher Rev. Talmage catches wind of Darwin’s evolution theory and begins giving disapproving sermons across the nation.</time>
      <text>
        EVOLUTIONISTS.
        Rev.Dr.Talmasre Designates Them
        Out-and-Out Infidels.
        the World' Bent Progress, Ho Declare!
        Hit" Come Through Christianity
        Revelation sod Evolution t'oiu-pared-Ood
        the First Cans,
        of Everything,
        In the following sermon, the ques
        tion of human origin, so prominent
        In religious circles to-day, is discussed
        by Dr. Talmage in his characteristic
        and forcible style.
        At the present time the air is filled
        with social and platform and pulpit
        talk about evolution, and it is high
        time that the people who have not
        time to make investigation for them
        selves understand that evolution in
        the first place, is up anu down, out-
        and-out infidelity; I put upon the witness stand living
        and dead the leading evolutionists
        Ernst Heckel, John Stuart Mill, Hux
        ley, Tyndall, Darwin, Spencer.
        Darwin says that the human hand is
        only a nsn s nn acveiopeu. lie says
        that the human lungs are only a swim
        bladder showing that we once floated
        or were amphibious. He says the hu
        man ear could once have been moved
        Dy xorce oi win just as a norse nits
        its ear at a frightful object. He says
        the human race were originally web-
        footed. From primal germ to tadpole
        from tadpole to fish, from fish to rep
        tile, from reptile to wolf, from wolf to
        chimpanzee, and from chimpanzee to
        man. Now If anybody says that the
        Bible account of the starting of the
        1 human race and the evolutionist ac
        count of tne starting of the human
        race are the same accounts, he makes
        an appalling misrepresentation.
        Prefer if you will Darwin's "Origin
        of the Species" to the Book of Genesis,
        but know you axe an infidel. A for
        myself, as Herbert Spencer was not
        present at the creation and the Lord
        Almighty was present, I prefer to take
        the divine account as to what really
        occurred on that occasion.
        There Is one tenet of evolution
        which it is demanded we adopt, that
        which Darwin calls "Natural Selec
        tion," and that which Wallace calls
        the "Survival of the Fittest." By this
        they mean that the human race and
        the brute creation are all the time im
        proving because the weak die and the
        strong live. Those who do not survive
        because1 they are the fittest. They say
        the breed of Rheep and cattle and dogs
        and men is all the time improving, na
        turally improvirg. No need of God, or
        any Bible, or any religion, but just
        natural progress.
        You see the race started with "spon
        taneous generation," and then it goes
        right oil until Darwin can take us up
        with his "natural selection," and Wal
        lace with his "survival of the fittest,"
        and so we go right on up forever. Beau
        tiful! But do the fittest survive? Gar
        field died in September Guiteau sur
        viving until the following June. "Sur
        vival of the fittest?" Ah! no. The
        martyrs, religious and political, dying
        for their principles, tiielr bloody per
        secutors living on to old age. "Sur
        vival of the fittest?" Five hundred
        thousand brave Northern men march
        ing out to meet five hundred thousand
        brave Southern men, and die on the
        battlefield for a principle. Hundfedi
        of thousands of them went down into
        the grave trenches. We stayed at
        home in comfortable quarters. Did
        they die because they were not as
        fit to live as we who survived? Ah!
        no; not the "survival of tha fittest."
        How lias It been In the families of
        the world? How was it with the child
        physically the strongest, intell actually
        the brightest, in disposition tie kind
        est? Did that child die because it was
        not as fit to live as those of your fam
        ily that survived? Not "the survival
        of the fittest." In all communities
        some of the noblest, grandest men
        dying in youth, or in mid-life, while
        some of the meanest and most con
        temptible live on to old age. Not "the
        survival of the fittest."
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 8 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1906-10-14/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Darwin+Darwinism+fittest+Herbert+Spencer+survival+survive+survived+surviving</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1900 	Darwin’s theory of evolution gains national acceptance and his intellectual pursuits are credited for “progressing the country.” His theories are even used in advertisements to promote furniture sales.</time>
      <text>THE WAR OF EXISTENCE
        it was Charles
        Darwin who advanced the first logical
        I theory accounting for the development
        of the various gcrnif from the. primal
        t germ, and he established his theory by
        a. most comprehensive array of facts
        gathered from all parts of the world.
        New Creation Theories.
        \u25a0 Darwinism met with religious op
        position almost as bitter as that which
        assailed Copernicus -when he first de
        iclared that the world was not flat, but
        round. In recent years, however, we
        have come to realize that the Biblical
        story of the creation should not be
        j literally interpreted any more than
        f certain other parts of the Bible and
        that the idea of creation covering
        •millions of years and accomplished
        I jtritbout violating the laws by which
        nature is now governed is not*one whit
        less marvelous or divine than a crea
        tlon in six literal days.
        Darwin did not claim that the breed
        log or evolving of new species in na
        j ture was conducted in a haphazard
        fashion, but that it was governed by a
        law, workir.gr toward the constant bet
        i terment of the Fpeojps. This law he
        called natural selection, or as Herbert
        Spencer termed it. "the survival of the
        fittest." and it may be briefly explained
        las follows: All nature Is at war. Ti*e
        animal kingdom preys on the vegetable
        kingdom, and the vegetable kingdom
        in turn, chiefly in the form of bacteria,
        preys on the animal kingdom. Aside
        from this there is extensive civil war
        within the animal kingdom. Mammals.
        birds, reptiles, fish and insects all are
        constantly battling with one another.
        In the vegetable kingdom also there is
        a .civil war. the stronger and hardier
        plants overpowering the weaker ones
        and choking them. We little realise
        how fearful is thi« struggle about us.
        It has been estimated that, taking
        en average of all forms of life, 999 in
        j dlvlduGls out of every 1000 die an un
        natural or violent death. Were this
        not so the earth would not be large
        enough to contain all the life that
        *rould b* produced at the end of a few
        years. A single pair of almost any
        animal If exactly adapted to its sur
        rounding* and not Interfered with in
        any way, would in a comparatively few
        jreneratlons overrun the earth. Ele
        phants are the slowest breeders we
        know, yet it has been estimated that if
        every offspring- were permitted to reach
        maturity the living descendants of a
        single pair would, at the end of 750
        years, number 19,000,000 individuals.
        Universal -warfare is thus absolutely
        necessary to keep the living world
        •within bounds. Now the theory of nat
        ural selection holds that only those
        Individuals best fitted for the battle
        of life stand a chance of surviving.
        Generation after generation this war
        hn* wasred. ar.d nature has been killing
        off all those that vrere unfitted to hold
        th«ir own. co that eventually races have
        been evolved which are admirably
        •idapted to their surro-Jndlnge.
        Some animals have earned their
        right to a plsr? in t>.e life of this
        world by developing sreat strength.
        Others owe their existence to the de
        velopment of high speed in getting
        away from their en*iai*.s. An example
        of the latter class is the horse, which
        now has but one toe to each foot,
        whereas fossil remclns Indicate* that
        the present horse has gradually
        evolved from a horse having five toes.
        This evolution is due to the \u2666hoe* animals which rose on their toes
        succeeded best in running away from
        their enemies. The middle. to«t was
        thus brought most, into action, and nat
        'tiral selection encouraged its develop
        ment at the expense of the otner toes,
        which were gradually lost.
        A large part of the animal world
        owes it« survival to the fact that it
        bears co close a resemblance to its
        surroundings that it cannot be readily
        discovered by its enemies. One of the
        most Interesting examples of this is
        Surnlshed by the kalllma butterfly,
        •whidi 1« found In India. This butterfly
        is very brilliantly marked, with bands
        cf bright oranre and blue, but the un
        ider side of Its wings are the exact
        \u25a0 shape of a leaf, with Vela markings,
        in perfect Imitation of the Itaf, *o that
        jwiien It alights oa c branch and folds
        ltc wines it can hardly bo distin-
        Isrulebed. from the Icnv*«. To heighten
        Ithe illusion the lower ends ef the
        '•wins* are -prolonged "lnto a tip, which
        By A. Rus£eH Bond;
        norms a stem Sflr the leaf, while one
        edge of the wings is indented In a
        manner resembling a damaged Jeaf.
        Strangely enough, the wings of those
        butterfliea, which are bred in the fall,
        have a reddish hue corresponding to
        the color of fall leaves. It is said that
        Portuguese explorers of early days
        brqught home the story of a peculiar
        tree which in a windstorm sheds Its
        leaves, but that after, the storm the
        leaves flew back to their places on the
        tree. These animated leaves were
        doubtless the kallima butterfly. An
        other odd Insect, ls the "walking stick,"
        which bo resembles twig that it eas
        ily, escapes notice. The oranee-tlnped
        butterfly Is usually found among .the
        Rowers of the mustard plant, of which
        in the matter of color it Is an exact,
        copy. The "hickory horned devil" is
        an example of another kind of protec
        tion. This catorplllar Is very large,
        sometimes half a foot or more in
        length, and its liorns give it really a
        most ugly appearance, whereas It is
        really a very harmless individual.
        Xow, according to Darwin's theory
        of evolution, tl>es&lt;»- characteristics have
        been gradually developed by natural
        selection in gereration after genera
        tion. That Is, those butterflies which
        most closely resemble loaves and those
        caterpillars which develop the most
        terrifying aspect stood the best show
        of survivinr. while the poorer Imita
        tions were discovered by tneir enemies
        and devoured. The same selection tonic
        place in the next generation rind the
        next, and so on, until. tve now have, an
        almost perfect imitation. Thlsl. how
        ever, docs not mean that the butter-
        fly's battle is now over, for, according
        to the theory, its enemies in their
        search for food have become more and
        more keen and better able to detect
        the differences between the butterfly
        and the leaf.
        This theory of natural selection ls
        very good as far as it goes, "but re-,
        cently new ideas have sprung up. Dar- j
        win's theory required thousands of
        generations to form a new snecles,
        whereas new breeds are artificially de
        veloped in f very few years.. The orl-.
        gin of the American trotting horse, for
        "ianil». dat»s back to the year-H25.
        Breeders and fnnciers do not follow
        the methods which Darwin a««ert«?d
        are employed by nature. If a fancier
        should try to produce a new breed by \u25a0
        selecting those SDecles .which showed;
        slight variation* in the direction of the
        desired breed the bhances are that h«
        would be no nearer his Roal at the end
        of a dozen generations than he was at
        the beplnnlnar. Thrre Is another thing
        which is rather dlfficult.to explain by
        Darwin's theory.
        Consider, the family tree of^a
        butterfly. According:, to. Darwin, .each
        hutterflvjs verv-wllP-iulv different from"
        \u25a0its pa r«nts. -and if; th« difference is "uh
        favor«bl*> that branchVof"the;butt«rnv.
        is. pruned off the. -family tree. .This
        constant, pruning, according'. tn-tsie, 'lie-'
        crimination of nature,' will make a: fan
        jily tree In, which -there wlU* be a stead j
        bent toward one Ideal I bu tterfl y. or. se v-*
        eral Ideal speoiea of butterflies, each
        exactly adapted to, its surroundings.
        Darwin's theory required,
        ages upon ages:, for the life of this
        world, to have developed from the.orig
        inal germ to its present multitude of
        species, while i v De' Vries accounts for
        the species In a much 'shorter, period..
        as Darwin
        claims, we cannot definitely state, for
        Darwia's theory requires tens of thou
        sands of years for the formation of a
        Mingle species, whereas man's life ts but
        four score years and ten. However, the
        evidence* we \u25a0 do have seem ..to be
        against, Darwin's teachings, and. to re
        turn to our original question of th*
        owl and the eg*, recent investigations
        seem to prove that the egg came first:
        for It must have been a mutant of some
        other species of bird which was the
        prototype of the present owl.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 9 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1903-05-03/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=DARWIN+Darwin+fittest+Herbert+Spencer+survival+surviving</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1900: Darwin’s theory of evolution gains national acceptance and his intellectual pursuits are credited for “progressing the country.” His theories are even used in advertisements to promote furniture sales.</time>
      <text>
        THE EASTERN FROSTS.
        "More Letter* of Charles Darwin." t>. Xf
        pie ton Co., New York. Two volumes. Prte*
        95 net.
        The discussion concerning the power of
        nature to "select" raised, of course. th»
        older problem of the extent to which ln
        telligtnt "design" is evident in nature.
        On that point Darwin wrote to Hooker:
        "Your conclusion that all speculation
        about preordination is idle waste of .time,
        is the only wise one; but how difflcuTE it
        is not to speculate. My theology is a
        simple muddle; I cannot look at the uni
        verse as a result of blind chance, yet I
        can see no evidence of beneficent design,
        or Indeed of design of any kind In the
        details. As for each variation bavin*
        been preordained for a special end, I can
        no more believe In It than that the spot
        on which each raindrop falls has been
        specially ordained."
        To any one interested In the develop
        ment of science, every letter in the two
        volumes has something of instruction.
        Even casual readers will find a fund of
        entertainment In the familiar interchange
        of thought among men of such eminence
        and no one will have occasion to grudgs
        the time spent in reading what was writ
        ten either by Darwin or by his friend*.. In Dar
        win's own family the doctrine of the sur
        vival of the fittest was soon familiar even
        to the children. A story is told of one of
        them saying' to his father: "If every one
        would kill adders they would come to
        sting less." Darwin replied "Of course
        they would, for there would be fewer."
        Darwin's use of the phrase, "natural
        selection." gave rise to a good deal of
        confusion and put the supporters of his
        doctrine at a disadvantage In the con
        troversy with their opponents.' and Wal
        lace wrote urging him to adopt the term
        of Herbert Spencer, "the survival of the
        fittest." In advocating the change Wal
        lace wrote: "This term Is a plain ex
        pression of the fact. 'Natural selection'
        is a metaphorical expression of it. and
        to a certain degree indirect and incor
        rect, since, even personifying nature, she
        does not so much select special variations
        as exterminate the most unfavorabls
        ones." In reply Darwin stated that had
        he received Wallace's argument on th«
        point earlier he would have mads use of
        Spencer's phrase, but the revised edition
        of his book was then ready for publi
        cation and it was too late to alter it. Ha
        then went on to say: "As in time tha
        term must grow intelligible, the objec
        tions to its use will become weaker and
        weaker."
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 10 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040340/1898-08-26/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Darwin+Talmage</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1898: Firebrand preacher Rev. Talmage catches wind of Darwin’s evolution theory and begins giving disapproving sermons across the nation.</time>
      <text>
        IT IS INFIDELITY.
        Br. Talmage Takes Stand Against
        Evolution of Darwin and Huxley.
        'Th Theorv nt Involution Oppo.ril to the
        Itlhle and to Ileal hclenre Survival of
        th Fittest Ii n t ytti nml Natural
        selection Mere Words.Dr. Talmage, among other
        things said:There Is no contest between genu
        ine science and revelation.
        At the present time the air is filled
        with social and platform and pulpit
        talk about evolution, and it is high
        time that the people who have not
        -time to make investigation for them
        tiolves understand that evolution in
        the first place is up-and-down, out-and-out
        infidelity; in the second place it is
        contrary to the facts of science, and
        In the third place, that It is brutaliz
        ing in its tendencies.
        Huley suld that nt the
        first reading of Darwin's book he was
        convinced of the fact that teleology
        hud received its death blow at the
        liund of Mr. Darwin All the leading
        ncientlsts who believe In evolution,
        without onu exception the world overf
        arc. infidel. 1 say nothing uguinst in
        fidelity, mind you. 1 only wish to
        define the belief and meaning of the
        .rejection.
        Now, I put opposite each other, to
        dhow thut evolution is infidelity, the
        liible account of how tho human race
        started and the evolutionist account
        of how the human race started, lfiblu
        account; "Clod said, let us make man
        in our image, God created man In Ills
        own image; rnulo nnd female created
        He them." He breathed into him the
        breath of life, the whole story setting
        'forth the idea thut it was not u perfect
        kangorun, or a perfect nnrnng outnng,
        but a perfect limn. That Is the llible
        account. The evolutionist account:
        Away back in the age there were four
        or five primal germs, of seminal spores
        from Which all the living creatures
        Jmve been evolved. (So uway back, and
        thnru you will find u vegetable stuff
        that might be called a mushroom. This
        mushroom by Innate force develops a
        tadpole, the tadpole by Innate force
        develops a pollywog, the poly wog de
        r"bk
        tgspwt
        &amp;2L
        velops a fish, and tho fish by natural
        force develops Into a reptile, tho, rep
        tllo develops Into a quadruped, the
        quadruped develops Into n baboon, the
        balionn develops into a man.
        Darwin suys thnl the human hnnd Is
        only a fish's fin developed He says
        that the human lungs are only a swim
        bladder sliowlug that we once floated
        or were amphibious. He says the hu
        man ear could once have been moved
        by force of will just as n horse lifts its
        ear nt H frightful object. He says tho
        human race were originally web
        footed. From primal germ to tad
        pole, from tadpole to fish, from fish to
        reptile, from reptile to wolf, from
        wolf to chimpanzee, and from chim
        panzee to man.
        Now, If anybody says
        that the llible account of the starting
        of the human raco and tho evolution
        ist account of the sturting of the hu
        man nice, are the same accounts, he
        makes an appalling misrepresentation.
        Prefer, If you will, Darwin's "Origin
        of the Species' to the Itook of Genesis,
        but know you are an lufiel. As for
        myself, os Herbert Spencer was not
        present nt the creation and the Lord
        Almighty was present, I prefer to take
        the divine account as to what really
        occurred on that occasion. To show
        that this evolution is only un attempt
        to eject God nnd to postpone Him, nnd
        to put Hhn clear out of reach, I ask a
        question or two.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 11 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96076641/1899-04-20/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Darwin</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 12 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84031492/1873-07-27/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Charles+Darwin+Natural+Selection+evolution</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1863‐1898: Darwinism is occasionally discussed in newspapers. Scientists begin to lecture on Darwin’s evolution theory, mainly to the scientific community.</time>
      <text>
        DARWINISM STATED.
        DT MABOATIET F. BUOHANAK.
        Bo mnoh is constantly being written obout
        Darwinism, that a plain statement of it, divest
        ed,so for as is possible, of all scioutiflo tonus,
        may not bo unprofitable.
        As America was not called for Us discoverer,
        Darwinism is not original witli Mr. Darwin. Tho
        theory of evolution is venerable as natural sci
        ence. Tho external resemblances of all animals
        was.oa certain to suggest evolution to Anstotlo
        as to Kant; and that it was quite generally be
        lieved by tho scholarly minority In purely Pagan
        days, it Is reasonable to suppose, since ignor
        ance of science and tho absence of defined
        relations between God and Nature must
        havo strengthened Materialistic theories to
        a dogroo boyond our comprehension. Tho ideas
        that provailod wore, however, as Sir Charles
        Lyoll shows, vary vague.
        Evolution was suddenly revived la tho Nebu
        lar Hypothesis of La Place, aud by tho Specula
        tions of Kant in tho latter half of tho eighteenth
        century. In tho beginning of tho nineteenth, La
        marck, Professor of Zoology at tho Qardoa of
        Plants in Paris, surprised the scientific world
        with a volume of testimony in its support, and
        tbQ_book would have been hailed with delight in
        the grove of Acadomus, for Lamarck demon
        strated by evolution that life is a moro physical
        phenomenon, that tho nervous system produces
        Ideas, and that there is no distinct vital principle.
        As Lamarck wont back with hla black thread into
        the labyrinths whore tho Christian idea Is wholly
        absent, so tho latest German disciples of Dar
        win have gono back toLnmorok. The Garden
        of Plants in Paris was tho appropriate field for
        tho constant debate of tho theory. In Its favor
        woro Lamarck, Geoffrey St. Hilaire, and tho
        young Hocks who followed them. To thoir old
        arose a school in Germany, conspicuous among
        whoso advocates woro Okon and tho poet
        Gootho, whoso discovery of tho intermaxillary
        bone in man, aud his volume on evolution of
        plants, although not original iu conception, gavo
        him ns high rank in science as Faust” did in
        literature. Okon furnished the germ of Hux-
        ley's protoplasm, aud ho is entitled to tho dis
        tinction of calling it by oven a harder name—
        primordial mucosity.” But Cuvibr appeared to
        reduce evolution to an absurdity in 1830, despite
        tho number nud the rank of his opponents; nud
        little was said of it, except iu tho satires., until
        Alfred Wallace, tho author of puro Darwinism,
        sent to Loudou, in 1808, tho results of seven
        years' observation in the Malay Archipelago. Iu
        this paper ho onuucratod tho hypothesis of
        Natural Selection, with which evolution, as ad
        vocated by Darwin, must stand or fall. Dar?
        wluism is essentially Natural Selection; and
        this latest rovlval of evolution would, therefore,
        bo moro appropriately called Wallacblsm. The
        honor of tho narao has, somewhat naturally,
        bcou transferred to Darwin, because his first
        publication on evolution was medo simultane
        ously with Wallace’s; and because, having le
        gitimately adopted tho hypothesis of Wallace,
        ho hccamo, nt once, its most eloquent, most per
        sistent, and most successful advocate.
        Evolution assumes that all forms of lifo havo
        boon produced by previous forms, through tho
        constant operation of natural laws. Tho special
        evolution known as Darwinism assumes that
        this constant production and constant modifica
        tion of forms has boon, and, therefore, is being,
        accomplished by natural selection. In a revised
        edition of his “Origin of Species”(lßC9), Mr.
        Darwin is led to admit that natural selection
        may not havo boon tho exclusive means of
        modification, but that it was tho most important
        ono.
        What, then, is Darwinism, or Natural Selec
        tion?
        This: As all animals and plants tend to in
        crease iu geometrical ratio, moro are produced
        than can live; a struggle for existence con
        stantly ensues; tho weakest perish, the fittest sur
        vive. Those survivors, said thus to bo naturally
        selected, transmit, by tho strong principle of in
        heritance, their most striking modifications to
        their offspring. Tho offspring are never precise
        ly like tho parents. Their miuuto modifications,
        modified through many generations, produce, iu
        time, varieties, and varieties, in time, bocomo
        now species.
        To a Pagan, observing merely tbo resemblances
        among all animals, and tho apparent crescendo of
        intelligence from tho lowest up to man, it would
        seem as if tho general theory of evolution would
        bo almost instinctive. Christian theology did
        not impair tho possible genuineness of tbo theo
        ry that is, God was as free to create
        animals derivatively pokntialitcr as to
        create them all absolutely (/ormaWcr);
        but Christina theology contributed nothing to
        ward on affirmative answer to tho problem. It
        was tho revelation of nature —geology, zoology,
        and compavativo anatomy—that was lacking.
        God surely might produce now species remotely
        from individuals ns to produce any animal proxi
        matoly from au older one. Tho question is not
        ono of theology—might Ho do so ?—but ono of
        natural history— Did Ho do so
        It Is a more question of facts. If tho theory
        bo true, it was true iu tbo days of Aristotle, and
        iu tho days of St. Augustino but it could not
        have boon satisfactorily dismissed, much
        less demonstrated, at either period, be
        cause tho progress of mankind in nat
        ural science had not supplied facts enough.
        Had geology uncovered prior to 18110 tho won
        ders it has since revealed, Cuvier would prob
        ably have taken tho other sido for if, witji tho
        knowledge then at hiu command, ho was able to
        believe tbo doctrine of Catastrophes—that, at
        different times, all life had boon destroyed by con
        vulsions, and now lifo been created—ho wo.uld
        have required loss than half of Darwin’s obser
        vation to havo made him a Darwinist.
        Darwin maintains that a preponderance of the
        testimony of nature is in favor of evolution by
        Natural Selection. This claim is not lightly to
        bo overturned. Hut in an article of the length
        of this it is possible only to indicate thoclnssosof
        facts, whoso existence is not disputed, which aro
        offered in support of tho claim.
        A diagram of evolution, iu a condensed, but
        popular, form, would bo this s
        f Living Jelly.
        Worms.
        Onhn‘ hn
        liuentH.
        l^Oyblcru.
        I Fishes,
        Frogs.
        Having Utrillos.
        lilrda.
        (.Mammals (Man).
        What proof is there that tho formless moving
        Jolly became, of itself, a wriggling worm, that
        the worm, in time, made itself into a star-fish,
        that tho star-fish evolved a son-urchin, that In
        sects are tho product of fishes How do we
        know that reptiles begat birds, and when and
        how did creatures without backbone become
        creatures with backbone
        1 It la not claimed that all those questions can
        1 be answered. If they could, there would be no
        room for dobato loft. If thoy could, Agassiz
        would bo ollonfc. If thoy could, tho power of
        Qod In His universe would not bo overturned,—
        confirmed, rather. And, if thoy could, Natural
        Selection would not, necessarily, bo established.
        What Is tho evidence iu favor of natm*al boIoo
        tlon? To make a beginning, it Is necessary to
        assume that lifo, In tho Jolly form, in order to
        preserve Itself, did so uso its modicum of intel
        ligence as to booomo ft worm. Than tho worm,
        to prosorvo Itself against too natural elements
        conspiring against Its life, puts on a coat of
        mall. Mailed-worms arc of recent discovery.
        Thoy constitute tho link between tho ooft
        worms and tho star-fishes. It is necessary
        to assumo also that tho time occupied by
        the soft-worm In becoming a mailed-worm,
        is, so far as human knowledge goes,
        practically infinite. A microscopical class pf
        worms has a caso precisely liko a crab’s, and is
        tho link between crabs and soft worms. Another
        worm which has a mouth, gullet, stomach, and
        intestines, is tbo link between the worms and
        the species of shell animals, A worm inclosed
        iu a bag distinctly resembles a tad-polo, and has
        as much of a backbone as tbo simplest of tho
        backboned creatures. A number of worms, out
        of tho Instinct or doslro of solf-prosorvation,
        cling together, sometimes five of tbom, some
        times forty, and become a star-fish. Thoy unite
        at their posterior ends. A little worm moves
        through tho water.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 13 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045085/1919-12-22/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Charles+Darwin+Natural+Selection+evolution</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1900: Darwin’s theory of evolution gains national acceptance and his intellectual pursuits are credited for “progressing the country.” His theories are even used in advertisements to promote furniture sales.</time>
      <text>
        "MUIATION."
        Orthodoxy received the most stun
        ning blow ever given it, at the hands
        of Charles Darwin, and it is ever on
        the lookout for an opportunity to
        make reprisals. It is only necessary
        for some fledgling to challenge Dar
        win's theory of the origin of coral
        reefs and offer some grotesque as
        sumption in its place, and it is at
        once announced from a thousand pul
        pits that Darwinism,-that enemy of
        God and man-is dead.
        HIugo DeVries, however, could
        hardly be called a fledgling, and the
        supporters of Darwin had real cause
        for apprehension, it would seem,
        when the rumor gained ground that
        no less a person than the Amster
        dam professor had overthrown Dar
        win's theory, and substituted one of
        his own.
        Alas, this latest "death of Darwin
        ism" was no more fatal than its
        numerous predecessors, as the fol
        lowing quotation from DeVries him
        self will show:
        "lily work claims to be in full ac
        cord with the principles laid down
        by l)arwin." And again, "To D)arwin
        was reserved the task of bringing
        the theory of common descent to its
        present high rank in scientific and
        social philosophy." And, "Notwith
        standing all these apparently unsur
        mountable difficulties, (absence of
        experimental evidence since gather
        ed) Darwin discovered the great
        principle which ruiles the evolution
        of organisms. It is the principle of
        natural selection. It is the sifting
        out of all organisms of minor worth
        through the struggle for life."
        The greater part of the adverse
        criticism. aimed at Darwinism ap
        plies only to the extravagant claims
        put forward not to be found in the I
        works of Darwin himself. As we
        shall see later, one of the greatest
        offenders in this respect was no less
        a person than the co-discoverer of
        the selection theory--Alfred Russell
        Wallace."
        Of all the mischievous misconcep
        tions of Darwin's theory none have
        worked so much harm as that which
        regards natural selection as the ac
        tive and efficient cause of evolution.
        Although evolution is an estab
        lished fact, our knowledge of its
        processes are incomplete and imulst
        always remnain so until we have
        solved that most vexed of all biologi
        cal problemls, the "causes of varia
        tion."
        As to the nature of these causes.
        natural selection is dumb. For its
        purpose, variation is simply assumed
        to be a fact, and Darwin's acknowl
        edged ignorance as to how variation
        is brought about is expressed in the
        term "spontaneous variation." Un
        til variation has played its part by
        producing new and various forms,
        selection has no function or office to
        perform. Then it simply decides
        which forms shall survive by destroy
        ing the rest. As Wigand has pointed
        out, selection does not do miiore tlihan
        determine the survival of what is of
        fered to it, and does not create any
        thing new. As DeVries very strik
        ingly puts it, "it is onily a sieve, and
        not a force of nature, ino dilrect caiis'
        of imlproveuellnt, as mally of I)arwill's
        adversaries, aild unfortunately many
        of his followers also, have so often
        asserted. It is only a sieve which
        decides which is to live and which is
        to die With the single steps
        of evolution it has nothing to do.
        Only after the step has been taken,
        the sieve acts, eliminating the unfit."
        MThus Prof. Cope's point that Dar
        win's theodry does not explain the
        "origin" of the fittest, is well taken,
        or as Mr. Arthur Harris puts it, "Na
        tural selection may explain the sur
        vival of the fittest, but it cannot ex
        plain the arrival of the fittest."
        It was around this question of the
        "causes" of variation that the Neo
        Lamarckians and the Weismannians
        fought their battle, the former in
        sisting, as we have seen, that varia
        tion was caused by the hereditary
        transmission of acquired characters,
        while Weismann maintained that
        variation arose solely through the
        comlbining of two portions of differ
        ent individuals, and producing a new
        individual unlike either,-a "varia
        tion" from both. While whatever
        there was of victory fell to Weis
        mann, neither side has experimental
        ly proven its case, and we are still in
        the dark as to the "causes of varia
        tion." Our ignorance is still cloaked
        in the convenient word "spontane
        ous;" to Darwin's "spontaneous va
        riation" we now add DeVries' "spon
        taneous mutation."
        It is another tribute to Darwin's l
        caution and insight that he recog
        nized the possibility of variations:
        arising either suddenly, as DeVriesI
        asserts they do, or gradually as Doe
        Vries denies.
        Not only did Alfred Russell Wal-I
        lace seek to limit the operation of;
        natural selection in certain fields, in
        order to make room for his spiritlnl-I
        ist theories--an adventure which
        failed disnally--but he denied the l
        sudden appearance of new species or[
        sub-species, thereby restricting Dar
        winisum, as he understood it, to the
        origin of new species by the gradual
        accumulatlon of those almnost imper
        ceptible variations usually described
        as "fluctuations." WVhtever conflict
        there may be hctween Darwinism and
        miutation must be ascribed to 'Wal
        lace. As DeVries clearly recognizes,
        Darwin is in no way responsible.
        "Darwin." says DeVries, "recognized
        both lines of evolution."
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 14 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036012/1899-01-16/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Charles+Darwin+Natural+Selection+evolution</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 15 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022957/1882-04-27/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Charles+Darwin+Natural+Selection+evolution</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
  </results>
</topic>