<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-exercise-tips</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-08-31/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>August 31, 1902: The latest exercise fad comes in the form of barrel rolling—using a barrel for fitness purposes.</time>
        <text> Rolling A Barrel For Health
          THE latest fad in the line of
          physical culture Is barrel
          rolling. Nowadays both men
          and women may be found
          who daily make It a duty to
          exercise for a certain length
          of time with a common, everyday barrel.
          Corpulent people may now rejoice, for
          this latest acquisition to the catalogue of
          health and figure improvement methods
          has been proven to do everything claimed
          for it.
          Thin, sickly people may also join th*
          chorus, for it not only reduces flesh with
          fleshy individuals, but makes flesh atd
          muscle. Improves the breathing apparatus,
          invigorates the action of the heart and
          brings about a graceful carriage.
          All the properties needed consist of ,a
          small barrel or keg. The exercise may
          be taken in a bedroom, although out of
          doors is better.
          Barrel-rolling, like all other kinds of
          exercise, must be taken In regulated!
          doses. The man who goes at It like ha
          woulJ to a fire will realize little real bene
          fit He will derive the greatest who
          makes it a business as well as a pleas
          ure, begins on a small scale and works up
          to his greatest capacity gradually and
          naturally.
          The exercises given in the following are
          prepared especially for those who are
          earnest erough to have a try with this
          new method and who will be really con-
          scientious in their work.
          For the first exercise the barrel Is laid
          on the floor on its rolling surface.' The
          body should be so arranged that only the
          tips of the fingers and the palms of the
          hands touch the floor, the greater weight
          of the body ing borne by the keg. The
          body should then be propelled forward,
          the hands being used for that, purpose.
          The legs and arms must be kept as rigid
          'as possible, and the feet must not be
          moved until the barrel, moving naturally
          downward, reaches the knee. Now re
          verse the movement, pushing backward
          with the hands until the barrel is rolled
          up to the arms. This exercise should be
          repeated several times. It is the most
          important of all for reducing the weight,
          although It tends equally with the fol
          lowing, others to develop the arms,
          broaden the chest and make the abdom
          inal muscles flexible.
          The second exercise Is practically the
          reverse of the.first. Rest with the back
          en the cask this time. Place the arms
          downward, and rest the heels on the floor
          —the heels only, mind; no other part of
          the legs. In order to get the barrel in
          motion, move the arms alternately as far
          forward as possible. The cask will then
          reach the heels, the body being raised
          from the floor. As before, reverse this
          movement and "bring the cask up to the
          small of the back, still taking care to
          keep the legs stretched out straight.
          "While performing this exercise, keep the
          lungs well filled, the stomach drawn in
          and the chest expanded. When the keg
          is up to the part of the back referred to
          lift th* arms from the floor and extend
          them along the side of the body.* with
          open palms on hip. Keep this position as
          long 1 as possible without strain.
          The third exercise is a pretty one. It
          la performed by lying with the left side
          of the body, just above the hip, resting
          'on the" barrel. If you wonder why, in the
          picture, the right hand is upraised, you
          will know as soon as you begin the exer
          cise. vlt is to balance the body, for the
          feet qnly touch the floor. "With your left
          hand pull your body forward as far as
          possible until the feet can be raised from
          the floor. This is not as easy as it looks,
          but a little perseverance will manage it.
          Then move back to the former position.
          .When this exercise has been fairly well
          jnnEtered, repeat it. but by lying on the
          richt side of the body and holding the
          hft hand in the air. This exercise is
          liable \to strain the body if it is perse
          vered In with too much zeal, and care
          should, therefore, be taken to be conser
          vative.
          The fourth movement consists of lying
          with the back on the cask, the arms, at
          first, folded. This, while appearing to be
          similar to exercise number two, is quite
          rent, for here the feet only are U3ed
          to force the body over the barrel until
          the latter has reached the shoulders anl
          back of the head, when the arms are then
          placed at the side, as in the illustration.
          As in the second exercise, do not neglect,
          while in this position, to keep the stom
          ach drawn in and the chest expanded. No
          person with a weak back should prac
          tice this movement, for the strain upon
          the neck is rather severe, and an acci
          dent might be attended with unpleasant
          consequences.
          The fifth is a fine exercise, easy, grace
          ful and at the same time beneficial. Stand
          straight up, with the feet together, stom
          ach in. chest out, shoulders square, and
          head back. Place the small barrel first
          upon the toes. Bend down and grasp hold
          of it. and bring it, not too quickly, up to
          the waist line and thence above the head.
          Hold it there for a second or two, being
          sure that your figure is perfectly
          straight. !V
          A good method of regulating the breath
          ing apparatus, the functions of which are
          rather severely drawn upon in this exer
          cise, is to count, one, two, three, four,
          etc., at each swing-up of the cask, and
          inhale air through the nostrils only at
          the even numbers, two, four, six, and so
          on.
          The sixth exercise follows naturally
          from the fifth. Raise the cask from the
          toes to the chin line, still keeping the
          body rigid, though the legs may bo
          stretched a trifle apart, to preserve the
          equilibrium, and swing the barrel to the
          right and the left alternately. Follow
          the same rules about breathing as in the
          preceding movement.
          The next exercise, the seventh, is one
          which can be done expertly only by the
          man who has Indulged in this form of
          barrel-rolling exercise for some time, but
          so many parts of the body are brought
          into play during It that nothing should
          be neglected to bring one's salf to the
          pitch of necessary ability. Stretch the
          legs so that the feet are apart about
          twenty-four inches. Then swing the bar
          rel down briskly between the legs and
          Tiigh up over the head, bending the back
          and allowing the knees to bend slightly
          forward as the barrel passes under the
          body.
          Go slowly about this exercise, for It is,
          as has been intimated, no small strain
          over the whole of the body, and it is not
          one to be performed by the weakling. Yet
          the weakling can easily get to it by prac
          ticing the previous exercises. It is a
          matter only of degree. Keep the lungs
          partly filled as you exhale, because it la
          neceesary to use the thoracic and ab
          dominal muscles, for the Improvement of
          which this exercise has been partly de
          signed.
          The cask ls placed In a novel position
          for the eighth exercise—as far a? the
          body Is concerned. That Is. one must re
          cline upon it stretched lengthwise in the
          tame direction as the body. Place th?
          hands on the floor In front and let the
          toes, the tips of which touch the ground,
          support your legs.
          Now roll from left to right, or the bar
          rel from right to left, according to the
          way of looking at It. Refrain from be
          coming too enthusiastic at this pastime,
          or the barrel will slip away from under
          you and you may flatten your face
          against the surface of the floor or
          ground.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1906-06-24/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>June 24, 1906: Women are encouraged to canoe, walk, golf, swim, and play tennis with both hands over vacation.</time>
        <text>How to Make The Most Of Your Vacation (text is fudged due to bad scanning)
          no better panacea for ills, real I
          supposed, than judicious exercise J
          a the open.
          I Growing girk and -women living
          to'ns or closely confined in city of
          .fctt should endeavor to obtain
          in the open air aa possible, and to
          wmmer sports during their holidaya
          '"Wj anemic, undersized, under-wcigiit-,"ou(5
          cornea are the ones that most
          wre'.B mapc healing.
          Riificient exercise tho Bvstem becomes
          the Utah Boft and flabby, the skin
          Tinkled, the muscles lax and easily
          iitS D m1,ow" and one's whole being
          d it v"n( anbition on account of the
          ffiWj laws.
          u f outdoor exercise ib cultivated
          f "npoaiblc to give it up. Even in
          bil Birls rcul lar8c hnlla for lcn'
          U iT muncles wll not become lax and
          itg firmness.
          OUTDOOR EXERCISE A HABIT
          I rcgUrd exercise in the open light
          it tlft game or croquet or walk a
          WJiMl are dcad tire(1- noor thj6s
          tilt Untii tue' Rtir un a Healthy
          1 educes vigor and energy by cor-
          ka 0r narrow-chested, others have
          .-MVt r Slr l P Incasurcinent is deficient
          W'tat defects, too, but never
          m 7 be cured, and a splendid mimcular
          -e'
          i
          development induced by exercise bet fitted ior
          individual requirements.
          And when the caves begin to turn in tnc au
          E artificial beautifies arc no more. Ihe
          fcSfhy Sow on check, the sparkle of her eye,
          he natural sheen of her locks, her broadened
          ehea lar arms and limb, arc the souvenir
          of her healthy, natural life in the open.
          H around exercise is capital; no one will din
          put c that, but it is possible that certain parts
          of your anatomy require further development,
          thai may be pained by certain forms of exercise
          that bring muscles into play.
          For example, swimming develops the rniiFclc
          of the chest, arms, limbs, and abdomen, but its
          greatest benefit lies in its powcrB of increasing
          the circulation through reactionary causes. Row
          ing, also brings into active condition both nius-J
          cle aud blood.
          Tennis is a diversion more likely to bo within
          reach of the average city bred girl than any
          other, lln's will develop tho muscles of her
          arms, particularly the forearm, to a surprising
          extent. -But here let nic whisper a note of warn
          ing; play with both hands, or the one that wicldi
          the racquet will cause the left arm to have th
          appearance of being lop-sided.
          When a girl is ambidextrous she can keep tho
          development of both t-ides equal. And though
          it may be tedious and uninteresting for a good
          player to start all over again by playing villi tbu
          left hand, it is worth all the trouble in the end.
          In golf both hauda are used, and the mighty
          swings not only stretch the musclcn of the arms,
          but the chest and back as well. Add to this tho
          benefit of walking over tho links.
          Horseback riding is a most excellent form of
          exercise, advised by doctors and physical cultu
          rists alike.
          It brings into play all the muscles, Fends the
          blood thundering through the veins aud assured
          ly gives a woman self-confidence, self-control as
          Hi'do issues. A couple of months' riding will do,
          more -to' develop the bust than a year of massaging-
          Your bones will ache and your muscles vnll be
          eore,' but cheer up. Any kind of exercise taken
          when you are uuaccustdmcd to it will produce
          imilar results.
          The benefits of walking arc well known. This,
          the most common form of exercise, is recommend
          ed for fleshy people who wish to part with their
          superfluous flesh, but the lean kind need not
          worry- When walking is not too strenuously a
          plied it is a most excellent all around exercise,
          made doubly beneficial when the practice of cor
          rect breathing becomes a part of your regime.
          Remember that your exercise in the fresh air j
          will have but little value unless you. take deep 'j
          vitalizing breaths', filling your lungs to their ca- !i
          pacity.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1906-11-25/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>November 25, 1906: Women with cold feet are encouraged to make running motions while standing still, tiptoe up and down, and lie on the floor and move legs as though running a wheel.</time>
        <text>EXERCISES TO KEEP THE FEET WARM
          M"^^ ANY women in winter suffer habitually
          from cold feet.
          ■pets This is not a vulgar slangism, if you
          luaßsl I please, but an undesirable physical
          condition, known also to men.
          Nine times out of ten women so af
          flicted hold sedentary positions, where there is
          little chance for exercise, and as the average wo
          man is too tired at night to walk a dozen squares
          after dinner, she goes to bed with cold extremi
          ties.
          All the inner Roles, woolen hosiery nnd pee
          per sprinkled in the bottom of trie shoes will not
          temporary relief.
          The only way to effect its cure is to Ect right
          down to the seat of the trouble, to improper cir
          culation, the bane of ho many women's troubles.
          Besides the acute annoyance of having cold feet
          this condition indicates that you ore not in good
          health, that your constitution has become weak
          ened, that your heart is none too strong and that
          in consequence tlm circulation is languid.
          And what some women would consider the
          "unkindest cut of all," i* that a clear, unblem
          ished complexion is absolutely impossible with a
          sluggish circulation.
          Nothing that fifty doctors can give you will so
          materially help you as the following exercises,
          which draw tlie blood to the feet and stir up an
          all around good circulation.
          If you are a chilly, bloodless creature ilon't
          pamper yourself and keep close to the fireside.
          No mutter how cold the day, j;o out and take an
          airing, and walk, walk, miles if you can. Breatne
          deeply as you go, holding your breath until you
          count 25, then slowly exhale. Throw your
          shoulders bad-, chest out, abdomen in; there you
          have the correct position. Learn to make cor
          rect breathing habitual.
          Sleep in a well ventilated room. There is noth
          ing worse for your health than a stuffy, ill-venti
          lated room in which to sleep. Eat only whole-
          some food and be sure to include such necessary
          things in your diet us fresh fruits, olive oil with
          your meals and after them, with grt^s juice whe
          taken as a tonic, and distilled water.
          EXERCISE I.
          Place lice's together, toes apart, take a deep
          breath. Then raiie heels from the floor as high
          us you can. standing on tiptoe. Repeat £he ac
          tion witlioir taking hold of any object; and so
          continue as long as possible, without making
          your muscles too tired,
          Do it ten times if you can. Of course, it will
          make the muscles of your limbs tired, but it soon
          wears off. Increase the nuiuber of times at every
          exercise and you will soon get up to 25.
          I sure to take deep, full breaths while doing the
          exercise.
          EXERCISE 11.
          Standing in the same position put your weight
          on the heels and raise toes. Repeat, breathing
          deeply.
          EXERCISE 111.
          Women who are afflicted with any organic dis
          ease, especially heart trouble, should only take
          up the following exercise under the supervision j
          of a physical culture teacher or doctor.
          Take correct position, heels together, toes'
          apart, hands on hips. Take a full deep breath.
          Now you arc required to do a funny little stunt-
          Stnrt on a run, but stand just wnere you ore
          lienil you kners far forward, then put left foot
          out in front, then right. Repeat exercise without
          allowing the herl.« to reneh the floor. Hold the
          breath for a second, expel. Continue the motion
          Until you fen] tired, rest, and resume it.
          EXERCISK IV.
          Place both hands over the head, locking the
          thumbs together. Take a deep breath, rsieiug
          your chest hign, and walk about yoxir room on
          tiptoe; hold the breath for a few neconds, eipel,
          take another, hold, expel; and bo walk about the
          apartment until you are quite tired. Be sure to
          keep your arms stretched high above your head.
          When it possible to do thia exercise during
          the day besides morning and night, so much the
          better.
          EXERCISE V.
          Lie on the floor or on a very hard couch; for
          in this exercise there must be no yielding under
          the body. Take a deep inhalation through the
          nose, raising the abdomen as you do so. Then
          still holding the breath, force the chest upwards,
          letting the abdomen down. Repeat movements,
          and exhale through your nose while the chest is
          raised. Practice until capable of doing move
          ments five times without letting your breath out,
          abdomen nnd chest up alternately.
          EXERCISE VI.
          Here ia another good exercise taken recum
          bent position, lie on the floor, take a deep
          breath, raißO the abdomen and feet without bend
          ing tbe knees. When they are nearly perpendic
          ular, bend knees and move limbs as though mov-
          tag Ihe pedals of n bicycle. Be careful to turn
          tile toes up and down an you mnke the revolu
          tions. Continue for a minute then rent, Bnd con
          tinue agnin, taking full inhalation* while exer
          cising.
          EXERCISK VH.
          Stand erect, take a deep breath. Bend knee of
          right limb and try to touch shoulder with it. D
          thin ten times, breathing, holding breath, and ex
          pelling; then take up exercise with left limb.
          There is considerable work attached to these
          exercises and some may be considered vigorous;
          but they will certainly do the work for you if
          faithfully followed.
          For invalids and elderly people T should advise
          having the feet and ankles rubbed and kneaded
          with the bare hand, another's hnnds are bent;
          they will impart new strength. Press the hands
          against the iect ju»t as hard as the patient can
          stand, do this for fifteen minutes a short time
          before retiring. Just after a hot mustard bath
          is good. A good cold cream bein^ used occasion
          ally in place of the bare harirlc
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-07-28/ed-1/?sp=38</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>July 28, 1907: Exercise is recommended for girls because nowadays girls should be “strong and ruddy,” whereas before they were expected to be “frail” and “delicate.”</time>
        <text>EXERCISE FOR GIRLS
          T* I IIERK is no disputing the fact that
          girls need exercise as much as boys,
          and the day has long gone by when
          I a frail, delicate, white-faced girl
          was regarded as being a model of
          femininity.
          Girls are no longer afraid of being strong
          and ruddy They are beginning to thoroughly
          understand that good health is not the pre
          rogative of one sex, and that good health can
          only Be preserved by exercise.
          It is true that all girls cannot exercise as
          they should. Some are so situated that ev
          ery hour from sunrise to sunset has its duties,
          each one confining; others inherit ailments
          that prevent walking or running, and a few
          perhaps are restrained by false ideas oi
          dtcorum from developing their frames by ex
          ercise. But the majority remain in a state
          of ill health simply because they will not ex
          ercise, or do not know how to set about it.
          Perhaps many do not know what exercise
          really is. A carriage ride is not exercise,
          neither is housework nor any exacting labor,
          no matter how hard it may be. II that were
          bo, the blacksmith would be the most long
          lived of men; but statistics prove otherwise.
          Gymnastics are not always exercise in the
          true sense. No pennnncnt good can come of
          ¦winging clubs or dumb bells in a close
          room, unless followed by a brisk walk and
          a bath. Croquet is exercise, and lawn tennis
          is best of all. But. neither •of these games
          is beneficial if played for fashion's sake.
          The girl who gets herself up in a "stun
          ning" costume and plays for the effect on
          the spectators, might as well be reading a
          novel in the parlor. Loose clothing, com
          mon sense shoes and an ardent desire to win
          tin 1 game, are the requirements for exercise.
          Mowing is another capita] exercise for girls,
          if they can overcome their natural timidity;
          and swimming is better sitll. It is not gen
          erally known that girls swim more gracefully
          than boys and learn quicker. Both these ex
          ercises have an additional value in the fact
          'that they may some time preserve life.
          Pitching quoits is beneficial exercise, and
          trains the eye and hand. Badminton, a vari
          ation of the old game of battledore and shut
          tle-cock, is a game which forces all the
          muscles of the legs and arms into action,
          nml puts the players into a glow of pleasura
          ble excitement.
          Where good roads abound, cycling is an
          exercise timt is beneficial, if not carried to
          excess. No girl should attempt to ride more
          than twenty miles a day: to ride more is re
          ducing exercise to work. It is injurious to
          try to pee how far or fast you can go in a
          given time. Take it moderately and you will
          ?ever tire of your wheel.
          Lastly comes walking, and I think that is
          the ben( exercise of all. •It is the simplest
          of all exercises, yet there are some rules to
          be observed if you would get the greatest
          bnefit. The best time to walk is before nine
          in the morning or after five in the after
          noon. Begin with a mile walk every morn
          ing or evening and increase the length until
          you can cover ten miles a day?
          Walk in the country if possible; if that is
          impracticable, choose wide streets, those nneci
          with trees preferred. Mind how you walk.
          Square your shoulders, expand your chest,
          and hold your head high. Keep the mouth
          closed when not talking, and breathe through
          the nose. Step out easily and firmly, letting
          the ball of the foot strike the ground first.
          Vary the location of the walk each day if
          possible, and exercise the ere and mind as
          well as the body. Never let the walk become
          a drudgery.
          When you return home take a Rponge bath,
          a vigorous rubbing, a cool gown, a glass of
          milk and a nap. If you do not feel healthy,
          happy and wise after a month of this exer
          cise, you may be sure that yoii have some
          chronic disease.
          In summing up, remember that all exer
          cise, to be beneficial, must be taken in the
          open air. You may amuse yourself over a
          billiard table or a game of cards, or you may
          have a lovely time in a ball room, but you
          cannpt develop your form or add an ounce to
          your weight unless you breathe fresh air.
          The simplest exercise in the open air will do
          you more good than the most elaborate gym
          naßtics"in a closed room.
          You must also bear \p mind that exercise
          must be continuous to be beneficial. Once
          you get yourself in good condition, you must
          keep there by constant exercise.
          Do not look upon this as a task: with in
          creaaing strength the exercise will be a posi
          tive pleasure, which you will not think of
          shirking. You will be proud of your ability,
          arid your ambition will grow with your
          achievements. Try it for one year, and see
          if I am not a true prophet.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1911-12-31/ed-1/?sp=21</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>December 31, 1911: Women are encouraged to keep fit by lifting imaginary pianos and removing corks from bottles.</time>
        <text>How to Keep Fit
          An indoor exercise that will help
          to keep you ''flt" Is the imaginary
          motion of lifting a piano, and the
          other of drawing a cork from a bot
          tle. Hold the bottle between your
          knees and pull and pull at the
          tightly driven cork. Both of these
          contract the muscles of the abdo
          men.whlch In most women are flac
          cid and fall, giving them a balloony
          appearance. Another exercise for
          this purpose is to hold the knee
          firmly by both hands, drawing It up
          on a level with the waist Stand
          thus for as long as you can. Then
          shift to the other foot and repeat
          exercise. This, like the two fore
          going exercises, make tho mus
          cles of the abdomen firm; form
          lng a natural corset and giving
          a naturally straight front Also
          they reduce the hips.
          walking and the exercises I
          have described, combined with
          deep breathing and the baths I
          have mentioned, and plenty of
          rest every woman knows how
          long she must sleep to awaken
          refreshed will keep her beauti
          fully "fit"
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-10-25/ed-1/?sp=22</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-07-13/ed-2/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-01/ed-1/?sp=27</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-28/ed-1/?sp=13</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>September 28, 1915: An American 1915 beauty displays a stretching exercise that is “better than medicine.”</time>
        <text>BETTERS THAN MEDICINE! 1915 BEAUTY SHOWS. STRETCHING EXERCISE FOR HEALTH
          Exercise is "better than medicine. If
          one would keep healthy. Better still
          exercise brings beauty and grace. It's
          the. best sort of tonic to keep the fig
          ure from "sagging" or "settling" r
          the dread of all women who care
          about their appearance.
          Exercise that gives the spine and
          the abdominal muscles something to
          do are best and America's famous
          1915 beauty, Kay Laurell, of "Zieg
          feld's Follies," is pictured in the ac
          companying illustration in one posi
          tion of a good stretching exercise.
          To do this exercise lay- flat on the
          back, and then keepingthe knees stiff
          raise the legs to the position shown
          in the Illustration. Hold for a count
          of five, then lower and relax. Then
          -repeat five times taking deep "stom
          ach" breaths with the exercise.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020645/1904-12-11/ed-1/?sp=72</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>No timeline found</time>
        <text>THE BEAUTY QUEST
          Exercises for the development of the arms, the shoulders and
          THE CHEST—YOU MAY' REVERSE THE OLD SPANISH PROVERB IF YOU
          CHOOSE.
          Hear what the Spanish says "No
          /woman under thirty has a beautiful
          ihrm, and then she has ceased to care.’1
          It Is very pessimistic, but worthj
          of consideration. Reverse It and form
          !/or yourselves another proverb: "The
          [■woman under thirty may have a beau
          jtlful arm and after that ahe may be
          glad of one."
          Nature, unaided. Is not often in
          clined to round out an arm to Its full
          [perfection In youth. Even a compar
          atively stout girl is inclined to be
          /Slender between wrist and shoulder.
          (But exercise and massage will give
          'the desired outline.
          The exercises which you take for
          arm development extend in their ben
          leflcial effects to shoulders and chest,
          thus rounding out the upper part of
          (the figure and giving symmetry. It
          would be Impossible, eveu if you wish
          ed to Increase the arms alone by
          [movements and leave the shoulders
          /unaffected. Fortunately, no one cares
          Co do so, for the "chesty" girl of the
          /modern athletic life has come to stay.
          «nd no matter how fashions change
          'you will notice that her healthy vigor
          ‘remains the same—admired year in
          land year out.
          f A beautiful forearm is extremely
          Irate, even though there be sufficient
          ‘/plumpness between shoulders. and el
          bow. It should be well rounded at
          (the elbow, from there taper down to
          'a slender wrist. Most women have a
          /forearm that is almost straight. It
          books like a slat.
          Indian clubs do more than anything
          /else to develop this particular part
          (of the arm. although their good work
          ‘does not cease there. They bring
          Unto play the wrist muscles. They are
          /twisted constantly, and this motion is
          (made by the muscles of the lower
          farm. When the broad savings of the
          clubs are Introduced, then the shoul
          V ders and other parts come In for their
          ^.a^are of the gain, but the twirling
          Ss especially designed for the fore
          arm muscles. Work with the clubs
          (fifteen minutes at night and fifteen In
          She morning.
          I A simple exercise for the same part
          cf the arm is this: Let the bacys of
          the forearms rest upon the hips, draw
          ing the elbows back so that the arms
          Wich the hips near the wrists^ J 1“
          hands are palms up. In this Poslt1'’"
          clench and open the fists, spreading
          the fingers as you do so.
          To vary the monotony of this mo
          tion. stretch the arms forward h°*‘:
          sontally, palms down. Clench and
          open the fists.
          i For the upper arm. use this motion.
          Raise the arms laterally until the el
          hows are at shoulder level. Let the
          'tips of the fingers rest lightly upon the
          shoulders. Now force the elbows for
          ward and backward as far as you can.
          Drop the arms naturally against the
          aides. Bring up the forearms against
          l the chest until they stand vertically,
          the edges of the palms forward, the
          lingers straight and pointed upward.
          Thrust the arms upward straight above
          the head. To bring them back to the
          ‘original position, force them obliquely
          «back and slowly let them fall to the
          Bides again. Perform this exercise In
          four counts: One, to raise the fore
          arms: two, to thrust upward; three and
          four, to let the arms fall.
          An exercise used by Uncle Sam’s
          Soys In blue is worth everything to
          Jncle Sam's girls, as well, If they
          •ould QU the hollows that lurk about
          undeveloped shoulders. I^et the arms
          fall at the sides. Raise them laterally,
          palms up, and bring them to a grace
          ful circle above the head, ending by let
          ting the finger tips louch the top of the
          head. The difficult part of this exer
          cise Is to bring the backs of the fingers
          against each other, while they meet on
          top of the head, at the same time forc
          ing the elbows back. When you have
          learned to do this, forcing the elbows
          back Into tje same plane as the body,
          then It will be good for you to hold the
          position for several seconds. You will
          feel your chest forced forward under
          the strain. To return, separate the
          hands, turning the finger tips outward,
          and let the arms describe a graceful
          circle to the sides again.
          A very old exercise, one used by
          laborers to keep warm as well as by
          women to round their shoulders, Is
          simply swing the arms back and forth
          outstretched, bringing the palms to
          gether behind you as high as you can
          make them reach.
          A splendid shoulder exercise Is this:
          Raise the arms laterally, palms up.
          until they are at shoulder level. Keep
          ing them outstretched, describe circles
          with them, holding the palms always
          up and never letting the arms pass In
          front of the line of the breast.
          Raise the elbows laterally to shoul
          der level, letting the fingers rest light
          ly upon the chest. Throw the arms
          back until each entire arm Is out
          stretched laterally, palms forward. You
          must force them In such a way that
          you can feel the chest pressed forward.
          Raise the chest at the same time.
          Let the arms fall at the sides. Raise
          them laterally until the elbows are at
          shoulder level, the finger tips resting
          upon the shoulder, then let them fall
          to the sides again. Do this lightly ten
          times, then imagine a heavy weight
          in the hands, and lift it powerfully to
          the shoulder. Go through this ten
          times.
          Stretch the arms forward at should
          er level, palms laid together. Separ
          ate them, turning the palms down
          ward, and move the arms back until
          they are outstretched literally, still at
          shoulder level. Let fall to the sides
          slowly and repeat.
          For the especial development of the
          upper arm. resort to dumbbells. Al
          most all of the elementary dumbbell
          exercises have some effect upon this
          part of the arm. The newer school
          of extension work with dumbbells is
          not devoted to this particular develop
          ment, but the old-/ashioned exercises
          are. for the most part, including? chest
          and shoulder work. Do not use the
          heavy Iron bell, however, as the old
          school often prescribed. A two-pound
          wooden bell Is best.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1893-03-02/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93057084/1912-10-17/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1937-07-30/ed-1/?sp=21</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>No timeline found</time>
        <text>
          Business women who sit at their
          desks all day and have little oppor
          tunity to exercise have more of a h;p
          problem than women in the home, who
          can get about if they like, play a
          round of golf, walk, exercise. Business
          women should stand as much as they
          can, walk, pick up their own papers
          instead of having the office boy do
          it. There's the danger of having the
          spread attributed to old age instead of
          sedentary work, you know.
          From what I've seen of the Fall i
          silhouette a firm, even but feminine j
          line will be the vogue. Exaggerated
          hips won't be in the running at all.
          There's consolation, though. In the S
          fact that there is still ample time to j
          roll the excess pads away. j
          Summer is so conducive to exerrpe. j
          The casual clothes, the Ioosp slacks, j
          shorts, culottes, make exercise easv. j
          If you are at the beach you can j
          exercise, squat, jump—it's done, and j
          no one thinks anything of it. j
          You can lie right on thp sand, op i
          i'our back for on floor or mati. hate i
          the shoulders touching the floor, mat
          ir sand. Arms out at shoulder level
          at right angles to rest of body. Now
          raise right leg and bring it over, trying
          to touch the tips of the left hand. I
          Repeat a few times and then try it i
          left leg to right hand. I
          The bark roll is one you ran do j
          (good for you If you rani if you want
          to attract an admiring crowd and
          whittle hips down at one and the
          same time. It is a little difficult for
          oeginners. But. with practice cornea
          finesse. Same position on back, j
          shoulders touching floor, arms at sides, I
          palms down. Raise both legs off the i
          floor and draw them back overhead. j
          5ee if you ran touch your toes to the i
          floor back over your head.
          This exercise does wonders for hips,
          strengthens the bark, flattens the
          abdomen.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1904-06-19/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>