  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-electric-chair/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032490/1887-04-17/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Death+Dynamo+Electric+Chair+Capital+Punishment&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.267,-0.077,1.535,1.535,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          "If the law i3 changed from hanging to
          death by electricity then it should and
          would bo made to include women as well as
          men. Any discrimination between the sexes
          would make the law unconstitutional."
          ""Would there b3 any objection to execut
          ing women with electricity.'"
          "No, sir; there would not. I think there
          would no longer be tho samo prejudico that
          thcro is now, because Imaging is a poor way
          of inflicting the death penalty."
          "How would you uso electricity?"
          "Just seo here," said Dr. Southwick,
          jumping up and .seating himself, in an arm
          chair. "Tho condemned man cansifc natur
          ally in a chair like this, placo his liands on
          the metal arms and converse with those
          around him. Tho metal plates would ba
          connected with a powerful d3namo and at
          tho proper moment somebody in another
          room would press a button, closo tho current
          and tho fatal shock would pass through tho
          body of the subject. Tho chargo would go
          straight through tho heart and lungs and
          penetrate the system, death instantly result
          ing. Tho expense of the apparatus with which
          to execute by electricity ia this city would
          bo about $150. Connection cculd bo made
          with the electric light station, and tho ex
          pense of an execution thereafter would bo of
          littlo consequence. It would not cost any
          more than a cigar to kill a condemned man
          after that. It would not bo necessary to
          maintain extensive and powerful machinery
          in nil tho prisons, anil it would bo vastly
          cheaper than hanging."
          "You believe then in electricity?'
          "Electricity Ls tho coming power. Death
          is instantaneous and tho body i not defaced.
          There is not tho morbidness of n hanging,
          which is a relic cf barbarism. Just seo a
          recent execution here Heman's I think it
          was when tho hanged man breathed fifteen
          minutes afteV the drop fell. If that is in
          stantaneous death then I would rather havo
          u lingering death."
          "Have you considered jwisons as a means
          of executing criminals''
          "Prussic acid has been raggested, but
          neither that nor garroting has met with any
          favor. A few havo advocated tho guillotine,
          but I thin!; it is a barbarous mode of causing
          death. Hardly any one favors hanging in
          preference to electricity,
          "I am heartily in favor of the application
          of electricity for tho purposes in question,
          for the reason that it is simple, sure and
          painless. 1 think that if the places of execu
          tion wero limited to two in this state, say
          ono at Auburn and ono at Sing Sing, the
          two stato prisons, and that all convicts as
          Foon as condemned to suffer tho death
          penalty should bo confined in ono of those
          two prisons (depending somewhat upon the
          locality of tho trial), it would be a vast im
          provement upon tho present method of hav
          ing tho criminal confined in the county jail
          till the daj- of execution."
          Regarding tho machinery to Iw used
          Senator llcl.lillan says: "Theso 'executions
          could take place in tho jail proper, in a room
          set apart for that purpose, with no appli
          ances save that of a chair, with tuo nana
          rest of each arm properly connected with
          an electric machine, in which tho condemned
          might bo seated and tho connection made by
          strapping a hand to the hand rest on each
          chair. There can bo no difficulty whatever
          in procuring a current of electricity of suffi
          cient strength to paralyze tho muscles of
          tho heart by this method. Indeed, tho cur
          rent that is used in this city for electric
          lighting purposes is of sufficient strength to
          absolutely dismember the body of nay human
          being, but a current of electricity of suffi
          cient strength to cause instantaneous death
          by passing from hand to hand through the
          heart wi'l not mark the body in tho least."
          San Vranelsco'a X"nr Trade.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075267/1888-12-13/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Electrical+Electric+Chair+Capital+Punishment+Killing+Electricity+murderers+lightning</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          APTAN PROPOSED.
          gow Will Electrical Execu
          tions Be Accomplished?
          TlE LAST THING IN KILLING.
          How Various Nations Do Their Criminals
          to Death--New TYok State the Flrat
          commeunty to Adapt the Newest Thing
          in Capital PlUnihment.
          After Jan. 1, 1880, murderers in New York
          sate will depart this life on a streak of light
          ing. Any man who has been sentenced to
          death will go off. so quick that he won't
          know anything about it. The subject of
          putting murderers to death by electricity has
          been agitated in the Empire state for more
          than a year.
          After mature deliberation it was concluded
          that hanging would have to go.
          Hanging has been the fashionable mode of
          punishment for centuries, but a commission
          *appointed by Governor Hill concluded that it
          was too harrowing. They made a number
          of experiments, and finally decided upon
          electricity. A bill was passed by the legis
          lature, but-no provision was made as to the
          way the fluid was to be applied. Finally the
          Medico-legal society took the matter Uo, ap
          pointed a commission, and the result was
          that a particular form of applying the elec
          tricity was suggested. This way of killing
          off the refuse population will probably be
          used in New York state hereafter. Three
          ways of applying the fatal electricity were
          proposed, but none of them answered the
          purpose. One was passing the electri.
          iots city from wrist to
          wrist through the
          body, another
          was passing the
          current from the
          head to one of the
          wrists, the third
          Swas topassthecmu
          rent completely
          t through the prison.
          S1 etr's body from head
          to foot.
          c c m The objections to
          A CURRENT IN THE BRAIn these methods were
          that the prisoner might have convulsions.
          It was desired, of course, to take the utmost
          care of the prisoner. He was to die as pleas
          antly as possible. Then the attendant under
          this method might make a mistake and be
          struck himself.
          The commission finally concluded that the
          best way would be to have the current pass
          through the hoad from the top to the back of
          the neck. One electrode is fitted to the top
          of the prisoner's head, another placed in con
          tact with the small of his back. The top
          electrode connects with the positive pole, the
          bottom with the negative pole. A leathern
          rest holds the prisoner's head and bands
          keep him from moving. The current, in go
          ing from one electrode to another, does not
          keep in a straight line, but spreads out and
          goes through the entire brain. It resembles
          somewhat a bundle of faggots tied at the two
          ends and swelling out in the middle. The seat
          of consciousness being in the brain, and the
          headquarters for all the nerves being located
          there, it is of course as plain as day that,
          when an electro-motive force of 8, 30 volts
          is applied, the prisoner is bound to die. The
          great beauty of this system is that the pris
          oners don't know it either.
          Heroe we have a villain who is too bad to
          stay around and commit murder any more.
          Step up, ladies and gentlemen, and gazoon
          the wayitisdone. Here we have astouttable
          covered with rubber cloth and having holes
          around its borders for binding. Prisoner,
          come up here and lieon the table. Attendant,
          bind the prisoner to the table. Here is an
          electrode (the negative one) which comes up
          through the table and touches the small of
          the prisoner's back. Here we have a helmet,
          to which the other electrode is joined, and
          t helmet is put on the prisoner's head. The
          Wtrode now touches the top of the prison
          9~head, which has been moistened bywarm
          ater. Prisoner, are you ready? Then, let
          'cgo, Gallagher, and the thing is done. The
          man is as dead as a
          door nail. Another
          modification of this
          method is to let the
          prisoner sit in a
          chair. Some pris
          oners will undoubt
          edly prefer to sit
          in a chair, whleilo
          others who were
          born tired will pro- e'O
          for to lie at full
          length. Eerthinug THE DEATH APPARATUS.
          will be done in regard to the com ort of the
          prisoners, and their taste will be consulted
          in every particular.
          This, in brief, is the way the prisoners will
          "lick the bucket" after the 1st of January.
          When Elbridgo T. Gerry, Mathew Hale
          and Alfred P. Southwick wero appointed last
          winter to investigate the matter they took
          the trouble to look up the various methods of
          Panishment in different countries.
          Now, however, the main object in
          to get the prisoner out of the way as soon as
          possible. In order to understand how quick
          a man can die under the force of electricity,
          let us consider first how fast a man can think.
          Well, it takes just one-tenth of a second fora
          nerve to communicate with the brain, ac
          cording to Professor Hemholz Now Pro
          fessor Tyndall estimates that an electric dis
          charge occurs in one hundred thousandth of
          a second, or ten thousand times more rapidly
          than nerve transmission. So you see that it
          it were possible a man would die by the
          process described ten thousand times before
          his nerves would have time to communicate
          with his brain.
          Last winter, for the purpose of ascertain
          ing the effect of the electric light current on
          the action of the heart, the thorax of a
          chloroformed dog caught in Buffalo was
          opened, so that the lungs and heart could be
          seen in action by forcing respiration as in
          conscious life. At the instant when the cur
          rent passed through the heart it became a
          mass of quivering flesh. It was noticed that
          an attempt to breathe was made after the
          current was passed through the dog. This
          indicated that the brain had not lost its sus
          ceptibility to impressions, and shows that in
          execution the current should be passed
          through the center. It should not be for
          gotten, however, that the dog was from
          utffalo. The commission couldheaveselected
          no tougher subject than a Buffalo dog.
          There can be no question, however, that
          electricity is the thing to do the business.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075267/1888-12-13/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Electrical+Electric+Chair+Capital+Punishment+Killing+Electricity+murderers+lightning&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.248,-0.075,1.496,1.496,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          APTAN PROPOSED.
          gow Will Electrical Execu
          tions Be Accomplished?
          TlE LAST THING IN KILLING.
          How Various Nations Do Their Criminals
          to Death--New TYok State the Flrat
          commeunty to Adapt the Newest Thing
          in Capital PlUnihment.
          After Jan. 1, 1880, murderers in New York
          sate will depart this life on a streak of light
          ing. Any man who has been sentenced to
          death will go off. so quick that he won't
          know anything about it. The subject of
          putting murderers to death by electricity has
          been agitated in the Empire state for more
          than a year.
          After mature deliberation it was concluded
          that hanging would have to go.
          Hanging has been the fashionable mode of
          punishment for centuries, but a commission
          *appointed by Governor Hill concluded that it
          was too harrowing. They made a number
          of experiments, and finally decided upon
          electricity. A bill was passed by the legis
          lature, but-no provision was made as to the
          way the fluid was to be applied. Finally the
          Medico-legal society took the matter Uo, ap
          pointed a commission, and the result was
          that a particular form of applying the elec
          tricity was suggested. This way of killing
          off the refuse population will probably be
          used in New York state hereafter. Three
          ways of applying the fatal electricity were
          proposed, but none of them answered the
          purpose. One was passing the electri.
          iots city from wrist to
          wrist through the
          body, another
          was passing the
          current from the
          head to one of the
          wrists, the third
          Swas topassthecmu
          rent completely
          t through the prison.
          S1 etr's body from head
          to foot.
          c c m The objections to
          A CURRENT IN THE BRAIn these methods were
          that the prisoner might have convulsions.
          It was desired, of course, to take the utmost
          care of the prisoner. He was to die as pleas
          antly as possible. Then the attendant under
          this method might make a mistake and be
          struck himself.
          The commission finally concluded that the
          best way would be to have the current pass
          through the hoad from the top to the back of
          the neck. One electrode is fitted to the top
          of the prisoner's head, another placed in con
          tact with the small of his back. The top
          electrode connects with the positive pole, the
          bottom with the negative pole. A leathern
          rest holds the prisoner's head and bands
          keep him from moving. The current, in go
          ing from one electrode to another, does not
          keep in a straight line, but spreads out and
          goes through the entire brain. It resembles
          somewhat a bundle of faggots tied at the two
          ends and swelling out in the middle. The seat
          of consciousness being in the brain, and the
          headquarters for all the nerves being located
          there, it is of course as plain as day that,
          when an electro-motive force of 8, 30 volts
          is applied, the prisoner is bound to die. The
          great beauty of this system is that the pris
          oners don't know it either.
          Heroe we have a villain who is too bad to
          stay around and commit murder any more.
          Step up, ladies and gentlemen, and gazoon
          the wayitisdone. Here we have astouttable
          covered with rubber cloth and having holes
          around its borders for binding. Prisoner,
          come up here and lieon the table. Attendant,
          bind the prisoner to the table. Here is an
          electrode (the negative one) which comes up
          through the table and touches the small of
          the prisoner's back. Here we have a helmet,
          to which the other electrode is joined, and
          t helmet is put on the prisoner's head. The
          Wtrode now touches the top of the prison
          9~head, which has been moistened bywarm
          ater. Prisoner, are you ready? Then, let
          'cgo, Gallagher, and the thing is done. The
          man is as dead as a
          door nail. Another
          modification of this
          method is to let the
          prisoner sit in a
          chair. Some pris
          oners will undoubt
          edly prefer to sit
          in a chair, whleilo
          others who were
          born tired will pro- e'O
          for to lie at full
          length. Eerthinug THE DEATH APPARATUS.
          will be done in regard to the com ort of the
          prisoners, and their taste will be consulted
          in every particular.
          This, in brief, is the way the prisoners will
          "lick the bucket" after the 1st of January.
          When Elbridgo T. Gerry, Mathew Hale
          and Alfred P. Southwick wero appointed last
          winter to investigate the matter they took
          the trouble to look up the various methods of
          Panishment in different countries.
          . In order to understand how quick
          a man can die under the force of electricity,
          let us consider first how fast a man can think.
          Well, it takes just one-tenth of a second fora
          nerve to communicate with the brain, ac
          cording to Professor Hemholz Now Pro
          fessor Tyndall estimates that an electric dis
          charge occurs in one hundred thousandth of
          a second, or ten thousand times more rapidly
          than nerve transmission. So you see that it
          it were possible a man would die by the
          process described ten thousand times before
          his nerves would have time to communicate
          with his brain.
          Last winter, for the purpose of ascertain
          ing the effect of the electric light current on
          the action of the heart, the thorax of a
          chloroformed dog caught in Buffalo was
          opened, so that the lungs and heart could be
          seen in action by forcing respiration as in
          conscious life. At the instant when the cur
          rent passed through the heart it became a
          mass of quivering flesh. It was noticed that
          an attempt to breathe was made after the
          current was passed through the dog. This
          indicated that the brain had not lost its sus
          ceptibility to impressions, and shows that in
          execution the current should be passed
          through the center. It should not be for
          gotten, however, that the dog was from
          utffalo. The commission couldheaveselected
          no tougher subject than a Buffalo dog.
          There can be no question, however, that
          electricity is the thing to do the business.
          HE LET HIMSELF DROP.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025891/1895-09-07/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Lizzie+Halliday+Lunatic+Asylum+Murder+Electricity&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.306,-0.081,1.611,1.611,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          She next stole a horse. She was sent
          to an insane asylum, but discharged as
          aured, and in September, 1893, the bodies
          Df Margaret McQuillan and her daughter
          Sarah, whom she had lured from their
          lome in Newburg, were found under the
          oarn. Si s had shot them and buried
          :hem. The corpse of her husband was
          found a little while afterwards, riddled
          with bullels, buried under the house.
          The woman was plaoed In the jail at
          Monticello: There, she had frequent vio
          lent outbreaks, attacking the jailer's wife
          n one occasion. She also set fire to her cot
          md later hanged herself to her cell door.
          Then ahe was put on trial at Monticello,
          found guilty of murder In the first decree
          md sentenced to be killed by electricity.
          3he was removed to Dannemora gagged
          md bound on account of her violence.
          Governor Flower commuted her sentence
          ;o life imprisonment on the ground that she
          xras insane, and she was transferred to
          the lunatic asylum at Matteawan.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016758/1899-06-01/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Death+Chair+Penalty+Capital+Punishment+Murder</id>
        <rel>0</rel>

      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1901-10-29/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Repentance+Czolgosz+Electric+Chair+Electrocuted+Deadly+Current</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          In the Electric Chair.
          Cowardice Quivered on His Lips, But Unsustained by Prayer or Hope of Eter
          nity He Felt the Mask of Death Upon His Face and Passed to Oblivion,
          Hated and Despised.
          Auburn, N. Y., Oct 20.-(Spl.)-Loon
          F. Czolgosz, alias Fred Nieman, was
          successfully electrocuted at Auburn
          prison this morning. He was pro
          nouncod dead at 7:10:15 a. in.
          With the purely animal courage that
          bud sustained blm and the Innate cow
          ard within him struggling to his lips,
          the youthful murderer, hated by tho
          nation and tho world at largo, paid the
          ponalty for his crime.
          Ho took tho chair at 7:15 and In less
          itlmo than It takes to tell it, tho deadly
          current had paaHod through his body,
          rubblnrr 'nmfeshla miserable existence
          with merciful and unerring swiftness.
          Seated In tho chair, with the fatal
          curroilt about to bo applied, Czolgosz,
          V facing tho witnesses said;
          "I shot the President becauso 1
          thought It would benefit good work
          ing people by ridding them of abom
          inations. I am not sorry for my
          crime."
          During Oils time tho attendants wcro
          busy strapping him to tho enalr. His
          last words were: "I am heartily sorry
          I did not see my father."
          This was said after tho strap had
          been drawn across his face, yet his
          words were heard distinctly by all tho
          witnesses in tho roomi Ho went to
          his death unsupported by tho com
          forting thought that ho had mado
          pence with his God.
          For Uie lrst time In the history of
          the prison a condemned man marched
          to tlie fatal chair unaccorupnnicd by a
          Spiritual advisor, Spiritual aid hod
          been offered hUn, but ho scorned all
          entreaties. Ho wanted no one to prny
          tpt his soiuV
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1903-10-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Chair+Fifteen+Minutes+Van+Wormers+Electrocuted+Willis+Frederick+Burton+Electric</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          3 VAN WORMERS J
          J
          OlE IN THE CHAIR
          IN FifTEEN MINUTES
          The Brothers Are Electrocuted One
          After the Other with Marvellous
          i Speed Without a Hitch in the Triple
          Tragedy Each Displaying Nerve
          I Willis the Eldest Was the First tcTDie
          Then Came Frederick the Youngest
          I 1 and Burton Most Composed and De
          l termined of All Was the Last
          I
          I I
          QUICK WORK OF DEATH SHOCKS
          WILLIS VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          113430 The current was turned into his body one
          minute later He was dead at 1137
          FRBDBRICK VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          11413O At 1142 the current was turned on He was
          declared dead at 114330
          I
          BURTON VAN WORMER entered the deathchamber at
          1147 The currant wai turned on at 114730 He was
          declared dead at 114830
          lbe actual time of the triple execution was less than
          fifteen minutes
          1
          Special to The Evening World
          DANNEMORA Oct tThe lives of the three Van Wormer boys
          p tyho were condemned to death for the murder of Peter Hallenbeck were
          forfeited to the tw In extraordinarily quick time today The ceremony
          1 of shocking them to death in the elecfrtfc chair consumed but thirty sec
          I onds over fifteen minutes That length of time elapsed from the moment
          when y1illis Van Wormer left his cell and started for the death chamber
          until the physicians pronounced Burton Van Wormer the last of the trio
          deadTherewas
          Therewas not a hitch in the proaling The fascinated witnesse
          sat and watchedandvscarcely breathed as ihe men were led in killed anc
          carried out with strict adherence to a prearranged time table The boy
          died with the most surprising composure None can tell the horrible
          ordeal through which Burton Van Wormer passed as he awaited his turn
          3Ut he showec no sign of fear when led out to face his doom
          GLOOM TO BEFIT TIlE OCCASION
          It was an eternity of gloom within the purlieus ot Clinton walls am
          black ae an Ink well upside down
          t At 1135 oclock five minutes earlier than usual the prison whistle
          ii which regulates the life of tho penitentiary and marks the uprisings an
          downslttlngs of tho people in the village of Dannemora gave fortlh a
          shrieking blast The whirring wheels and belts in tho factories came to c
          rest and the time of tho triple killing had arrived A boll rang In the
          Wardens office and a guard appeared at tho door and beckoned to the wit
          nesses Two by two they followed him to the rear of the administration
          I building through the alleyway which Is between the north tter of con
          demned cells and the structure wall
          r As they passed a mumble Of voices came from the quarters of the
          doomed Father Beranger who hail been so attentive to the condemned
          f men was with the Van Wjornjors giving promises of hope and receiving
          responses of belief
          Tho ears ot theboys must have heard the tread of many feet going
          by The death watchers said after the legal tragedy had ended that they
          i heard and that their limbs shook
          Soon tho crowd was in the chamber of death and each ones seat was
          pointed out to him as ln a playhouee and each sat down to talk In
          whispers with his neighbors With their eyes upon the stage and its grue
          some 5ettgatbe chair with leathern straps and strange metal fittings
          they had not long to wait before the curtain was rung up
          The breaths of the witnesses could be heard at times as they sat there
          and waited The noise of the opening of a lock made a rasping sound be
          t hind the scenes and a catch came Into cacti ones throat There was the
          f round of shuffling feet on the cement floor outside the door of death Now
          L 1t was afthe threshold now Inside Some turned their heads to look most
          4 stared straight ahead at the chair
          WILLIS LED TO HIS DOOM
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1912-08-11/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=Victims+Death+Chair+Execution+Electric+Executed+Electricity</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Aug. 10- Twenty-two
          jears ago this week, on August C,
          1890, William Kemmlcr, a condemned
          murderer, was put to death In the
          electric chair In Auburn prison. Kern.
          mler ttas the first victim to be legal
          ly executed by electricity in tb Unit
          ed States and his case was the sub
          ject of wide discussion at the time.
          The action of New York In substitut
          ing the electric chair for the gallows
          has been found generally satisfact
          ory and her example has been fol
          lowed by Ohio, Virginia, South Caro
          lina, Massachusetts, Kentucky auJ
          New Jersey.
          ijlnce the execution of Kemmler
          there hae been 151 persona put to
          death In the electric chair In New
          York. The state prison authorities
          estimate that It costs about J4000 per
          individual to carry, out the capital
          punishment mandate. On the basis
          of Oils estimate New York state haa
          expended about JC3.000 for electro
          cutions since that form of Inflicting
          the death penalty was introduced.
          Several times the electric chair at
          Sing Sing has had two victims in
          one day, and on one occasion a short
          time ago three persons were put to
          death within a period of twenty-four
          hours. Rut never before has there
          been such a wholesale execution of
          death sentences Imposed on prison
          ers In this state as is scheduled to
          take place at Sing Sing next week.
          Nino men are to die on the same
          day, and In as rapid succession H3
          they can be led to the death chair.
          -:ix of the nine prospective victims
          are the Italians who were convicted
          of the atrocious murder of Mrs Mary
          Hall at Croton Id Kit. Westchester
          County, on Nov 9, 1911.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1915-07-31/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Death+Electric+Chair+Electrocuted+Executed+Execution+Murdered+Rosenthal</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          BECKER IS EXECUTED
          WITH PRAYER ON LIPS
          (Continued From Page 1.)
          The one time police officer hesitated
          as he entered the execution room. It
          seemed to the witnesses as if he was
          startled that the death chair was so
          near at hand. He looked quickly at
          the double row of witnesses, glanced
          at the floor, swept with his eyes the
          whitened walls of the room and then,
          suddenly, as if coming to himself,
          walked briskly over the rubber mat
          and seated himself in the electric
          chair. Behind Becker followed the
          prison priests chanting the prayer of
          death, which was repeated by the con
          demned man.
          "Jesus, ijtfary, Joseph, hkve mercy on
          my soul," nervously spoke Becker as
          deputy wardens stepped forward and
          adjusted the electrodes. Hardly a
          minhte elapsed before the electrode
          was applied to the right leg, a slit
          having been previously cut in the
          trouser leg from the knee down. After
          the electrode had been firmly adjusted
          against a shaven spot on the back of
          the condemned man's head, the state
          executioner looked at Deputy Warden
          Johnson, who surveyed the figure that
          was ctlll mumbling the death prayer
          in the chair. Johnson half turned his
          head and the executioner jammed the
          switch.
          Three Shocks Given.
          The first shock lasted a full minute
          and the executioner said that it was
          1,850 volts and ten aniperes in
          strength. It came while Becker was
          still commending his soul to his
          niflknr.
          I The two prison physicians stepped
          forward to examine the collapsed flg
          ure that sat supported in the death
          chair by the thick black leather straps.
          The stethoscope was applied to the
          heart and Dr. Charles Farr, the prison
          physician, pressed his finger against
          the artery in the neck. There was
          still a feeble fluttering of the heart.'
          The physician stepped back from
          the rubber mat and again the electric
          current pulsed through the body. The
          shock lasted seven seconds and the
          current was then turned off. After 4
          hasty examination Dr. Farr asked that
          a third shock be given. This lasted
          nve seconds. An examination that
          took several minutes followed. Three
          physicians among the witnesses then
          made an examination and Dr.- Farr at
          5:55 o'clock proriounced Becker dead.
          Writes Last Statement.
          During the night Becker penciled on
          a piece of paper what he captioned
          "My Dying Declaration." It was tak
          en to the warden's office where two
          copies were typewritten, which Becker
          signed with his fountain pen in a bold
          hand To Deputy Warden Johnson,
          who bad charge of the execution in
          place of Warden Thomas Mott Os
          borne, who does not believe in the
          death penalty,
          Electric Chair Gets Men Who Murdered Rosenthal
          £L&amp;C7WC
          CHA/&amp;
          S/A/G vT/Att
          ik
          Lsrry lows
          which I must die. You are now about
          to witness my destruction by the state,
          which is organized to protect the lives
          of the innocent! May'Almighty God
          pardon everyone who has contributed
          In any degree to my untimely death.
          And now on the brink of my grave I
          declare to the world that I am proud
          to have been the husband of the pur
          est, noblest woman that ever lived—
          Helen Becker. This acknowledgment
          is the only legacy I can leave her. I
          bid you all good-bye. Father, 1 am
          ready to go. Amen/'
          (Signed) "Charles Becker."
          Talks All Night.
          After his wife had said farewell,
          shortly after midnight, Becker main
          tained a casual conversation with
          Deputy Warden Johnson who sat be
          side tne screen in front of his cell.
          Sometimes he smoked cigars, after
          jwhich he would let his head fall on
          I his hand and gaze reflectively at the
          I floor for minutes at a time. Dawn
          found him seated on the edge of his
          cot carefully pinning a photograph of
          his wife on his white shirt just over
          his heart. Then, as if he desired to
          have her all to himself, Becker put on
          a thin black alpaca coat, which he
          tightly buttoned. The photograph was
          not seen by the witnesses until the
          prison" physician opened his coat as he
          sat in the death chair.
          Becker was put to death by the state
          executioner whose name is unknown
          to the public. This man succeeded
          State Electrician Davis and he said he
          would not take the job unless his name
          wis kept secret. He lives in a little
          town up-state and went about his
          work briskly.
          Becker's executioner said that in his
          opinion the man had died instantly at
          the first contact.
          Negro Follows Becker.
          An autopsy on the body of Becker
          was performed, according to law, im
          mediately after the execution. After
          Becker's body had been removed from
          the electric chair, Samuel Haynes, a
          nefgro murderer, was brought into the
          execution room and electrocuted. One
          of Becker's last requests to Warden
          Osborne was that''he be put to death
          before Haynes.
          Mrs. Becker Makes Statement.
          A statement credited to Mrs. Becker
          was given out here shortly after her
          husband's death.
          TWO ELECTROCUTED
          IN KENTUCKY JAIL
          Eddyville, Ky., July 30—For the
          third time in the history of Kentucky
          a double electrocution took place this
          morning at 3:30 o'clock at the Eddy
          ville penintiary.
          The firBt to be executed was Turn
          er Graham, Jr., 24, a white man, con
          victed for the killing of R. J. Mc
          Murtry, sheriff of Hardin county. The
          second was William Lane, 25, a negro,
          convicted at Pineville, on a charge of
          killing his wife. Lane was the first
          negro to be executed in Kentucky
          since the adoption of electrocution as
          a means of inflicting the death pen
          alty. Both men passed the night
          calmly and walked unassisted to the
          death chamber.
          an ordinary human being—and per
          haps that Is why I loved him so."
          History of Case.
          Herman Rosenthal, the gambler for
          whose murder Charles Becker was sen
          tenced to die in the electric chair, was
          shot to death by hired gunmen in the
          early morning of July 16, 1912, in front
          of the Hotel Metropole on Forty-third
          street, a few stepB from Broadway.
          The murder was' the swift culmination
          of sensational charges made a few
          days before by Rosenthal against Beck
          er in which Rosenthal asserted that
          Becker, then head of the strong arm
          squad of detectives, freely sold police
          protection and had accumulated thou
          sands of dollars of graft money.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045389/1916-03-05/ed-1/?sp=48&amp;q=Die+Death+Electric+Chair+Electrocution+Electricity</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Scientists Have Just Discovered
          Many Secrets Which Have Long
          Puzzled Them in Regard to Death
          by Electric Shock From the Exper
          ience of a Man Who Was Electro
          cuted and Brought
          Back to Life
          WHKN the electric chair was sub
          stituted for the old fashioned
          gallows in New York it was be
          cause it was believed that electrocution
          was painless. But just what were the
          sensations of death in the electric chair
          scientists were unable to say, because
          no electrocuted victim came back to life
          to tell tliern.
          It was assumed that the shock of the
          powerful current would instantly render
          the condemned man unconscious. But
          the unpleasant feature of m^st electro
          cutions has been the necessity of re
          penting the shock several times. This
          was not foreseen
          Experience in ilie death chamber has
          shown that the electric current does
          not usually destroy life at the tirst shock.
          Evidences of pulsating life compel the
          executioner to turn on the current asain
          and yet again. This distressing failure
          of the electric charge to instantly end
          life has caused much speculation among
          scientists and humanitarians.
          Does the first shock end the conscious
          ness of the condemned man?
          Or is the victim siiil conscious?hover
          ing between death and life, does themau
          In the chair realize what is going on?
          What, if any, was the agony of the
          ti rs shock?
          What were the agonies of the victim
          during the moments elapsing between
          tiie tirst shock and the second impact of
          the current? Was he entirely uncon
          scious, partly conscious or fully conscious
          of the horrors of the situation which the
          law never meant to be inflicted on him?
          And if the tirst shock of the current
          benumbed the condemned man's brain,
          did returning consciousness bring with it
          tortures of bodily misery which have
          never been known or suspected?
          The Victim
          Falls Apparently Dead.
          Nobody has been able to answer these
          questions until an accident happened
          viiit-h unexpectedly illuminated this wholo
          subject of what the victim in the elec
          tric chair really sees, hears, foels and
          cu ffers.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 Extra Documents -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83035682/1959-04-30/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=electric+chair</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038220/1947-04-07/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=electric+chair</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090369/1911-11-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=death+chair</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          F. P. SMITH BEATTIE DIES IN
          ELECTRIC CHAIR
          Convicted Wile Murderer Elec
          trocuted After Acknowl
          edging His Guilt.
          NEVER LOSTJIS NERVE
          Condemned Man Walked Calmly
          and Unshaken to the Death
          Chair—Executed Shortly
          Alter Daylight.
          j _
          Associated Press Special.
          J Richmond, Va., Nov. 14.—Henry
          Clay Beattie, Jr., wag electrocuted In
          I the death chamber of the state pent
          lentlary this morning at 7:2i
          o’clock. One minute after the shock
          he was pronounced dead by the at
          tending physicians.
          After the execution of Beattie It
          was learned that he confessed to the
          murder of his wife. Although the
          prison authorities who were present
          at the execution said that Beattie
          made no statements which might be
          construed as an admission of guilt.
          It was afterwards learned that he
          lert a written statement with his
          spiritual advisers In which he admit
          ted his guilt. This statement was
          given out by the family some time
          after young Beattie's death.
          The confession of Beattie, which
          bore hla signature. Is aa follow*:
          “I, Henry Clay Beattie, Jr., desir
          ous of standing right before Ood and
          man, do on this the twenty-third day
          of November, confess my guilt of
          the crime against me. Much that has
          been published concerning the de
          tails was not true, but the awful
          fact without harrowing clrcumstau
          ces remain. For this action I am tru
          ly Borry, but believing that I am at
          peace with God and am soon to pa
          Into his presence, this statement Is
          made.”
          Beattie went to the death dealing
          chair unshaken and displaying the
          same remarkable nerve that charac
          terized him throughout the entire
          trial of his case and his subsequent
          fight to escape the chair.
          During his last night on earth
          Beattie slept well, but tossed rest
          lessly as though bad dreams had
          been his companions throughout the
          long time. There were no signs of a
          breakdown when he arose this morn
          ing, the prisoner dressing with the
          same fastidious care that he has
          taken ever since he entered the state
          penitentiary and the death cell.
          The death chamber Is undor
          ground and the only light waa above
          the death chair where It seemed to
          culminate with a ghastly glare and
          to leave the balance of th* room In
          almost total darkness. The twelve
          witnesses required by law wero
          ranged along the sides of th* cham
          ber back In this grewsome darkness.
          During the few momenta Beattie
          was a'lve after he entered the death
          chamber he saw nothing but the
          chair in which he was to be rtrapped
          to receive the deadly current.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1947-02-25/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=death+chair</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Sullivan Asked to Aid Youth
          Who Survived Death Chair
          By the Associated Press
          Gael Sullivan, executive director
          of the Democratic National Com-j
          mittee, said yesterday a group of i
          educators has asked his aid in seek
          ing executive clemency for Willie
          Francis, young Negro facing a sec
          ond trip to the electric chair in
          Louisiana.
          Mr. Sullivan told reporters he Is
          studying the case, but has taken no
          action and did not know what he
          might do. He discussed the matter
          when asked about reports that he
          would ask President Truman to
          commute Francis’ sentence.
          Francis, convicted of a holdup
          killing, went to the electric chair
          once but escaped death due to me
          chanical difficulties with the chair.
          His attorneys appealed to the Su
          preme Court to save him from a
          second trip to the chair, contending
          that would be cruel and unusual
          punishment barred by the Consti
          tution. The court split sharply on
          the question, but the majority held
          j Louisiana may legally attempt once
          j again to execute him.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1903-05-25/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=death+chair</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          HARDEST MAN IN
          WORLD TO KILL
          Slaying of Murderer Triola
          Proves the Greatest Task the
          Death Chair Has Ever Had to
          Perform
          The remarkable vitality of Antonio
          Trlolo put to death today tn SIng Sing
          prison for the murder of Maria Orolll
          the child actress proved him to toe the
          hardest man to kill that has aver been
          la th electric chair
          Triola was remarkably oool when led
          Into the death chamber He helped the
          attendants adjust the straps and elec
          tric appliances of the death chair It
          required five shocks of 1700 volts each
          the first four amperes and then eight
          for each of the other four times to
          kill the Italian No one In the prison
          had ever before seen INch difficulty
          at an execution
          Triola was very 0001 He roSe at tho
          first sign of dawn Other men con
          demned to die Including lawyer Al
          bert T Patrick and Arthur Flanagan
          who was to have met death today
          with Triola but was reprieved wer
          also up early
          An Hoar of Prayer
          When the ReT Fathers Mahoney and
          Martin called he knelt In prayer for an
          hour after receiving holy communion
          Shortly before 6 ocloclc the witnesses
          and State Electrician Davis gathered In
          the death chamber The apparatus of
          the death chair waa tested and found
          to bo In perfect condition
          Tho little procession then started
          from Trlolai cell The priests walked
          on one side of the condemned man
          hlUle time won lost In atrapplne the
          prisoner In the chair The signal was
          given and 1700 volts shot throurh the
          condemned mans body
          Dr Irvine Immediately MW that the
          man was not dead Again the current
          was turned on for thirty seconds but
          ngnlnlt failed although eight s
          ere used
          Onco more the current was shot
          through TrlolVa body but still he kept
          alive It was not until the fifth shock
          was given to him that life became ex
          tinct
        </text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>