<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-american-female-pilots</id>
    <results>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1911-07-24/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=aeroplan+aeroplane+aeroplanes+bird+birds+Lady+Mathilde+Moisant</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>July 24, 1911:	Mathilde Moisant begins working toward her pilot’s license, even after the death of her brother by flying. She later becomes the second woman in America to earn a license after Harriet Quimby.</time>
            <text>
            You might think that a girl whose brother had been dashed to death In an aeroplane would be about the last girl to take up aeroplan-Ing as a profession. Not so with Mathilde Moisant. There are so few women now fly-ing that she may be said to be one of the first to go into the game. She is taking lessons daily at Min-eola, and expects before many weeks to be earning money as an aviator. Miss Moisant Is a handsome young woman, of the dark, Span-ish type, spirited in her speech and actions, and there seems little doubt that she will make good. She has all the necessary nerve, and while she is Btill in the "grass-cutting" stage of flying, she is learning very rapidly to guide and control her machine. "My brother John always told me," she says, "that to be a suc-cessful flyer meant to anticipate every move of the machine, and to be able to take steps to meet an emergency the Instant it occurred. That la what I am trying con-stantly to keep in mind." After John was killed, I vowed never to get Into an aeroplane again, but the old longing that I had always had, when I saw him fly, came back, until I was no longer able to resist It. My fam-ily has opposed me In every way, but I am determined. No Fear In Machine. "I think anyone can learn to fly, but I don't think everyone can learn to be a really great aviator, and that Is what I Intend to be-come. I think it is born In me. I have no feeling of fear when I get into a machine. I know I shall learn to do the things John did-, and perhaps more than he ever did." Although supposed to stick to the ground, Miss Moisant made a flight a few days ago, greatly to the surprise of her instructor, An-drew Haupert. She pulled the clutch without knowing it and shifted her planes so as to send the machine up in the air several feet. She landed as lightly as a bird. Miss Moisant has her brother's famous cat, "Paris-London," and he flies with her as he did with the ill-fated aviator who carried him across the channel. </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-10-17/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Aeroplane+aeroplane+bird+birds+Mathilda+Moissant</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>July 24, 1911: Mathilde Moisant begins working toward her pilot’s license, even after the death of her brother by flying. She later becomes the second woman in America to earn a license after Harriet Quimby.</time>
            <text> 
            MERE EARTH BEINGS MARVEL AT MISS MOISSANT'S FLIGHT
            NEW YORK, Oct. 16. Miss Mathilda Moissant, at the aviation field in Mineola, Long Island, this evening made a flight which was as good as any since the spring. Friends from South America and France had come to the field, and it was for their benefit that she gave the exhibition.  
            Leaving the field, she arose 1,500 feet. [Special Dispatch to The Call] She flew across to Meadowbrook and Westbury, flew south, crossing the motor parkway, and kept on until she was over the Great South Bay.  
            On her return flight, when she flew over the field, she made several sensational dips, to the terror of her friends, who feared she was falling, but she alighted gracefully.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1911-11-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Ladies+lady+Mathilda+moisant</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>WOMEN AVIATORS TO FLY
            IN THE CITY OF MEXICO.
            They Will Show President MiKlero
            and Then Tour Country Be
            fore Coming Hack.
            Four women sailed to-day "n the Mal
            lory I.lnn steamer Impnsas for the
            Oty of Mexico, where th v are to give
            avlutlon exhibitions at the Inauguration
            of President Madcro, after which they
            plan an extended tour of M. xlco, cover
            ing many long diet an era tiefore the;,
            aeturn.
            Miss Mathldle Molsant Is to pilot one
            machine, with her elster, Hate Louise
            Molsant. ar. her passenger. -Ml- Harriet
            yulmby took with her Miss M. C Long
            Both young women have frequently
            been aeen In flights In the New YorK
            section.
            Copt. I'ntrlck Donald Hamilton went
            on the lAtnpusaa as escort for the
            yourg women.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1912-04-21/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=aeroplane+Blanche+Mathilda+Moisant+Scott</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>MATHILDA MOISANT, SISTER OF DEAD
            AVIATOR. MAKES HER: FAREWELL FLIGHT. Mathilda Molsant in monoplane and irf
            r Aviation costume.
            Wichita Falls,, 'Texas, April 20. Mi6s
            Mathilda Molsant. avlatrlx and sister
            cf John B. Molsant, who was killed In
            an aeroplane accident at New Orleans
            In December, 1910, all but lost her life
            iu her farewell flight which she made
            here recently. Her machine struck a
            ridge of earth Just outside the base
            ball park. It came down right side
            up with the young woman still In her
            scat, but the framework crumpled
            from the Impact. In an instant the
            wreckage was ablaze, and before the
            hvlatrlx could escape her clothing was
            in flames.
            Ihe fire was extinguished before
            she had sustained serious Injury, but
            the machine was totally destroyed.
            Miss Molsant was one of America's
            three women aviators, the other two
            being Miss Harriett Quimby and Miss
            Blanche Scott. Only Miss Quimby
            and Miss Moisant hold diplomas en
            titling them to fly at organised
            meets. All three women have made
            numerous exibltion flights, and until
            the accident here the other day all
            could boast that they had never had
            a real smashup. Miss Moisant's ex
            perience here will probably make her
            more determined than ever not to re
            turn to the aviation field.
            For flying purposes Miss Moisant
            adopted the knickerbocker costume.
            She is small and dark.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-01-19/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=aeroplane+Blanche+lady+Scott</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>January 19, 1912:	Blanche Scott calls Harriet Quimby and Mathilda Moisant “grass-cutters”, a harsh insult in early flying.</time>
            <text>LADY VIATORS' SPIRIT
            'GOES "UP IN THE IR"
            New York, Jan. 19. War has
            broken out among the 'avatrices"
            of America, and war. among the
            female of the species is more
            deadly Oh, much more deadly,
            than ,war among the male
            Charges of being a "grass cut
            ter" which in air language is
            equivalent to one colored gentle
            man telling another that a yellow
            streak runs up and down his back
            are being bandied across the
            1 continent. And rouge is not nec
            essary to redden the wrathy
            cheeks of the birdwomen.
            c Miss IBanche Scott, now in
            Los Angeles, began it. Miss
            Scott 'is not the possesor of an
            aviator's license, and perhaps she
            thinks she has been discriminat
            ed against in this matter. A r
            Anyway Miss Scott, she up
            and said 'that Miss 'Harriet
            Quimby and Miss Mathilde Moi
            sant who. be it noted, possess
            aviator's' licenses were afraid to
            qompete with -her, because she
            was. too daring and spectacular"
            for them.
            r When this was reported to Miss
            Harriet Quimby, that lady drew
            a long breath and assumed a
            s'cornfnl look.
            "Of course, she began, in icy
            tones, "you must understand that
            Miss Blanche Scott has never
            been awarde'd a license by the In
            ternational Aero club.
            "Under these circumstances, it
            is impossible for me, who has
            b'een -awarded a license, to chal-Jenge-
            her.
            "Otherwise"! should not hesi-
            tate to challenge Miss Scott
            "fie sides, this Miss Scott can
            nofdo the 'right hand turn.' That
            is 'one of the hardest things to do,
            and necessitates a1 spiral glide.
            I can do it.
            "The idea of Miss Scott saying
            that I am afraid to compete with
            her is too ridiculous to talk about
            I am not afraid of her, nor of any;
            man. Why, if I had the same pow
            er aeroplane 3S1 Claude Grabame
            White, I should not hesitate to
            challenge him for a race.
            "I don't believe hvthis circus
            flying. But 'I'm certainly not
            afraid of Miss Scott
            "Now if only she were.prqperly
            licensed, I should but .what is
            the use of talking she is NOTi
            licenced."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85059715/1912-02-28/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Blanche+ladies+Scott</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>1 NERVIEST WtfMAN lN T
            WHAT BIRDMEN CALi
            I,
            IB
            7 ISL^NCMElSCoXl
            Mlsa Blanche Scott, the only vomai
            Los Angraloi and Oakland, Cal., meets,
            noted rblrdmcn who flaw In, competltk
            .an In the" business." SfieY swept up In
            only a four minutes after Tom Qunn, tl
            Oakland and narrowly escaped death.
            bad no visible effect on her spirits,</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053157/1912-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=aeroplane+Blanche+Scottt</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>BLANCHE STUAR T SCOTT.
            Aviatrice Who Will 7 y to Fly Twice
            Over vHe En gl is-.i Channel.
            Blanche Stuart Scott, since Harriet
            Quimby's death America's only profes
            sional aviatrice, has auuouuced her in
            tention of not merely duplicating but
            of doubling Miss Quimby's successful
            Sight across the English channel. Miss
            Scott will start from Dover In au ef
            fort to fly to Calais in a h.vdroaero
            plane and return.
            Miss Scott has not been influenced
            by Miss Quimby's tragic death, which
            K
            It;
            MISS BLANCHE 8TITAHT SCOTT.
            she witnessed from her aeroplane, to
            entertain any fears of ber own ability
            to escape a like fate.
            "A death is only an Incident in the
            development of the science." she says,
            "and pioneers have died in the early
            struggles of all causes. It remains for
            those who are left to keep on striving
            for the ultimate triumph for which
            those who died gave up their lives."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93055779/1911-07-26/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=aeroplane+Aeroplane+bird+Blanche+Lady+lScott</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>July 26, 1911: Blanche Scott is the first woman in America to fly cross-country.</time>
            <text>First Women To 'Drive Aeroplane Cross Country In New World
            Many aviators and other air enthusiasts are congratulating Miss Blanche
            Stuart Scott of Rochester, N. Y who drove an aeroplane across county in a twelve mile flight from
            the aviation field here in ten minutes. Miss Scott is the first woman to achieve such a feat in America.
            She ftew. one of Captain Thomas S. Baldwin's biplanes, overtaking a, mere man aviator who' had started
            first, circled over the village of W 'stbury and returned to the field, making a safe landing. Miss Scott
            once drove an automobile all the w.vv across the continent. She is a pupil of Captain Baldwin and has
            made several trial flights on the aviation field.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1917-12-12/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=aeroplane+Katherine+ladies+lady+Stinson</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>December 12, 1917: Establishing a new non-stop distance record, Katherine Stinson flies from San Diego to San Francisco.</time>
            <text>
            SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 1. Miss Katherine Stinson, Texas aviatrix who started from San Diego at 7:31 a.m. today on a non-stop flight to San Francisco, reached her destination at 4:39 p.m. today. She was the first person to pilot an aeroplane over the Tehachapi mountains on a non-stop flight.The distance between San Diego and San Francisco on an airline is 461 miles. The distance Miss Stinson traveled was unofficially announced at 550 miles, which breaks the non-stop record held by Miss Ruth Law, who flew from Chicago to Hornell, N.Y., a distance of 512 miles.Miss Law was compelled to alight at Hornell by engine trouble. It was said by officials of the Pacific Aero Club that an official check could not possibly reduce the distance traveled by Miss Stinson by more than 10 miles.  
            Miss Stinson had been in the air nine hours when she alighted, and she showed the tremendous strain under which she had labored. Miss Stinson landed at the Presidio, a military reservation, by special permission.  </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065526/1963-06-20/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=female+pilots</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>	Various lady pilots wanted to
            be included in the training pro
            gram. argued that women weigh
            less than males, therefore would
            be more adaptable to space
            flights. But Webb said no. His
            excuse was a rule that only
            veteran jet test pilots could
            qualify for the astronaut pro
            gram. and there are no female
            jet test pilots. Some aviation ex
            perts disagree with Webb on this
            qualification, but he stuck to his
            guns.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96090217/1912-06-28/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=female+pilots</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>Springfield, 111., June 19 only
            twenty-eight years old and one of the
            three flying licensed female aviation
            pilots. Miss Julia Clarke of Denver
            was killed at the Illinois state fair
            grounds Monday wfa*-n the tip of one
            of the wings of a Curtiss biplane In
            which she was making a flight struck
            the limb of a tree and the machine
            was dashed to the ground, crushing
            her skull.</text>
        </result>
    </results>
</topic>