  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-league-of-nations</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-01-08/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.918,-0.048,2.835,1.284,0</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1918-01-08</time>
	    <text>
            SUMMARY OF WILSON'S
            nr.rn m rnr rAMinrnn
            rKUUKAiVl IU WHUKCaS
            FOR WORLD PEACE
            WASHINGTON, Jan. 8. President Wilson in an address to Con
            gress io-day restated American war aims in agreement with the recent
            declaration by the Urilish Premier, David Lloyd George.
            The President presented a definite programnu for world peace con
            taining fourteen specific considerations, as follows:
            "1 Open covenants of peace without private interna
            tional understandings.
            "2 Atijolute freedom of the seas in peace or war, ex
            cept as they may be closed by international action.
            "3 Removal of all economic barriers and establishment
            of equality of trade conditions among nations consenting to
            peace and associating themselves for its maintenance.
            "4 Guarantees for the reduction of national armaments
            to the lowest point consistent with domestic safety.
            "5 Impartial adjustment of all colonial claims based
            upon the principle that the peoples concerned have equal
            weight with the interest of the Government.
            "6 Evacuation of nil Russian territory and opportunity
            for Russia's political development.
            "7 Evacuation of Belgium without any attempt to
            limit her sovereignty.
            "8 All French territory to be freed and restored, and
            reparation for the taking of Alsace-Lorraine.
            "9 Readjustment of Italy's frontiers along clearly
            recognizable lines of nationality.
            "10 Freest opportunity for autonomous development
            of the peoples of Austria-Hungary.
            "11 Evacuation of Roumnnin, Serbia and Montenegro,
            with access to the sea for Serbia, and international guaran
            tees of economic and political independence and territorial
            integrity of the Balkan states.
            "12 Secure sovereignty for Turkey's portion of the
            Ottoman Empire, but with other nationalities under Turkish
            rule assured security of life and opportunity for autonomous
            development, with the Dardanelles permanently opened to
            all nations.
            "13 Establishment of an independent Polish state, in
            cluding territories inhabitated by indisputably Polish popula
            tion, with free access to the sea and political and economic
            independence and territorial integrity guaranteed by inter
            national covenant.
            "14 General association of nations under specific
            covenants for mutual guarantees of political independence
            and territorial integrity to large and small states alike.
            "For such arrangements and
            elusion, "we are willing to fight and continue to fight until they are but ,0 kefip whal they have got Thc negotlations hav5 b4fin f
            achieved, but only because we wish the right to prevail and desire aThe Russian reprcsenta(im w sincere and in carnfit. Th.y cannol
            just and stable peace.' nronou f rnn,... nnfj Hnminniinn
            .Such a programme, he said, removed chief provocations for war.
            "The moral climax (if thi, the culminating and linal war for
            human liberty has come," said the President in ending his address, "and
            thev (people of the United States) arc ready to put their own strength,
            their own highest purpose, their own integrity and devotion to the test.''
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071134/1919-01-26/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1919-01-26</time>
	    <text>
            LEAGUE OF NATIONS IDEA IS ADOPTED
            CONFERENCE

            APPROVES OF PRESIDENT
            WILSON'S PROPOSITIONS
            President Wilaon and Colonel House Arc Named a The
            American, Representatives on Commission to Elaborate
            A Constitution For the League Including lis Preroga
            tives Would Guarantee Peace
            An Integral Part Of The Treaty
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1919-02-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1919-02-14</time>
        <text>
            PARIS, Feb. 14. -The foil text and covenant of the League of
            Nations was officially announced today as follows:
            COVENANT PREAMBLE
            "In order to promote international co-operation and to secure
            international peace and security, by the acceptance of obligations not
            to resort to war, by the prescription of open, just, and honorable re
            lations between nations, by the firm establishment of the understand
            ings of international law as the actual role of conduct among govern
            ments, and by the maintenance of justice and a scrupulous respect
            for all treaty obligations in the dealings of organized peoples with
            one another, the powers signatory to this covenant adopt this con
            stitution of the League of Nations.
            "ARTICLE ONE.
            "The action of the high contracting parties under the terms of
            this covenant shall be effected through the instrumentality of meet
            ing of a body of delegates representing the high contracting parties,
            of meetings at more frequent intervals of an executive council and
            of a permanent international secretariat to be established at the seat
            ot the league.
            "ARTICLE TWO.
            "Meetings of the body of delegates shall be held at stated inter
            vals and from time to time as occasion may require for the purpose of
            dealing with matters within the sphere of action of the league. Meet
            ings of the body of delegates shall be held at the seat of the league or
            at-such other place as may be found convenient and shall consist of
            representatives of high contracting parties. Each jof the. contracting
            parties shall have one vote, but may have not more than ihree rep
            resentatives. L
            "ARTICLE THREE.
            "The executive council shall consist of representatives of the
            United States of America, the British Empire, France, Italy, and
            Japan, together with representatives of four other stales, members
            of the league. The selection of these four states shall In made by the
            body of delegates on such principles and in such manner as they think
            fit. Pending the appointment of these representatives of the other
            states representatives of shall all be members of the executive
            council. Meetings of the council shall be held from time to time as
            occasion may require and at least once a year at whatever place may
            be decided on, or failing any such decision, at the seat of the league,
            and any matter within the sphere of action of the league or affecting
            the peace of this world may be dealt with at such meetings. Invita
            tions shall be sent to any power to attend a meeting of the council at
            which matters directly affecting its interests are to be discussed, and
            no decision taken at any meeting will be binding on such power un
            less so invited.
            "ARTICLE FOUR.
            "All matters of procedure at meetings of the body of delegates
            or the executive council, including the appointment of committees to
            investigate particular matters, shall be regulated by the body of
            delegates or the executive council, and may be decided by a majority
            of the states represented at the meeting. The first meeting of the
            body of delegates and of the executive council shall bo summoned by
            the President of the United States of America.
            "ARTICLE FIVE.
            "The permanent secretariat of the league .shall be established
            :l which shall constitute the seat of the league. The secre
            tariat shall comprise such secretaries and staff as may be required
            under the general direction and control of a secretary general of
            the league, who shall be chosen by the executive council; the secre
            tariat shall be appointed by tho secretary general subject to con
            firmation by the executive council. The secretary general shall act
            in that capacity at all meetings of the body of delegates or of the
            executive council. The expenses of the secretariat shall be borne by
            the states members of the league, in accordance with the apportion
            ment of the expenses of the international bureau of the universal
            postal union.
            "ARTICLE SIX.
            "Representatives of the high contracting parties and officials of
            the league, when engaged on the business of the league, shall enjoy
            diplomatic privileges and immunities, and the buildings occupied by
            the league or its officials or by representatives attending its meetings
            shall enjoy the benefits of extraterritoriality.
            "ARTICLE SEVEN. J w
            "Admission to the league of states not signatories to the covenant
            and not named in the protocol hereto as states to be invited to adhere
            to the covenant requires the assen t of not less than two-thirds of the
            states represented in the body of delegates and shall be limited to
            fully self-governing countries, including dominions and colonies. No
            state shall be admitted to the league unless it is able to give effective
            guarantees of its sincere intention to observe its international obliga
            tions and unless it shall conform to such principles as may be pre
            scribed by the league in regard to its naval and military forces and ar
            maments. "ARTICLE EIGHT.
            "The high contracting parties recognize the principle that the
            maintenance of peace will require the reduction of national arma
            ments to the lowest point consistent with national safety and the
            enforcement by common action of international obligations, having
            special regard to the geographical situation and circumstances of each
            state; and the executive council shall formulate plans for effecting
            such reduction. The executive council shall also determine for the
            consideration and action of the several governments that military
            equipment and armament is fair and reasonable in. proportion to the
            scale, of forces laid down iri the program of disarmament; and these
            iimits, when adopted, shall not be exceeded without iha permission of
            the executive council.
            "The high contracting parties agree that the manufacture by
            private enterprise of munitions and implements of war lends itself
            to grave objections, and direct the executive council to advise how
            the evil effects attendant upon such manufacture can be prevented,
            due regard being had to the necessities of the countries which are
            not able to manufacture for themselves the munitions and implements
            of war necessary for their safety.
            "The high contracting parties undertake in no way to conceal
            from each other the conditions of such of their industries as are capa
            ble of being adapted to warlike purposes or the scale of their anna
            men ts, and agree that there shall be full and frank, interchange of
            information as to their militarv and naval programs.
            "ARTICLE NINE.
            "A permanent commission shall be constituted to advise the league
            on the execution of the provisions of Article Eight and on military and
            naval questions generallv.
            "ARTICLE TEN.
            "The high contracting parties undertake to respect and preserve
            as against external aggression the territorial integrity and existing
            political independence of all states members of the league. In case
            of any such aggression, or in case of any threat or danger of such
            aggression, the executive council shall advise upon the means by
            which the obligation shall be fulfilled.
            "ARTICLE ELEVEN.
            "Any war or threat of war, whether immediately affecting any of
            the high contracting parties or not, is hereby declared a matter of
            concern to the leauo, and the high contracting parties reserve the
            right to take any action that may be deemed wise and effectual to
            safeguard the peace of nations.
            "It is hereby also declared and agreed to be the friendly right of
            ?acli of the high contracting parties to draw the attention of the body
            of delegates or of the executive council to any circumstances affecting
            international intercourse which threaten to disturb international
            peace or the good understanding between nations upon which peace
            lepends.
            "ARTICLE TWELVE.
            "The high contracting parlies agree that should dispute arise
            between them which cannot be adjusted by the ordinal- processes of
            diplomacy they will in no case resort to war without previously
            submitting the questions and matters involved either to arbitration
            or to inquiry by the executive council and until three months after
            J he award by the arbitrators or a recommendation by the executive
            council, and they will not even then resort to war as against a mem-
            Continued on Page 2, Column 1)
            ALLIES SOLID
            WITHSUPPORT
            ESIOENI
            READS DRAFT
            By FRED S. FERGUSON,
            United Press Staff" Correspondent.
            PARIS, Feb. 14. The first world
            constitution was made public this af
            ternoon when President Wilson read
            the draft of the league of nations er
            ganizaticn before the general peac
            congress.
            "While not containing a provisioa
            for any sort of international police
            force, the constitution iwciwie
            striegent-raeasures designed to prc
            ventfuture' wars. I -case any na
            tion makes war without first submit
            ting the questions at issue to arbitra
            tion there are the following possible
            courses open to the league:
            Slay Combine Against Olfcwter.
            Severance of diplomatic relations
            between members of tho league asi
            the recalcitrant power.
            Economic blockade of ihe nation
            refusing arbitration.
            Recommendation by the executive
            council fccforc the use of force.
            The use of force, however, will
            leave to each power freedom of ac
            tion under its action to make the
            necessary declarations of war.
            The international police force, or
            general staff, urged by the French,
            and put to a vote yesterday after
            noon after a stirring speech by Sen
            ator Kourgcois was overwhelmingly
            defeated. Only the French and
            Czechs-Slovaks voted in favor o it.
            With this feature eliminated the con
            stitution was adopted unanimously.
            Add Five New Articles.
            The constitution includes a pre
            amble and twenty-six articles,
            having teen increased from the orig
            inal twenty-two articles during yes
            terday's session of the league com
            mittee. The last articles arc devoted
            to purely parliamentary matters, the
            others covering organization of the
            league.
            Congratulations on securing adop
            tion of the league constitution poured
            in to American headquarters at the
            Hotel Crillon before this afternoon's
            plenary session. Members of the
            League to Enforce Peace declared
            this "is the golden day in the history
            of the world." They declared that,
            despite rumors circulated in Paris
            France s solidly behind the league
            plan.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-03-04/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1919-03-04</time>
        <text>
            37 Senators Reject Wilson's Peace League Plan;
            Demand Swiit Settlement With Germany First
            16,000 to
            Strike at
            6 A. M. in
            N. Y. Harbor
            100,000 To Be Affected
            if Plans of the Union
            Leaders for Tie-Up of
            AH Crafts Succeed
            Yraiy and Navy
            Tugs Will Work
            Police Prepare to Take
            Caro of Crowds That
            Rush to Tunnels;
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-04-12/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1919-04-12</time>
          <text>
              Lord Robert Ceril Comes
              Out Flatly in Support of
              Wilson. and League Clause
              Is Adopted Without Vote
              PARIS, April 11 (By The Associated
              |Pres3).--Discussion of the Monroe
              Doctrine amendment by the league of
              nations commission last night is de?
              scribed by those present as having
              been nf a dramatic character, conclud
              ing with a speech by President Wilson
              deprecating the opposition which had
              been expressed nnd upholding the doc?
              trine as one of the great bulwarks
              against absolutism. The debate came
              lato in the session, after other sub
              jects had been passed upon.
              The British attitude had been in
              doubt until the last, but Lord Robert.
              Cecil turned the scales by announcing
              that he savv no objection in the amend?
              ment in the form presented by the
              President. M. Larnaude, of the French
              delegation, followed Lord Robert with
              objections to inserting the Monroe
              Doctrine.
              The Chinese also offcred objection to
              the amendment on the ground that its
              i language war. so extended that it might
              validate certain principles and claims
              J affecting Chinese affairs.
              Tho President paid thc closest at-
              tention to the opposition to the amend?
              ment and jotted down notes for a re?
              ply. In his speech the President spoke
              with great enrnestness and with some
              evidence of feeling.
              The President declared the .Monroe
              Doctrine was enunciated t.o combat. the
              Holy Alliance nnd to hold back the
              throat of absolutism which was then
              menacing Europe and seeking to spread
              its power to the Western Hemisphere.
              It. served its purpose in keeping this
              absolute power from the Wesvtern
              World
              One of its great purposes, he said,
              was to raaintain territorial and politi?
              cal integrity, and. having served its
              great purpose in the Western World, it
              now was being brought to the lands
              which had felt the hand of absolutism
              and militarism. It was a source of sur
              prise and discouragement, the Presi?
              dent said, to hear opposition expressed
              to such a doctrine and such a purpose.
              The President's speech closed thc
              4iscussion. There was no vote, and,
              when there were no further remarks,
              the chairman of the meeting said the
              amendment would be considered adopt?
              ed. The commission thi n took up the
              next article of the covenant.
              While the text of the .Monroe amend?
              ment is withheld, its main features are
              substantially along the following line
              "Article X -Nothing in this cove?
              nant shall be construed as invali
              dating any agreement, such as th"
              Monroe Doctrine, for the maintcnanc
              of peace."
              The exact language of the amend?
              ment ia closely guard* d, and i ffoi
              to obtain a copy of the text met with
              the statement that although there iS
              peculiar American interest in the
              announcement there was 110 reason or
              departing from the definite policy 0f
              tiie commission not to disclose textual
              changes in the covenant as the wort
              progresses.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1920-01-16/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1920-01-16</time>
          <text>
              By the Associated Tress
              Paris, .Tan. 10. Representatives' of
              France, Great Britain, Italy, Greece,
              Belgium, Spain, Japan and Brazil,
              members of the council of the
              league of nations, met in the clock room
              of the French foreign office at 10 o'clock
              this morning for the first meeting in the
              history of tho league.
              The council organized at 10:.10 o'clock
              by electing Leon Bourgeois chairman,
              and confirming the choice of Sir Eric
              Drummond, of Great Britain, as general
              secretary.
              The first official act of the council
              was the appointment of a commission to
              trace upon the spot the frontiers of the
              territory of the Sarrc basin.
              j Irish Attach League
              The council received the first formI
              ipiotest to be presented to It almost
              1 before it came into bing. The pro
              test was irom "the envoys 01 the
              elected government of the Irish Repub
              lic" against "the unreal English simu
              lacrum of an international league of
              peace."
              No melition of the nrntrat. wim ma7
              during the meeting of the council, buti -t
              iuinra were nanuea to the newspaper;
              I corrcapondents after thev Ipft tn fwilsMt
              1 eign ofhee. The document was sisnwlis&amp;N
              Ouaklaigh Duffy." It registered "ob-i?
              lections, in -the "pretended league- VitLJUU
              I naiious, and declared the league to be
              an engine of empire, designed to Se
              cure and jierpetuato English hegemony
              throughout both hemispheres."
              I The protest insisted that the league
              was illusory and incomplete, lacking
              authority and sanction, nnd declared
              that the I'nited States stood out "in
              indignation and repudiation" of it.
              Bourgeois Addresses Council
              I.con Bourgeois. French representa
              tive, who presided, said in his openinjt
              address
              "Tho task of presiding at this meet
              ing and inaugurating this great inter
              national institution should have fallen
              ro President Wilson. We respect the
              jeasons which still delay final decision
              by our friends in Washington, but ex
              press the hope that their difficulties will
              soon be overcome and thnt a represen
              tative of the great American republic
              will occupy the place uwaiting him
              among u..
              "The work of tho council will nn
              assume definite character and will have
              that particular force which should be
              associated with our work.
              "January 10, 1020, will go down in
              history as the date of the birth of a
              new world. Decisions- to bo reached
              today will be in Mho name of all na
              tions adhering to the covenant nt i,
              I league. It will be the first decree of all
              free nations leaguing themselves to
              I gether, for the first time in the world,
              to substitute right for might
              1 "But the organization of the league
              of nations will not be complete until
              the assembly of all the states meets."
              British Loyal to League
              Hail Carzon. British secretary ef
              state tor foreign affairs, and that bu
              tion"s representative on the council of
              the league, said
              ';Ou behalf of the British empire I
              1 desire to express the lojaltv of my gov-
              miu-ui. .win mi- exiernni dominions of
              the British crown to the spirit under -l.ving
              the covenant of the league of
              nations. It is our intention by every
              means in our power to insure its prac
              tical efficieucv
              "It is our firm belief
              its instrumentality alone
              to insure that such miseries that tb
              world has experienced during the past
              thnt through
              we can hope
              mssiyasM
              iwsme waiiiig or ine storm to break.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1920-01-16/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1920-01-16</time>
          <text>
              League Of Nations
              Convenes In Paris
              Without America
              Leon Bourgeois, French Representative, Calls Meeting
              to Order in Absence of President Wilson; Declares
              Day Will Go Down in History as Birth of New
              World; worK or tne uouncu is not uompieie.
              ARIS. France Jan t Bepre-
              i sentatives of France Great Brit
              ain. Italy, Greece, Belgium. Spain.
              Japan and Brazil, members of the
              council of the league of nations, met
              to the -dock room" of the French
              foreign office at 10 oclock this morn
              ing" for the first meeting in the his
              tory of the league
              The council organised at 10 30
              oclock by electing Leon Bourgeois
              chairman and confirming the choice
              of Sir Brie Drummond of Great
              Britain as general secretary
              The first official net of the
              counell wa the appointment of
              a commission to trace upon the
              spot the frontier of the terri
              tory of the Sarre bait la.
              Leon Bourgeois. French represen
              tative, who presided, said "The task
              of presiding at this meeting and in
              augurating this great international
              institution should have fallen to
              president Wilson We recent the
              reasons which still delay final de
              cision by our friends in Washington,
              but express the hope that their diffi
              culties will soon be overcome and
              that a representative of the great
              American republic will occupy the
              place awaiting him among us. The
              work of the council will then assume
              definite character and will have that
              particular force which should be as
              sociated with our work
              Birth of Aew 'Nation."
              "January 16, 120. will go down in
              history as the date of the birth of a
              new world. Decisions to be reached
              today will be in the name of all na
              tions adhering to the covenant of the
              league.
              It will be the flrat decree of
              all free nations leamilnc them
              welve together, for the first time
              la the world to substitute rla-ht
              for might. But the organisation
              of Ihe league of nation will not
              be complete until the assembly
              of nil the states meet.
              1aavi nwtnn nr4lal rtirff t.t
              state for foreign affair and that
              nation's representative on the coon-
              .i r ..j I
              -On behalf of the British empire
              I desire to express the loyalty of my
              government and the external domin-'
              ions of the British 'crown to the spirit
              underlying the covenant of the league
              of nations. It ia our intention by
              every means In our power to insure
              Its oracucal exiteieacr it ts our
              firm belief that through Its instru
              mentality alone we can hope to in
              sure that such miseries that the
              world has experienced during the
              past five year shall not be repeated
              ana mat a new era oi international
              relationship shall dawn.
              "V Universal Desire.
              "The league of nations is an ex
              pression of the universal desire for
              saner methods of regulating affairs
              of mankind, and provides machinery
              by which practical effect may be
              given the principles of international
              friendship and good understanding
              The success of the labors of the peace
              conference ts a good augury for the
              future of the league of nations. For
              the first time an attempt was made
              to bring together under the ausnices
              iot tne league representatives oi gov
              ernments, employes and labors and
              an advance exceeding the results of
              the entire work of th" previous quar
              ter of a tentury has be n made in
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-11-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Wilson+League+Geneva</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1920-11-14</time>
          <text>
              League Meets
              In Geneva; 41
              Nations There
              All Delegates Present Ex?
              cept Balfour, of England,
              Who Is 111; Swiss
              Try to Assist Covenant
              Germany the Big Issue
              Lloyd George Is Expected
              to Swing the Assembly on
              the Important Question

              By Arthur S. Draper
              Special Cable tn The Tribune
              Copyright, 1920. New York Tribune Inr.
              GENEVA, Nov. 13.?The scenery is
              all set for the opening of the League
              of Nations assembly Monday. All the
              delegates from forty-one countries are
              now present, with the notable exception
              of Arthur Balfour, of Great Britain,
              who has been slightly ill and will not
              reach Geneva until the middle of the
              week.
              Elaborate preparations have b?en
              made for the first historic meeting in
              the Hall of Reformation. The flags of
              twoscore states, with the exception of
              the United States, Germany and Rus?
              sia, are flying from the hotels and pub?
              lic buildings, while the hall itself is a
              mass of color.
              Geneva is just beginning to realize
              what an important responsibility it ac?
              cepted when it became the headquar?
              ters of the League of Nations, but it is
              Handling the unexpectedly large num?
              ber of distinguished visitors in a way
              such as only experienced hosts could.
              The state authorities are making'
              every effort to assist the league. Mo*v i
              of the Swiss are sincere supporters of:
              the organization.
              Germany the Big Issue
              The final meeting of the league coun-
              eil before the assembly gave the mem- j
              bers an opportunity to consider the
              program to be followed at the meetings
              at this place and to canvass opinion
              j on such questions as mandates, the
              protection of minorities, international
              finance and the Polish-Lithuanian dis-
              pute. Although all of these matters
              are to be under discussion, that of j
              chief importance among them all is
              Germany.
              Most of the delegates arrived with
              instructions as to their attitude to?
              ward the .admission of Germany to the
              league, but the situation shifts hourly
              and it is difficult to say exactly what
              the final turnup will be. Lloyd George
              is expected to make a dramatic ap?
              pearance some day next week and
              (Continued on page three)
              Turkish Nationalists
              Proclaim Soviet Rule
              Mustapha Kemal Named Peo?
              ple's Commissariat; Forces
              ('ailed to Smyrna Front
              PARIS, Nov. 13. -A Bavas Agency
              dispatch from Constantinople, dated
              'Thursday, says the Nationalist A.ssem-
              bly at Angora has adopted sovietism i
              i and proclaimed Mustapha Kemal, the
              Turkish .\ationa! Leader, as the people's j
              i commissariat.
              The military council at Angora is
              declared to have decided to transfer
              i the National forces to the Smyrna
              front when the operations in Armenia
              i are concluded.
          </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 additional -->
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026853/1919-03-07/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=league+of+nations&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.364,-0.021,1.728,1.728,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1919-03-07</time>
          <text>
              Resolved, That America Should Join
              the League of Nations.
              AFFIRMATIVE.
              America should join the League to
              protect tc* liberties of the world.
              t? :J~?4- w;i_
              (If we do tot join, as riesmcuu
              son sayi, '^e will set up a great j
              ideal oi liberty' and then refuse to;
              aid th? Drld to win the privileges!
              which we ourselves enjoy. But, to j
              do this would be against the principles
              which Washington fought for;
              it would be contrary to the ideals
              which sent our sons to France. The
              oppressed peoples of Europe look to
              us to show them the way to freedom.
              We are today the hope of the world.
              Quoting further from Wilson's
              speech at Boston: "If America were
              of +Vmc -innM-nre to fail the world,'
              I what would come of it? Men will be
              thrown back upon the bitterness, not;
              only the disappointment, but also
              the bitterness of despair. Think of;
              the picture?think of the utter blackness
              that would fall upon the world.,
              America has failed I America made,
              a little essay at generosity and then
              withdrew.
              America said, 'We are your
              friends,' but it was only for today,,
              not for tomorrow. America said,;
              'Here is our power to vindicate right' j
              and the next day said, 'Let right take
              care of itself, and we will take care,
              of ourselves.' America said, 'Wej
              set up a light to lead men along the
              lik?*?4-xr Tirn liovo IaW-!
              UB pauis Ul liUCl l/J f I/Wif nv "Uiv *vtf
              S3 ered it. It is intended only to light,
              9 our own path.'
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1919-09-09/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=league+of+nations&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.189,-0.291,1.378,1.378,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1919-09-09</time>
          <text>
              "Will the President deny that the
              "League of Nations gives the supervision.
              of our trade In arms to the league, while
              the Constltutldn gives It to Congress?
              "Is It not true that the covenant of
              the league provides that when the else
              of the army nnd navy has been fixed as
              provided under it they cannot be In
              creased without the consent of the
              league, while the Constitution gives Con
              gress the absolute power to raise armies
              and navies?
              "It Is not true that the covenant
              Obligates us to defend the territorial In
              tegrity Of all of the proposed members
              of the league? How can we defend their
              territorial integrity without war? What
              voice would -our people have In such a
              war, provided for In advance by the
              League of -Nations, If we are to keep our
              obligations under tho league?
              "Is It not truo that every question
              likely to lead to a rupture Is to be de
              cided by the league, and we are bound
              to obey ita decisions? Does not this In
              volve every interest of the United Stated
              without exception? In this decision,
              dees not Great Britain with her colonies
              have six votes In the body of delegates
              while the United Stntes has only one?
              Why should Great Britain havo six
              tlmjfs as many votes as the United
              BtalcB? And why should Iledjaz or
              Haiti or Liberia have each as many
              votes as the United States?
              "The President says limitation of
              armaments cannot be Obtained without
              the League of Nations. Is that so? If
              It Is so, how Is it that we have limitation
              of armaments between the United States
              and Canada without a League of Na
              tions? Does not the President himself
              ray that' disarmament can only come by
              International conference? Cannot we
              have International conferences without a
              League 'of Nations? Ho says there Is an
              International agreement for disarmament
              In the, covenant or the League of Na
              tlpns. Thero Is no such agreement
              t.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076241/1918-11-29/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=league+of+nations</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1918-11-29</time>
          <text>
              To Senator Reed of Missouri belongs the distinction of discover
              ing in the proposed League of Nations to Enforce Peace a treasonable
              conspiracy against the honor and interests of the United States. Such
              a league, he says, would involve us in every European quarrel; it
              would expose the president to the cabals of raonarchs, all closely re
              lated; it would necessarily result in the creation of an international
              army powerful enough to coerce any nation, the United states in
              eluded, of course, which in time might be commanded by a German
              field marshal, and in, its councils, eacn nation voting as a unit, this
              mighty republic would have no more influence than Hayti or Liberia.
              If the senator can-be made to understand that the League of
              Nations is not altogether a hallucination but a practical conception of
              international action which is soberly indorsed by many far-seeing
              men, he will realize that every one of his objections has been or will
              be answered, the New-York World declares. We hesitate to assume
              that Mr. Reed has intentionally misrepresented the plan which he as
              sails, but, plainly enough, he is lll-inrormed as to its inspiration and
              purpose.
              The war now ending has shown that never again can wre ignore
              European quarrels. We did our best some people thought our worst
              --to keep out of this one, and failed. The nations of the earth are
              too closely associated to hope ever again to be disinterested observers
              of war between important belligerents. In that role we suffered
              many wrongs and humiliations, and the-neutrality of such states as
              Holland, Norway and Denmark has been hardly less costly than war.
              A League of Nations has always beenpredicated upon the dls
              appearance of autoeracyy-which has been the parent of aggresion
              and strife. The last of the autocrats has gone, and the monarchs of
              whom Mr. Reed stands in such fear have less actual power than the
              governor of an American commonwealth.
              How a League of Nations would arrive at its conclusions and en
              force them against offenders has not yet been worked out, but we
              think it must be.taken for granted that before such an organization
              can be effected the purpose of the world to maintain peace and jus
              tice will be made known beyond a peradventure, and that, with that
              common aim once established, the method by which it is to be at
              tained will be reached without much difficulty. Afterall, it is noth
              ing but democratic self-government on a large scale, j
              Inother words, a League of Nations presupposes a membership
              of free and civilized and not enslaved and savage nations. It must
              rest also to some extent upon mutual respect and confidence. To be
              effective it must mckide every considerable nation. Its success will
              depend more upon the principles of its members than upon any meas
              ures of disarmament, although it is expected, of course, that in time
              the great war machines ot the present day will be seen no more.
              Such a League of Nations as most people have in mind wHl not
              execute its decrees with the sword, and so Mr. Reed's hideous dream
              that a German may in time lead an overpowering international force
              against the United States falls to the ground. Its' discipline in the
              first instance will be commercial and financial. No unruly govern
              ment can long survive an international boycott. None but unruly
              peoples need fear anything more drastic than that.
              A Leagiie of Nations to Enforce Peace should be no more ter
              rible to well-disposed nations than the rule of law to communities
              long subject to assassins, mobs and lynchers. It would seem that this
              truth might appeal to Mr. Reed as a distinguished member of the
              bar, even if he were not a senator of the United States.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84001718/1920-10-29/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=league+of+nations&amp;r=-1.137,-0.042,3.274,1.482,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1920-10-29</time>
          <text>
              Under the name of "mandates” of
              the League of Nations, a military gov
              ernment is being imposed upon Meso
              potamia and Syria. It may be neces
              sary; but it is neither necessary nor
              proper that the United States shall
              become a party to it. Whether we
              shall or not not may be finally deter
              mined by the senate, and by a single
              vote in the senate.
              The Republican party proposes to
              maintain those separate fortunes for
              which our fathers fought. America
              independence of Europe has meant
              much for the world as well as for
              ourselves, and its sacrifice would be
              a sacrifice for all mankind as well
              ns for ourselves.
              ~lf disarmament can be brought
              about it will be by friendly agreement,
              as with Canada, and not by a military
              league, as established at Paris.
              If the future peace of the world
              is to encouraged, it will be by the
              eonditieation of international law and
              the establishment of a court of law
              judges, to which the nations, in a free
              association will submit disputes.
              Only war will come from the setting
              up a centralized military power,
              which by its assembly, exercising, as
              the President has said, "the major
              forces of mankind." will subject the
              world to an unscrupulous and irre
              sponsible politicial and military des
              potism.
              Thi! Democratic party will deny
              that such a power will be unscroupu
              lous or despotic. The history of the
              world proves that It will be.
              The safeguard of the nation Is the
              election of u senate pledged to sup
              port our Constitution, or interests,
              and our American policies of peace
              and friendship with all nations and
              governmental union with none. We
              have fought four wars with Eunropean
              nations to prevent the control of
              American affairs by Europe, and won
              them all. It is certain that if the
              League of Nations had been in exist
              ence we would never have gained our
              independence. Do not let us now
              commit the supreme folly an dthe “su
              preme sacrifice” of voluntarily sur
              rendering the independence and sepa
              rate station in the world which we
              have won.—Miles Poindexter.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076241/1920-10-08/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=league+of+nations&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.29,-0.079,1.579,1.579,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1920-10-08</time>
          <text>
              Governor Cox states that as president he will bring the League
              of Nations before the senate at the tirst opportunity for ratification
              with any helpful reservations that are advanced.
              Senator Harding states that the League of Nations is dead, that
              he is against it and so the issue is clearly denned.
              In the event of the election of Governor Cox the first official act
              he performs will be to enter the United States in the League of Na
              tions and to cause this nation to assume its rightful place in the pro
              gress and advancement of the world. He will bring about that for
              which the American soldiers went overseas the elimination of wars
              in the future through the agreement of the nations of the world act
              ing in harmony through the League of Nations.
              Senator Harding offers no substitute. He is -boldly, unutter
              ably against the League of Nations.
              This is the situation presenting itself in this campaign. Will
              the American people vote for Cox and the League of Nations or will
              they follow blindly a candidate who offers them nothing tangible
              to prevent future devastating wars?
          </text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>