<topic>
   <id>
   https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-theft-mona-lisa
   </id>
   <results>
    <result>
         <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016810/1910-08-20/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Lisa+Mona
         </id>
         <rel>1</rel>
         <text>
         RARE CANVAS GONE Da Vinci's "Mona Lisa," Missing From Louvre Gallery. Celebrated Painting Has Been a Mystery for Four Centuries- Savants Puzzled Over Beau-tiful Model's Smile. 
         Paris. - The "Mona Lisa" of Leonardo da Vinci, the world famous painting for which offer of $5,000,000 is said to have been refused and which is reported to have been stolen from the Lovure in Paris, for 400 years
         has been as much a riddle as the Sphinx itself. But one man-Solomon Reinach, brother of the Reinach of notorirty in the Dreyfus affair-ever has been so brazen as to proclaim the solution of the smile tat wreathes the face of the woman in the picture.
         His answer was laughed to scorn by art critics. Others have commented ont he painting, but Reinach aline authoritatively announced that the mystery was ended.
         </text>
      </result>
      <result>
         <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87078082/1911-09-06/ed-1/seq-6/#words=Lisa+LISA+MONA+Mona
         </id> 
         <rel>1</rel>
         <text>
         DISAPPEARANCE OF THE "MONA LISA" RECALLS THEFT OF FAMOUS GAINSBOROUGH Leondaro's Painting IS Regarded as the Finest In the World "Duchess od Devonshire" Was Returned After Quarter of a Century
         By JAMES A.EDGERTON THE dissapearance of the famous "Mona Lisa" of Leondardo da Vinci from the Louvre, at Paris, is the lastest nine days' wonder in the world of art. This great painting, also known as "La Giocondo", has been pronounced by many the finest in the world.
         It certainely stands in a list of the world's half dozen greatest paintings and in popular regard perhaps ranks second only to the "Sistine Madinna" by Raphael. Some think "The Last Supper," also by Da Vinci, greater than "Mona Lisa," but this sort of comparison is fruitless, as the two paintings 
         are quite different in the subject and treatment. The loss of this picture is regarded by the FRench as a national calamity. To them it is not only priceless, but a part of their very life. It has been reported, and is probably true, that the French government once refused an offer of $5,000,000 for the painting. 
         Upon its dissapearance the Louvre was closed for several dats, a large force of police was set to work searching every nook and cranny of the great building, and sixty detectives were started working on the outside. One of the theories of the authorities was that the theif was a young man who was known to have become enamored of the painting and who had visitedit at intervals 
         for several months, sitting before it with a rapt expression for hours together. They believe that he fell in love with the face, as painters have been known to become enamored of their own works, and grew insane upon the subject, his mania finally prompting the crime. So much people were affected by this masterpiece that some shed tears at sight of it. Not a few letters have been received at the Louvre addressed to "Mona Lisa" and expressing love to her as to a living person.
         That the deed was the owrk of some deranged person seems almost certain for the reason that the picture could not be disposed of and hence would be without value of the thief. A painting is only valuable when shown. If the criminal could dispose of i to a private collector and it cannot be conceived that any thief would dare to offer it for sale or that any collector would be so foolish or depraved as to buy such collector would not dare exhibit it for fear of detection. While there are many
         copies of the painting that the average man could hardly detect from the original, there are always those who can distinguish and now that the whoel world is on the lookout for the picrure every copy will be subjected to closer inspection. Moreover, an old master is chiefly valuable because it is an original, and to be able to refer to it as such and to know in his heart that the claim is true constitute its chief value to the collector; hence insanity of one form or another is the only rational explanation of the act. That paradox and all.
         An interesting fact in this connection is that several months ago it was reported in the public print that "Mona Lisa" had been stolen and a copy substituted in its place. This was afterward denied, but the dissappearance now makes it seem a strange coincidence, almost a prophecy. There is one other possible explanation. It is notorious that in Europe the trade of making fake "old masters" flourishes apace, chiefly for the purpose of guilling American millionaires. These copies are properly aged by processes that the fakers know and are then sold for
         fabulous prices to those who have more money than expert knowledge or perhaps real appreciation of "old masters." To do this work fakers have to posses originals in order that the copy may be as nearly perfect as possible. Sometimes these imitiations are so close that they fool even the experts. Many pictures have been stolen in the past, but none even approaching the values of "Mona Lisa." The most famous case in modern times was the theft of Gainsborough's famous portrait of the "Duchess of Devonshire." The "electioneering duchess" she was called, having been active in her husband's
         political canvasses. This painting was missing nearly a quarter of a century and was finally returned through the instrumentality of the late Pat Sheedy, the "square" gambler. Sheedy's version of the affair was that the theif was Adam Worth, whom Sheedy regarded as the greatest criminal of the last century. The painting wasoriginally stolen to be used in an effort to get one of Worth's accomplices out of jail. The man escaped on a technicality, however, and Worth had the picture on his hands. He did not dare to sell it or even to mention its existence. The painting was kept in a hermetically sealed case in the false bottom of a trunk. The Pinkertons,
         believed that Worth wasthe thief, but could not prove it. This is where Sheedy came into the case. Worth had at one time done Sheedy a kindness-$2000 worth of kindness, to be exact. Pinkerton heard of this and asked Sheedy that if he ever saw Worth again to find out about the Gainsborough. Some years later, when Sheedy was running a gambling joint in Constantinople, he received word from Adam Worth, who was in trouble, as usual. Sheedy, of course, more than made good the former loan and got Worth out. He then mentioned the matter of the Gainsvorough, and Worth replied that he was on the point of breaking the ice on that subject himself. The upshot of it all was that Sheedy acted as a go-between 
         got the picture out of the false bottom of the trunk where it was in storage in Boston, had the British owners over to examine it, collected the $25,000 reward, presumably turned over the money to Adam Worth and his pals and as a result of the incident got into "art" himself. Worth was so grateful for Sheedy's action in the Gainsborough affair that before his death he insisted on giving Pat an original Murillo which had been stolen out of some monastery. When this came into his hands Sheedy tried to find the rightful owners, advertising extensively in South America and elsewhere, but failed. Some years later he heard that Raisuli, the Moroccan bandit, had in his possession a Correggio, which was also
         obtained. Pat;s reputation as a connoisseur in high art was made.
         </text>
    </result>
    <result>
         <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066313/1912-05-23/ed-1/seq-2/#words=Lisa+Mona
         </id>
         <rel>1</rel>
         <text>
         On August 21, 1911, the picture was missed from its place in the Louvre.The guard thought the official photographer had taken it to his studio to copy it, as he often did. It was not until late Tuesday evening that the guard announced the picture had been stolen. After a hasty search, heavy frame was found under a stairway leading to one of the cloakrooms. A scaffold against the facade of the Louvre, placed there in connection with the installation of an elevator, made it easy to enter or leave the building. A persom acquainted with the interior and provided with keys to the various rooms could easily reach the Salon Carre where the picture hung. Some say the portrait was stolen as an object lesson, to show how
         careless the keepers of the Louvre were and how easily pictures could be stolen. Others think perhaps an artist has stolen it and will return a reproduction and keep the original, or that a big reward will be demanded and its payment the picture will be returned in an indirect way after the excitement has dies down. More romantic than any of these conjectures is that "Mona Lisa" is another Helen of Troy. Some one has fallen in love with her and in desperation carried her off to his secret altar from the stare of the croeds and jealousy guard her from the eyes of other worshipers.
         Where "Mona Lisa" is hidden, she is carefully guarded, for no trace has been found; and Paris, as well as thousands of sightseers who have gazed upon her beauty, are still wondering and talking of her dissappearance.
         </text>
    </result>
    <result>
         <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084272/1913-10-26/ed-1/seq-30/#words=Lisa+Mona
         </id>
         <rel>1</rel>
         <text>
         Trying to Steal Mona Lisa's Sister How the Authorities at the Louvre Hope to Save Leonardo da Vinci's Other Masterpiece from the Fate That Overtook "La Joconde." PAris, SINCE "Mona Lisa" was so mysteriously stolen from the Louvre, the authorities of that world-famous art museum have been warned, and have taken unusual precautions to save Leonardo da Vinci's sister masterpiece from a similar fate. This painting, equally esteemed by art connoisseurs, but overshadowed for the mass of visitors by the enormous fame of "Mona Lisa"
         -or "La Joconde," as the French call it, because of its haunting smile-is an idealized portrait od Lucrezia Crevelli, the beautiful young Lombard poetess who inspired Lombardo's brush during the earlier period of his fame. Owing to the jewelled band which encircles the brow, the picture is called "La Belle Ferronniere." In this case Leonardo performed marvels with a pair of wonderful eyes, which are hardly less compelling in their influence than the elusive smile of "Mona Lisa." paris devotees at the shrine of the great Lombardo have always divided
         their acts of devotion pretty equally between "Mona Lisa" and "La Belle Ferronniere," standing before them for hours in evident rapture over that smile and those eyes, and then going home and writing love letters to them. These love letters of prtraits of Italian beauties three hundred yeaers in their graves are always opened and read by the Louvre authorities. To the writer of some such letters they attribute the theft of "Mona Lisa." Since the dissappearance of that masterpiece the devotional visits and letters to "La Belle Ferronnieere" have doubled in numbers, and the actions
         of some of the visitors and letter writers have been so fanatical that the painting has been placed under a competent guard night a day. It is also guarded against a too close approach by nay but its official custodians. When Leonardo da Vincii painted Lucrezia he was still a "primitive." He had not yet discovered the effect of light and atmonsphere When he painted the poetess he was a pagan-when he produced "Mona Lisa" he was a mystic. Not less marvellous either in conception or execution is the portrait of Lucrezia than that of her better known sister. It is more subtle more difficult to understand,
         that is all. In all the world there does not exist more than a baker's dozen of absolutely authentic paintings by Leonardo. He produced but one great work of sculpture, a esquestrain statue that stood before the feudal castle of his princely, but illigigtimate ancestors, the Sforzesco family of Milan. During the wars that swept over Europe between Charles the Fifth, Henry the Eigth and Francis the First, from which northern Itlay suffered so much and when so many princely treasures were destroyed, this historic monument and the majority of da Vinci's paintings dissappeared. Since the recent dissapearance of the "Mona Lisa" a most
         rigid surveillance is kept over this other great portrait. Already the fickle public is fast losing interest over the lost "Mona Lisa" and the beautiful poetess who held the younger Leonardo under her magic sway is to replace the sphinx-like "La 
         Joconde." Instead if the unfathomable smile, one ponders over the tempting bow-mouth, the finely chiselled lips with a sensitive turn at the corners; instead of those glistening with humor, sometimes cruel and snake-like, ever enigmatical, ine revels in the depths of those glorious eyes that Leonardo has preserved for us those great intresting eyes of the Lombard poetess whose inner mind is so revealed in the face yet who seems to ask the question that "Mona Lisa" knew and defied the world to answer. It was the Salle Carre(Square Hall) of the Louvre that contained "Mona Lisa," as ther the light is most favorable. That the equally beautiful "La Belle Ferronniere" has been kept in the semi-seclusion of the long, narrow gallery, however has not hidden it from Leonardo enthusiasts, and now the general public has discovered the
         sister painting, thronging the less favired gallery and adding to the perplexities of the custodians.
         </text> 
        </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1913-12-13/ed-1/seq-4/#words=LISA+Lisa+MONA+Mona+Perugia+Vincenzo
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        STOLE 'MONA LISA' TO AVENGE ITALY Italian Workingman Resented Art Spoliation by the First Napoleon. ITS RETURN TO FRANCE TO BE WITH CEREMONY Art Dealer Through Whom Painting Was Recovered May Get Reward of $48,000. FLORENCE Italy, December 13.-the authenticity ofthe "Mona Lisa" found yesterday in possession of Vincenzo Perguia was confirmed by experts after further examination today. The picture bears the seals of the Louvre and other galleries in which it has been hung, while the traces of repairs ar the back of the canvas also are visible. The prisoner was again interrogated by the police authorities this morning. He
        repeated his story of having stolen the picture as an act of patriotic vengeance for Napoleon's depredations in Italy. He displayed the utmost indignation at his treatment by the police, declaring it unjust after the risks he had run and the abnegation he had demonstrated out of patriotic sentiment. A number of prominent Italians have written to the Italian piblic instruction requesting him to permit "Mona Lisa" to be placed on exhibition in Florence, its former home, before returning it to the French government. Some weeks ago an Italian wrote to Signor Geri, an antiquary of Florence, saying :"I am in possession of the missing "Mona Lisa, " but being a patriotic Italian I desire that it shall reamian in Florence, the center of Italian art." he igned the letter "Leonard," and the antiquary at first paid small attention to it, thinking he had to do with a madman . Later, however, he communicated with Dr. Poggi, director of the Florentine museums, who suggested that he continue the correspondence with the man. This was done, and an appointment was arranged whereby Geri was to view the picture at Milan.
        The date set was November 17, but unforseen circumstances prevented the meeting. Recognizes "Mona Lisa." A young man fairly well dressed, visited Geri thursday. He said he was "Leonard" and was staying  at the Hotel Tripoli. He asked Geri to go with him to see the picture. The dealewr notified Dr. Poggi, who hastened to the hotel, and on being recognized it as the genuine "Mona Lisa." Dr. Poggi asked to be allowed to take the picture with him, so that he might compare it with other works. He made an appointment to meet "Leonard" yesterday afternoon at the hotel, to agree upon the price, The director took with him several officers, who placed the man under arrest. On being interrogated the prisoner said his real name is Vincenzo Perugia, thathe was born in the province of como, is by profession a decorator, and is unmarried. For six years he lived in France, and for three years was employed at the Louvre. Perugia posed as a patriot. "I was ashamed he said, "that for more than a century no Italian had thought of avenging the spoliation committed by Frenchmen under Napoleon, when they carried off from the Italian mueseums and
        galleries pictures, status and treasures of all kinds by wagonloads, ancient manuscripts by thousands, and gold by sacks." Stolen Early in Morning He had often observed, he said, in the Louvre many works of art stolen from Italy, and conceived the idea of returning to its true home Leonardo da Vinci's masterpiece. He entered the Louvre early in the morning, detached the pciture beneath his workman's blouse, and succeeded in leaving the place without attracting suspicion. At the time of the theft Perugia was not employed in the Louvre, but he knew all the exits and entrances, and how to avoid attention. He kept the painting concealed. he said, until his patriotism led him to offer it to the Italian people. the picture was identified by Dr. Corrado Ricci, director general of the department of fine arts, who was dispatched hurriedly to Florence from Rome by the minister of public instruction, Luigi Credaro. Finger Prints Confirm Confession. PARIS, December 13.-Rene Viviani, French minister of the public instruction, announced at the cabinet council today that there was no doubt the picture "Mona Lisa" had been recovered and was now at Florence, Italy.
        He said he had telegraphed to the Italian premier thanking him and the Italian government for their prompt action. A representative of the fine arts department is on the way to Rome to bring the picture back to Paris. Fresh proof that "Mona Lisa" was taken from the Louvre by Vincenzo Perugia was established today when his finger prints taken when he was convincted some time ago of carrying firearms without a permit were compared with those on the frame and glass of the picture and found exactly similar. The finger prints on the glass and frame were preserved by the police and the similarity with those of Perugia is apparent. Excitement in Paris. With "Mona Lisa" found what was one of the unfathomable mysteries has been solved. The sensatuon caused by its recovery was equaled only by that caused by its dissappearance in August, 1911. Special editions of the newspapers carried the news the length and breadth of Paris, and last night it was the sole topic of conversation. The Florence dealer, Geri, it iis believed, will be entitled to claim reqards amounting to 240,000 francs ($48,000) offered by the Society of Friends of the Louvre and Paris newspapers. 
        Regarded as Priceless. "Mona Lisa," or "La Joconde," is one of the world's famous paintings, and regarded as priceless. Leonardo da Vinci took as his model for the pictureLisa del S=GIocondo, a woman of Florence. He worked on the picture for four years, from 1500 to 1504. It was bought for France by Francis I. The value of the work can only be imagined since all offers to buy it were refused, among them ine reported to have been made by the British government of $5,000,000. The famous painting had hung in the place of honor in the Louvre in a room which was supposed to be always watched. It dissappeared on the morning of August 22, 1911, and its absence was not noticed by its guardians until some hours later.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045396/1913-12-13/ed-1/seq-12/#words=LISA+Lisa+Mona+MONA
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        "MONA LISA" RECOVERED; THEIF IS IN CUSTODY it to its familiar place and guard it o that theft will be impossible." the Florentine dealer, Gri, it is believed, will be entitled to claim rewards amounting to 240,000 francs($48,000) offered by the Society of Fruends of the Louvre, and a paris newspaper." Expelled Director Joyous. M.J.Thomolele, who was director of the Louvre when "Mona Lisa" was stolen, and who was suspended by the French cabinet because of the loss of the painting, was overcome with jou when he learned of its recovery. Seymour de ricci, an eminent art critic of Paris, declared his faith in the certification of Dr. Corrado Ricci at Florenece of authenticity of the "Mona Lisa". "I do not think there is the slightest doubt," he said, "that the painting will be restored immediately to France." Italy has no claim whatever on the "Mona Lisa," which was given or sold to the French king, Francis I, by Leonardo da Vinci himslef. M. Viviani, minister of public instruction and M. Jacqueir, under-secretary for beaux arts, were both highlt elated over the auspicious event which ushers in their term of office. The Itlaian government has advised them that it will deliver over the picture at once and they are considering the best and safest means of conveying it back to the Louvre.
        The french government will take the earliest opportunity to express its gratitude to the italian givernment for the great service it has rendered in restoring the lost treasure. Perguia resided near the St. Louis hospital. He left here hurridely on Wednesday, saying he was obliged to go to Italy on important business. He is 22 years of age. The son of a carpenter. He came to Paris every year during the season and earned about eight francsa day, returning to some village when work was slack. Outside of a few compatriots, humble workers like himself, he was not known to have any friends in Paris. A neighbot of Perguia described him as an ordianry workman, having no special technical knowledge and completely ignorant in artistic matters. The neighbor, therefore, was astonished to hear that Perugia was accused of stealing the painting and believed that id the accusation were true he could only have been acting at the istigation of someone who had exploited his patriotic sentiments. It was possible, said the man, that Perugia had worked at the Louvre, but neither his relativesnor friends ever have heard it. ITALY WILL RETURN PICTURE TO FRANCE FLORENCE, ITALY DEc. 12 - "Mona Lisa," Leonardo da Vinci's great painting, which was stolen from the Louvre in paris more than two years ago has been found. It is now in the hands of the Italian authorities and will be returned to France.
        "Mona Lisa," or "La Giaconda," as it is more popularly known, the most celebrated portrait of a woman  ever painted, has been the subject of exhaustive search in all quarters of the globe. The mystery of its abstraction from the Louvre, its great intrinsic value, and the strange fascination of the smile of the woman it portrayed-Lisadel GIacondo, wife of a rich Florentine-have combined to keep alive interest in its recovery. The picture was recovered under curious circumstances. An Italian wrote to Signor Geri, an antiquary of Florence, some weeks ago saying: "I am in possession of the missing 'Mona Lisa,' but being a patriotic Italian, I desire that it shall remian in Florence, the center of Italian art." He signed the letter "Leonard," and the antiquary at first paid small attention to it, thinking he had to do with a madman. Later, however he communicated with Dr. Poggi, director of the Florentine mueseums, who suggested that he continue the correspondence with the man. This was arranged whereby Geri was to view the picture at Milan. The date set was November 17, but unforseen circumstances prevented the meeting. A young man, fairly well dressed, visited Geri yesterday, He said he was "Leonard" and was staying at the Hotel Tripoli. He asked Geri to go with him to see the picture. the dealer notified Dr. Poggi, who hastened to the hotel and on being shown the painting recognized it as the genuine "Mona Lisa." Dr Poggi asked to be allowed to take the picture with him so that he might comapre it with other works. He made an appointment to meet "Leonard" this afternoon to agree upon the price. The director took with him several officers, who placed the man underarresr.
        Passes as Patriot On being interrogated the prisoner said his real name was Vincenzo Perguia; that he was born in the province od Come, was by profession a decorator and unmarried. For six years was employed at the Louvre. Perguia, posed as a patriot."I was ashamed," he said, "that for more than a century no Italian had thought of avenging the spoilation committed by Frenchmen under Napoleon. When they carried off from the Italian mueseums and galleries pictures, statues and treasures of all kinds by wagon loads, ancient manuscripts by thousands and gold by sacks." He had often observed, he said, in the Louvre many works of art stolen from Italy, and conceived the idea od returning to its hime Leonardo da Vinci's masterpiece. He entered the Louvre early in the morning detached the picture and removed the painting from the frame. He concealed the frame under the back stairs, where it was afterward found. He hid the picture beneath his workaman's bliuse and succeeded in leaving the place without attracting suspicion. At the time of the theft Perguia was not employed in the Louvre but he knew all the exits and entrances and how to avoid attention. He Kept the painting concealed, he said, until his patriotism led him to offer it to the Italian people. Ricci Takes Big Risk. The painting has also been identified by Dr. Corrado Ricci, director general of the department of fine arts. Who was dispatched hurriedly to Florence from Rome by the minister of public instructiom, Luigi Credaro. After a careful examination, Dr. Ricci telephoned to the minister, who was incredulous. Ricci said: "I will stake my head." To this Senor Credaro replied: this news, after it is published, is found not to be true,
        you will be dismissed." Dr. Ricci answered: "I will take full responsibility and am willing to risk dismissal." News of the discovery of the "Mona Lisa" spread in the chamber of deptuies, in session at Rome, where extremist members were enagaged in flsticuffs in an endeavor to prevent a vote on the election of a Nationalist deputy for Rome. The disorder ceased immediately. The depties surrounded the minister of public instruction who exhibited a telegram from Dr. Rucci, confirming the statement he had already made by telephone. All laughed at the defense of the theif. Some of them remarked that Napoleon's deeds were too antiquated to constitute grounds for feuds. If it were not so Italy would quarrel with the whole world, as all countries, including the United States, had stolen masterpieces from her. The famous "Ascoll Cope," stolen from the cathedral at Ascoll, which was returned by J.Pierpont Morgan, was cited, however, as an instance of american generosity. Will Be Returned to France. Signor Credaro announced that Italy would apply the same generosity. He said he had immediately notified the French embassador, Camille Barrere of the discovery of the painting. He added: "Mona Lisa" will be delivered to the embassador with a solemnity worthy of Leonardo da Vinci and a spirit of happiness worthy of 'Mona Lisa's' smile. Although the masterpiece is dear to all Italians as one of the best productions of the genuis of their race, we will willingly return it to its foster country, which has regretted its loss so bitterly,as a fresh pledge of friendship and brotherhood between the two great Latin nations." The painting is in an almost perfect state of preservation, not withstanding the vicissitudes it must have undergone. Perguia, although he has not made a complete confession, 
        has admitted that he concealed it under the false bottom of a trunk, or fixed behind the canvas of a worthless sketch. MONA LISA MAKES A ROMAN HOLIDAY ROME, Dec. 12-All Rome rejoices at the finding of "Mona Lisa" King Victor Emmanuel was among the first to be informed. The news spread through the court and caused great gratification. The papal secretary of state, Cardinal Merry Del Val, conveyed the information to Pope Plus, when he was making his evening report. The pointiff said: "I am very happy that such a priceless treasure, after all, Is not lost to the world, and to the French nation." The French embassador expressed his thanks to the Italian premier, Signor Giolltti; the foreign minister, Marquis di San Giuliano and the minister of public instruction, Senor Credaro, for the notifications he had received regarding details of the discovery of the picture. He said that the French government and the French people would feel the deeepest gratitude for the generosity of the Italian government in desiring to return the masterpiece to the Louvre.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result>
         <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1913-12-14/ed-1/seq-4/#words=Lisa+Mona
         </id>
         <rel>1</rel>
         <text>
         HOW PAINTING WAS FOUND "Mona List," Missing Two Years, is Recovered. THEIF OFFERS TO SELL IT Conceived Idea of Returning Masterpiece to Its Trur Home to Avenge Looting of Nation b Napoleon. FLORENCE, Italy, Dec 13 - "Mona Lisa," Leonardo Da Vinci's great painting, which was stolen from the Louvre in Paris more than two years ago, has been found. It is now in the hands of the Italian authorities and will be returned to France. "Mona Lisa" or "La Jacomde." as it is more popularly known, the most celebrated portrait of a woman ever painted,
         has been the object of exhaustive search in all quarters of the globe. The mystery of its abstraction from the Louvre, its great intrinsic value and the strange fascination of the smile of the woman it portrayed, Lisa Del Giocondo, the wife of a wealthy Florentine, have combined to keep alive interest in its recovery. The picture was recovered under curious circumstances. As Italian wrote to Signor Geri, an antiquary of Florence, several weeks ago, saying: "I am in possession of the missing Mona Lisa, but being a patriotic Italian, I desire that it shall remain in Florence, the center of Italian art." He signed the letter, "Leonard," and the antiquary at first paid small attention to it, thinking he had to do witha madman. Later, however, he communicated with Dr. Poggi, director of the Florentine museum, who suggested that he continue the correspondence
         with the man. This was done and an appointment was arranged whereby Geri was to view the picture at Milan. The date set was November 17, but unforseen circumstances prevented the meeting. A young man, fairly well dressed, visited Geri yesterday. He said he was 'Leonard' and was staying at the Hotel Tripoli. He asked Geri to go with him to see the picture. The dealer notified Dr. Poggi, who hastened to the hotel and on being shown the painting, recognized it as the genuine 'Mona Lisa.' Dr. Poggi asked to be allowed to take the picture with him so that he might compare it with other works. He made an appointment to meet 'Leonard' this afternoon at the hotel to agree upon the price. The director took with him several officers, who placed the man under arrest. On being interrogated, the prisoner said his real name is Vincenzo Perugia, that he was born in the 
         province of Como, is by profession a decorator, and is unmarried. For six years he lived in France and for the three years was employed at the Louvre. Perugia posed as a patriot. 'I was ashamed,' he said, 'that for more than a century no Italian had thought of avenging the spoliation committed by Frenchmen under Napoleon, when they carried off from the Italian museums and galleries, statues and treasures of all kinds by wagon loads, ancient manuscripts by thousands, and gold by sacks.' He had often observed, he said, in the Louvre many works of art stolen from Italy and conceived the idea of returning it to its true home, Leonardo Da Vinci's masterpiece. He entered the Louvre early in the morning, detached the picture, and removed the painting from the frame. Hides it Under Blouse. He concealed the frame under the back stairs, where it was afterwards found.
         He hid the picture under the workman's blouse and succeeded in leaving the place without attracting suspicion. At the time of the theft, Perugia was not employed in the Louvre, but he knew all the exits and entrances and how to avoid attention. He kept the painting concealed, he said, until his patriotism led him to offer it to the Italian people. The painting has also been identified by Dr. Corrado Ricci, director general of the department of fine arts, who was dispatched hurriedly to Florence from Rome by the minister of public instruction, Luigi Credaro. After a careful examination, Dr. Ricci telephoned to the minister, who was incredulous. Ricci said: 'I will stake my head.' To this, Signor Credaro replied: 'I do not care for your head; but if this news after it is published, if found not to be true, you will be dismissed." Dr. Ricci answered: "I will take full 
         responsibility and am ready to risk dismissal." News of the discovery of the "Mona Lisa" spread in the Chamber of Deputies, in session at Rome, where extremist members were engaged in fisticuffs in an endeavor to prevent a vote on the election of a nationalist deputy. Disorder Ceases at Once. The disorder ceased immediately. The deputies surrounded the minister of public instruction, who exhibited a telegram from Dr. Ricci confirming the statement he had already made by telephone. All laughed at the alleged motives of the thief. One of them remarked that Napoleon's deeds were too antiquated to constitute grounds for feuds. If it were not so, Italy would quarrel with the whole world, as all countries, including the United States, had stolen masterpieces from it. The famous "Ascoli Cope," stolen from the cathedral at Ascoli, which was returned by J. Pierpont Morgan, was
         cited, however, as an instance of American generosity. Signor Credaro announced that Italy would show the same generosity. He said he had immediately notified the French ambassador, Camille Barrère, of the discovery of the painting. He added:'Mona Lisa' will be delivered to the ambassador with a solemnity worthy of Leonardo Da Vinci and a spirit of happiness worthy of 'Mona Lisa's' smile. Although the masterpiece is dear to all Italians as one of the best productions of the genius of their race, we will willingly return it to its foster country, which has regretted its loss so bitterly, as a fresh pledge of friendship and brotherhood between the two great Latin nations."  The painting is in an almost perfect state of preservation, notwithstanding the vicissitudes it must have undergone. Perugia, although he has not made a complete confession, has admitted that he 
         concealed it under the false bottom of a trunk or fixed it behind the canvas of a worthless sketch. Sensation in Paris. PARIS, Dec. 12—The sensation caused by the recovery of 'Mona Lisa' was only equaled by that caused by its disappearance in August, 1911. Special editions of the newspapers carried the news the length and breadth of Paris, and tonight it was the sole topic of conversation. The finding of 'Mona Lisa' had been so often announced, only to be contradicted, that the news was at first received with skepticism. However, Ambassador Barrère's dispatch from Rome to the French minister of public instruction, though brief, was explicit, and the names of the eminent Italian experts mentioned seemed a sufficient guarantee that it was the original painting. Henry Marcel, director general of the French National Museum, for a moment was inclined to doubt the news, saying:
        'We have so often been cruelly hoaxed that it is only natural that we should feel skeptical that the painting has been found. The telegram which I have read seems so clear and shows such detailed knowledge, however, that it seems to me the news must be true this time. In any case, the theft undoubtedly was the act of a madman. The motive—to avenge thefts committed in Italy by Napoleon—clearly shows this. 'If the experts' examination proves the picture to be authentic, we will restore it to its familiar place and guard it so that theft will be impossible.' The Florentine dealer, Geri, it is believed, will be entitled to claim rewards amounting to 240,000 francs ($48,000) offered by the Society of Friends of the Louvre and Paris newspapers. M. J. T. Homolle, who was director of the Louvre when 'Mona Lisa' was stolen and who was suspended by the French cabinet because of the 
        loss of the painting, was overcome with joy when he learned of its recovery. Seymour de Ricci, an eminent art critic of Paris, declared his faith in the certification of Dr. Corrado Ricci at Florence of the authenticity of the 'Mona Lisa.' 'I do not think there is the slightest doubt,' he said, 'that the painting will be immediately restored to France. 'Italy has no claim whatever on the "Mona Lisa," which was given or sold to the French king, Francis I, by Leonardo da Vinci himself. M. Viviani, minister of public instruction, and M. Jacquier, undersecretary for beaux arts, were both highly elated over the auspicious event, which ushers in their terms of office. The Italian government has advised them that it will deliver over the picture, and they considered the best and safest way of conveying it back to the Louvre. The French government will take the earliest opportunity 
        to express its gratitude to the Italian government for the service it has rendered in recovering the lost treasure. Perugia resided near the St. Louis hospital. He left here hurriedly on Wednesday, saying he was obliged to go to Italy on important business. He is 32 years old, the son of a carpenter. He came to Paris every year during the season and earned about eight francs a day, returning to some village when work was slack. Outside of a few compatriots, humble workers like himself, he was not known to have friends in Paris. A neighbor of Perugia described him as an ordinary workman, having no special technical knowledge and completely ignorant in artistic matters. The neighbor, therefore, was astonished to hear that Perugia was accused of stealing the painting and believed that if the accusation were true, he could only have been acting at the instigation of someone who
         had exploited his patriotic sentiments.
         </text>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1914-02-15/ed-1/seq-20/#words=Lisa+Mona
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Safeguarding the Treasures of the Louvre: Police Dogs, Locking Rods, Electric Signals, and Spy Chambers to Stop the Next Man from Quietly Walking Off with an 'Old Master' as Perugia Took 'Mona Lisa. Paris, February 8. The French Government is determined that 'Mona Lisa' shall not be stolen again. Extraordinary precautions have now been taken to prevent this or any other of the treasures of the Louvre from being taken away. One of the first steps taken to safeguard the Louvre was to employ a number of dogs of the clever breed known as police dogs. One of them guards every fifty feet of wall space day and night. No man can now put a hand over the railing in front of the pictures without having a dog after him. The next protective measure was to connect the pictures by a rod so that all those along a certain wall space can be locked up from one lock. Formerly, every picture hung
        separately. Under the new arrangement, each line of pictures hangs upon one flat rod by hooks in the frame, which only admit the rod when it is turned edgewise to the opening in the hook. Then the rod is turned so that the picture cannot be removed from it and is locked in that position. Little chambers have also been constructed behind the carved moldings near the ceiling, from which the guardians of the Louvre can secretly watch every person in the rooms. The knowledge that a hidden guardian is watching them is expected to have a terrifying effect on would-be thieves. The pictures have also been connected by electric wiring. Any tampering with them closes a circuit and causes an electric bell to ring loudly. The return of 'Mona Lisa' has only emphasized the necessity of guarding against similar occurrences in the future. The confession of Vincenzo Perugia has revealed the astonishing
        ease with which he was able to walk away with what is probably the most valuable art treasure in the world. It was on the morning of August 22, 1911, that the world was startled by the announcement that Leonardo da Vinci's great masterpiece had been stolen. Its disappearance from its accustomed place in the Salon Carré, or Square Salon, was noted on August 21. To some reporters who inquired intelligently about its disappearance, the officials on that day explained that it had been taken down to be cleaned. On the following day, the government decided that it was useless to attempt to conceal any longer the fact that it had been stolen. Its value was estimated at $5,000,000. It is interesting to recall some of the extraordinary speculations and theories that were advanced concerning its disappearance. Some argued that it was incredible that a government possession of such incalculable value 
        could be taken by a common thief. They said that some person of great influence, a Cabinet Minister or other high official, had taken the picture to photograph it, had damaged it accidentally, and was keeping it until he could repair it. Another theory was that the mysterious psychological and sex influence of the picture would prove to be the clue to its disappearance. It is well known that this exquisite and subtly fascinating portrait of Mona Lisa del Giocondo exerts a very diverse influence upon the two sexes. Men of impressionable temperament are strongly drawn toward it and feel a deep and even passionate pleasure in the radiations of its 'enigmatical smile.' Women, on the other hand, are, with equal frequency, repelled by it, and are even stirred to hate and fury by the same smile. The partisans of this theory fell into two groups. One group said that a man mentally disordered by 
        the strange fascination of the picture must have stolen it to enjoy its subtle charms in secret. The other group argued that a woman had taken it to vent the rage of her sex upon it. One thing became clear from the mass of theories and interesting facts brought out by the episode. The contents of the Louvre were not, and never had been, well safeguarded. Pictures worth from $1,000,000 to $5,000,000 could have been pulled off their hooks at a favorable moment any day without detection. Officials, moreover, had been in the habit of lending the art treasures to artists and persons of influence. It was stated that 250 pictures had been stolen or 'borrowed' in the course of the nineteenth century. Gradually the months wore on and The recovery of the great picture came to be regarded as hopeless. Then, on December 12, 1913, came the news that it had been found. An art dealer informed the director
        of the Uffizi Gallery at Florence that an Italian workman named Vincenzo Perugia had taken the picture and had it in Florence. This statement was verified and the 'Mona Lisa' returned to France. The confession of Perugia shows that the subtle psychological influence of this picture had, indeed, much to do with his act. Perugia said: 'I am a patriotic Italian. I saw that the Louvre was filled with masterpieces stolen by Napoleon from Italy. I longed to take something back. 'I thought of taking a Raphael, a Titian, a Correggio, and several other masterpieces. But the Mona Lisa seemed to me much more appealing. 'Here she is. I give her back to my country. It is the greatest sacrifice of my life.' From Perugia’s confession, it appeared that he had worked as a painter for a decorating contractor of 280 Rue St. Honoré, Paris. He had worked as a painter on the Louvre for some weeks but gave up this
        work on January 24, 1911. Between this date and August 21, he meditated upon and carried out his plan for stealing the Mona Lisa. It was 7 o'clock in the morning of August 21 when he entered the Louvre. The building was open then for the workmen and guardians or caretakers, but the general public was not admitted that day. Perugia wore the long blouse commonly used by French workingmen, especially by house painters. He looked, of course, like a man working on the building. He walked straight up to the picture in the deserted Salon Carré and took it from the hooks by which it was hung. A man standing on the floor could reach his hand to the top of the small picture. Then he realized that the frame would be heavy and hard to conceal. He quickly removed the picture from the frame. He left the picture lying in the salon and carried the frame to a doorway a few yards away at the head of a small 
        stairway and left it outside the door. Then he returned for the picture. He thrust it under his loose blouse, where it was scarcely noticeable. Hearing footsteps, he decided to leave hurriedly by the small stairway where he had left the frame. As he went out, he put the key in his pocket to prevent anyone from pursuing him that way. Having reached the ground, he crossed the Courtyard of the Sphinx, and then passed out through the gateway known as the Porte Visconti, which faces on the Seine. The French authorities summoned Perugia, together with all the workmen who had worked on the Louvre at the time of or just before the theft. He proved that he had not worked there since January 24, and this seemed sufficient explanation. No one discovered that he was the thief until he revealed it himself.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result> 
        <id>
        https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1914-03-20/ed-1/seq-10/#words=LISA+Lisa+Mona+MONA
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        THE RESTORED MONA LISA By Frederic J. Haskin. "More deadly than the male," a woman outraged England and made all art lovers weep by hacking the incomparable Rokeby Venus. She did it to get the vote. It recalls the most famous of all art thefts—the stealing of the Mona Lisa by an Italian to avenge the depredations of Napoleon a century old. The complete story of that famous mystery only now may be told with authority. Smiling the same inscrutable smile which the master genius, Leonardo da Vinci, imprisoned upon canvas 400 years ago to the vexation of generations of interpreters, Mona Lisa, mysterious portrait, restored to her admirers after strangely vanishing under the eyes of her guards and eluding the frantic search of a nation of art lovers, again looks down from her place in the Louvre, Paris, the interest of her subtle, mystic expression enhanced by reason of her peculiar adventure.
        Mona Lisa, or, as the Italians call her, La Gioconda, on account of the haunting challenge which the artist divined in the face of his sitter and which he wove into the fabric of his colors, has enthralled and fascinated beholders from the beginning. Many explanatory pages have been written on the meaning of this famous painting, and, provoked by its indefinable charm, its elusive suggestion, many an art student has brought the full power of his critical acumen to the task of finding suitable words for the description of the picture’s strange appeal. Each attempt has failed, and each writer has dwelt with peculiar emphasis upon the qualities of the Mona Lisa smile. This masterpiece is one of the most treasured of the Louvre collection. It has been tentatively valued at more than a million dollars. Painting One of the Most Treasured. It was begun by da Vinci about 1503, when the master 
        stood at the zenith of his fame and power, and, according to Vasari, it took four years of intermittent labor to complete. The woman in whose likeness there was, or into which the artist wrought an intangible something, compelling, unrestful, questioning, in the mind of each who stared back at it, lived in Florence. She was Mona Lisa di Antonio Maria di Noldo Gherardini, a native of Naples, who was married in 1495 to Francesco di Bartolomeo di Zanobi del Giocondo, a prominent citizen of Florence. When she began her sittings for what has since become one of the most renowned of all the world’s portraits, she was probably twenty-five or younger. Da Vinci, painter, poet, engineer, philosopher, and mystic, was fifty-one. Was it an unusual woman that the ripened master painted or was it a forceful symbol coined by his rich, discerning mind? Many times this question has been put to the lady 
        of the superior smile, answered only by the tantalizing glance through the thick, protecting varnish. No wonder, when the loss of their treasure was discovered on the morning of August 21, 1911, a Monday, all Paris was wrought to a frenzy. The news of the theft was received in all parts of the civilized world with the same feelings of dismay. The picture missing from its place in the Salon Carré was the most beautiful from Leonardo’s brush and one of the most precious creations of Western culture. Two Years Pass Without a Clue. Two years and four months passed by without a trace of the vanished work. All efforts of the French police remained fruitless. High rewards offered for the return of the painting went unclaimed, and every clue as to the Whereabouts of the thief ended just without the Louvre gates. As the months sped by while the endeavors of the police proved vain and not even 
        rumors came of a Mona Lisa in foreign lands, all hope that the picture would ever be recovered was given up. It was concluded that the work had been destroyed. The fate of Mona Lisa was put to the account of one of those unintelligible acts of vandalism which go to swell the records of human pathology. Boundless was the enthusiasm, then, which greeted the sudden, unexpected reappearance of the Gioconda Thursday, December 11, 1913, at Florence. In Florence, the original Mona Lisa had sat for a portrait by one of the greatest painters of all time, and in a dingy inn at Florence, the lost painting was found again. The Italian authorities obtained immediate possession of the picture, which was taken in triumphal procession through Italy, under police guard to Rome, to the French ambassador Barrère, and then to Milan, where the director-general of the Louvre, Henry Marcel, and the director 
        of paintings, M. Léprieur, came to take charge of it. The Mona Lisa was again safely housed in Paris last New Year’s Day, and was again hung in its accustomed place at the Louvre, which place had been filled during the time of its loss by Raphael's Castiglione. The theft of this irreplaceable work was an extraordinary one, in that the criminal had been able to penetrate one of the best-guarded treasure houses of Europe and make away with one of its most prized and precious possessions, and disappear with his loot without leaving a single trace behind. The thief was an unusual one, in that for two years and four months he kept his secret, the priceless Mona Lisa hidden away in his garret bedroom in Paris, only in the end to fall into the hands of the criminal authorities through an act of childish carelessness, an almost imbecile simplicity. Immediately, after the discovery of the theft,
        it was thought in Paris that the thief had hidden himself away in the gallery Saturday afternoon, remained in the place all night, and escaped with his spoil Monday morning. The glass casing and the frame of the picture were found leaning against the wall of a narrow stairway leading from the gallery des sept metres, where the old Italian pictures are hung, to the Court of the Sphinx. The door opening from the stairway, part of glass protected by ironwork, was locked, and, at the investigation, Sauvet, one of the workingmen in the Louvre, remembered having opened the door at the request of a person upon whom he came sitting at the bottom of the stairway. He failed to take further notice of this person, other than that he was wearing a blouse similar to those worn by the regular guards. As Monday is cleaning day, and visitors are barred, no suspicion crossed his mind but that the man was
        what he seemed—an official. Here the trail ended. A print of a left thumb upon the abandoned glass frame was all that remained in the way of a clue to the police. Notwithstanding full reports of the matter in L'Illustration, and other papers, nothing more of the criminal was learned. L'Illustration immediately announced that it would pay 40,000 francs, about $8,000, to anyone who would return the picture by September 26, and 45,000 francs—or $9,000—if the picture was brought to them by September 1. It was further announced that no questions would be asked. The editors received some five hundred letters in answer to their announcements, investigated some one hundred cases, and learned nothing. The Museum Club (Amis du Louvre) gave the police 25,000 francs to be used for the obtaining of the painting. The court of investigation convened August 22, and in its hearings the photographed thumb
        print played a leading role. No less than 257 persons were ordered by the court to submit their thumb prints for comparison. Among those furnishing such prints were the directors of the Louvre. The theif of course was not upin the list of those investigated. Vincenzo Peruggia, an Italian, the real despoiler, as established by his own confession and the exact agreement of the fingerprint found upon the glass case with that of his own thumb, when taken into custody by the Italian police, cleared up the murky mystery. He maintained that he entered the Louvre, together with other workmen, Monday morning, made his way unobserved to the Mona Lisa, removed it from its hanging, carried it to the stairway where the frames were found, cut the painting loose from its casing, concealed it in his blouse, and persuaded a passing workman to open the door for him without so much as seeing a guard around. 
        Once outside the Louvre, he proceeded to his lodging house, a nest for a colony of Italian workmen, where he hid the picture and went on with his regular work—that of a house painter and glazier. He continued to ply his trade for more than two years, a thing worth to him a tremendous fortune concealed in the false bottom of his wooden trunk, before trying to dispose of it. Only once was the suspicion of the police directed upon him. But how he escaped that once is another mystery. Peruggia had been employed at the Louvre as a glazier and had been entrusted with the work of framing some of the most costly masterpieces. In October 1911, Prof. Pierre Marcel of the École des Beaux-Arts wrote an open letter to the paper Figaro, suggesting that trace of the criminal was to be sought among the Louvre glaziers. The director of painting took the suggestion, obtained the names of those so employed 
        and formerly so employed, upon which list appeared the name of Peruggia, who, with the rest, was subject to an examination and a house search. The mystery is that the police did not take the fingerprints of these men for comparison, as had been done at the first investigation. Peruggia's downfall came with his attempt to dispose of his spoil. He wrote on November 28, 1913, to Alfred Geri, owner of the Galleria d'Arte e Moderna, at Florence, a dealer in art works, offering, under the name of Leonardi, to sell him the Mona Lisa, which he explained, as a patriotic Italian, he felt ought to be returned to Italy, the land of its production. This plea, strengthened to one of patriotic bitterness that rich Paris should not be decorated with the spoils of Italy robbed during the times of Napoleon, he maintained after his arrest. Geri sought counsel from Prof. Giovanni Poggi, director of the 
        Florence galleries. As a result of his conference, he answered the letter from Paris, entering heartily into the writer's proposals and sentiment, finally arranging a meeting in Italy, which took place at Florence on December 11, when the lost Mona Lisa was drawn from her hiding place under the false trunk bottom and returned to the world after her long seclusion. Nor has the Mona Lisa's smile lost aught of its subtlety.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id> 
         https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042303/1914-06-05/ed-1/seq-4/#words=Lisa+Mona
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        "Mona Lisa" Thief on Trial. Florence, Italy, June 4.—The trial of Vincenzo Perugia, on the charge of stealing Da Vinci's masterpiece, "Mona Lisa" from the Louvre in Paris, began here today. The disappearance of the picture on August 22, 1911, caused a sensation throughout the world, and search for it was not successful until December 12, 1913, when Perugia offered it for sale to a Florentine antiquarian. D. R. Analdi, an alienist, said at today’s hearing that Perugia was only partially responsible for his actions. Perugia did not deny that he had taken "Mona Lisa" from the Louvre. He said it was his desire to have it placed in the Palazza Degli Uffizi in Florence. Testimony as to the authenticity of the picture was given by several experts. Other witnesses gave evidence as to the details of the theft.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87007277/1914-02-13/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=mona+lisa&amp;r=-0.583,0.027,2.166,1.128,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        MONA LISA'S STORY Return to Paris Recalls Long Misunderstood History. Salomon Reinach, a French Searcher for the Truth, Tells of His Efforts to Learn the Facts of Remarkable Portrait. Paris.—The unprecedented enthusiasm over the return of the Mona Lisa to Paris takes us back to the days of her first arrival, 400 years and more ago. Vincenzo Perugia, the Italian artisan, who abducted her from the Louvre in 1911 to "give her back" to Florence, is completely mistaken in his facts. Mona Lisa was always a Paris resident. At the moment when Perugia imagines her to have been "stolen" from Italy "by Napoleon," she had not been living in Italy for 300 years. Mona Lisa was brought to Paris by her father, Leonardo da Vinci, who sold her to King Francis I for $40,000 of our money—a terrific price in those days. When first exhibited in the palace of the Louvre 400 years ago there was a rush of all the
        notables of Paris to see her, comparable only to the present ovation of her return. Leonardo was the star guest of the French king, more run after and admired in Paris than in his native Italian city; and he could sell every scrap of his works. In his baggage when he came to France he brought the Mona Lisa. "Why does she smile so sadly?" asked the French king. Leonardo never told him. Yet he knew why. Why does Mona Lisa smile so sadly? Here at last is her true pathetic history. Now is the time to tell it. Mona Lisa has too long been misunderstood. "During 400 years past," says Paul Leprieur, curator of the Louvre paintings, who went to Italy and brought her back, "during 400 years past Mona Lisa has addled the wits of those who have talked about her after having looked too long upon her.”“Four centuries is rather much,” replies Salomon Reinach. This Salomon Reinach is the very type of the
        exact archaeologist. He will not permit geniuses to create facts, and is the enemy of wind and flapdoodle, breaking in on lofty theories with a marriage or death certificate. He is curator of the St. Germain museum, a remarkably distinguished man, perfectly well known in America. And Salomon Reinach pricked the bubble of all this wind about Mona Lisa. Leonardo da Vinci took four years (1501–1504) to paint the wife of his friend, Francesco del Giocondo; and, so far from being in love with her or she with him, he dropped both portrait and sitter again and again, on a moment’s notice, to go on pleasure or business trips. Reinach is a terrible man. He chases a date through a hundred manuscripts until he traces it. Leonardo quit Florence in 1499, to return only in 1501. In 1502 he traveled in Umbria as architect of Valentine Borgia. He returned to Florence in 1503, went on a pleasure jaunt to 
        Venice in 1505, returned, and went to Milan in 1506. That is not four years of loving contemplation, is it? The truth is, that Leonardo painted the portrait gratis for his friend, the husband dropping in when business called. It bears every mark of such a non-paid, purely friendship portrait—to the last, in which the painter sells it to a third party. Salomon Reinach has found it. We know the melancholy of Mona Lisa. Married in 1496, she had no children until 1499. Then came a little daughter. Salomon Reinach remembered that once a librarian of Florence communicated to Muntz, the great French art historian, an extract from the ancient Libre del Morti—records of deaths in Florence. By this, it appears that on June 1, 1501, the little daughter (fanciulla) of Francesco del Giocondo and his wife Mona Lisa was buried from the church of Santa Maria Novella. Why, the very costume of Mona Lisa in the picture is heavy mourning! You see
        now. Her smile is a constrained smile, the best she can do to please the kindly painter who has paid singers, musicians, and buffoons to entertain her.
        </text>
    </result>
    <result>
         <id>
         https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1914-01-02/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=mona+lisa&amp;r=-0.074,0.438,0.657,0.342,0
         </id>
         <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064469/1911-09-10/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=mona+lisa&amp;r=0.585,0.119,0.578,0.301,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        Mona Lisa," The World's Finest Picture. The mysterious disappearance of Leonardo da Vinci's masterpiece, the "Mona Lisa," or, as it is popularly known, "La Giocondo," from its place of honor in the Salon Carre of the Louvre, at Paris, caused consternation in the art world. The "Mona Lisa" is one of France's greatest art treasures, ranging with the sculptures "Venus de Milo" and "The Victory of Samothrace" and Murillo's painting, "The Immaculate Conception." It is held priceless. At one time it was reported that the British government offered $5,000,000 for the work. This offer was declined. It is the most celebrated portrait of a woman in the world. Da Vinci’s model was the wife of Francesco del Giocondo, a Florentine of the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries. When Da Vinci painted her, she was about thirty years old. The subject is shown seated in a low chair, on the left arm of which she is leaning. The gown is simple and
        drapes the figure in easy folds. Dark hair, hanging loosely, drapes an oval face with expressive eyes and aquiline nose. About the mouth is seen the sweet smile which has been the chief characteristic in making the painting famous. It is said that Da Vinci, in order to obtain this effect, had musicians, singers, and jesters near his subject to amuse her as he painted. The greater number of the comparatively few finished paintings left by Leonardo da Vinci have been lost. Of his masterpieces "The Last Supper," on a wall of the refectory in the monastery of Santa Maria delle Grazie, Milan, nothing remains but a few crumbling patches of color. This left the "Mona Lisa" the finest surviving example of one of the great masters of the high renaissance, and it is perhaps more famous than any other portrait in the world. Leonardo is said to have worked on the picture for four years (1500-1504). In July, 1910, it was reported on the 
        authority of the Cri de Paris that the Mona Lisa had been stolen from its frame to be sold to an American millionaire and a copy substituted. American art dealers were not incredulous and spoke of similar thefts from the Louvre in the past. The report was immediately followed by an official denial. Fears for the safety of the picture were always rife, and in 1907, when a young woman fanatic had slashed a picture by Ingres in the Louvre, the authorities put the Mona Lisa behind glass. There were instant protests from art lovers the world over, and the glass was removed. Last winter a controversy arose as to whether the Mona Lisa in the Louvre or a copy in the Prado at Madrid was the genuine picture. Spanish critics writing to the newspapers held that the genuine one was in the Prado. Dr. Wilhelm Bode, director of the Royal Museum at Berlin, appeared in print with a lengthy refutation of this claim. The only parallel with this 
        in the history of art thefts is the case of Gainsborough’s famous Duchess of Devonshire, which was taken from its frame in the showroom of an art firm in London some years ago, but later returned to its owners by the late Patrick F. Sheedy, a well-known American gambler, who acted as intermediary between the thief and the art dealers.
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1912-05-11/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=mona+lisa&amp;r=0.242,0.242,0.361,0.188,0
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
        <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92051126/1913-12-28/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=mona+lisa&amp;r=0.202,0.418,0.474,0.247,0
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
</results>
</topic>