<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ping-pong-craze</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-12-23/ed-1/?sp=29&amp;q=TABLE+TENNIS&amp;r=-1.337,-0.016,3.674,1.667,0</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
	    <text>
            TABLE TENNIS.
            HI'LKS OF TLAY FOR THE NKW INIM>OR
            GAME. AI^SO CALLED POMPOM."
            Table tennis is the name of a new game which
            was introduced in England a short time ago.
            and has already become one of the most popu
            lar of indoor amusements. It is the came
            of lawn tennis in miniature, played on an or
            dinary dining table. The net is a tiny one, made
            of gauxe stretched between two uprights, which
            rest on a bar laid across the table. The balls
            are made of the thinnest kind of pyroxyline ma
            terial, and are consequently very light. The
            racquet has a slender handle and a blade with
            a frame about one-half inch thick, which Is cov
            ered on both sides with thin drumhead Material.
            The play and counting are practically the satnas in lawn tennis, but, according to the rules,
            '•the player serving must not put his racquet
            over the table nor have it above his wrist." That
            is, he must serve underhand and never over
            hand, but after service he may hit the ball as he
            likes, but he most not volley.
            The contact of the light ball with the drum
            head racquet produces a pleasant sound, and
            because of this sound th(» game received the
            name "pompom."
            Among the rules for playing the game are the
            following:
            No faults are allowed: if a fault is served.
            that is, the ball does not go over the net or goes
            off the table without touching the opposite side
            to the server, a |M>int is counted to the non
            server.
            If the net is touched by the l»all. and the ball
            goes over, and otherwise the service is correct,
            it is a let. and counU nothing to either side.
            If a volley is taken a point is counted against
            the person roUeytas-
            I.WSHOUM.'S I'Ehl.F.li WrHsTOll.
            THK lU:M.\KK.\ItI.K POtnCDKB "I" A IJR" -I KS*l-
            L.ISII Hul SK
            From The London Chronicle.
            Though he is one of the richest nea in Par
            liament, and has a house in Park Lane worth
            a fabulous sum, the new Foreign Secretary is,
            or ought to be. a man of stron human sympa
            thies. He owes his title and estates to a pedler.
            who was so poor that he lived in Paris for
            three weeks entirely on walnuts. Managing to
            earn an honest penny, he took out a patent for a
            letter copying machine, wrote on art and sci
            ence, practised chemistry and physics, sum
            moned the first meeting of the Royal Society at
            his lodgings, was appointed an army physician,
            invented a double bottomed ship to sail against
            wind and tide, founded iron works and opened
            l^ad mines, began a fishery and timber trade,
            and left a fortune to his sons. Such was the
            founder of the house of Lansdowne.
            Whether his podl^r ancestor's will has influ
            enced lAird Lansdowne in taking the Foreign
            Secretaryship or not we do not know, but in a
            remarkable will thai he Jeft behind the founder
            of the house conjured all his successors to "labor
            in public works" at their peril. "As for legacies
            for the poor." said the testator. "I am at a
            stand; as for beggars trade and election. I
            give them nothins: as for impotents by the hand
            of God. the public ought to maintain them; as
            for those who have been bred t.> no calling nor
            estate, they should be put upon their kindred;
            wherefore I am contented that I have
            assisted all my poor relations, and put many
            into a way of fretting their own bread; have la
            bored in public works, and by inventions have
            sought out r.-al objects of charity, and 1 do
            hereby conjure all who partake of my estate,
            from time to time, to do the same at their peril.
            Nevertheless, to answer custom, and to take the
            -idler side, I give £38 to the most wanting of the
            parish wherein I die."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1902-01-05/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=PING-PONG</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
	    <text>
            AN ABSORBING HEW INDOOR GAITS
            WHICH HAS ATTAINED GREAT
            POPULARITY IN LONDON;
            The three men who occupied the studio flat
            were having their quiet end-afternoon srnoks
            together. There was the artist, w hose hair haj
            turned gray after long years of painting an*
            black and white doings; the youth who, fcesi
            from art school, was just making a start, and
            the man of business, who was the saving clause
            of the combination. He put up the money wh»3
            black and whites would not sell and the youths
            checks from home were delayed In the mails.
            "I wish people would find something new wia
            which to entertain us, said the man of buij.
            ness, in a bored tone.
            "New Year is coming," chirped the youth, aa
            obvious statement, setir.g that Christmas «xj
            just one day past. "Perhaps Santa Claus tLpgti
            off' the dear girls to a new game."
            There*! nothing new under the sun. Billy*
            said the •Id artist. "If taert was I'd draw it jj
            hurry."
            Then there came a knock on the door, and a
            messenger appeared with a dainty note. Billy
            grasped it hastily. Billy was in love.
            "It's addressed to all of us," he said, with di*.
            appointment.
            "All the more reason you should hurry up aaj
            lead it,"' commanded the man of business.
            "It's from Harriet," he murmured, as he read
            it to himself.
            "Head out loud, uli>.t"" commanded one of the
            older men.
            "Won't you ccme up to-morrow night and
            play ping-pong." read Billy. "Now, what is
            ping-pong?"
            "Search me?" remarked the one who was nut
            artistic, except when it came to making money.
            "Sounds Chinese," said the artist.
            "I've heard of 'pom-pom,' remarked BiUy.
            "That's a sort of big gun which makes a funny
            noise." Billy had ence had the idea of beeoininj
            a military man. "But ping-pon^r— that's a new
            one on me."
            "Some new style of bridge. I suppose." mut
            tered the artist. "It's not for me. I've sacri
            ficed enough on that altar."
            "Well. I'm going up to play ping-pong," an
            nounced the youth. "I don't care what it is, tit
            name's new. Better come along. Jack. You
            were growling a minute ago about there being
            nothing new, and here you are."
            Dilly went to Harriet's and played ping-pong,
            and when he had not retumeO by midnight th«
            other fellows knew that he was enjoying it. H«
            would not tell them what the new game was
            when he finally put in an appearance, but ad
            vised them to find out for themselves.
            An indoor edition of tennis is ping-pong, til*
            name coming from the curious sound which tie
            parchment rackets give forth when they striis
            the little balls. It is played on the dining room
            taMe, across the centre of which a low net is
            stretched. Th> rules are almost the same as
            in tennis, and the points are counted tennis
            fashion. There is even mure chance for skilful
            handling of the ball than In outduor game*
            and there are tricks innumerable which add
            interest and variety. Skilful players can ii??
            up the volleying process until interest reaches
            fever pitch. It is almost as exciting for tie
            spectators as for the players, which U core
            than can be said of tennis.
            It is an absorbing game, as the EngHsh S«l
            tell you. It his been played i:i London ilisisj
            romis for the last two or three years; but ha
            never been strictly in vogue until this winter
            The ollieers of the British army carried pir.g
            peng sets to South Africa with t'.u-m. and have
            set up their tab) on tho wldt when the Ecea
            let them remain Ln camp long enough.
            Why the game has not taken hold in tiia
            country is something which Americans who live
            In London cannot understand. They have writ
            ten home about the beauties and delisht3 o! v
            ping-pong. They laud it to the skies for tie
            exercise it affords to busy c.tn who have o
            work in offices all day. and to women who
            occupied with a round of teas a^d recepucsi
            PING-PONG.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071197/1902-03-02/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=fad+table+tennis&amp;r=-1.114,-0.075,3.228,1.464,0</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-04-06/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=ping-pong+table+tennis&amp;r=-0.326,0.178,1.969,0.893,0</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016357/1902-05-03/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=PING-PONG+ping+pong+craze&amp;r=-1.345,-0.063,3.69,1.674,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              Our greatest demand for complete completesets completesets completesets
              sets including the regulation tables tableshas tableshas tableshas
              has of course come from the clubs clubssaid clubssnld clubssaid
              said a dealer yesterday But the thewomen thcwomcn thewomen
              women women and children hare got the thefever thetever thefever
              fever as bad ba as their brothers and andfathers andtathers andfathers
              fathers If youre writing about the thepingpong theplngl1011g theping
              pingpong ping pong craze you cant make it t too toostrong oo oostrong oostrong
              strong So far as I know we havent haventsold haventsold haventsold
              sold a set to any old ladles la les home yet yetbut yetbut yetbut
              but I dare are say the game will reach reachthem reachthem reachthem
              them in time This craze beats any anything anything anything
              thing I ever heard of Our belief is isthat Isthat Isthat
              that its only beginning Hot weather weathermay weathermay weathermay
              may affect our sales somewhat but butwo butwe
              wo look for an increased demand next nextfall nextfall nextfall
              fall fallOur
              Our indoor putting green In the theback theback theback
              back of the th store has been occupied by bya bya
              a pingpong ping poug table for several weeks weeksLfits weeksL weeksLets
              Lets L ts of people who never saw the thegame thegame thegame
              game come In here and watch a few fewsets fewsets fewsets
              sets get fascinated by the play and nndcud riudend andend
              end by buying racquets and balls anda and anda anda
              a net to take home and set up on their theirdiningroom theIrdlnlngroom theirdining
              diningroom dining room or billiard table Theres Theresa
              a game going on here almost every everyhour ceryhOUl everyhour
              hour of the day People cant seem to toget toget toget
              get enough of IL ILThe It ItTho ItTho
              Tho clubs have been and are still stilltlys stillt10 stilltl
              tlys t10 tl o stronghold of the craze although althoughthe nlthouhtho althoughthe
              the newspapers have had more to say sayabout sayabout sayabout
              about the play In brokers ofllces of lces and andon andon andon
              on ocean steamers So sudden has been beenthe beenthe beenthe
              the passion for the sport and so much muchroom muchroom muchrOonl
              room does a regulation table take up upthat upthat upthat
              that most of the clubs have had to togive togive togive
              give up some other sport in whole or orIn 01In orin
              In part for a time or else sacrifice sacrificepart sacrltleepart sacrificepart
              part of their diningroom space No Nobody Nobody Nobody
              body seems to object however Even Eventho Erentho Eventhe
              tho most sedate of club loungers al although nltbough although
              though he may begin by scoffing at atthe atthe atthe
              the childs play ends in becoming becomingcither becomIngeither becomingeither
              either an enthusiast entllUslastor or a disappointed disappointedbut lsappolnledbut
              but persistent duffer dufferCollege dufferCollega dufferCollege
              College clubs or other clubs fre frequented tree treequented frequented
              quented by younger men are the worst worstsufferers worstsufferers worstsufferers
              sufferers from the pingpong ping pong malady maladyTho maladylo maladyI1he
              I1he Tho lo Harvard 1 alvald Club early In Inthcwlutol Inthcwlutolput the winter winterput winterput
              put up the little nets on its billiard billiardtables bllliardtables billiardtables
              tables and billiards have scarcely
              been played there since Members Memberspay Memberspay Iemberlpay
              pay the same amount per hour for forplaying forplayIng forplaying
              playing pingpong ping pong that they formerly formerlywere 1ormerl 1ormerlwero formerlywere
              were cbnrgdtl for fortbe the use of the bit billiard bllliard bitHard
              liard tables The club has since set up upIn upIn upin
              In addition a veal ping pingpong pong board boardThe boardThe boardThe
              The Yale Club has four tables in one oneof oneot oneof
              of the class diningrooms on the ninth ninthfloor ninthfioor ninthfloor
              floor The Cornell University Club Clubgives Clubgives Clubgives
              gives up half Its diningroom to the thopastime thepastime thepastime
              pastime and the House UouseOommlttee UouseOommltteenow Committee Committeenow Committeenow
              now talks of letting the whole apart apartment apattment apartment
              ment bo used for It so many of the themembers themembers themembers
              members want to play and pingpong pingpongtables plngpongtables ping pong pongtables
              tables can be used ns dining lnlnl tables if ifit ItIt ifit
              it takes too long to make the change changeIn changeIn changeIn
              In n Brooklyn Droold n athletic club the ping plugpongcrs pingpongers pingpongers
              pongers have Invaded the the handball handballcourt handballcourt handballcourt
              court Most of these resorts Ies rts have had hador hador hador
              or are having pingpong ping pong tdurnamentsand tdurnaments tournamentsnnd
              nnd clever players bare Jave been dowel developed deeloped doweloped
              oped in the course of a few weeks weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses
              Boardinghouses In all parts of town townhave townhave townhave
              have been hard hit by the craze The Thelong ihelong Thelong
              long table ta ble in the back parlor l llor makes a agood agood agood
              good pingpong pl ping gllong pong board and a till the young youngman youngman youngman
              man In the hall bedroom two flights flightsup filghtsup flightsup
              up takes delight In making the star starboarder starboatder starboarder
              boarder look like thirty cents The Thelandladies Thelandladies rholandladIes
              landladies are arc rc not enthusiastic overthe over overthe 001the
              the game because when played In the theevening theevening theevening
              evening it has a n tendency to develop developa developrobust
              a robust appetite for late suppersThe suppers suppersThe suppersThe
              The vernacular of tbo sport has not notyet notyet notyet
              yet reached a l high degree of development develop development oelop11ent
              ment For the present as Is the case casewith casewltbany casewith
              wltbany with any new game players make free freewith treewltb freewith
              with words nnd phrases plll ses proper to toother toother toother
              other branches of sport Expressions Expressionslike Expressionslike
              like You dealt cm the last time timeThis timeThis timeThis
              This cue Is rotten Off side are areheard areIleard areheard
              heard around the board Picturesque Picturesquelanguage Plctulesquelanguage Picturesquelanguage
              language of n different character is isalso Isnlso isalso
              also common The elusive celluloid celluloidsphere celluloidsphere celluloidsphere
              sphere is as conducive to profanity as nsthe asthe asthe
              the guttn guttnpercha percha A well known lawn lawntennis lawntennis lawntennis
              tennis player has n novelty in the way wayof wayof wayof
              of pingpong ping pong profanity When he hemakes hemakes hemakes
              makes a fault he shouts Fudge I or orGoodness 01Goollness oreGoodness
              Goodness gracious
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016353/1902-05-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=table+tennis&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.266,-0.027,1.533,1.533,0</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-05-18/ed-1/?sp=46&amp;q=PING+PONG+ping+pong+ping-pong&amp;r=-1.155,-0.002,3.31,1.501,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              Wher
              ever there is room for a dining table therfj
              is room for ping-pong, and tho fascination
              that the gamo nor. holds, especially amon
              tho smart set. cannot bo downed by warn;
              m cather.
              Among tho particularly pood plng-ponr;
              rooms in bt, Louis, asldo from tho clubs,
              are those at tho Drummond's. Mis Wtck
              him's and at tho McKittrick's. Cvery evo
              ning ping-pong holda sway. It is proper
              nowadays for young ladies to take soma
              form of physical exercise, and ping-ponB
              combines all the pleasure that they- may
              find in any exercise and affords all tha
              sport of play. j
              Ralph and Walter McKittrlck, Arthua
              Shepley and Dan KIrby- are among the best
              and most enthusiastic players In the city.
              The Country Club and tho Florissant Club
              are utterly crazed over tho game. At pres
              ent It holds the trumps over all other
              games, and from Indications it will be tha
              popular game of the summer at both clubs.
              Of course, this does not mean that tenn!
              and golf and polo will not havo their de
              votees, but ping-pong will bo tho most frequently-
              played gamo of tho season.
              The women of the city are us enthusias
              tic .as the men-possibly more so. and they
              havo their claims upon the attention of tho
              men and their sports. Ping-pong looks and
              sounds llko a game that does not requira
              as much cndtiranco and strength as other11
              spons anu tint is sid to bo tho reuson
              that the women have taken It up. As t,
              matter ot fact. It is as violent as nlmnst
              any gamo th it Is popular with many peo
              ple, but It seems so playful that tho weaker
              be. have seized upon It.
              It is a fact that one business man of this
              c ty a man or more than usual corpulence-
              has reduced his weight by forty pounds
              playing ping-pong. And If the truth mi.ro
              known, it is probably true tint several
              women have been enabled to become mora
              sylph-like through the medium of the game.
              But that Is .v matter concerning which
              women will not talk.
              Women who are onenlv .anient nl.-ners
              of
              ny
              ping-pong are rot the ones of whom any
              one can say they play to reduce thel
              weight. They- are modern women In every
              may, and have taken up tho game not only
              because it Is tho fad, but also because it
              Is a g ime that enables them to keep In
              good physical condition It is proper no
              longer for momtn to be weak and requiring
              the attention of maids and menr but they
              mut be able to cope with the strongest.
              Accordingly, they tako as much exercise,
              comparatively, as men And ping-pong of
              fers them something in the way of a gam
              that has not been offered by any thins
              else.
              Among the more prominent women play
              ers of ping-pong are Mrs. James Drurr
              mond, Mrs. William' Gregg, Mri. Laurence
              J. Mornn MIs ickham. Mis Mitchell.
              Mrs. E O. Stanard, Mrs. W. II. Walker
              and Mrs. Goodman King. Each of theso
              has an elaborate ping-pong room fitted up
              nt her house, and parties are frequent. It
              is not at nit unusual for them to meet in
              the morning and play arduously befora
              luncheon. It serves as an excellent appe
              tizer. The game was hroiight 'to St. Louis by
              two people at about the same time. Mrs.
              E. H. Semple ot Westminster place be
              came enamored of the game while abroad
              last summer, and when she returned she
              set up a table at once. Sirs. Sidney Walker
              appeared on the scene at about the sama
              time, an enthusiastic player of the game.
              That mas its start In thi3 city. It did not
              take long to bring the sport to its present
              position, but these two St. Louisans havo
              been instrumental In making it a fad.
              One of the best players among the women
              is Mrs. Lewis Haywood She has for sev
              eral months been a devotee, and lias ac
              quired remarkable 'kill in handling tho
              racquet. Mrs. John Fowler Is another ex
              cellent player, and Mrc Dan Taylor, Mrs,
              Campbell Smith and Mrs. Frank HammeS
              are also in the first class.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-05-25/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=daft+ping-pong</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              DAFT ON PING-PONG
              Washington Entranced With
              Game, Which Is Played
              in Many Homes
              'fcOOM OF TIGHT CORSET
              f(Xew Diversion Has Phenotncnal
              Hold on All Sort* and Condi-
              tion*. From 9teM Senators
              tv DudtliiiK Debutantes.
              Special to The Globe.
              WASHINGTON, D. C. May 21.—Mover
              j lias the national capital been so com-
              T-letely enslaved by the fascinations of a
              game, indoor or outdoor, as it has fallen
              (under the seductive influence of the won
              jdc-rful new game, which, having set all
              J l^ngland crazy, has come with- a power
              to] stride across the Atlantic to exercise
              its potent influence upon our social life.
              i As a prominent leader of Washington
              I society remarked the other day, "Wash
              ington has fairly gone ping-pong mad."
              Conversation in capital society has now
              i foe-come impregnated with the peculiar
              I terms of the new pastime. Where for
              merly one would hear "social precedence"
              and "rising man," one now hears "clever
              i (half volleyer" and "invincible striker
              I out."
              "Love" and "advantage" as topics of
              social conversation have now a ping-pong
              significance entirely foreign to their for
              xtx-r meaning among the capital gossips.
              The ping-pong party has entirely sup
              planted the whist party arid the bridge
              circle.
              The peculiar ping-pong of the celluloid
              balls as they are beaten to and fro (from
              ■which the game derives its name) is now
              to be heard j in every Washington home
              from the palatial mansion of the fam
              -1 ily of the men who shape the nation's.
              I destiny on Pennsylvania avenue to the
              humble residence of the congressional
              I bootblack in the eastern section of the
              i city. Years are a matter of no consid
              ©ration among the devotees of the sport.
              The mature matron whose nod or frown
              I Oias settled one way or the other the so
              cial aspirations of mar.v- a newcomer
              .at the capital is as frequently to be seen
              i exerting herself in a manner wonderful
              to behold, to keep the little swiftly pass- j
              ing celluloid ball from dropping on her
              I side of the net, as is the beautiful bud
              ding debutante who, with flushed face,
              eyes sparkling with enthusiasm- and ex
              citement. and bared arms wildly but
              Withal skillfully circling the air, is a
              cSaily testimonial to the aethestic features
              of the game.
              Strike* nil Classes.
              Nor are the enthusiasts of the new
              gam" to be found only among the fairer
              sex, Washington masculinity has given
              itself to ping-pong with an abandon
              ,Nor ar^ the enthusiasts .of the now
              which would furnish a profitable study to
              the seeker- of pysehologieal phenomena.
              Staid congressmen, dignified senators.
              Learned members of the bench and bar
              When they meet together nowadays dis
              cuss not, the political significance of the
              lim.s. but the latest-make of ping-pong
              racquet.
              This -may be regarded as gross exagger
              ation. It is a potent fact, however, that
              ping p has attained a surprising vogue
              ■among Washington's public men.
              All the leading hotels and cafes are
              hastening to open up ping-pong parlors
              on their premises, so that their distin
              guished patrons may indulge .to their
              heart's content in the game.
              Senator Maur.a. when asked the other'
              ■day whether he favored the. erection of aj
              ping-pong parlor in the national capital,
              l>uckercd up.his brow* and gave the mat
              tor a few minutes' serious consideration
              before discussing the idea with a smile.
              Congressman Sulzer, when asked to ex
              plain the tremendous hold that ping-pong
              has taken upon members of the-house,
              said that it is a wonderful game for~ex
              erclse. and gives one a good hand to
              sustain the handshaking proclivities of
              the vast army of well meaning citizens
              who swoop down upon unwilling repre
              sentatives of the people with all the re
              lentless energy of the notorious New
              Jersey musquito upon its helpless victim.
              As may be supposed, the stores have
              not been slow to take advantage of the
              commercial possibilities of the craze. In
              -addition to the fact that some of the
              larger dry goods emporiums are opening
              up ping-pong saloons for the accommo
              dation of their patrons, the new game
              has an important bearing upon the latest
              styles. The ping-pong waist is prom
              inently- displayed in the shop windows,
              find is a phenomenal seller; while the
              new forms of neckwear for women and
              men bear handsomely embroidered figure.*
              ■of ping-pong racquets and balls upon
              their silken folds.
              Doom of the Tight Corset.
              One important reform the game prom,
              ises to effect, which may render rational,
              the development which has been lavished'
              upon it by England and America and im
              mortalize the new game as one of the
              most valuable and beneficent reform fac
              tors of the century.
              Ping-pong may abolish the tight laced
              ■corset.
              Ping-pong is essentially an informal
              game to be played at the spur of the
              moment, as the whim seizes. It is a
              game to be introduced by the smiling
              hostess after the last vestige of the din
              "■ner has been cleared away and ti;o
              white table cloth is removed to make
              way for the ping-pong net. Consequently
              as the rapid movement and freedom of
              body S necessary to me ping-pong player
              renders the corset impossible, the charm
              ing diner out has either to leave off her
              corsets when she dresses to attend a
              modern dim party or run the risk of
              having to stand against the wall in ail
              the-prim symmetry of a corseted waist
              and, watch the merry movements of her
              more fortunate sisters who, with grace
              fully swing forms, keep the merry cellu
              loid ball ping-ponging across the table
              at a lively pace to the intense admira
              tion of the man with the racquet on th^
              other side of the table and .every other
              man In the room. v
              This good may ping-pong do; bu other
              wise what peculiar qualities has the same
              to '-rive it phenomenal popularity? Strict
              ly speaking it is nothing more or less
              then a table adaptation of lawn tennis
              and tennis, while possessing to an equal
              and even greater degree the same physi
              cal benefits and sporting fascinations of
              its replica has never attained the vogue
              which has been vouchsafed to ping-pong.
              Played on Dining Table.
              Ping-pong is played on an ordinary din-
              Ing table and its only accessories are
              posts tp hold the net, the net itself
              vellum string or wood-racquets and cellu-
              loid balls: The game is for two people
              one standing on one end of the table,
              the other opposite. The player who first
              delivers the ball is called the server The
              Other the striker out. i The service is
              strictly underhand and is delivered from
              beyond the end of the table.
              The: ball served must drop on the table
              beyond the net and is then in piav. if
              it dops into the net or off the table it
              counts to the striker out
              The server wins a stroke if the striker
              out fails to return the service or ball in
              play of the table.
              The striker out wins a stroke If the
              server fails to return the ball in play or
              makes a foul in service.
              On either player winning his first stroke
              the score la 15. The second stroke brings
              the score to 30; the third stroke is called
              •40 and the fourth stroke wins a game
              The player who wins the first six games
              -wins a set.-
              This is all there really is to the game
              of ping-pong. Certainly it Is a skill de
              manding and skill acquiring game. It
              lias simplicity and cheapness to recom
              mend it. It is far better from a hygenie
              standpoint than a majority of parlor
              prames and is an extremely socialble and
              interesting pastime. It is. for these rea
              sons and its similarity to tennis, a game
              calculated to prove attractive to the"
              younger members of both sexes.
              But why It has set the people of two
              countries almost crazy: why old as well
              as young-have taken up ping-pong when
              they would not as much as look at an-
              Our Opening of Summer fliilinery.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-06-01/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=PING-PONG&amp;r=-0.252,0.339,1.717,0.779,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              "It has been said that the muscles of
              the legs and arms are often wearied By
              the game. This .is true in a. sense, but I
              think that the eye and the brain -will be
              exhausted :n ping-pong long before the
              muscles used in sending and returning
              balls can be affected to any appreciable
              extent."
              ISEASES with strange names have
              Dloliowtd in the wake of ping-pong,
              J.ut the real pang is not a fanciful
              une. for the watching of the cellu
              loid* sphere really strains the eyes.
              Let London surgeons talk as they will
              about tei.dosyr.ovitis "and p^ig-ponS an
              kles: all these are as nothing compared
              to tho'strair.ed muscles of the eye of the
              Ail ping-pong devotees, even experts,
              suffer from the ping-pong eye more or
              Jess. Other muscles employed to playing
              th* game are ""speedily co-ordinated. To
              develop a proper technique is^ing-pong
              is no easy matter, and in the endeavor
              the eye suffers the most.
              There is a ping-pong wrist, of course,
              and a ping-pong back, but the player who
              can return a ball a hundred times or so
              suffers comparatively little from these.
              The tyro who bends often to pick up the
              balls -which bound upon the carpet is the
              one who is most likely to complain of
              In time he learns, however, to make the
              optical nerves save the exertions of the
              muscles. Then he requires a ping-pony
              i ji^jlimii
              Not much strength is required in tho
              game. A little more vigorous than bil
              liards and not quite bo arduous as tennis.
              of which it is a cousin german, pins-
              THE S U^J)AY CALL.
              pcng appeals to those who have the quick
              eye.
              The skillful player can keep his body
              almost rigid, and standing In front of the
              table send the ball backward and forward
              with scarcely a movement of a muscle
              except those of the wrists. Many or the
              players are able- to sit In one of the
              chairs such as are used by spectators in
              billiard games, and still keep the ball go
              ing rapidly.
              Physicians say that many ping-pong
              players suffer from an inflammation of
              the eye. and champion players add their
              Testimony. The constant watching of the
              ball is liable to cause heaoaclies, or, 'in
              other words, to cause irritation to spread
              from the overworked optical mu.-des.
              The pir.g-ro"g eye is often bloodshot.
              The only way to cure it is to stop play
              ing and to give the overworked eye a
              chance to rest. Th!s the ping-pong devo
              te*- objects to doing. When ho becomes
              absorbed in the game he persists in play
              ing it in season and out of season.
              There are many ping-pong table's which
              served originally in dining-rooms. The
              man who plays upon them is prone fo
              contract the ping-pong eye. The ideal
              table should be dark green^This color is
              easy on the eye. A retired billiard or
              poo! table is well adapted to the game,
              as far*"as the effect upon the eye is con
              cerned. The ball is dazzling white.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-07-13/ed-1/?sp=39&amp;q=ping-pong</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-09-21/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=ping-pong</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              It Is the reactionary influence of ping
              pong on tennis Itself that Is «o surpris
              ing, for In a greater degree a far greater
              degree— than Is generally supposed ping
              pong is responsible for the sudden and
              growing popularity of tennis In the courts
              at Golden Gate Park.
              solely of the possibilities for dainty
              rowEic* which it afforded, nor of the
              .hitherto unsuspected opportunities for
              'flirtations that resulted seriously. There
              would be no need to epeak of those things
              here. Every girl learned them for herself
              very early in the ping-pong craze, and
              made the most of the game.
              PING-PONG, childish Imitation of
              tennis though It is. has done won
              ders for our sex. Every girl ought
              to be'* very clad that she learned
              It, though I'm not thinking now
              Then there is the underhand drive,
              wherein you bring the racquet round and
              up, knocking the ball high above the net
              for a volley serve. In executing the
              underhand drive, take lots of time and
              don't strike the ball until It Is falling close
              to the ground.
          </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 additinal -->
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064676/1902-05-22/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=ping+pong+craze</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              The Craze for Ping-Pong.
              Ping pong continues the craze in
              England. Recently a big tournament
              was held in the town hall at Leeds
              for the benefit of the local war relief
              fund. Twelve tables for the game were
              gathered in the large room, which
              was densely packed with spectators.
              The fever, too, rages among the offi
              cers of the navy and the game is
              played regularly in the evenings after
              dinner. The junior midshipmen act
              as caddies, and with the pitching of
              the ships the young men have lots of
              fun retrieving balls that bound from
              the tables.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022060/1902-05-22/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=ping+pong+craze</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              The ping pong craze has reached Carson
              and Reno.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1902-08-13/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=ping+pong+craze</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              Ping Pong
              are certainly the two most popu
              lar games just at present. And
              everything points to a lasting pop
              ularity for both. It:s a fact that
              the Ping Pong craze has given
              Tennis a boom unsurpassed in
              the history of the game. Wo
              carry All of the Better Grades of
              Tennis and Ping Pong Goods.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/ca05000846/1903-07-16/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=ping+pong+craze</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1902-06-28/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=ping+pong+craze</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
</topic>