<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-statue-of-liberty</id>
    <results>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026497/1878-04-17/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Statue+Harbor+Liberty+Lighting+World+Bartholdi</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>The Statue for IKevr York Harbor.
            A French paper eaya The colossal
            statue of "Liberty Lighting tho
            World, erected by France and Ameri
            ca in remembrance of their old friend
            ship, is coming ont little by little from
            the immense workshops established
            expressly for its construction in the
            Kiie de Chazelle', No. 25, near Mon
            ceaux Park. The arm aud hand hold.
            ing the torch are already in America,
            and at present the sculptor. Bartholdi.
            is finishing the principal portion of the
            lioa.l IR. ill 1
            .v,.4, .J.UD iiu3bci uiuuei it ueariv com
            pleted. In a few days it will be strip
            ped of the Fcaffolding which surrounds
            ii ana upon which several gangs of men
            are at work. The first sentiment in
            spired by tho enormous head, nearly
            thirty feet high, is almost terror. Its
            gigantic dimensions are stupefying; but
            ujr uegrees mo eye Decomes accustomed
            to the colossal forms, and the mind
            reconciles itself to the extent of those
            great lines, and we discover in the midst
            of them the majesty and the light
            which the author has endeavored to give
            ti the features. But the publio will
            soon have an opportunity to see the beau
            ty of this work.for the head of the statue
            of Liberty is to be exhibited at the
            Universal Imposition.- Nevertheless,
            we strongly advise every one before-
            nana to visit the establishment on the
            Ruo de Chazelles and see how the dif-
            rerent portions of this head are prepared,
            worked nud adjusted. M. Bartholdi is
            making copies in plaster of his statue of
            liinerty. lwo huLdred of them only
            will bj executed, numbered and regis
            tered with the name of the niirnh
            who iany in this may preserve a souvenir
            or tmsniagnmcentcomniemorativeof the
            centennial anniversary of the independ
            ence of the United States, and destined
            to renew aud enliven the old friendship
            between franco and America.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014424/1881-10-11/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=COLOSSAL+STATUE+Liberty+Bedloe%27s+Island+Bartholdi</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Tho Colosanl Kliitne of Liberty
            New York Times October 0
            Tho presence In Now York of tho French
            visitors to tho Yorktown celebration sug
            gests tho propriety of reminding tho Ameri
            can public of tho efforts which tho French
            nro making to keep alive- nnd pcrpctuato
            tho memory of tho disinterested friendship
            and generous aid given by Franco to tho
            colonics of North America in their strugglo
            for liberty nnd independence Sovcrnl
            years ago mi association was formed In
            Franco by somo of tbo most distinguished
            Eonubllcam with tlio titlo of Tho Franco-
            American Union under tho presidency of
            Americas special lrlcnii senator iiDouiago
            tho object of this association being to per
            notuato tho memory of tho friendship
            twecn Tranco nnd America by presenting to
            tho pcopl of tho United States a colossal
            statuo of Liborty to bo erected on
            Bedlbos Island in tho harbor of Now
            York and to servo as a beacon by moans
            of an electric light to bo placed In tho
            diadem on tbo head of Liberty Tho mate
            rial of tho statuo is hammered copper it
            will bo somo 120 feet In height aud was
            designed by and is being executed under
            tbo immcdlato direction of M A Bartholdi
            one of tho foremost of living scnlptcrs Tlio
            money for tho purposo was raised by volun
            tary subscription throughout France and
            tho work is steadily piogrcssing nnd will
            undoubtedly bo finished by midsummer
            18S3 A special act of Congress has given
            Bcdloos Island for tho purposo of tho erec
            tion of this statuo which is to bo placed
            upon a pedestal of masonry abotit 100 feet
            high A CDmralttco has been appointed
            Lore Under tbo chairmanship of tho Hon
            Win M Kvnrts to ralso tho necessary funds
            for tbo construction of tho pedestal and to
            have it built according to a design fur
            nished by tho sculptor and it Is contldcntly
            hoped that it will bo ready in timo for tho
            reception of tho statuo in 1883 And thus
            this glgantio monument willstand as nn en
            during manifestation of tho friendship bo
            tween tho two great republics of tbo world
            Diiulcl llooncM Nunkc</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075021/1885-05-20/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Liberty+Enlightening+World+Bartholdi+Statute</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Let LTh Good Work Go Os. Public sentiment hbar been thorough-ly aroused at last, ini favor of the move-ment toward the erecting of Bartholdl's statute, "Liberty Enlightening the World," inu the harbor of New York. Americans now understand that those among them who subscribe to the completion of this grand work, will perform an act of patriotism, and at the same time one of International comity worthy of the enlightened ideas permesting this nineteenth century. Some idea of the extent of the pub-lic sentiment is shown by the fact tbat the New York World has been able to report subscriptions of over $30,000 in a month's time, in sums averaging less than $1" each, the great bulk of these contributions being in dimes and quarters.
            What a aiagniflcent object it will be, towering almost into the clouds from New York's beautiful harbor! It will stand as a grand symbol of liberty be-fore the eyes of every one coiaiug frol l the oppressed countries beyond the ocean. At the gateway of no other nation oould it stand with such ap-propriateness. Here it symbolizes the fullest achievement of human freedom and will forever stand to tell that story.
            The committee in charge of the erec-tion of the pedestal for the reception of this great work have prepared a beautiful statuette, as a souvenir tb send to eob person who sab uilbe. -Ought not the beat of every Acan to respond with pride when he bas the opportunity of contributing toward the erection of such a monou-ment? It is one of the grandest undertak-ings of modern times and eminently fitting that it should be built from the hearts and pockets of our people.
            The committee does not believe the American people are indifferent to this great work, therefore calls upon them for their aid. Every person wishing to secome a sobscriber should soend their address to Richard Butler, Secretary American Committee of the Statue of Liberty, No. 88 Mercer street, New York, incloling $1, and will re-orive In return a mlnature reproduc-tion of this great work. While large subscriptions are aways desirable it would be far more to he credit of this great nation if evqtl man, woman and child should *ro *block In the pedestal wbi Wle ll spp/W the everlasting mosamelt of LIIIBAY ENLIOMTaRei s3 WORLD</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016187/1885-05-28/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=BARTHOLDI+STATUE+Liberty+Enlightening+World+Wonder+Colossus+Bedloe+Island</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>BARTHOLDI'S STATUE.
            Liberty Enlightening the World.
            This now Wonder of the World, which is
            now being loaded on the French transport lsere
            for shipment to this country, is tho largest
            statue in tho world. Somo idea of its magni
            tude may bo obtained from tho fact that 40
            persons found standing room within the head.
            A six-foot man standing on tho level of tho
            lip3 only just reached the eyebrow. Whilo
            workmen wero employed on the crown of her
            head they seemed to bo making a huge sugar
            caldron, and they jumped with caso in and out
            tho tip of tho nose. Fifteen pcoplo might sit
            round tho flame of tho torch, which elevation
            can bo reached by a spiral staircase within tho
            outstretched arm.
            Tho London Daily Ncics, in speaking of it,
            says It is out aud away the largest statue of
            modern times. Tho Colossus of Rhodes was
            nothing to it. It could carry tho 'Bavaria' or
            tho 'Hermann' in its arms. It towers to tho
            skies from tho yard of the Ruo do Chazelles,
            whoro it has been eight years in construction,
            and tho view from its coronet sweeps clear of
            the six-story hbuses and beyond tho walls of
            Paris."
            Tho weight of this stupendous statuo is 440,
            000 pounds, of which 170,000 pounds are cop
            per and tho remainder wrought-iron. It is
            expected to arrivo in New York about the 25th
            of May, whero it will bo erected ou Bedloe's
            Island, this being the location selected for it by
            Gen. W. T. Sherman, who was appointed by tho
            President to mako the selection. When placed
            in position it will loom up 305 feot above tide
            water, tho hight of tho statuo being 151.2 feet,
            that of tho pedestal 91 feet, aud foundation
            52.10 feet.
            This imposing statue, higher than tho enor
            mous towers of the great Brooklyn Bridge or
            the steeple of Trinity Church, which is tho
            loftiest in tho city of New York, higher, in
            fact, than any of tho colossal statues of anti
            quity by its rare artistic proportions, as well
            as by its stupendous dimensions, will add an
            other to tho Wonders of the World. A word
            should bo said of its artistic "merit. The pose,
            stride, and gesture, with its classic face, aro
            pronounced perfect; the drapory is both mass
            ive and fine, and in some parts is as dclicato
            and silky in effect asif wrought with a fino
            chisel on tho smallest scale.
            The committco in charge of the construction
            of the baso and pedestal for tho reception of
            this great work aro in want of funds for its
            completion, and have prepared a miniaturo
            statuct, an exact counterpart of tho original,
            six inches in hight, tho ilguro being made of
            bronze, the pedestal of nickel silver, which
            they aro now delivering to subscribers through
            out tho United States for tho small sum of $1
            each. Aside from its being a lasting souvenir
            of this colossal statue, it will ornament onr
            homes and bear testimony that wo have con
            tributed to tho completion of ono of the grand
            est works of modcrn times. All remittances
            should bo addressed to, Richard Butler, Secre
            tary American Committee of the Statuo of Lib
            erty, No. 33 Mercer Street, New York. Tho
            committee aro also prepared to furnish a model,
            in samo metals, twelve inches in hight, at $5
            each, delivered.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040340/1886-11-05/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Liberty+Light+Statue+Bartholdi+Colossal+Bedloe+Island</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Ins Bartholdi statue of Liberty Enlight
            ening the World was unveiled on the Sth
            in the presence of the President, tho Cabi
            net and tho French visitors. Immense
            numbers participated in the procession in
            .New York, and it was calculated 1,000,000
            sightseers were present
            A new post-office in Dakota has just been
            named Bartholdi by the Post-olllce Depart
            ment
            Tun London Xeics does not think tho IJar
            tholdi statue will increase tho friendship
            between France nnd America.
            The French visitors to the Bartholdi
            celebration wero greatly annoyed by auto
            graph cranks.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89064939/1878-09-18/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=PARIS+LETTER+Liberty+Statue+Bartholdi+Colossus+Exhibition</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>OUR PARIS LETTER.
            The head of the new Colossus,
            *'Liberty," which is in future to
            light all nations into the harbor of
            New York, has produced a profound
            impression on the visitors to the
            Exhibition. It is placed on the
            left-hand side of the grounds of the
            Champ de Mar's, looking towards
            the Seine. The face is very fine
            somewhat resembling that of the
            Apollo Belridere, and the effect from
            the othr side of the grounds, two
            thousand feet off, or so, is remark
            ably grandL- For the first time a
            modern sculptor has achieved that
            in which the' Greeks seemed to fink?
            no difficulty whatever, namely, the
            necessary exaggeration of parts to
            produce effect at a great distance.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89064939/1885-07-29/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=BARTHOLDI+GIRL+Liberty+Enlightening+World+Statue+Pedestal+Colossal</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>BARTHOLDI BIG GIRL
            The Prejudices Met By a Canvasser for the Pedestal Fund.  
            The Bartholdi pedestal fund is nearly complete. The statue has arrived, and soon New York Harbor will be graced by the most magnificent colossal statue the world has ever seen: "Liberty Enlightening the World!" What a priceless blessing personal liberty is. It is the shrine at which people, ground under the heel of tyranny in the older worlds, worship with a fervency that Americans can scarcely realize. It is a principle for which Nihilists willingly die the death of dogs; and fit and proper it is that, at the very entrance of the Bay of New York, this emblematic statue should flash a welcome to the world.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1886-10-24/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=Statue+Liberty+Bartholdi+Goddess+Bedlow+Island</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text> THE BIG STATUE OF LIBERTY  FINAL PREPARATIONS FOR UNVEILING
            The canvas mask that has hidden the face of the Goddess of Liberty since last Wednesday was taken off for an hour or two yesterday afternoon, as if in compliment to the immense crowd of visitors to Bedloe's Island. The steamer John Field, instead of reappearing as promised, was put through another course of repairs, and the little steamer Water Lily took its place, to the great delight of all who have to travel often to the statue's out-of-the-way site. The island itself looks fresher and cleaner than it has in weeks. The grandstand and the speaker platform are built along the parapets and are all set up. The barren parts of the grounds have been cleared and leveled on the top and sides. Grass seed has been sown all over, and it is beginning to sprout here and there. The unsightly old boards have been burned, and the loose stones and rubbish from the work have all been carted back to the gullies at the island's western end. The hammering still continues on the right arm and shoulder blade of the Goddess, but practically, the great figure is ready for unveiling at any time.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071854/1886-10-29/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Liberty+Statue+Grand+Bedloe+Island</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text> The Statue
            The statue which was unveiled today is entitled "Liberty Enlightening the World.The name was bestowed upon it by M. Bartholdi. The idea aimed at was the symbolization of the progress of civilization and the growth of freedom, as expressed in the republican form of government. It was also meant to perpetuate the friendship of the French and American nations, begun in revolutionary days when this country was struggling to throw off the English yoke. The height of the statue from the base to the torch is 151 feet, 1 inch. The total height from the foundation of the pedestal to the torch is 305 feet, 6 inches. From heel to top of the head, it measures 111 feet, 6 inches, and the length of the hand is 16 feet, 5 inches.  Its entire cost was about $700,000.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83032011/1886-11-05/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Statue+Liberty+Bartholdi+Goddess+Pedestal+Colossal+Bedlow+Island</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>THE STATUE OF LIBERTY: HOW IT WAS MADE AND PUT IN PLACE.  The New York Tribune thus recounts the history of the great work of M. Bartholdi, which was unveiled on Thursday of last week in the New York harbor. The history of the Bartholdi statue from its inception to its unveiling is a checkered one and goes back through all sorts of delays and difficulties for almost twenty years.It was, strangely enough, just at the close of the disastrous war with Germany and while the horrors of the Commune were still raging in Paris that M. Laboulaye, the founder of the French-American Union, first definitively broached his patriotic project of building in this country a joint memorial of the struggles of the French and Americans in the Revolution, and sent the young sculptor Bartholdi to the United States to find, if possible, some suitable and happy idea.The first suggestion of the statue, perhaps, dates still further back to a dinner given under the Empire by M. Laboulaye at his country house, "Glavigny," near Versailles.  </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045217/1921-03-13/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;q=statue+of+liberty</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053305/1920-05-14/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=statue+of+liberty</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>CONSERVATIVE ORGAN DECRIES
            SUPPRESSION
            CHICAGO TRIBUNE SUGGESTS
            SENDING STATUE OF LIBERTY
            BACK TO FRANCE.
            Chicago, III.-Under the title of
            "Send the Statue of Liberty Back to
            France," the Tribune of this city, long
            known as one of the most reaction
            ary of American newspapers, pub
            lished a surprising editorial in its is
            sue of April 26.
            This editorial, which may well mark
            the beginning of the reaction against
            high-handed violence to popular
            rights, ran in part as follows:
            "A veteran, writing in, wants to
            know why Americans should contrih
            ute to a fund for a statue to he sent
            to France. 'If we are to give the
            French a statue, send them back the
            statue of Liberty. We haven't had
            any use for it since July 1.'
            "Do we any longer need the statue
            Iiberty? We are not free in any
            sen:; that an intelligent white people
            interpret freedom. It is not only beer
            andl booze which as outlaws reveal
            the limitations of individual decision
            tnd choice. The greatest uproar is
            utout that Ibe:use the greatest mln
            ber of people there find that they can
            not have what, they want.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075284/1947-07-18/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=statue+of+liberty</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Statue of Liberty Is a New Yorker
            WASHINGTON. Although Bed
            loe’s island, on which the Statue of
            Liberty stands, is part of New York
            state, the water surrounding it is
            part of New Jersey.
            Upkeep of the statue, which is
            now a national monument, is budg
            eted at about $60,000 a year. The
            seven families of National Park
            service employes, who live on the
            island, vote in New York City.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn79000083/1955-12-31/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=statue+of+liberty</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82006551/1935-12-26/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=statue+of+liberty</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>October 28 The Statue of Liber
            ty on Bedloe's island In New York
            harbor was .dedicated. It was the
            work of Auguste Bartholdi, an Al
            satian soulprnrr-who, ns he entered
            the harbor In 1871, conceived the
            Idea of a statue of "Liberty Enlight
            ening the World" to stand at this
            gateway to America. Funds for the
            erection of the statue were raised
            by the French people as evidence
            of their friendship for the people
            of the American republic. On this
            date, Bartholdi drew the cords of
            the huge tricolor of France which
            concealed the statue and unveiled
            It In the présidence of President
            Grover Cleveland, members of his
            cabinet, a delegation of French offi
            cials, members of congress, military
            and naval leaders and "a vast
            throng of onlookers."</text>
        </result>
    </results>
</topic>