<topics>
<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-women-aviation/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042373/1910-09-01/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Aviation+aviators+women&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.009,0.136,0.872,0.985,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>October 16, 1910	Women are becoming more frequent flyers</time>
        <text>V«H:-
ii
By CHARLES N. LURIE.
SAID"Well,my
I to friend the woman
hater:
why shouldn't wom
en fly if they wish to do so?'
Said my friend the woman hater:
"No reason In the world. They 'go up
In the air* often enough."
So they, are going up in the air, as
the pictures show, but not In the sense
In which the misogynist used the
words. Aviation for women has reach
ed the point where the Parisian cos
turners are designing special costumes
for the sport or pastime or vocation
or avocation. That means that It Is
fast becoming 'an "institution." One
of the lady aviators is shown In the
picture garbed for a flight
What Shall We Call thsi Lady Flier?
"Lady aviators" brings up another
point. 'What shall we call the women
who are ascending in aeroplanes and
balloons? 8hall we refer to them as
avlatrlces plural of avlatrix, of which
the masculine Is aviator, or shall we
adopt the suggestion of an English
magazine and refer to the fair fliers as
"aeroine*?" The latter suggestion hits
merit, but the word has one fatal de
fect—It is difficult of pronunciation.
From some mouths it will emerge' with
so close a resemblance to "heroines"
as to be mistaken for that word. Per
haps it is well to suggest a relation
ship between "heroine" and "aero
ine," since the latter Is undoubtedly
worthy of enrollment in the lists of
the former. At this, stage of the flying
game any woman wko' accomplishes a
flight Is surely a heroine.
Up to the date of writing there had
not- been many women aviators.
Italy had the Duchess of Aosta, cousin
by marriage of King Victor Emmanuel.
France^ in some respects the leader In
aviation and in many respects the
world's mentor in "feminism," had only
three prominent lady fliers—Baroness
de la Roche, Incapacitated for an in
definite length of time by very serious
WHEN
the government of
th* United States want*
Information on military
matters to whom does It
turn? To the .same man to whom the
state of Ohio look* for advice and
guidance In regard, to its citizen sol
diers.- And that man I* Major General
Charles William Frederick Dick. Don't
recognize th* name? Well, you are
not to be blamed. When the name of
the senior aenator from Ohio 1* printed
In It* usual form the two middle sec
tions are cut out and th* name pro-
4^^ '»vr
IM
I...:.
Tt
*'C
1
••jk ii MAJOR GENERAL DICK AND STAFF.
ceed* on the main line as Senator
Charles Dick of Ohio. If Dick were
an Englishman he would be known as
Major General th* Honorable Charles
William Frederick Dick. But H* I* not
a Britisher, only a plain—very plal*.
In fact—0iloan, who sheds luster on th*
title of Unlte*8taU» senator by add
ing to It that of major general In th*
Ohio national guard.
Com* to think of IV major gwMMls
are *caro* ln th* **nat* these day*,
pick I* th* on|y on* at pi«*ent now In
active service, and hte title Is only a
militia on*, after all. Pressing him
injuries dueto a fait lime. Franck.
also "injured JuBt after she had an
nounced her Intention of making a
flight across the English channel, and
Mme. Paulhan, wife of the famous
tiouls. There have been a few others,
but their exploits have attracted lit
tle attention. England has two or
three women fliers In heavier than air
machines. Germany has produced no
women fliers of note—none, that is. In
aeroplanes. The Zeppelin, Parseval
and Gross dirigible balloons have had
female passengers In some of their fa
mous flights. In America we have had
Hiss K»therlne Wright, Mrs. Hart O.
Berg, Mrs. Cortland Field Bishop,
Mrs. Clifford B. Harmon, Mrs. Wil
liam K. Vanderbllt, Jr., and a few
others as passengers with the "man
birds" when they made flights above
the earth. Mrs. Bishop was the first
woman to fly In America. But no
American woman so far as known has
been daring enough to go aloft as an
aviator. That will come In time, no
doubt, and in the meanwhile we may
rest content with the fact that we have
the only genuine, bona fide woman
airship Inventor on earth. She is
worth a separate paragraph.
Only Woman Airship Inventor.
The name of the lady is Miss E.
Lillian Todd, and her postofllce address
is New York. She Is called 'probably
the first woman In the world to de
sign and build an aeroplane" all by
herself. The Todd machine was a col
lapsible or folding aeroplane, and the
fact of Its existence was first made
public two years ago, Since that time
Miss Todd has kept busy designing
and making improvements to her aero
plane. She Is a member of the Aero
Club of America and one of the found
ers of the Junior Aero club, which
aims at teaching the young American
idea how to fly. Miss Todd has the
added distinction 'of being the builder
of her flying machine as well as Its
Inventor. Recently she had the good
fortune to attract the notice of Mrs.
Russell Sage, and It was announced</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-10-16/ed-1/?sp=56&amp;q=dutrieu+helene&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.056,-358.174,1.111,717.778,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>October 16, 1910	Women are becoming more frequent flyers,</time>
        <text>OIF [FINTEBEST i
MNiE. FRANK, WHO INTENDS TO
ESSAY A FLIGHT ACROSS THE
ENGLISH CHANNEL.
0. WHITHER SO HIGH?
Twentieth Century Woman Is
After Aerial Colrxebs.
In the course of T*n or twenty years it
tnay be as s»jperf talk about wom
en, who ride lr. machines as it
\pcmld be now to J d forth or. women
*rho rifle in streetcars. In the year 1310.
however, woman aviator is still a nov
elty. The International Aviation Tourna
■tent at Belmont Park will be an cxclu
•tlvely masculine affair, and the heroism
of those women ho have begun to mount
up with wings like eagles occasions
JCTKVJ deal or surprise, though It Is hard
to see why it should be so.
Nobody is surprised when women drive
automobiles, and in the matter of acci
dents, automobiles are up to the wire with
anything- that travels. Women are gener
ally ■where the danter is.
It «at not until last November, hough,
that a woman actually went aloft alone.
•Women had frequently gone as passengers
with aviators of the other sex. but it re
mained for the Baronne Raymonds de
Ijaroche to strike out in a new field as
the first "woman navigator through air cur
rents. This she c.i at Mourmelon. By now
she Is a. veteran at the sport. At the flying
contests held in Egypt last spring no one
was more venturesome than she.
The very first woman who ever flew -was
a Flemish girl. Mile. P. yon Pottelsberphe.
She chanced to be on the field as a spec
tator when Henri Farman was making
one of his first exhibition flights. in Bel
gium. A lightweight passenger was
needed, ana Mile, yon Pottelsberghe vol
•unteerefi.
Not very lons afterward, at Turin. th«
French tnas, Mme. Therese Peltier,
took a flight with L£on Pelagranpe in his
Voisin biplane. Mme. Peltier was very en
thusiastic about the biplane then, and was
V jrolng to learn to drive it. but she never
it did. Probably the tragic death of Dela
franc* gave her a dislike for the fpon_
Th*. im woman in America, to fly was
Mrs. Ralph BL Van aa Man. wife of an
army captain. She has cine, all sorts of
daring thine- she- is said to r* able to ride
any horse that goes, and when one of the
Wrights invited her to go aloft with him
near Washington, last October, she jumped
at the chance. Miss KatßCftae Wright,
elster of the famous brothers, has ascend-
Some Ways of the World
The "silence" treatment at West Point
appears to be nothing to the "melting
stway" act as practised by omen when
they want to Intimate to another woman
Chat ehe is cot of their social set.
"I witnessed the latter treatment this
SBimner," said a woman who has just re
turned irom a. fashionable summer resort.
-and I had the satisfaction or witnessing
also the triumph or the victim ever her per
rwcutors. She was a very rharming' girl
Trho had come to the place because she had
heard it was attractive and because it
-was convenient lor the men of her family.
"She knew some of the eligible young men
of the place, so counted on having a good
time, but she aid not court en the lact
that because she knew these men the belle
of the colony would confer her a deadly
rival, and having been ther* first would
treat tier as an intruder instead, of an ad
dition, and a laßcinating one at that. The
men gave fcer family a dinner, invited tile
"SseJle to meet her. and innocently thought
•they bad done th* right thing-, but they had
snerely added fuel to the flames, and be
-Sore two weeks were lip the newcomer was
aware of what she had to lace. t>ne would
■bravely don hex exquisite Frencn irocks
and Join the •women, ■who bowed gra-clousiy
•.t first, but In naif an hour see would be
left alone, and the little crowd ■would have
collected Just a short distance away. The
never raw her unless there were men
croend. and then "he would come over
•wit* a ssreet smile and a few intima' re
marks tr.at eouia not be resented because
of the boys. Finally, the new girl went olt
to visit, ana was gone Tor six weeks or
more. On her return ehe encouni^-red the
old girl, who was with one of the men, ana
■who accordingly showed fome interest, ask
ing whers she bad been. hearing the
name Of the place, she said. 'Oh, I know
Mrs. Blank there. She has often wanted
in* to name a time to visit her, co I think
I'll write and go up. for she gives every one
Fuch a pood time. Perhaps you've heard of
J-.er'' Th** tr.Fwer came sweetly, 'Yes.
I've bast been with her; Mm is ray cousin.
and I told her I had met you here,* The
PARK &amp;TILFORD
Fifth Avenue and T^ecty-MX'h Street And H ranch Stores
We call your attention to our Cand Department
at this, as well as at our Hrant h Stores.
AH our Chocolates, Bon Bons, Caramels and Candies
are manufactured by ourselves.
Only the Purest and finest Materials used.
PRICES: lh
Chocolates and Bonbon*, .M
Peswrt Battle, .35 French CsrsmeU, .W
Pepp*ramt Dainties, .35 Chocolate Mellow Mftflto, .45
CboeoJste Cream Royals, .45 French Nougat, 'A-\b. Hot .50
5 CbocolsteMuruichinoCherries
Vanilla Walnut Fudge, Jf per box .40
Chocolate Fudge, .35 large box .80
Deliveries out of town by freight and express.
ttmm Catalogue with COMPLETE Price-Lists i'.ad!\ smt psm
n:lle. helene dutrieu, who
holds the record among
women pilots in distancs
and altitude.
Ed with them, but that was at Pau. and
not in America.
Of course, Mrs. Glenn H. Curtiss has had
trips in her husband's biplanes with him.
She, Is her husband s right hand, by the
way. In his work of constructing biplanes.
She attends to the Business details, being
fortunate enough to have a mother who
manages the house, leaving her free to
help her husband.
Women professionals are appearing in
the flvinff field. HGlene Dutrleu is a bird
woman who has filled engagements to ap
pear at amusement fields in a biplane. She
holds the record amMg women aviators for
distance, and altitude, having made a re
turn night from Ostend, Belgium, to
Bruges with a passenger, a distance of
twenty -eight miles, and gone up thirteen
hundred feet. Mlie. Dutrien has done near
ly everything daring there was to do.
More than a decade ago she won the
world's championship for women in cy
cBBC and no woman has been able to take
from her the hour record. She has done all
sorts of trick riding, and nearly lost her
life "looping the loop," so when she cot a
had fall in a Santos-Dumont "Dragonfly"
it did not leaze her in the least. N T o man.
spectators asid. could have taken it more
atnsrslTr
Mrne. Frank, another French •woman, also
has a record for long flights, and is now
planning to fly across the English Channel.
Miss Gertrude Bacon, a member of the
English Women's Aerial League, who has
been one of Farman's passengers several
times, can compare the different methods of
ajcrial tiavelllng from experience, for she
has tried them all— the spherical balloon.
the dirigible ar.d the aeroplane. For dreamy
delight she chooses the balloon.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-07-02/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=aeroplane+fly+FLY+flying+Harriet+machine+piloted+Quimby</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>July 02, 1911 : Announced that women will take part in the aeroplane racing at Harvard Aeronautical Society in Cambridge</time>
        <text>WOMEN WHO FLY
riiotolMwlnl.rvlck, N. V
Mile. Dutrieu, leading French Aviatrix
WHEN women take to aeroplane rac
ing, as it is announced will be done
at the summer meet of the Harvard
Aeronautical Society in Cambridge,
Mass., it will be only a matter of a short
time before the interest in the sport will
be so general that airship contests will
be as common as tennis tourneys ami
golf competitions are today.
Three countries will be represented by
women contestants at Cambridge, with
Mile. Dutrieu, a French airwoman of
considerable expe
rience, in the lead.
Mrs. James V.
Martin will wear
the English col
ors; and Miss
Emily Willard,
who has already
made several as
cents with her
Jand Miss
II y Willard,
has alread
c several as-
S wit b her
brother at Min
eola, L. 1., is, up to
date, the third
woman entered for
the race.
Mile. Dutrieu is
looked upon as
perhaps the most daring woman aviator
in the world, although several of her own
countrywomen press her closely for sec
ond place. She first began to fly in a
Demoiselle monoplane about two years
ago. She changed to a barman biplane;
and it was in the latter machine that she
made her longest flight, winning the
Coupe Fcmina after making 105 miles,
and remaining in the air for two hours
and 35 minutes.
Photo Edwin Levlck, N.V.
Miss Harriet Quimby,
Journalist and Flier
Mrs. Martin is an Englishwoman who
married a former instructor in the Har
vard Aeronautical Society; but who later
became an in
structor in Gra
hame-Whit c's
School of Aviation
in France. She has
not only ma d
many flights with
her husband in the
machine, belong
y ing to the Harvard
Society, which he
designed; but she
is now flying in
Grahame-W h i t c's
Baby biplane,
which is a small
copy of the Farman machine.
Other influences which will induce
many more women to learn to fly are
the opening of the A. J. Moisant School
of Aviation at Garden City, L. 1., and
Photo Edwin Levlck.N.Y.
Mrs. E. Edwards,
an American Aviatrix
THE FAMILY MAGAZINE.-■ SECTION
the prospect that a Wright machine will
be kept at Belmont Park for the sum
mer, for the instruction of students and
the carrying of passengers. These ad
vantages will make it possible for many
women to become aviators; and will also
give an opportunity to scores of others
who have been longing for a chance to
try the experiment as passengers.
The first woman to try to fly her own
machine was Miss Harriet Quimby, New
York journalist. She is very enthusias
tic over her monoplane, in which she has
already taken several long lights, with
but one mishap of minor importance.
Other women who have made several
flights alone at Mineola, are Mrs. E.
Edwards and Mrs. Francois Raiche.
Miss Mary Shea, winner of the Bridge
port Conn. Post competition, made a
flight of about five miles on May 14,
from the Bridgeport Aerodrome, .out
over Long Island Sound and back.
Mrs. Frank Coffyn, whose husband is
connected with the Wright Company's
instruction camp at Augusta, Ga., flew
30 miles with her husband on March 3,
from Augusta, Ga., to Aiken, S. C. They
left the former place at 7:10, arriving
at their destination at 8:21, just in time
to eat breakfast with some friends.
Most of the time, they traveled at a
height of 500 feet.
Across the water, are many French
women aviators who have won trophies
in various contests. Among these may
be named Mile. Hervieu, who won the
Coupe Ftmina at Pau in 1910, traversing
eighty-seven miles and remaining in the
air two hours and five minutes, and
Baroness Raymonde de Laroche, who
was one of the first airwomen in France.
A list of women flyers would be incom
plete if it did not mention the Hon.
Assheton Harbard, a famous English
balloonist, who has frequently piloted
her own balloon from England across
the Channel into France.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093220/1911-08-03/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=aeroplane+air+Aires+event+fly+flying+machine+plane+planes+race+RACE+STUNT&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.683,-0.005,0.5,0.565,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>August 3, 1911 :	Mrs. Russell Sage patrons Miss E. L. Todd, who is designing and building her own plane.</time>
        <text>MRS. RUSSELL
SA G E has
ad no u need
herself a pntron of
aviation So Inter
ested is she In the
doings ot the fly
men thai she took a
motor spin to Mine
ola, where the Aero
n a u t i c society
houses a dozen men
and biplanes in a
bis red shed, and
looked over all the
engine driven birds
@19u; by Lazarnlck
MRS. R. BAC.F.
Especially was she Interested In the
big biplane being built by Miss E. I.
Todd, the woman aviator I'he plane
Is a large one, but Mrs. S;ii;e went
over its every detail and showed by
her questions to Louis Adams, an In
ventor who was showing tier round,
that she understood a great deal iilmui
air craft.
"It la very gratifying." snlil Mrs
Sage, speaking of Miss Todd's effort.
MIRfl B r.*ri!A TODD.
"to see women take up these tilings,
and I am always willing to encourage
anything that is done by a woman.
"I have watched Miss Todd's prog
ress with much concern and hope she
will succeed In making a successful
flying machine. If she needs any more
help I am willing to give it to her.
"I am receiving so many letters from
people who want help! Yesterday I
received four letters from ambitious
aviators or aeronauts—which should I
call them? I would be willing to help
any woman to accomplish something
that is worthy, mucb more than the
men."
If Mrs Rage should decide to help
tbe woman aviator: she would already
discover a flock of them who have en
tered the Held, some of them wives
or sisters of the "man birds" who are
flying and others who are determined
to bo woman birds without waiting for
any mere man to lead the way.
Miss E 1.11 urn Todd of New York
is probably the first woman In the
world to design and build an aeroplane.
This was a collapsible device, which
she first made known to tbe public In
tbe summer of lUOB. /t that time.
MISS K ATFTKRTVK WMOFTT
while giving no detailed description of
the machine, she said it called for a
spread of forty-five feet, with a width
of seven feet. The plane was to stand
six feet in height and to weigh several i
hundred pounds less than any other I
aeroplane of the time. The engine was I
to he of special design and of exceed
ing lightness and strength. j
Miss Todd not only designs her aero
planes, but. being skilled in the use
of tools, is her own model builder.
It is believed that Miss Catherine
Wright, sister of the Wright brothers,
was the first American woman to make
a flight in an aeroplane. This she did
on Feb. 15, 1909, at I'au, France, wheu
she made an ascent with a brother.
Mr. Wilbur Wright
Women were one of the big features
of the aviation meet at Los Angeles
last January After M. I'aulhati hud
performed some of his startling feats
he took Mine Paulhan in tils machine
and Hew away with her to Hcdondo
Beach and back again, a distance of
thirty tulles The light lasted thirty
six minutes
To Mm#. Raymondi' do Laroebe. who
Is a I- ronch baroness, belongs the dis
tinetion of Ijeinu itic pioneer woman
avintor of Prnii'-e. althouch seven oil!
or women liavc been licensed ns ulr
pilots by the Prench Aero club Sin
was one ol the tirsi women to take a
practical interest in aviation and soon
after tlit tlrst International eu| event
at Rheltns purchased a Volsin biplane
and later was an entrant for the prize
of 5.1RH1 francs offered the votnan mak
tac the best time for ten kilometers.
Her efforts at the meet resulted In
one of the most distressing accidents
In aviation She was drl Ing her bi
plane at a helcht of fifty meters when
she suddenly loot control of the ma
Chine and foil with It to the ground
Eler lep ami arms were broken and'
her wholp hodv terribly bruised.
Carpet Mills.
The first carpet mill in America was
not established until after the clnsi
of the Revolution. It was in l"!'l at
Philadelphia, that carpet making as an
industry was born In t!i" t'nltcd States
Since then, however. thiT"country lias
become rre-oniinent tn carpet making</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1911-08-06/ed-1/?sp=52&amp;q=HARRIET+QUIMBY</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>BLNK</time>
        <text>M,SS MATILDA MOISANT. SISTER OF THE LATE JOHN MOISANT. WHO IS LEARNING TO FLY A MONOPLANF.
r?-'-'-1
Scorners of the Ground
Three Birdwomen at Mineole, First Americans
of Their Sex to Wing the Blue Deep.
sra m By
K, Mlaa rtarnV
I
Tueada at Um Herapatead Plahu h.
beb mta a\ at"
II
twtab
f\
I

r
at thought ha was

tha m
an 1 ln thfl
n the macl
aglrj

aad i
i

:nf.nf up
ra two
aad 01
I through
?K







I
I
I m

I

oan a*/l



I

raa.



i ed to
iu a rac

Some Scasor
A rei immer day

d and
j-..- i H.3

im tbe




t
I

I





Add
or two


_

water. lf tl
i


-it tlu*

fr
ng


Mlaced
X |?a iTfiiare a eicelj s?u
in a biplans tbs asaglafl la dlraetly bark
&gt;f tbs aperator, and If tbs machlne fall.i
tiier?* a.-*- hundrada of ncnnfls of solid
,,f him. In a mono
plaar. however, I bba dlstaaee
lf ne fallfl he only
?Ot Ct ished

M Qulmby and Miss
rr, a! type.i of air
MlBSftla. hut
ea ln appearan
sHa atid ilarK
ea wlth 1
lUni barma daa

nt .-rnplo
Waekli Mm
a pro
&gt;H,ir nnt
rasohlls tour
ainc-r
fortable, rotuad aatoar
?he appeara to bi
.1 Ip, aii'i.
ni.nks roas-oouatry

_ for 'prosfl
nj,&gt;ri*
n ana
wouldn en: to
aae waj the avia

i. a*bi ra th? m*n
n flxhlbl

I infei
lha a 4;: id custom
M f &gt;n inann


"tbsra is one
a auf*
a lt ahe

;b of
Mght from
retura. It ls

g] i
a dda't waat
I

Tl
-even ihe
Btlmea
i

rame,
lt fnr
the excitement of IL I'm
srorld
n Ca Ifora
1
there. all


B, thea nol

lt lB 4

I
John M
i
naa

M .fl M
I
tora oi

t laa
ar.
l
ofly
xablc 'RecipcJ

_

ln the
I




eat until

in tv
tli- mlxt*



MISS BLANCHE STUART SCOTT. IN
HER BIPLANE.
w j
THE END OF GOSSIP
Women Who Couni Stitches
Can'l Talk Scandal.
A balcyoi
Torh n ara i ni l
I
led from Ihe
fact tl aork??
hairs.
ibeth Barrett Broa

opialoi
?I itnble
orar
But If
a g tha
a ecl attentl n
thtion
muat be counta
j out ri| womai
fou
e can'l loud oi
a thal
m i i
i

ln fi
wai ed almoal
*4lnf .1 t r a woman, that ll
at handa rii-w aa sla
tha fl end
Doubtleaa tha dovotl

fact that there 1
_
ira i
r
V.

BOOl 'he

I

.1

1
MISS HARRIET QUIMBY, THE FIRST AMERICAN WOMAN
TO RECEIVE AN AVIATOR'S LICENSE.
The SeerofucKer Family</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1911-12-15/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Matilda+Moisant</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>December 15, 1911 :	Articles published about how women may make better pilots than men because of the nature of their sex.</time>
        <text>Miss Moisant, in her aeroplane. She
the sister of John B. Moisant.' the
famous aviator killed in New Orleans,
La., by his machine falling. Miss Moi
sant is ambitious to take her broth
former place in the aviation world.
era
Why a Woman Can Run an
Airship Better Than a Man
By Prof. Rudolph Hensingmuller, of Vienna University.
BECAUSE she
full retina.
has retained the primitive faculty of seeing with he?
Enforced modesty and flirting have caused thia..
BECAUSE she has scattered attention Instead of concentration. Thle
is invaluable to the aviator who must notice many things at once.
BECAUSE she has the faculty of Intuition that quality of the mind
which can take in a number of causes simultaneously and Instantly de
duce a conclusion an essential in successful aviation.
BECAUSE her specific gravity fs Itfss than man's.
BECAUSE she needs less oxygen and tnerefore can better meet the
suffocating rush of air. Altitude effects her less than ft does man.
BECAUSE her sneezes, In man an actual spasm, have been controlled
by ages of polite repression
BECAUSE she feels more quickly warning atmospheric changes.
BECAUSE she loves to speed.
Ww JET Mm Ef 4m JUHF V SSf &amp;rai
mW Bf Mr MW Mr Mr MWmW Wr fi&amp;JBr Mfjti&amp; Mr s&amp; Mr Smw Wm is
F MW Mw MY MY m Mm SB E2&amp; Bz8 5risS&amp;&amp;'&amp; 4"" $m$M Wm&amp;
JJm JIj&amp;sT mm m
lmmmmXBmlkSi&amp;&amp;Kji$s3k!il.-L fWvmWmMmmmmwmWk Tiff! '1 1 T fm 1 H!'T'flrTTffTfipifiHM T1nifr lnrtifffTjnlBHMtWBB A ilftf MeSwSE9HHHsP9K
tomwHmr iijffii wPvimBmHm IHbHbi
a i t..- .x. alKgM&amp;g-. jd. flHransHBKr BBBB'wPBiK akBMHKBiibft
fffrV? SSrA Tn fcy- JWJs Harriet Quinby. m TTS
WOMBN -will rale the air!
They are the naftural avia
tors. -N
History repeats itself. Men by the
score will Have died the death in
the air before aerial navigation is
safe. Then w oraan, the- cautious, the
conservative, the primitive, will step
in and rale.
Why is the air woman's own do
main? The answer is perfectly
'plain to both psychologists and
physiologists.
The periphery, the outer rim of
a woman's retina, Is as sensitive to
objects as is Its centre. A woman
can look- away from you and still
see you.
Her arc of sight is almost twice
that of man's, in whom, as a rale,
the periphery of the retina is ex
tremely blunted to impressions. Try
the experiment of having a woman
look straight ahead and telling you
how much she still can see on each
'Bide of her without directly looking
at the objects.
There is a deep psychological rea
son for this. Primitive man, who,
surrounded by dangers, had to keep
looking on every side at once, had,
it is probable, almost periscopic
sight, such as the birds have. He
could never know what side d&amp;Bgss,
was coming from, and so eves
though looking ahead, his retina,
sensitised to the rims, caught Im
pressions necessary to warn him of
enemies or of game.
Ever since woman has been the
subject of man she has practised
modesty. Sh has been forced to
go along with downcast eyes. And
yet her coqeettry has enforced upon
her the necessity of seeing. The
accomplished flirt has the peripheral
sensitiveness to the maximum but
every woman has it more or less.
Walking with averted eyes for fear
of husband or lover, she still sees
every male and female that goes
by her. She has retained this primi
tive retinal faculty.
By experiments at Harvard and
Vienna and at Paris, a woman's
arc of sight has been, measured.
The accompanying diagram shows
its relation to man's and to the
bird's. Manifestly the sight, which
more closely approaches the peris
copic, is better adapted for flying,
else a blrd would net have de
veloped this sight. A twig moving
far to his right in his field of vision
may be the signal of a hidden
enemy to the bird; in the same way
The Retina of a Woman's Ejre Every Part Sensitive to
Impressions. The Sketch Shows the Faculty in Action.
The Retina of a Man's Eye the Periphery Blunted to Impres-
The Sketch Shows His Necessarily Direct Gaze.
SKms.
JOHEX have entered the con
test for the laurels of the
thy. Miss Harriet Ouinbv.
the first woman aviator to receive
a pilot's Keens from the Aero Club
of America, has eeen followed 6jr
Miss Matilda Moisant, sister of the
unfortunate John B. Moisant. who
lost his life after having made an
enviaolcname for himself in avia
tion. According to Professor Rudolph
Hensingmuller, of Vienna University,
science foresees woman's domination
of the sky.- She will he the better
aviator, because she's the better flirt
On the other hand. Mr. Claud"
Grahame-White, the English aviator
and instructor declares that women
joill never achieve glory in the air
The arguments of these two authori.
Ues are presented in full on this page
WWHiHf
This Diagram
Shows the
Comparative
Arcs of Sight
of Man,
Woman and
Bird.
Woman's
in the
Centre,
by Reason
of Retinal
Periphery
Sensitiveness,
More Closely
Approaches
The Retina of an Owl's Eye Sensitive Equally in All Parts.
The Black Centre Is the Nerve-Feeding Blood Vessel.
No Place in the Air for Women
By Claude Grahame-White,
I HAVE taught many women to fly and
I regret it My. experience has taught
me that the air is no place for a
woman.
When calamity overtakes my women pu
pils, as sooner or later I fear it will, I
shall feel in a way responsible for their
sodden decease.
I have often taken ray. mother and my
sister in the air as passengers. They un
derstand aviation thoroughly. But I would
never let them fly alone.
The truth Is that women lack qualities
which make for safety in aviation. They
are temperamentally unfitted for the sport
Bravery and courage are not essential
in aviation. Supreme confidence in one's
self a Women may possess the former,
but they generally lack the latter Safety
in an areoplane depends upor absolute
coolness the facultj of rpj.1,1 j jurat-
the Leading English Aviator.
tied," If I may use the word, no matter
what happens. Men sometimes possess this
faculty, but It Is very rare In women.
Professor Hensingmuller may be correct
In his premises, but the conclusions he
draws from them are not sustainable.
Thus women may possesa a greater
range of vision than men, although I have
never heard the proposition advanced be
fore, but that will not make them better
aviators, for a greater range of vision is
not needed. The aviator has all he can do
to look straight ahead, and the power to
see further to the right and left would
prove at all serviceable.
Gusts of wind and currents aTe not vis
ible. As a matter of fact their presence
can usually be felt long before they affect
the planes. Woman's superior vision
would therefore be of no value to her In
that respect
It Is said also that women have greater
tuition than men. That may be so', but I
I.do not think that the kind of Intuition
they possess Jn such abundance would be
of any practical use in aviation.
Diffused attention, too, would be mtre
xof a handicap than an advantage. What
the aviator needs more than anything else
is the ability to concentrate his mind on his
levers.
It is true that women are lighter than
men. It is equally true, however, that
weight will be of no conseouence In the
aeroplane of the f utare, except perhaps that
the greater the weight the more effective
will be the aeroplane. The future aero
plane will be of steel wood and canvas
will be eliminated.
As far as woman's milder manner ot
sneezing Is concerned I cannot see how
that will be of advantage. In view of the
fact that, in my own experience, I have
never found It necessary to sneeze at all
while In the air.
I do not believe that aviation increases
the. tendency to sneeze, nor shouM I con
sider it of the slightest Importance even if
it did. It takes considerably more than a
sneeze to wreck an aeroplane, or even to
disconcert an aviator.
The sense of balance comes to the avia
tor naturally. One elevates or lowers his
planes almost Instinctively, the same as
one turns the handle-bars in bicycling or
varies the stroke in swimming or tennis.
In these instantaneous motions there Is no
time for consideration. Instinct takes the
place of foresight. I do not think that
women are better equipped in this respect
than men. t is rather a matter of experi
ence than natural fitness.
ftls true that with one or two excep
tions women aviators have so far escaped
serious accidents, it must be remembered
however, that their efforts have been con
fined exclusively to aerodrome flights
which is a very different proposition to
cross-country work and the hazardous
achievements undertaken by men.
When the airship becomes absolutely
safe, lis It will, women may make good
aviators, but they will never dominate the
air to the exclusion or iron uiv more than
they have domlna id an., utbei similar
sphere of activity
Mllll-Il Tnnmmi
B" mmm I j""", the
Mr.
Claude Grahame-White, Who Says Women Have No Place in the Air,
Taking up a Feminine Passenger
it may mean danger in a snddea
gust of wind to the aviator.
Diffused attention is the opposite
of concentration. Woman has the
first, man has the second. By dif
fused attention we mean the quality
of mind that can take in a number
of details at once. This is also x
prlmtlve Quality. The savage need
ed it while going through the
woods, and for the same reasons
that be needed peripheral sensi
tiveness of his retina.
Throughout the ages man has
steadily, single-mi&amp;dedly concen
trated upon a particular point
Woman's attention has been di
rected to her. babies, to the care of
them, to her household duties, to
the manifoI task of pleasing her
lord and master, and most of these
things she has had to consider
practically all at once.
The advantages of dtttassd atten.
tJon In flying are obvious. Where
the contour of the grooad, the an
pearance of the sky, the sound of
the motor, the "feeding" of the ma
chine, and a hundred other things,
must be taken into consideration
and weighed all at once. Only dif
fused attention of the most expert
kind can make a perfect aviator.
the birds. Her bones are lighter
and more hollow than those of maa.
Her specific gravity is less
As a rale, her sight is "better
She craves excitement, and has
more nervons endurance than man.
Watch the speed machines at your
parks the toboggans, the slides, eta
See the percentage of women to
men. Once she is assured that a
t5u,Ji,"'VBd lf te Wstkm
of speed, she becomes a speed
maniac It is woman who promote
man to go fast in his autos'SK
take her on the chute-the-chntes.
She has more intuttlon. Intuluoa
is nothing more than the powers
rapidly percelvta a number of
causes and Instantaneously synthe-
Hf A woma cannot do
this in abstract subjects, but to
crete subjects, in her surroundings
SS ""k 5f r faInd te oallow-b?t
JX eaects nunber of things
ed mind of man cannot Intuition
is an essential in aeroplanlng
Her skin and her nervoug system
are. as a rule, more susceptible to
rapid, warning atmospheric changes.
Religion has foreshadowed this by
picturing angels as feminine.
Some aviators have pointed out
that high altitudes and strong winds
create a tendency to sneeze, which
in many cases proves disastrous. It
Is well known that women sneeze In
a milder manner than men.' and Is
thl resnoor therefore, they have
another natural qualification for
aviation which men lack.
Better equipped naturally than
man for this new sphere, she must
eoiuuoB "Wire man out of It,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1913-04-13/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=Harriet+Quimby</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>July 2, 1911 :	Harriet Quimby joins the list of female aviators as the first licensed female pilot in America.</time>
        <text>TheO
maha Sunday Bee Magazine Page
Copyright 113, bjr tha Star Company, Great Drttaln ntRhta ReaerreO.
m
"WOMEN Will Rule the Air
s f
No. 1 The Skeleton of
the Bat., IlIunralnK the
QBadrupedil or "All
F"otiru" roaltlon of Firing.
The Primitive Tendency of
of Woman Ttmnrd That
Poaltlon Glrea Her One Ail
rnntnge Over Man In Ilun
nlng? the Aeroplane.
No. 2 The Skeleton of a
Knntcnrno. The Gigantic
I.eapN of Thla Animal Are
Made Poaalhle Largely by
Ita Combination of Up
right nnd All Foura Attl
tude a Poaltlon Into
Which Woman S t n k a
Naturally When Piloting
on Aeroplane.
No. 3 The Skeleton of a
Snnkr. The llrptllr, Al
though It Orliclnally
Sprung: from the Same An
ceator aa the Iilrd, Una a
Compactneaa of Skeletal
Strnoture Which Man
Bharea In a Leaatr Deirree
T hat Abanlutely For
bid It from Flylngr.
'No. 4 The Skeleton of
a lllrd. in I.lshtnraa of
Frame nnd Structure It
More Cloaely Ilearmlilra
the Skeletal Formation
of Women, Whoan Spc
clflc Gravity, the Sclen
.tlata flay, la Leas Than
Mau'a.
No. ft The Skeleton of
n Man. The Jlonra Aro
Heavier and More Com
pact Than That of
Woman. The Cheat la
Larger, Showing the
Need for More Air a
Matter of Importance In
Itartfled Atmoaphtrea,
No. 8 The Skeleton
of a Woman. The
8 1 1 g a t Differences
Between It and That
of the Man Glvea
Her an Eaormoua
Advantage and Pota
Her More on a Level
rrlth the Creaturea
That Fly Naturally,
Better Than Men for Flying Because They Are More Primitive, Not So High
Strung, Feel Pain Less, See More, HavelSJo Concentration, Sneeze Less
Heavily and Are Closer to the QuadrupedsClaims the French Government,
Making
Its Foremost
Woman
Aviator a
Chevalier
to Encourage
Others
Vlllo. Dutrieu, the Daring French
Woman Aviator, Who Has Been
Made a Chevalier pf the Legion of
Honor hy the French Government.
MLLH. HBLENB DUTRIEU, the "Hawk
Girl of Franco," has just been made
a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor
as a reward for her skill as an aviator. Mile.
Dutrieu Is one of few women to receive this
decoration.
France has g,lven it to her because the Bu
reau of War has become convinced that
women make better aviators than men, and
so, In Its struggle to perfect Its aeroplane
Bervlce, wishes to encourage women to enter
that field of action!
The great ambition of the French Is to keep
far ahead of all other nations In aviation.
The belief that the victories of the future
will 'belong to those who aro strongest In
the air has becomo firmly Ingrained in the
national mind. Therefore, France Is spend
ing more than any other nation on this
branch of service and is making extended
and varied researches into the problems and
possibilities of aviation. In the course of
these experiments, not long ago, a series of
tests were made to determine the effects of
altitude and speed on tho human body and to
test the reactions under the conditions of
flvlnit Both men and women were used in
the experiments, and when the results were
tallied It was found that the woman had far
outstripped the men on all Points'
Other experiments were made and the ex
perts in charge, as a result, have come to
the surprising conclusion that woman make
n much better aeroplane drivers than do
men that In the future she will literally rule
thThelr'report of the scientists to the -Var
Department, as cabled from Paris, gives eight
controlling factors for this supremacy:
First Because woman is more primitive
than man.
Second Her nerves are not so delicate,
and so she is less nervous.
Third she feels pain less than man does.
Fourth She needs less oxygen In her
br?fth The arc of her sight Is nearly double
that of man. A
Sixth She has tho faculty of "diffused at
tention," which man ordinarily lacks.
Seventh That her specific gravity Is less
than man's and that the slight differences
in her skeletel structure givo her an enor
mous advantage in the air over her heavier,
more compact mate.
Eighth That her sneeze is less violent.
Tho perfect aviator, says tho report, am
plifying these points, needs not nerve, but
comparative nervolcssnoss. The possession
of what is called "nerve" implies a psycho
logical conflict In which courage is continu
ally overcoming fear. The truly courageous
man is ho who fears something mightily, but
who goos on and fights in spite of his fear.
The man who "never knew what fear Is" Is
not truly courageous, In tho higher sense,
because It does not requlro courage to fight
something of which wo nro not afraid.
The "hlghor courage" is positively detri
mental to tho aviator, tho experimenters say,
because the psychological conflict between
"nerve" and fear uses up energy and koops
the aviator at a tension which does not al
low tho highest efficiency as a flier. Conse
quently, the typo that makes the perfect avi
ator is the one that is nerveless, who has no
conception of fear and faces tho perils of the
air courageously because ho does not recog
nize that there are any perils.
Woman, it was found, has this quality to
a surprising degree. She has It because she
Is still the primitive sex, has doveloped less
than man, not only physlologlqally, but psy
chologically. Back In a far distant age man and
woman were almost equally nerveless. But
man's activities caused him to acquire finer
and more delicate nerves. Ho has steadily
become more nervous and more sensitive to
pain. This incapacitates him for tho con
quest of the air, while woman's lack in these
respects fits her for it.
The comparative Insensibility to pain is
important because many an aviator has
dropped to death because tho stinging cold
of the upper altitudes has caused him, mo
mentarily, to lose control of his machine.
Again, in driving an aeroplane, the avi
ator's position is more nearly quadrupedal
than in any other form of locomotion. The
aviator almost literally flies on all fours. Ho
does this because ho can attain the best
balance in this position. Here the same
prlmltlveness which gives woman the lead
in nervelcssness also comes to her aid. Sho
is of structure more nearly the quadruped
than-1b man. It is more natural and easier
for her to drop on all fours and she can get
about more freely In that posture than man
A Photograph of
the Late Harriet
Quimby, the
Queen of Amer
ican Flying
Women and One
of the Very Few
Women to Lose
Their Lives in
Aviation. She Is
Shown Climbing
Into Her Aero
plane.
airship pilot than the breast of tho Missis
sippi is to the steamboat pilot and Mark
Twain has told of their complexities. The
peripheral sensitiveness of woman enables
her to see these signs whero man's concen-
can. Dr. Havelock Ellis makes the assertion trated sight misses them
that the realization that woman "is still an
atomically a quadruped Is the greatest sur
gical triumph of the nineteenth century." In
this connection he defended woman's use of
the corset, saying that it !s needed to keep
organs designed by nature for a horizontal
position, In a vertical one.
Man having learned what woman haB only
Imperfectly learned, to stand upright, needs
no corset. This quadrupedal tendency, to
gether with the fact that her bones aro
lighter and she has less specific gravity than
man, aids her In flying, as It does in swim
ming. When timidity does not restrain them
women are much better Bwlmmers than men.
The field of woman's sight is larger than
man's. The report states it thus: "The arc
of a woman's vision is nearly twice that of
man." In other words, while man, trained
to concentrate his sight upon one object, sees
with only a limited part, tho centre, of the
retina of his eye, woman, through centuries of
slde-glanclng habits, of looking, so to speak,
out of the tall of her eye, hw kept the faculty
of sight throughout tho periphery of her re
tina. While looking straight ahead she can
see what la happening at either side of her
and for a short distance behind her. This
power she shares with the savage and most
of the lower animals the rabbit and she be
ing about equal in this respect.
The faculty Is enormously valuable In tho
air. Graham-White, among others, has Bald
that it is of the utmost Importance to the
aviator to be able to see every change in the
skies above him and the land about him.
Trees moving in a breeze far to the left may
be a danger signal, which will mean disaster
to the airman it not heeded. So of changes
in clouds. The country under and the air
about are filled with more slcns to the perfect
In tho same way what the late great
psychologist, William James, called her,
"dispersed attention," helps her. Man's ad
vancement has developed in him a tremen
dous power of concentration. This his primi
tive spouse, or sister, lacks. Man concen
trates his attention. Woman scatters hers.
Man thinks of one thing at a time. Woman
tries to think of many things nt the samo
moment and succeeds. Tho span of conscious
ness Is wider in woman even if it Is .shallower.
Consuming less oxygen than man she 1b a
shallower breather she Is loss affecod by
the thin air of high altitudes.
For theao and other reasons cited In tho
remarkable statement by tho distinguished
New York, physician, Dr. A. Monao Lesser,
former chief surgeon of the lied Ctobh In tho
United States, and leader of tho Eed CroBS
forces in Cuba during the war with Spain,
tho French Army Department has ddtermlned
to recruit as many women as possible In Us
flying corps. A spoclal law will hava
to bo passed making them eligible to
army service.
Tho French aro tho most gallant ot
nations. But thoy repudiate the sug
gestion that they aro crowning women
queenB of the nlr to make up for tho
slight put upon them by art, which
never carved or painted a woman an
gel. Their course Is a sternly practical
one, thoy Bay, and Mile. Dutrleu's ele
vation to the ranks of a Chevalier la only
part of a practical campaign.
Dr. Lessor's statement follows:
Why HOME-LOVING Woman is the Best Air Woman
By Dr. A. Monae Lesser.
Former Chief Surgeon of the Ped Cross
of America.
THERE is truth in the contention that
woman because of her primitive
qualities may yet rule the air. But
tho type of woman who will do so is the
quiet, stay-at-home woman tho housekeeper,
housewife and mother.
That it should be she, the woman of the
hearth, Instead of the woman ot public ac
tion, is capable of Bclontlflc proof. Since
the dim ages of the world, when men and
women were of equal prlmltlveness, man
has developed far, and a penalty ot his
mighty concentration has been an acute ten
sion of the nervous system and a correspond
ing seusltiveneBs to pain.
If men were called upon to bear the pain
that i'j visited upon women, especially in
maternity, they would suffer doubly, and
many of them would die. Even lesser pains
ordinarily borne by women would send
them running about the house screaming.
They could not enduro what women bear
because women have a greater capacity for
suffering. All this is due to their: greater
nerve tension, which has come with their
greater advanco from prlmltlveness.
Tho greater nerve tension haB produced
a different kind of nerves. Scattered
through the membranes of their bodies are
nerves of a finer, more delicate order. Men
sneeze more violently than women because
in the membrane lining of the noao are a
finer grade of nerves, more delicate, moro
sensitive to intruding dust or to changes of
temperature.
The woman who has developed along
lines of domesticity has little or no such
nervous sensitiveness. Her sensibilities are
coarser, because they have never been de
veloped to the knlfo-llko edge of man's. It
is not, according to some aeronauts Claude
Graham White, I bellevo among them not
nerve, but lack of nervousness, that makes
great aeronauts, Nervousness during an
ascent Is fatal. That state which we term
"nervelessness," tho absence of finely attuned
nerves, is better than courage In an emer
gency. Imperturbability Is a safeguard, and the
woman of low order ot nervousness 1b im
purturbable.
One type of woman should be barred from
the air, and she, unfortunately, la the kind
that would rush Into it. That 1b the worn at.
who Is the opposite of the primitive the
advanced woman.
In the last hundred years a minority of
women has developed enormously in men
tality, and In tho ncuteness of nervous or
ganization that accompanies a high order of
mentality.
This minority of their sex has developed
with men, equally with them, and their
nerves have attenuated to the fineness I
have described. These are sterile women,
women who aro childless, and who have de
veloped almost abnormally their minds
Such as these, laboring under all the disa
bilities of men by the fineness of their
nervous organism, should never be permit
ted to make an ascent.
Take a woman from the nursery, from tho
Ironing table or from beside tho kitchen
range, but not a woman from tho desk or
studio, to make the conquest of the alrl
In such a woman as I first described the
primitive qualities have remained the
"peripheral visual attention" which William
James cites, the "dispersed attention." the
lack of necessity of the violent sneeze. The
other sort is too highly developed, too man
like, too highly strung for successful aer'V
feats,
Mr.. Gavin, an EnglUk Worn,
an 'Aviator to Whom EncIanJ
Will Givo Victoria Crow.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-07-07/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=air+flight+FLYING+flying+WOMEN+women</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>July 7, 1914 : Female Pilot, Mrs. Hornsby, argues that women should not fly.</time>
        <text>"FLYING NO JOB FOR WOMEN!" GREATEST
WOMAN FLYER SAYS SO
fi&amp;j i "j ?tvfr' jKLJ IS Mri
"Plying is no job for women and
never will be!
"Nature herself has forbidden
them to risk their lives foolishly in
the air. Through the mother in
stinct in them Nature will hold them
always close to mother earth."
It was one of the most expert of
the world's six licensed birdwomen
who, at my question, thus excluded'
the rest of her sex from participation
in the great air game of which she
herself is a master.
Mrs. Richberg Hornsby of Chicago
is the first and only pupil of Orville
Wright.
"The prettiest flying I ever saw. a
beginner do!" was Wright's exclama
tion, twice repeated, during "Mrs.
Hornsby's trials.
During the flight which has just
won her the license, her plane was</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1914-11-01/ed-1/?sp=51&amp;q=aviators+women&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.226,-0.073,1.452,1.452,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1914-10-02 : Suggestions for women aviators to participate in war made in England and France.</time>
        <text>Fighting Corps From the
Many Charming, Daring
and Skilled Flying
Women of
m England
ifc'i?
and
France
w I7*s*r
Lady Victoria Pery, the Prettiest
of the Bold English Airwomen
A London, Oct. 2."&gt;.
PROPOSAL lias been made to or
ganize a corps of women aviators
to servo with the allied armies of
England and Prance, now lighting the
Germans.
The idea Jsas oeon received with en
thusiasm by many women, who reject the
ancient theory of feiyinine weakness and
declare that their sex is fully as lit to t'aee
peril as the men.
The aviators have proved themselves
one of the most valuable factors in the
war. There is a great need of more of
them, and it* is impossible to train them in
a hurry. This Is one of the strongest
reasons urged in favor of using the many
skilled women aviators in the lighting.
The suggestion has actually appeared in
print that Lady Victoria May Pery, daugh
ter of the Earl of Limerick, i.hould become
chief of a British royal feminine flying
corps.
Lady Victoria is 0*e of the most dashing
jidJ certaluly the prettiest of English
women aviators. She was trained in avia
tion by Graharae White and the late, Gnstav
Hamel. in whoso company she "looped the
loop" in al most daring manner. Mantel
was eventually killed while doing this
trick.
It is not likely, however, that Lady Vic
toria will take the suggestion and join the
fighting aviation corps, for she has gone
to the United States and there become the
bride of Mr. James C. Brady. We have
probably not yet reached the point where
a bride will interrupt, her honeymoon to
go off to the war, aft^r the fashion of the
German submarine captain who left his
bride of the before to steam away and
blow up three British warships.
There are, however, plenty of English
women and French women without en
cumbrances who are ready to fight in the
air corps.
Why should not women serve as military
aviators? They have the courage and the
skill. They have the patriotism. If they
are inferior in weight ahd muscle to men,
these qualities are not of the first im
portance to the aviator. In steadiness and
nerve, which are the essential qualities in
the air, the modern girl claims to be fully
the equal of her brother.
?Is it contrary to the principles of civiliza
tion and humanity to expose gentle women
to physical hardships and the horrors of
war? This argument has largely been dis
posed of in recent discussions. Women are
employed in all sorts of occupations that
shorten and endanger life.
It has now been proved' that in every
war many women have fought, very'cred
itably, In spite of all rules against their par
ticipating. Many women took part in the
last. Balkan war, and it fs already certain
that a considerable number of French
women ere now fighting.
Women are freely risking their lives
with the Red Cross forces and as nurses
in other* organizations at the front. Many
W of these nurses have already been
killed, and there is little doubt that
oth??rK will be. N'o one seems to have
any strong objection to the employ
ment of women nurses at the front.
Tim prejudice is-not-against their
risking their lives, but against their
becoming combatants.
[?*rom all this It appears clear that If
conventional restrictions were removed
there would be a very great number of
effective women combatants.
And if they are to fight, why not in the
air. where their nerve and daring would
be of most value?
One of the most daring of women avia
tors is Mademoiselle Helene Dutrieu. of
France. She was the first woman to per-,
form the loop-the-loop trick, that "death
defying stunt that made men's blood stand
s;ill when they first saw a man do it
.Mademoiselle Dutrieu did it as coolly and
cleverly as any man.
.She is a tall, siender girl with an ex
quisite figure, as supplfc as a bamboo and
as strong as steel.
She,has carried a man passenger very
ot\en. and is therefore well qualified for
war aviation, in which two persons in a
machine are almost a necessity.
Mademoiselle Dutrit?V received the
Legion of Honor decoration for her ex
ploits. She would undoubtedly make a
daring leader of fighting aviators.
Among the many brilliant French air
women arr Madame Francis, Mademoiselle
Julienne Marehnl, the Baroness Raymonde
do la Roche, Mademoiselle Marvingt- and
Mademoiselle Valentine Duels.
The Baroness Raymonde de la Roche
started flying at Mourmejon and broke her.
arm in oye of her first flights, in Egypt
she flew over the Sphinx and the Pyramids.
At St. Petersburg she .flew over the city
anil was warmly congratulated by the Czar.
She flew over Budapest', in Hungary
In one of her first attempts she came
near having a faial accident, and many
people thought the experience would rob
her of her nerve completely. She was
t arried by the wind over a clump-of trees.
She did her best to avoid them with a swift
turn of the aeroplane rudder, but the ma
chine, rushing through the air at express
train speed, touohed the topmost branches,
and with a whirling crash it came sweep
ing to the ground and was wrecked irre
trievably.
Instantly the spectators rushed to the
spot, expecting to pick up the body of
the aviator, but the Baroness extricated
herself from the debris qtiiie unhurt and
not at all frightened. Indeed, she laughed
at the startled faces about Iter and said
calmly:
"An uncomfortable experience, it is true,
but I rather expected it."
The next day she was in the air again
with a new machine.
Mademoiselle Marvingt began her train
ing with two men, Wnchter and Laffont,
who were subsequently killed. This did
not daunt her, and she went, on and won
a cup for flying women.'
Miss Eleanor Trehawko Davies has the
reputation of being the i\ij&gt;st daring of
English aviatric.es. She has flown across
the 'English Channel several times.\On
one occasion, when crossing with Oust^v
Hamel, she saved them both by working
the second -pressure pump, when he was
partly benumbed with cold, at a height of
$,000 feet.
Phot o at Pa u c T t? s -v y.
Mile. Helene Dutrieu. -Who Looped-the-Loop, One of the
Most Daring of French Aviatrices.
Mrs. C?avin is anotner during Kngiisn
woman whe- has flown across tlie Chan
nel. She practised aviation In tlfe ]>art of
France where the war is now ragiug, ami
could give valuable assistance to thg/avmy.
Miss Spencer Kavanagh has aiso-dis
tinguished herself as an aviator. Miss
Kananagh has also been a sportswoman,
having hunted, broken horses, driven auto
mobiles in races and gone in for athletic
contests. She wished to learn to fly as
soon as it became known that it was a
possible achievement, and went to Pau, de
termined to master the art.
She tises the Bleriot monoplane, which
has been likened to a great dragon fly
when in flight. She has had some bad
accidents and was. laid up with a broken
wrist for a while. She lias learned to con
trol the machine now, and like other avia
tors she takes the dangers as part of the
game.
She is an attractive figure in her neat,
tight, red clotli skirt and flannel blouse,
with red cloth cap fastened under her chin,
after the fashion in which Mile. Dutrieu
wears hers.
Women who are learning to fly are
sometimes taught on a rather peculiar
Mrs. Gavin, an English
Woman, Who Has
Flown Across the Eng
lish Channel to France
and Back.
mechanism, which is arranged to operate
like tiiri aeroplane, but has no wings. It
has ail the controls like au aeroplaue
nud rims about on the ground like
an automobile. Uy permitting the pupil
to absorb the feel of riding in an
aeroplane it "is possible to save her some
bruises, perhaps broken bones ana costly
repairs to the flying machine. Every time
an aeroplane comes into unwilj' &gt;g col'
li.sion witli the ground the owner is poorer
by any sum ranging from $:?0o to $:!,000.
A French scientist. Dr. Babin, has re
The Baroness Iiaymonde de la Roche, One of the French Airwomen Who Wish
to Serve Their Country.
ceutly deinonstrated that woman is better
lilted for flying than man. for these rea
sons
First?Because woman is more primitive
than man.
Second?Her nerves are not so delicate,
and so she. is less nervous.
Third?she feels pain less than man
does.
Fourth?She needs less oxygen in-her
breathing.
Fifth?The arc of Iter sight is nearly
double that of man.
Sixth?She lias the faculty of "diffused
ntteutiou." which', man ordinarily lacks.
Seventh?That her specific gravity is
less than man's, and that the slight differ
ences in her skeletal,structure give Iter ai
enormous advantage in the tfir over her
.heavier, more compact mate.
Eighth?That her sneeze is less violent.
"The perfect aviator.*' says the doctor's
report, amplifying those points, "needs, not
nerve, but comparative nervelessness. The
possession of what is called 'norvo' implies
a psychological conflict in which courage
is continually overcoming fear. The truly
courageous man is lie who fears something
mightily, but who goes on and fights in
spite of his fear. The man* who 'never
know what fear is' is not truly courageous
in the higher sense, because it does not re
quire courage to fight, something of* which
we ?re not afraid.
"The 'higher courage.' is positively detri
mental to the aviator, because the psy
chological conflict between ?nerve" and fear
uses u| energy and keeps the aviator at a
tension which does not allow the highest
efficiency as a flier. Consequently tin; type
that uiakes the .perfect aviator is the one
that is nerveless, who has no conception
of fear, and faces the perils of tlic air
courageously because ho does not recog
nize that there are any perils.
?Woman has'this quality to a surprising
degree. She has it because she is still
Hie primitive sex, has doveloped less than,
man, not only physiologically, but psy
chologically. Hack in a far distant ago
man and woman were almost nerveless.
Uut mau'?s activities caused him to acquire
liner and more delicate nerves. He has
steadily become more* nervous and moro
sensitive to pain. This incapacitates liim
for the conquest of tho air. while woman's
?laclt in those respccts Ills lier for it.
'"The comparative insensibility to pain
is important, tor many an aviator has
dropped to deuiu because the stinging eold
of the upper altitudes had- caused him
momentarily to lose control of his machine.
"Again, in driving an aeroplane the avia
tor's ]K&gt;sition is more nearly quadrupedal
Mityi in any other form of locomotion. Q^ke
aviator almost literally Hies on all fours.
He does this because he can attain tho
best, balance in this position. Here^ihe
same primitiveness which gives woman
the lead in uervelessuess also comes, to
'her aid. She is of structure more nearly
the quadruped than is man. It is more
natural and easier tor her to drop on all
fours, and she can get about more freely
in i hat posture than man can."
A fearful prospect is thus sketched lor
ilie ordinary foot soldier tracked by a
hawk-like woman of the air.
Primitive, nerveless, quadrupedal ...in
structure, ignorant of danger and con
temptuous of the other sex, she planes
above him, ready to annihilate him, calmly
ami coldly, with high explosives or blaziug
gasoline! y</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1915-07-18/ed-1/?sp=33&amp;q=aeroplane+Moisant+MOISANT&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.255,0.598,0.401,0.453,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1915-07-18 : Ms Moissant Ura granted pilots license.</time>
        <text>MISS MOISANT ura the next American no.
man after her friend Miss Qiiimby to be
granted a pilot's license. She ascribes her gooil 1
t fortune in her flights to her lucky number 13,
i which is always attached to her machine. She
was taught to fly by her famous brother. Once
she escaped from an angry sheriff by aeroplane.
fust as Brave as Me]
Vk/
T3LAXCI1K STUART SCOTT'S excellent driving was first notice
when, as a motorist, she took a transcontinental trip in one of th
Glidden tours. She learned aviation at the Curtiss school, and made
record in a remarkable cross-country flight to Garden City, Long Islam
i, i in i
J
ttlfl H|
Copyright, li. V. Diuk.
pERNETTA ADAMS MILLER is a young
American pilot of the Moisant school, ana
flies a Bleriot type monoplane. There are now
about fifty women fliers, and their accident rate
has been no higher than that of men aviators.
Vf ATII.DE MOISANT was rescued from this burning
1 machine while flying at Wichita, Texas. This photograph,
the only one made of the accident, was taken by an
amateur.
fl
ie
rpHISu Mrs. Maw
^X J rjjf j"
machine that Mrs.
^ttj?, Hewlett has used a
/e^^. B great deal to demonstrate
her
PELTIER
was
woman
make an as
Dela^^^^HISRIr

fcy
j^V
I wine of his

1 1
IJARHIKT Ql'IMBY, journalist, uiitneuedan
aeroplane race for the first time in 1910.
-1 Two months later she was an efficient pilot. Miss
Quimby was the first American woman to receive
a pilot's license, the first to steer a monoplane.
and the first to cross the English Channel.
She met death in 1912 at Boston.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85059732/1915-08-01/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=aeroplane+crowd+death+Grand</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>August 1, 1915 : Helene Dutrieu is the first female air scout in the First World War.</time>
        <text>H?w the Daring
Oi ft J8 First Woman
tfj[ Belgium, Has
Aided in the Guarding of Paris by Night
and Day, and Three Times Was Able to
Give Warning of the Approach of the
Enemy?She Says: "The Man Who Wants
Me Must Catch Me in the Air."
Helena Dutrieu, Just Before Making One of Her
Sensational Flights.
HELENS DUTRIEU, the "Girl
Hawk," upon whom appre
ciative France has bestowed
the decoration of tht Legion of
Honor, Is surely one of the most
modest of heroines and Is less In
clined to dwell upon the fact that
she has the distinction of being the
first woman air scout In history than
?he Is to discuss generally the use
of the aeroplane In war.' She re
cently -was In this cfluntry In the
interests of the Red Cross, and Is
a sort of Elzevir edition of a flying
woman, being about only five feet
In height, even with the aid of her
dainty French heels, and weighing
about 1X0 pounds. She Is a girl In
vivacity and enthusiasms, and, ac
cording to one Impressionable wom
an visitor, "her mouth Is tilted In
an adorable childish fashion"?the
mouth that playfully uttered the
grim laconism In referring to avia
tion: "It is the sport of those who
would die young."
Mile. Dutrleu's complexion has
the exotic charm of a dead pallor,
which only goes to emphasize her
large and expressive oyei. You
might Justly mistake her for an
artist, a dreamer, poet, musician?
one who has spent the best mo
ments of her life amid intangible
beautiful Imaginings and exquisite
realities. Her well-formed hands,
with their tapering fingers, suggest
pretty sentiment, lace, perfume, ro
mance more than the tense, peril
ous work of guiding an aeroplane
through the blue seas of night high
abqye an anxious city.
An Unofficial Flyer
She Is not regularly enrolled In
the army, and, though she gladly
would die for her country, she has
no desire to become a soldier. That
the government receives her ser
vices unofficially gives her no of
fence at all. She fully agrees with
the Frenchman's point of view on
the sex question.
"He does not want his wife to
fight," she explains. "He will not
permit her life to be endangered.
He will not be responsible for her
death. Not that the French woman
Is not brave. All women are brave
when the lives of their dear ones
are threatened. But especially the
French woman. I think, for she is
more emotional. Ah, people now.
Just because of this war, are be
ginning to understand the character
of the French woman as she really
ts! All the fables of her lightness
In their true colors."
Gave Warning Thrice.
Mile. Dutrleu would make you
believe that some of the perils
through which she passed In times
of peace far overshadow thoso of
the war period, and laughs when
khe quotes a report that her duty
was to cnase away the raiding Ger
man taubes that dropped bombs
upon Paris. "All I did was to fly
up when I suspected that the Ger
man airmen were coming," she ex
plained, "and, then, if I observed
the enemy approaching, return and
report to the men, who immediately
rose to give battle or chase to the
Intruder."
When word was flashed to Paris,
Che boarded her aeroplane and took
to the skies, mounting in spirals
iilsfter and hlghc* until the plane
looked the size of a soaring dragou
fly. Then courageously would she
fly In the direction of the expectod
danger, circling round, rising and
descending with eyes kf-ou to the
Quest and nerves as steady as the
snetal of the mechanism that held
her afloat above the city. from the
streets of which thousands turned
their faces upward to watch, not
for the hostile taubes as much a3
to watch, adinlre and marvel at the
Intrepid "Girl Hawk."
Three times when the Germans
were advancing on Paris did she
give warning of their approach, her
swift monoplane affording her a
long advantage over the enemy.
"There was no danger," she says
simply. But there Is always danger
even the lay public knows, the fact
being emphasized by the peaceful
accident which ended the life of
the young Englishman, the first to
destroy a Zeppelin, who, after tak
ing part In the greatest of aerial
war achievements and escaping as
by a miracle, was dashed to death
when in the act of taking up an
American correspondent for an ex
hibition flight. Keen as are the
eyes of Mile. Dutrieu and skilled as
she is in the operation of her craft,
there was always the possibility of
sudden and unexpected onslaught
from the hostile craft; then there
was the peril which is always at
the elbow of those who adventure
Into the skies.
Bruges Chimed Her Honors.
She had already fallen from a
house during an accident in Odessa
and escaped without serious hurt.
Her monoplane had turned turtle
with her at Issy-les-Mollneaux and
she escaped only with a severe
shaking up, having been saved by
the upper stays of the machine.
She has had many another close
call. Always glad to escape the
discussion of the graver aspects of
the work, especially as it conce'rns
herself. Mile. Dutrieu very soberly
says that she felt one of the great
est elatlons c? her life when she
flew high above the historical belfry
of I-.es Halles at Bruges, celebrated
by Longfellow.
As the people wildly cheered In
the streets, the bells pealed out in
her honor whlJe she circled above
the structure and then flew back to
Ostend, carrying a passenger. But
no greater and yet scarcely justifled
apprehension did she ever reel,
looking into the face of danger and
sudden death, than that which
seized her when, on her arrival at
Ostend, she had to be protected
from a joyously hysterical crowd
bent on kissing and embracing her!
The record of this incident tells
us that: "The mayor and all the
officers of the city led In the shower
of congratulations that fell upon
Mile. Dutrieu. The men became
even more hysterical even than tho
women, gesticulating and shrieking
like mad?stirred to uncontrollable
laughter and tears, stretching their
hands toward her. Thus they
pressed around the girl and the
flying machine. And so she had to
be protected?so many desired to
kiss her."
She was the first woman to fly
Into Belgium. Two officers only
had done so before her. And over
the air lanes that she sailed in her
journey of a new achievement, now
speed swift, sinister things of the
air that spit singing death through
the void and on the earth below, or
drop thunderous destruction as
they pass swiftly through the night.
"Nervous?" she repeated the
query, smiled and was silent for a
moment. "My friend, one must
not be nervous la the upper air, or
one, will never go there again. The
true aviator must be without nerves.'
She'a a Homing Bird.
"Of course, I'd much rather fly
than vote," she continued; "though
you doubtless thluk it would be
well for a woman, having accom
plished the one thing to seek to
achieve the other. A woman may
rty a-id be at the same time a hom
ing bird by Instinct?this the view
as concerns myself, of course. You
"Then courageously would she fly in the direction of the expected danger, circling around, rising
and descending with eyes keen to the quest and nerves as steady as the metal mechanism that
held her afloat above the city."
see, therefore, I am not a suffra
gette. I think woman has all she
can do and all she should do, If she
is a home-maker and a good moth
er. And the French, husband thinks
so, too.
"As for voting, that would be an
Impossible situation in France.
The French women," and her
shapely hands fluttered prettily,
"are too emotional and excitable.
So, too. are our men. It can easily
be seea that they very likely would
become so excited over the issues
that life would be made utterly un
bearable."
The flrst woman air scout became
interested in flying about eight
years ago. and, noting her youthful
appearance now, one estimates that
the must have been a slip of a girl
when the fusillading motor sent th*
earth away from beneath her for
the llrst time. But what matters
the years? Mile. Dutrleu is still a
girl at hc-art nnd the tragedies of
which she has been a witness In
the army ambulance service, though
shadowing her speech and play of
facial expression at tim^s. canno*
Dr. L. Sarasln has succeeded, ac
cording: to La Nature, In making arti
ficial silk from the "slime" of the
seaweed which Is thrown up in im
mense masses on the coasts ot Nor
mandy. Norway, Scotland nnd Can
ada. An English company Is said to
bo exploiting the process, for which
a isrreat future Is prcdlctcd.
I i
Grand Admiral Princo Henry of
Prussia, the brother of the Kaiser,
who was the first royal nlrman, and
learned to fly when he was 49. hu3
become the flrst royal motion picture
operator.
Von Moltke, the grreat German gen
eral, would never begin a battle on
a Friday.
Helena Dutrieu, as She Looks in Street Garb.
divest her of that quality that
caused a sporting writer recently
to refer to her as "the captivating,
sky-flight kid."
Sky-flight scout, of course, would
have been a formal improvement;
but there is a certain element of
admiration and tribute in the sport

ing sharp's characterization?tho
very elements that have caused her
to receive many offers of marriage
and elicit this characteristic re
sponse from the first woman air
scout:
"The man who wants me mast
catch me In the air!"</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025316/1911-09-14/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=female+aviators</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>October 16, 1910	Women are becoming more frequent flyers</time>
        <text>SPORT OF AVIA IION
GETS WON
NUMEROUS FEMALE AVIATORS
ARE ENTERING FIELD FOR
MERLY HELD BY MEN.
New York, Sept. 13.-Although both
the Wright and C:urtiss schools
steadfastly refuse to teach feminine
pupils at any price, women are grad
ually forcing their way into the hIaz
ardous game of aviation and follow
ers of the sport are discussing with
interest today the report that Mrs.
Ralph Johnstone of Kansas City,
whose husband met death at Denver,
is soon coming to New York to master
the craft that widowed her. It is
understood she will take lessons at
the aviation colony on Long island
with a view to becoming a licensed
pirofessional aviator.
Today there are only two licensed
women aviators in this country-Miss
Matilda Molsant and Miss Harriet
Quilhby-hoth of whom are now on
Long Island. Blanchl Scott has made!
some noteworthy flights in Ohio, but
as yet has not obtained a license.
Miles Molsant, it will he recalled, took
up' aviation after the tragic death of
her brother, John Molsant, at New
Orleans, and in this respect her career
parallels Mrs. Johnstene's.
Flrance leads the world with more
than half a dozen prominent feminine
aviators and death has alfeady claimed
one of' them, Mine. Denise Moors.
'while the iiaroness Laroche, a flyer of
note, has been seriously injured. Only
yesterday in Prance Helena Datrap
flew more than 136 miles, estabhshlnlg
a record In the competition for the
WOml en's cup.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062169/1925-12-09/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=female+aviators&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.151,0.209,0.288,0.326,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>1925-12-09 : Plans for first aviation school for women proposed.</time>
        <text>Miss Kibe Shigepo, one of the few
female aviators of Japan, has asked
the government to aid her plan for
a flying school for women.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1916-12-08/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=female+aviators&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.006,0.377,0.131,0.148,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <time></time>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016758/1912-03-21/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=female+aviators&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.308,-0.081,1.616,1.616,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>December 15, 1911 :	Articles published about how women may make better pilots than men</time>
        <text>Mr. Bryan says he is not available.
Still, with a little repairing, it seems
that he might be able to run some yet.
Irish Standard.
William's mainspring appears to be
in good order, and the only thing
necessary, perhaps, to place him in
first-olass running condition is a lib
eral application of campaign oil to
the bearings of his other machinery.
A bill providing that free boxes be
furnished patrons of non-delivery
postoffices has been introduced in
eongress and it should become a law.
The fact that there is free delivery in
the larger cities and ID the rural dis
tricts shows plainly that persons liv
ing in small places are being discrim
inated againstit is a governmental
extortion which should be removed.
The "parachute" gown, which is no
more or less than a revivification of
the old-fashioned crinoline, or hoop
skirt, has made its appearance in
Chicago, and modistes say it will he
generally adopted in the course of a
year. As a safety device in this age
of airships it should prove a boon to
female aviators, who, in case of acci
dent, could jump from the machine
into space and sail gracefully to
earth.</text>
</result>
</results>
  </topic>
  </topics>