<topics>
<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-clara-h-barton</id>
    <results>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025287/1881-05-22/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>May 1881 : Clara Barton forms the first branch of the American Red Cross</time>
	<text>Miss Clara
Barton, prominently identified with sanitary
and hospital work during the civil war and
conspicuous during the Fninoo-Prus.-Un war,
as one of the red cross representatives,
read a piper showing the scope and efficiency
of the Red Cross societies in countries where
tbe order is recognized by government and ac
corded the powers and privileges which are
asked for it in the United States.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064205/1887-08-10/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>August 1887 :	President Cleveland appoints Clara Barton to represent the United States at the International Red Cross Conference in Germany.</time>
	<text>MISS UAKTONS AriOINTMKXT
Washington Aug Miss Clara
Barton president of the American
National Association of the Red Cross
and Dr J B Hubbell general agent and
secretary of the association have been
appointed by President CI vjlan dele
gates to represent the United States at
the fourth international conference of the
attend the Geneva conference in 1 4
the lirst international conference in
Red Cross to be held at the court of the
Grand Duke and Duchess of Baden
which opens at Cirlfiuhe Germany Sep
tember 22 This will be Miss Bartons
second errand to Europe as a Rd Cross
representative from this countrv having
which the United States was represented</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1889-06-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>BLNK</time>
	<text>Clara Barton of Washington the origi
nator of the well-known Red Cross corps nr-
rived hero this morning nnd will nt once assume
sumo charge of all the female relief corps.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1896-01-23/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>January 23, 1896 : Barton sails to Turkey to aid the victims of the Armenian massacre.</time>
	<text>MISS HARTOrf OFF FOR ARMENIA
With the Red Coa Fine FlantlnB from
the New Tort Mizzen Track
Miss Clara Barton President of the American
Tied Cross Society who Is going to try to take
charge of the distribution of American dona
tions for the relief of sufferers in Armenia ar
rived In this city nt 7 oclock yesterday morn
log from Washington She was met nt tho
station by a committee from the New York Red
Cross and escorted t Delmonlcos where n fare
well breakfast was given In her honor Mrs
Charles C Raymond President of the New
York Red Cross presided Those present were
tin P C Dennis Mrs C II H Cottrell the
Hon George C Barrett Gen and Mrs Olorov
icky Mr and Mrs Stephen E Iarton Miss
Myotls Barton Dr O Steger Mrs M W
Kraus Dr A tonne Lessor Medical Director
of the New York Red Cross and the other
members of the party who will accompany
itlss Barton on her foreign mission These are
George H Pullman financial agent Dr J I
Hubbell field surgeon Ernest Mason linguist
and Miss Lucy Graves secretary toMlss Barton
Mrs Raymond made a speech wishing Miss
Barton the successful accomplishment of the
object of her journey and a safe and quick re
turn Miss I Barton replied briefly and an
nounced her Intention of sending nt once to
this country for A competent corps of nurses
provided she Is l admitted to Armenia
After the breakfast the entire party left for
the American line pier to see Miss Barton safely
aboard the New York on which she suited at 11
clock Several newspaper men were awaiting
ber and In reply to their questions she said
I do not know that the Sublime Porte has
announced to the Turkish Minister at WashliiR
ton fund Its opposition t the distribution of this
tnd
fundDo
Do you mean to say then that you dont
believe that such announcement has been
made
made1s Barton replied laughingly I dont say
that You can say It If you want to I have no
definite plans I shall mature my plans ns I become
como more thoroughly acquainted with tho oh
tacles to be overcome I was asked to do this
work because her couldnt get any one else to
do II I am simply the agent for carrying out 0
great work I do not know the amount of tho
relief fund I am going to Armenia to care for
he sick and feed the hungry There Is no
bravado In my going abroad I am a simple
womanbent on ahumnno and difficult mission
Miss Barton expects to arrive In Constantino
ple In I about twentyone days Including short
stays nt nnl an and ileneva Immedi I
ately upon her arrival sue will confer with Min
sterTerrell l with 0 view to bringing the lion
poses ot her mission before the Sultan amid
securing the neeesarv permission for carrying
nits work I vvas said ypstenlay by those in
A position to know that Miss liarton now nas
50000 at her disposal and that moro will bo
forthcoming as soon as the attitude or the
Turkish Government toward tho movement becomes
comes settled
eelte
Many telegrams and floral tributes awaited
Hiss Barton aboard the New York One of the
alter came from the Armenians of this city As I
the big liner moved out into tho stream the tai
of the Red Cross Society floated at the inlzzen
truck nnd Capt Orant said that It should stay
here nil the way across the ocean
Before leaving Washington Miss Barton had
an Interview with Cardinal Sntolll who gave
her n letter to the Oran Patrlnrch ni Constantinople

Inoplc who U I said to be quite Intimate with I
the Sultan Miss Barton hopes that the letter
will prove a valuable means of securing recog
nition by the ulan
WARIIISOTOX Inn 2The following Is the
official announcement of the Red Cross on the
lepnrturoof Miss Clara Burton and a part of 1
he staff today for Europe
In accordance with its undcrntnndlnc with the Na
tional Armenian lUllef Committee of Xew York n1 I
the Armenian Relief romialttees of llmtoti arid Wor
ester the American National lied Cross starts toslny
for Turkey 10 lnv tlmti on the spot and ileteniilan
whether or not II will he able to distribute loC r
monu the nufTerera from famine want and fclcLiiem
BOc
in different sections of Turkey
As we never solicit funds for our work the above
named Armenian Hellef Committee fat whits soil
citation the Hoc Cross han responnedl have undi
taken the ralsnic of funds and supplies which will I
utilized b us
In ease It is I found Impracticable orlmposslhlefor
U is to adequately distribute the relief we will jots is I
he several cnmmtttfcs and other existing tiirenc let I
wii If Used 00 that all contributors may be mcureit I
hat motley and material given by them wilt reach
the sufferers
Thn lied Cross will be In constant communication
with these committees I who will I inuke renortfi lo tho
public I from tint to time of the progress or mir ol
In itt mean lime all funds should IMJ sent In MrKtirft
Irow n Pro I Co New York Ilo lnn and I Plilladt1
phis lo lip placed to mite credit of Cite Armenian relief
fund or to inn American I National lied Crns
CUIIA IURTOS President Am a Keel Cross
JTILL THE KULTAX ADMIT HER I
Krrbrt to Opt n Permit for the Red Cross
Hnclety to Enter Anntolln
CONSTANTINOPLE Jan 22 Minister Terrell 1
rays that he does not desire to make any state
ment In regard 10 the prohnblllty of thin Sultan
consenting to Miss Clara Bartons I proposed dis
tribution of relief among tint Armenians in
Asia Minor I Is learned from other sources
that Mr rell Is making earnest efforts both
at the palace anti the Porte tn secure tho ad 1
mission of tho lied Cross Society Into Aimtollu
with full permission to supply the needs ot thu
tarvlng Armenians</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-01-15/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>April 11, 1898 :	Barton sets off to Cuba to help the injured during the Cuban insurrection.</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON DESCRIBES THE RED CROSS WORK IN CUBA
In Her Forthcoming Book She Will Tell Ail About the Horrors of the Cuban Campaign as She and Her Assistants Saw It, and Wall Score the War Department.
IN her forthcoming book on the history of the Red Cross So
ciety, a review of whose preliminary chapters has already ap
peared in the New York Sunday Herald, Miss Clara Barton will
give to the world a thrilling— almost a grewsome— narrative
of official mismanagement. Through the courtesy of the pub
lishers the advance sheets of those newer portions of the work
that deal with the Cuban campaign are here reviewed. The state
ments are Miss Barton's, and will appear over her own name in
the volume to be issued next month.
It must remain for the War Investigation Commission to lay
the blame for the shameful mismanagement she describes on the
proper shoulders. Every candid reader will rise from the perusal
of the book with the fixed impression that had it nut been for the
aid cheerfully extended by the Red Cross and grudgingly accepted
by the military authorities, the loss of life and health at Siboney
and Santiago would have been well nigh unparalleled in the history
of modern warfare.
The publishers of the book are the American National Red
Cross at Washington, D. C.
IN reviewing Miss Barton's forth
coming book I must necessarily
pass over much that is Interesting
about the beginning of the Red
18 campaign in Cuba and the
official stumbling blocks placed in the
society's way, and come down to the
.Bltuatij-in just previous to the destruc
tion of the Maine. At this time Miss
■Barton was already well established in
r.Cuba, and was dispensing relief at
■-Ceno, a suburb &lt;.f Havana.
Explosion of the Maine.
It. was before this good work was well
In-hand that the explosion of the Maine
■'occurred. Miss Barton describes how;
on th/&gt; memorable February 15. the
clerical work to be dono was so heavy
..that it kept herself and Mr. Elwell, her
.'lnterpreter and secretary, busy at
tjieir writing table until late at nicht.
"The house had grown still, the
'ibises' on the streets were dying away,
..'When suddenly the table shook from
xinder -our hands, the great glass door
on the veranda, facing the
i-^a, flew open; everything in the room
was In motion or out of place, the
deadening roar of such a buret of
thunder as, perhaps, one never heard
lpefore, and off to the right, out over
the bay, the air waa filled .-with a blaze
THE CALL Sunday Edition.
of light,' and this, in turn, filled witn
black specks like huge epeters flying
in all directions.
"Then it faded away. The bells ran*,
the whistles blew and voices In the
street were heard for a moment. Then
all was quiet again. I supposed it to
be the bursting of some mammoth mor
tar or explosion of some magazine. A
few hours later came the terrible news
of the Maine."
Some forty of the wounded were
brought ashore and placed in the Span
ish hospital of San Ambrosio. All the
jni'mbers of the Red -ross hurried to
th ir relief.

Upon the advice of the Consul Gen
eral at Havana the lied Cross retired
when the President recalled all Ameri
cans home. The day before they ]*-f t
Cuba the Archbishop of Havana pub
licly blessed the Lee Orphanage in the
presence of a large crowd. In the eyes
Of nil Catholics, Cuban and Spanish
alike, this blessing was a symbol of
protection by the church and a warrant
of success. Hence Miss Barton was not
surprised to lea-rn several months after
the war had begun that the Spanish
authorities had not only taken the most
scrupulous care of the hospital, but
had also placed a guard around her
former private residence.
Return to Key Weet.
On April 11, 1898, Miss Barton and her
staff! boarded the ship Olivette and after
a great deal of discomfort caused by
overcrowding of passengt s and stormy
weather, reached Tampa, Fla., two daya
later. Leaving the rest of the party at
Tampa, Miss Barton proceeded to
Washington with Drs. Hubbell and
Egan. The Red Cross agents left in
Florida found work enoug-h to hand in
looking after the 1500 Cuban refugees In
Tampa and the 800 or 900 in Key West.
These people were almost entirely de
pendent for a period of some seven
months upon the good offices of the Red
Cross agents.
In the meantime Miss Barton, in
Washington, also had her hands full.
Early in April it had been decided by
the Cuban Relief Committee in New
York to charter a steamer in that port,
load her with supplies and send her
to different ports in Cuba, where her
cargo could be unloaded in such quanti
ties as might be required.
The steamer Btate of Texas was ac
cordingly selected. Notwithstanding the
departure of the Red Cross party from
Havana and the subsequent declaration
of war with Spain the preparations
were kept up and the steamer was load
ed with a cargo embracing a fine as
sortment of necessaries and delicacies,
medicine and other hospital stores. She
arrived at Key West on April 28, and
was met by Miss Barton, who had come
down from Washington, and all the
Red Cross assistants who had been left
in Tampa.
Key West at that time was a very
busy place, the harbor being filled with
naval vessels which came in daily from
the Cuban blockade squadron for coal
and provisions. There was scarecly
a day that some accident did not hap
pen to sailor or workman. The Red
Cross doctors were at all times in de
mand. In order to keep every one in
the best preparation for possible con
tingencies those on board the State of
Texas were instructed and drilled in
the various phases of their particular
work, and at all times of the day the
Red Cross boat, with its well known
flag floating, could be seen going from
one transport to another on Its errand
of mercy.
Prisoners Left to Starve.
There were other charities which
clamored for the attention of the Red
Crocs officials. Scarcely a day passed
that Borne of the blockading squadron
did not bring into Key West from one
to three captured prizes— ships, schoon
ers, steamers or fishing smacks. With
in a couple of weeks after the declara
tion of war there were between thirty
and forty of these boats lying at an
chor in the harbor with their crews
aboard under guard. Somehow it was
forgotten these poor foreigners must
eat to live! Or perhaps somebody
thought that somebody else was re
sponsible for this very important mat
ter.
At all events, when the small amount
of provisions aboard the boats at the
time of capture had been exhausted,
calls were made on the United States
Marshal for additional food. Having
no contingent fund upon which to draw,
and knowing the quantities of red tape
that must be unraveled before he could
SAN FRANCISCO, SUNDAY, JANUARY 15, 1899.
secure any relief, the Marshal came
to Miss Barton with his troubles. That
good lady reassured him by promising
to provide for all the prisoners until
such time as he could Ret his petition
through the circumlocution office.' Sev
eral boatloads of provisions were hasti
ly gathered and taken in tow by a
steam launch, which landed them
alongside of each prize.
Miss Barton visited every boat in per
son, learned the wants of the crews
through an Interpreter, and not only
supplied all needed foods, but ar
ranged to take all letters and forward
them to their destination through the
intermediary offices of the Red Cross at
Portugal.
Could Not Reach Reconcentrados.
On.' June 20, everything being in read-*
mess, and no disapproval having been
elicited from the Navy Department, it
was decided to sail and find Sampson's
fleet near Santiago de Cuba, Here it
was generally believed that General
Shafter would try to effect a landing.
On the 25th the State of Texas arrived
off Morro. Castle, at the entrance of
Santiago Bay. The Spanish flag was
flying over the land fortifications and
Sampson's fleet was stationed in the
adjacent waters.
Miss Barton sent a 'representative
aboard I the flagship New York asking
Rear Admiral Sampson for instructions.
Word was returned that General Sh.af
ter's army had disembarked at Bai
quiri, a point about twelve miles east
if Morro Castle. The admiral advised
Miss Barton to take her ship to Guan
tanamo.Bay, where she would find good
anchorage and calm water, and where
she would be able to learn more of
ivhat was taking v place on land, as
there was constant communication
from there with the invading army.
rho Texas accordingly drew away and
irrived that evening at Playa del Este,
lust inside the mouth of Guantanamo
F3ay and some forty miles from Santi
igo.
Here two reporters from New York
japers called. on Miss; Barton, inform
ng her that' they had Just come in
Crom Siboney, where there was great
leed of supplies and medical aid. They
old how, many of the wounded in the
Ight between the Rough Riders and the
Spaniards, on the previous Friday, had
iust been brought in and were suffer
ng from lack of everything in the way
if comfort and conveniences. The
steamer was at once headed westward
md started to the scene of suffering,
which she reached at 8 o'clock.
A party of doctors accomplished a
difficult 'landing' in an open boat and
found their way to the army hospital.
This was a rough wooden building
which had evidently been used for a
store and warehouse in more peaceful
times. The surgeon in charge, Major
Havard, stepped forward to greet the
visitors, who formally offered him. in
the name of Clara Barton and the Red
Cross, the personal; services of all their
doctors and nurses and any of their
supplies that might be needed. These
were courteously refused. Major Hav
ard thought that .he and his assistants
would be able to take care of all the
3ick and wounded, and, as for supplies,
lie knew that there was an abundance
of them on the transports, which he
hoped would be landed next day.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1900-09-17/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>BLNK</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON
IN GALVESTON
Red Cross President Horrified at the Awful
ScenesPraise for the World
ffUI t TT Ftltfil well i
tUIVBSfiX nnpr IMU tarn
Pnrlili Iriiirlini a qv Nllon Hnl
Irati rimlPit wit hoe rhnllP n the
iippllf ihi ti e print MrwnrilNl h
all Th Worlil Miff irMnf Attired
lyre till morIn will her urt Hhr
PO reNvel I MAIOr Jonni and wtlh
nlm umln K nmr of inni tlnn nl the
city
tiro llnrlon haA ben the rfrlpliit nf
ollltUI ittrntlon lnr lifmrrlvil H
llninlon Miir ilrarhner woe III
having nurciunli In Ihr trin of eA
crrell work hot ctlnir Mnyor I I
Taffy Ant in oflklnl rnfilliiltli rrprr
imllnr the muiuclpiilll nut tun rfikf
noelttlri to fret her nl the IliiUliln
Homo AAA named Mr IMrr Chilintri
tu iron Mill lUrton And ultft t tai
vmlon
Mar ntrton MJd to Thf World eorr
tion lent who unterrtt Ultrilon with
her patlr What I hate iwn Pled
what I hA t Urn ltd to unilclpilit from
the Tf roporli It II mirvfllnni in
twhnld how the city hu lUtvUrl the
dlllrr Thin li in linmtiu ninmini
of work to be don her The up
pile i that arrived htte on Thr World I
rlltt tralnn An Jut whet ire nr dil
And UAJnr Jonn wan ddlihlnl III hcnr
thai a Nw York firm mti IIrlloIIIIK
Ilvi IhoUMtid iilKini of dlnlnfrctlnK
iluli on a World rtlltf Itlill now epeMI
Inr toward this city
nom what I iw In lloutton and
hen todny I Thank tod that I hn
jn ptnnlllf to come to the tnicu
or thai Afflicted people
lln lUrlon and hr tuff whit Arc
lout aitabllalilni a r lltf depot al over
tof the dlitrlbuUim uf Th Viirlila rr
Itf tiljipllaa</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1902-08-06/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>August 06, 1902 : Carla Barton attends the Internaional Red Cross Conferenece as representative of the USA.</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON HOME FROM
RTTSSIA TELLS OF THE CZAR
e
I Great White Monarch
Rcfus vf to Let Bene
facto of the Worlds
Sold crs Bow to Kiss
i His Tand but Shook
Hers Instead
I
Miss Clara Barton the Pre ucnt of
the American Red Cross frcreiy arrl d
In Hoboken today on the Hamburg
American liner Pennsylvania She had
been to the qulntehnlnl conference off
the International ned Cross Association
I t and was full of cnthuslaim about It On
the boat nlfo were Mrs Harriet Hubbard
Ayer and her daughter Miss Margaret
f
Ayer who has been flnlihlnc her mu
r sical education abroad
S 4 Fifty nations were represented said
Mlis Barton by the hundred delegates
to the conference I was treated with
suchgreat kindness that I can hardly
find words to express my appreciation
The Czar personally decorated me
with the highest order with which he
can honor any one not of royal blood a
decoration which he has bestowed upon
I
many of the crowned heads of Europe
I was entertained In the royal palsccn
of Russia and the Imperial railway
trains were placed at my dlaposal
CaRr Doa to Her Honor
B F TJIIln hart another Red Cross
delegate spoke up
When Miss Barton was presented to
the Czar he said she bent to kiss
I I the monarchs hand as Is the custom
but the great white Czar drew back and
f said No not you Miss Barton and
shook her hand Instead Her whole tour
through Russia was a triumphal Journey
for this worldpopular woman
I was very much Impressed sold
Miss Barton with the Czars earnest
ness for desiring universal peace and to
I
assuage the horrors of war
Standing on the pier this aged om
I an hale and hearty despite her Ions
i years of beneficent service looked as
hale and hearty as a woman half her
age She was the centre of a throne
of steamer friends eager to speak to
her once more before leaving
Wore Armenian Decoration
She wore a green dress and a green
and red plaid shawl clasped with her
Armenian decoration which she prizes
very highly</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045555/1904-03-26/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time></time>
	<text>It may bo re
marked In passing that America was
not one of the original signatory pow
ers cither but It was through Clara
Barton ihe head of the American so
ciety In niter year that the victims of
natural calamities Biich ns earthquakes
and llooclc wero added as subjectH ot
Hell Cross work Incidentally Hnssla
was also concerned In this but ns a
recipient At tho time of tho great
Russian famine Miss Ilarlon under
this very provision organized mlpslon
of mercy that pained the undying grat
itude nf the Slav empire</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1904-05-15/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>May 14, 1904 : Barton retires after serving twenty three years as president of the Red Cross Society.</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON BARTON BARYON
RETIRING PRESIDENT OF RED CROSS CROSSMiss CROSSMiss CROSSMiss
Miss Barton for twentythree years was president of the society societyand societyand societyand
and gave to it the qualities of a vigoious and notable notablepersnaU notablepersnaUMrs personality personalityMrs personalityMrs
Mrs John A Logan chosen as vice president a year ye r2gO ago succeeds Miss MissBarton MissI MissBarton
I Barton as head of the Red Cross Society
HAS R SNtW NE HEA HEAl HEAD HEADMis l
1 1Ils
Mrs Ils Logan Log n Succeeds Miss MissClara MissClara
i Clara BartonEXECUTIVE Barton BartonEXECUTIVE DartonEXECUTIVE
EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE ACTS ACTSFormer ACTSFormer ACTSFormer
Former President PresicfentResignsVice Resigns ResignsVice Vice Presi Presii President
i dent d nt Is Chosen foFillVacanCY foFillVacanCYLetter to o Till 7ilf Vacancy VacancyLetter VacancyLetter
Letter and Memorial MemorialMiss MemorialMiss MemorialMiss

Miss Bartons Bart reslgnatlonpf r resignation slgno onpt of the presi presidency presidency presidency
dency dency of the American Amer cim lied Cross yes yesterday yestCrday es est
terday t rc ny andthe and andthoehctlon the election of Mrs John A ALogan ALogan j
Logan to the head he d of the society were werenot werenot j
not steps toward the reorganization of ofthe ofthe ofthe
the society on compromise lines sug suggested suggested suggested
gested by Gen JohnW John W Foster FpsterMrs F FosterMrs ster sterMrs
Mrs Logan denies denl s that she has had hadany hadany hadany
any official notification of the th Foster Fosterplan FosterpIAn Fosterplan
plan for reorganization which was laid laidj laldbetore laidbefore
j before the Red Cross Investigating com committee commlttee committee
mittee of which Senator Proctor Is Ischairman Ischairman ischairman
chairman The TheremonaWants remonstrants r monJtran1 who forced forcedthe torcedi forcedthe
i the investigation had nothing to to do with withthe withthee
i the advancement of Mrs Logan to the thepresidency thepresldenc thepresidency
presidency presldenc and say they will not sup support support
I port the society societywhile while It operates under underits underi underits
i its present constitution constltutlonand and bylaws bylawsConsequently bYlawsConsequently bylawsConsequently
Consequently the changes brought broughtabout broughtabout
I about In the organization yesterday by bythe bythe bythe
the Barton followers will have no effect ef effect
I fect on the controversy controe y between the two twofactions twoI twofactions
I factions of the tlffisoclcty society While Miss MissBarton MissJ MissBartonV
J Barton arton and her hersupporers supporters supprers allege that thatthey thatI thatthey
I they acted In the hope of restoring restoringharmony restoringharmcn restoringharmony
harmony harmcn it Is Intimated by the he remon remonstrants remonstrants rernonstrants
strants that the Barton faction brought broughtabout broughtaboutn broughtabout
about aboutn a change hang in tha th head hoadot of the Rod RodCross RodI RqdCross
I Cross in the hope of heading headlngoitf1rthor headlngoitf1rthori off further furtherInvestigation furthorinvestigation
i Investigation Im cstlgatlon of the finances ftnancesof of the socioty so soclety 50clety
clety V
Conference With Committee CommitteeImmediately CommitteeImmediately CommitteeImmediately
Immediately Immediately after Mrs frs Logan was
elected to the presidency of the organl organlzatlori organlzatIon organization
zatIon yesterday she held a conference conferencewith conC conferencewith renae renaewith
with the members of the executive ex c1tlve com committee aommlttce com committee
mittee Gen Nelson A Miles Eugene B BFlak BFisk BFisk
Fisk S S Hege and S W Y Briggs at atwhich ntwhich atwhich
which it was decided that a meeting of ofthe orthe ofthe
the full board of trustees shall be held heldon he holdon tl tlon
on May 2C 2 when the policy of the new newadministration newadministration newadministration
administration will be outlined It is issaid Issaid issaid
said that Miss Barton will win attend nttt nd that thatmeeting thatmeeting thatmeeting
meeting and transfer all the assets and andpapers andpI andpapers
papers pI tS of the society to Mrs Logan LoganA
A meeting Of the full society secI ty will also alsobe alsobe alsobe
be called for September 6 at which no noproxies noproxies noproxies
proxies will be b accepted The nnnounce announcement nnnouncerncnt nnnouncementthat
ment mentthat that proxies will not be beacccptod accepted la laespecially IJ3cspeclaJ1 isespecially
especially significant 1 as too tootJce free a use useqf UseQC useQf
qf them at tho annual meeting of the thesociety thesociety thesociety
society two years Qars ago provoked the thestorm thetorm thestorm
storm torm which whlC i1 caused the remonstrants remonstrantsto r monstrnntsto
to secede and force an Investigation of ofRed ofRed ofRed
Red Cross methods methodsWant methodsWant methodsWant
Want the Investigation InvestigationMiss InvcstigationMlss InvestigationMiss
Miss Mabel T Boardman and other otherremonstrants othorlemonstrants othertemonstrants
remonstrants who were wer sfeon tico1l last st night nightsay night3ay nightsay
say they will not agree to any compro compromise compromise compromise
mise measure which provides pr ldestor for a less lessthorough lessthorough lessthorough
thorough reorganization than thanth that t sug suggested suggested 5uggested
gested by Gen John W Foster Ac According 4ccording According
cording to his plan the society would wouldhave wouldhavc wouldhave
have a governing board boar of twelve tolv mem members membC1rs mombers
bers four fouro of whom would be named by byPresident byPresident byPresident
President Roosevelt Roos eltf four by Miss Bar Bartons BartOJ1S Bartops
tons supporters supporters and four by the reraon reraonstranjs re remonstrnnts on onstran
stranjs stranjsIn stran strnntsIn s sIn
In the t e presence pr sonce of tho executive com committee COnmlttee conltnittee
mittee of ot the thQROd Rod Cross Cross Miss Barton Barton</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1904-05-20/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Clara+Barton</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>May 14, 1904 : Barton retires after serving twenty three years as president of the Red Cross Society.</time>
	<text>MAKES MAKESANSER MAKESANSERS MAKESANSERTO ANSWER ANSWERTO S
TO REMONSTRANTS REMONSTRANTSlriend
Friend of Miss liss Barton Pre Prepares Prc1areS Prepares
pares 1areS Statement StatementWELL StntpluelltWELL State1llentWELL
WELL QUALIFIED TO SPEAK SPEAKJaact SPEAKJanet SPEAKJanet
Janet Jennings for Twenty Years As Associated Ass Asdated
sociated s dated atcd in the Work With WithMiss With3liss ith ithMiss
Miss Barton BartonFrom BartonFrom BartonFrom
From the inception of the move on onthe onthe onthe
the part of the remonstrants in tho thoAmerican thoAmerican theAmerican
American American Red Cross Society Soclel to effect a acomplete acomplete acomplete
complete reorganization of that body bodyClara bodyClara bodyClara
Clara Barton tho executive and chief chieffigure chloffigure chieffigure
figure of tho Institution has steadfastly steadfastlyrefused steadfastlyreCused stendfaatlyrefu
refused refu ed to mako any public statement statementconcerning alatementneernlng atatementcencerning
concerning neernlng It ItNow itNow L Low
Now ow that Miss Barton has resigned resignedhowever resIgnedhowever resignedhowever
however one of her associates AS oclates in the thework thoark thework
work ark for the past twenty years e rs has hasprepared hasJJrepnrld hasprepared
prepared an answer to the charges of ofthe oftht ofth
the th remonstrants That friend Is IsJanet IsJmet IsJanet
Janet Jennings a coworker in the Red RedCross RedCr08S RedCross
Cross with Miss Barton and her aide in inCuba InCuba inCuba
Cuba Her statement is as follows followsFor followsFor followsFor
For some years eArs Miss Barton as well wellknown wellknown ell ellknown
known desired to retire from the presi presidency pres presidency 1 1tncy
dency tncy of the Red Cross Sho had plans plansfor plansCer plansicr
for work that she believed would be bemore bemore bemere
more valuable to the cause than her herservice herrvlcc herservice
service rvlcc as president Again and again againduring againdurllg againduring
during tho past two years she has been beenheld beenhe1t beenheld
held resolutely back h ck by b friends who re refused refusro refused
fused to believe that her resignation resignationwould 1esignatIonwould oslgnaUonwould
would relieve the society soclet from further furtherdifferences turtherasrrertnces furtherdifferences
differences which of late have been In Ineffect Ineffect ineIeet
effect a personal attack on the president presidentof
of the Red Cross CrossMiss CrossMiss CrossMiss
Miss Bartons friends declared they theywould th theywould y ywould
would stand pat to the bitter end or orgo orgo orgo
go out with her She would not permit permitthem permitthem permitthem
them to do do cither The vice president presidentshe presidentshe presidentshe
she said as provided for in the bylaws bylawsshould b3lawsshould bylawsshould
should take her place and the organiza organization organization organization
tion would remain Intact until the an annual annual annual
nual meetinsr meeUn next January JanuRr when of officers otficers offleers
ficers will be elected The organization organizationshould organizationshould organizationshould
should not suffer another day from a apersecution n1eISecutlon apersecution
persecution directed at her through the thesociety thesodet thesociety
society sodet If the methods adopted by bythose b3tho bythose
those tho seeking to break up the Red Cross Crossare CrOSare Cressare
are to go on then the organization organizationshould organizationshould organizationshould
should be saved and she would stand standout standout standout
out alone In the open and give them a aclear aclear aclear
clear field before bbfore the American people peopleMiss peopltMias peopleMiss
Miss Barton had her way The vice vicepresident vicepresident Ice Icepresident
president became the acting president presidentthe presidentthe presidentthe
the moment Miss Bartons resignation resignationwas re Jgnatlon JgnatlonWas
was accepted by the executive commit committee committee committee
tee which alone had the power to accept acceptit
it as in the absence of a session of the theboard theboard theboard
board of trustees the executive com committee commltteehas cornrnittec
mittee mltteehas has all the powers of the full fullboard tullboard fullboard
board
What Will Miss Barton Do DoAnd DoAnd DoAnd
And now what will the expresident of ofthe ofthe orthe
the American National Red Cross do doWhat dohat doWhat
What hat will she not do She will never nevermake nevermake nevermake
make any an reply to her friend the ene enemy enemy onemy
my She will will never make any an defense defenseof defenseof defenseof
of her life to the American people who whohave whohae whohare
have never asked it and never desired do lred it itShe ItShe itShe
She will hold to her first decision never neverto neverto neverto
to be Interviewed on the events of ofthe ofthe ofthe
the past two years though appreciative appreciativeand
and grateful for every kind word in the thepress thepress thepress
press Nobody Nobod has ever heard her speak speaka
a retaliatory word wordno no criticism crltlclsmonly crltlclsmonlysilence criticismonlysilence only onlysilence
silence and suffering in agony of mind mindsuch mtncIsuch mindsuch
such as an oversensitive rotlcont proud proudnature proul1nllture proudnature
nature Is capable of ofLet ofLet ofLet
Let us hope that this cessation CC84atlonthe CC84atlonthefirst cessationthefirst the thefirst
first In twentyfive years yearswill ear8wlJl will enable enableher enableher enableher
her to leave to the world some record recordof rocordof recordof
of a 3 most remarkable life Who so sowell sowelJ sowell
well as herself could give this as a alast a1Mt aIaRt
last word ord to the people and the country countryshe oountryshe countryshe
she has so Iqng and faithfully served servedIt BenedIt servedIt
It will be interesting on the other otherhand otherhand otherhand
hand to know what the Remonstrants Remonstrantswill Remonstrantswill Remonstrantswill
will do Will 111 they th go on aTkl a1 d continue continuethe contlnuthe continuethe
the persecution pers uUan of Clara Baron through throughthe throughthe throughthe
the few short years that may be left leftto leftto leftto
to her Or will they now call a halt haltand haltand haltand
and bring their efforts to bear on the thecomplete thecomplete thecomplete
complete reorganization they have havepersistently haepersistently havepersistently
persistently demanded demandedIn In the face 6 6the bthe bf bfthe
the fact that never n ver er in its history has hasthe hasthe hasthe
the American National Red Cross had hatso hadso
so able a management so fine a per personnel personnlI personnel
sonnel as effected at the last annua annuameeting annual annualmtetlng annualmeeting
meeting December S 1888 The reiter reiterated relterattd reiteratcd
ated demands for complete reorganiza reorganization reorgnnlzatlon reorganization
tion ignore the prosont reorganiza reorganizawith reorganlzawith reorganizawith
with a cool audacity that Is both bothamazing bothamazing bothamazing
amazing and amusing</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89067390/1906-05-17/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=clara+barton+red+cross</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>April 1905 : Barton forms the National First Aid Association of America</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON ACME,
Red Cross Heroine Will Estab
lish Railroad Hospital Car
Service.
t Although Over Eighty Years Old She
tlu Started In with Great Energy
to Organize New Relict Work to
Cope with Wrecks.
Clara Barton, the famous Red Cross
leader, has Just given new evidence
that she is one of the most remarkable
women the world has ever known. Feol.
Ing that the Red Cross work has been
placed on a permanent basis and no
longer needs ber close supervision, this
untiring woman, although upward of
eighty years of age, has lately returned
to her old home In Massachusetts and
opened headquarters for a great new
movement to alleviate tuffering, name
ly, a project for organizing hospital
corps on all railroads In order that
with the aid of hospital cars speedy
succor may be brought to persons in
jured in wrecks.
The portrait here presented Is ot
especial Interest, inasmuch as It is the
only likeness which Clara Barton has
permitted to be made in many years.
The famous Red Cross worker has no
love for the camera, but her close per
sonal friend, Mrs. John A. Logan, after
much persuasion finally Induced her to
sit for this picture. Mrs. Logan is seen
standing by her side.
WOIi'.'-'D IN CIVIL AND FRANCO
l'UUSSIAN WARS.
Clara Barton, who is entering with
0 much enthusiasm Into a new mls-
MISS CLARA BARTON AND
slonary work, was born In Oxford,
Mass., In 1830. During the Civil War
she did relief work on the battlefields
and organized the search for missing
men for which Congress appropriated
the sum of $15,000. After the close of
that conflict she went abroad and car
ried on the Red Cross activities ot the
Franco-Prussian war, following which
he did heroic work at the Johnstown
flood, distributed relief in the Russian
famine in 1892, and the Armenian mas
sacre of 1896, at the request of the
President of the United States carried
relief to Cuba In 1898, and conducted
the Red Cross relief at the Galveston
flood.
America's most Interesting repre
sentative in the world's group of grand
old women has been loaded with hon
ors by all nstlona, and her home is
filled with valuable tokens of esteem.
Chief among the treasures cherished
by this Idol of conquering armies are
the jewels and decorations tendered her
by the royalty of many nations, and
constituting unquestionably the great
est collection ever bestowed upon any
citizen of the United States.
GIFTS FROM ALL SOVEREIGNS.
Conspicuous In the glittering array
are the amethyst cut In the form ot a
pansy, an Inch and one-hall square,
the gift of Miss Barton's personal
friend, the Grand Duchess of Baden;
the Servian Red Cross decoration pre
sented by Queen Natalie, the Gold
Cross of Remembrance bestowed by the
Grand Duke and Duchess of Baden, a
medal presented by the Queen of Italy,
an English decoration pinned on Miss
Barton's dress by Queen Victoria; the
Iron Cross of Germany presented by
the Emperor and Empress, the decora
tion ot the Order of Meluslne presented
bv the Prince of Jerusalem. Cyprus and
Armenia, and the brooch and pendant
it diamonds, the gift of the people of
'.Johnstown. In recognition of the great
service rendered by Miss Barton after
Mi fafnnns flood.
Miss Barton's father wal In boyhood
jne of the soldiers ot "Mad Anthony
Wayne, and Clarissa Hsrlowe Barton,
a. fipr name Is Inscribe. In the family
Bible, earns to the Bar Stat horns as
a toman Christmas present. Like many
another New England" girl Clara Bar
ton, when thrown on her own resources,
took up school teaching as a means of
livelihood, and when she was obliged
to abandon this because of falling eye
sight, she managed to secure a position
In the Patent Ofllce at Washington, and
here she continued her service until
the outbreak of the Civil War disclosed
to her a llfework. Her advertisements
in the Massachusetts papers that she
would receive money and stores for the
wounded soldiers and personally dis
tribute them at the front brought quick
responses, and from this small beginning
the scope of her "work broadened. The
ministering angel of the Army of the
Potomac was present at the battles ot
Cedar Mountain, the second Bull Run,
Antietam, Fredericksburg and the Wil
derness. WAS WITH THE VANGUARD.
In the Franco-Prussian war Miss
Barton was the first person to enter
Strasburg after the fall ot that city,
and was Instrumental in organizing
the relief. She performed a similar
service at Paris, which she entered with
the vanguard at the conclusion of the
siege. After her return to the United
States she directed relief work in addi
tion to the Instances above mentioned
during the Mississippi flood of 1882, the
overflow of the Ohio River in 1883, the
Louisiana cyclone of the same year,
and the Texas drought of 1889, ever at
the fore aiding, sustaining, and sup
porting by her "Untiring presence the
falling courage of those who In their
suffering learned to depend upon her
with passionate love and gratitude.
Mrs. John A. Logan Mary Simmer
son Cunningham Logan who appears
with Clara Barton In this picture, is
a native ot Missouri, but was educated
in Kentucky and married John A. Lo
gan In 1855. Since his death she has
MRS. JOHN A. LOGAN.
engaged in literary work, and has re
sided In the city of Washington, mak
ing her home in a quaint old bouse
filled with mementoes of her hero hus
band. This residence is on a most at
tractive little estate of about one-half
acre In extent, located xn the brow ot
a hill overlooking the nation's capltol.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86099906/1903-02-05/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=clara+barton+red+cross</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>BLNK</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON SARCASTIC.
Red Cross President Takes Mild
Fling at Roosevelt.
San Antonio, Texas,
FRENCH BUILDING, MAIN PLAZA.
BOTICA DEL LE0JSt.
Will practice in the federal and state J W
courts. Laud titles examined.
RHHE2EHEHHS
TV. F. DEKNETTl
Staple Fancy Groceries j
Cigars, smoking and chewing
tohacco, Fancy candies,
cakes and crackers,
Full line tin ware, crockery. Etc.
Washington- Street.
Old Furniture
t&amp;- MADE NEW. -a
i
Joseph Kuek
Cabinet Maker.
J
i. M. H. GROSS
t9MHl.KS1t.ai ItKAB.KXtS fjt
BKOWNSYILLE, Tsxas, and MATAMOE0S, Mexico.
WINCHESTER ARMS ANfi AMMUNITION
.ill
nr
mi
S if. FIELD
-0BALKU
ROGEBIESl
1!
And General Repairer is now ready MP
to repair and upholster furnitnre ii
Levee and lltb. streets. ljT
Shelf and Heavey Hardware,
rAGRI CULTUB.AL IMPLEMENTS
THE TAILOR. W
ELIZABETH STREET.
I am prepared to make snits
and clean Clothes
on -short notice. Work
Guaranteed.
Shop'Opposite Thielen Bakery.
111
Tin aud Wooden Ware,
Wupperman Nou- Breakable
White Enameled Ware,
Sheet Tin and Iron,
Round and Flat Bar Jron,
White Lead, Lubricating Oil,
Turpentine, Paint, Varnish
and Window Oass.
Mixed and Dry Paints for
Carriages and Bnildings,
'Jarriage, Wsgon and Build
mir Material.
Sash, Doors and Blinds to
order:
Lime, Cement and Bricks.
New York, Feb. 1. Replying to
the recent letter of the President's
secretary, George B. Cortelyou, re
questing that public announcement
be made that the President of the
United States and his Cabinet can
not serve as a board of consultation
of the American National Red
Cross, .Miss Clara Barton, president
of the association, has addressed' an
explanatory letter to President
Roosevelt. Referring to article four
of tho constitution of the Red Cross,
providing for a board of consulta
tion, consisting of the President and
his Cabinet and certain high offi
cers of the army, Miss Barton points
out that this provision was full
endorsed by President Arthur and
his entire -cabinet, and accepted by
succeeding administrations. Con
tinuing Miss Barton writes:
"I recite these facts to you, Mr.
President, as an earnest that neither,
was usurpation practiced nor dis
courtesy intended in the late need
ed changes of the article of the con
stitution.
"Thus, Mr. President, if, in the
continuing of -our honored name
and that of your cabinet in our ad
ministration of the Red Cross, I
have committed an error so grave
as to merit a reprimand and be re
quired to make an open denial be
fore the world of privileges, I have
assumed, the powers I have usurp
ed, the disrespect shown the honor
ed heads of the nation and my un
avoidable and deep humiliation
thereat, I shall prove my good citi
zenship by exact and willing con
formity with and obedience to the
commands by the publication of
your honored letter and such re
plies as I have been able to make,
jn order that no misunderstanding
of your relations can possibly oc
cur." The letter concludes thus:"
"Trusting that these concessions,
faithfully submitted, .may prove a
sufficient notice and guarantee to
the public of the disconnection
which you desire from the organi
zation which I have so long had
the pain to conduct, I have the
honor to subscribe myself.
"Your Obedient Countrywoman,
"CLARA BARTON."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1925-10-04/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=clara+barton+red+cross</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<time>BLNK</time>
	<text>Author of Work on Life of Clara
Barton, Red Cross Founder,
Succumbs in Boston.
Charles Sumner Young, the biogra
pher of Clara Barton, died yesterday
In Boston, according to word received
here. Mr. Young had gone to Boston
several years ago, where he organized
the National First Aid Association as
a memorial to Clara Barton, founder
of the American Ked Cross. He was
the author of the •Fife of Clara Bar
ton,” which he published to mark the
centennial of the birth of the famous
Civil War nurse. Two years ago, in
cooperation with the American Tree
Association, he began a campaign for
memorial tree planting In honor of
Clara Barton through all the Brand
Army of the Kepublic posts and the
Women’s Relief Corps organizations
in the United States.
Gen. Nelson A. Miles and Mrs. John
A. Logan, both of whom have since
died, planted a memorial tree for Miss
Barton at Glen Kcho three years ugo.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025294/1903-01-01/ed-1/?sp=57&amp;q=clara+barton+red+cross</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>BLNK</time>
	<text>Another of this country's great women
is Clara Barton. Who in America does
not know of Clara Barton, the Red Cross
nurse? But her work was really begun
in England by that wonderful woman
called Florence Nightingale, who was
moved to take tup the work by the fright
ful reports that came into England from
the battlefields during the Crimean war.
After much pleading and insistence this
fragile woman was allowed to go to the
battlefield of Sebastopol and gather into
some sort of shelter the maimed and dying
soldiers, who had been left to rot on the
field as they were. The work there an'
CARRIE CHAPMAN CATT,
P n
Prominent Leader of American Women.
compltislth l rest ltcI i: the w.orlhd cciil
that womaitn wa; Ielled oni the Iittle
fheldI to care for li hie C!i~,t 'Idolw int the
namne of patriotimt. hn. it wa% that the
nations of |utlrolpe INtnio I encoura:ge thei
training of nur".i out 1i.e the conventst
for the Sisters f 'l:i: ity hald aready
done good work to be s.et ,itih thil: ,l.
diers.
CLARA BARTON AND HER
WORK IN OOR OWN WAR
W'hen otur own terrible war spre;idl de
vastation tand dleath ultpotn this cotuntltry
Ilara lhartoin obtainedi paermi-ioni to
gather at few earinet, .v:f- acriticiiig
womenll togthller and w.:t oitti t, tclinderly
care for the wlounded onl It ilt hlel. It
would lie itmpissile to te l ii a short ar
ticle of this kind vhi't the gentlte min
istering of v.omllent in the war hospittals
was to the foot-sore, wounetiled and d iing
soldiers. blut in our last war 'lara Iar
ton, at the head of the Rled 'ross work,
came again grandly to thle front, and
proved once more that great womenlt are
born to lead great reforms.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093407/1912-04-12/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=clara+barton+red+cross</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<time>April 12, 1912 : Carla Barton dies of illness.</time>
	<text>CLARA BARTON, RED
CROSS FOUNDER, DEAD
CLARA BARTON. PHOTO TAKEN ON HER NINETIETH BIRTHDAY
Mr S*IM Preee I**e*4 Wire
WASHINGTON. April 12.—Mlsa
Clara Barton, founder of the Nation
al Red Croee movement, died today
at her home in Glen Echo, Md. She
had been ill for months.
Clare Barton *u more than &gt;0
y«*m of age. having baen born In
Oxford, Mun, ta IS2I. Bbe firet
came lmo national promiuenre dnr
in* the rlvil war. »hen ab* partlci
in and directed relief work
on the bsMlefielda. auil alao orkAO
I«h1 !h«- aear&lt; b for iniaainß men for
which congreaa made eitanaive ap-propriation*
After the rloae of the war Mlaa
llarfon a«*oInternational Red OttHM of ianara.
and aerved in relief work through
out the Franco I'runaian war. finally
uring the adoption of the UM««a
treaty by the I nited Hiataa in IK?.
Ten year* later ahe waa a&lt; 11v«- dur
in the famine in Rn*ala.
Mi*# Hart on founded and organ
lied the national Red Croaa in thi*
country in I*Bl and remained Ita
preaident until her resignation id
IX&gt;«</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

</topics>