<topics><topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-marie-curie</id>
    <results>
      <!-- article 1 -->
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88068010/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Curie+radium</id>
	      <rel>1</rel>
	      <text>
        Another cw Klement.
        Three French chemists M. and
        Mine, Curie and M. Bemont have dis
        covered a new metallic element, which
        they call "radium," because of its re
        markable property of emitting rays
        which resemble in their penetrative
        power Prof. Roentgen's celebrated X
        rays. Not long ago much surprise was
        caused by the discovery that uranium
        is capable of emitting similar rays, but
        the power of radium in this respect is
        Eaid to be 900 times greater than that
        of uranium.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 2 -->
      <result>
	      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1899-12-17/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Curie+Curies+polonium+Polonium</id>
	      <rel>1</rel>
	      <text>ELEMENT.
        Si"* or fight permanent additions to the list
        of .?hemic.?] elementa hav.? been made within
        the last three or four years. None of them,
        however, poaaeai such Immediate practical
        Importance the diaeovery of radium. The
        Unding of bellum lu terreatrla] minerais awak?
        ?.neil a ?peculiar degree of inter.'st. becauee it
        afforded fr. sh evidence that ti,?? .earth ami sun
        .in* mail?- ?if suli-t.nitially the same materials.
        Still. i?> ?me hal yel found any DM for helium
        I, waa a little itartUng to learn, as the world
        did from EUmaay'l isolation of argon, that the
        atmosphere contained one more "oiisiltnent
        than hail previously been roppoeed. Vet, so far
        as iv known, argon Is as useless as helium. And
        so on through the Hat of recent diacoveriee, until
        radium li reached. Regarding thla element,
        Professor Barker showed in Philadelphia last
        week li,at on :.nut ?,f the invisible radial.
        which it emita it Is a mon convenient and
        economical agent for surgical exploration than
        thai which mad?* R?ntgen famous
        The investigations of M. and Mme. Curie,
        which n-**,,it?*.i in the finding earl? In Mis. if not ?before, Bttd ???-re doubt
        l?^- ?stimulated, if no1 ragireated, by the Bl
        varia,i p**ofeiaor*i brilliant achievement. R.'.nt
        gen'l work naturally ?sailed t.. mind the ob
        ?ervationi r Becquerel, that uranium ami its
        salts exerted a very feeble photographic in?
        fluence. Bj experimenting with pitchblende,
        the mineral from which uranium is obtained
        .commercially, M. and Mme. ?'urie round that
        the former yielded ihe same effect much mor.?
        cnnaplcuoualy. This led them to suspect that
        they were on the track ?if a new element. They
        e\.*n went so far as t.? name it jir.ivislonally.
        although much difficulty was experictmed In
        ?Operating it from the substances with which
        Ii was ::-*-,n ?ned Just before the close of the
        year, with the co-operation of M. Bemont, thfey
        il?ta ned in,p..itlons ,,f ?till another ne?v el??
        ment The Oral Ihej called "polonium'' ami tha
        s.v..tai "radium.*' Polonium is believed t.i
        siirpas. uranium an.l Ita salts in ?-mis.Ive power
        five hundredfold, but ?Profcaaor Bark?erestimate!
        th?* efBdency sand times that of uranium. Por thi- l*eason,
        ami because of it** comparative cheapneaa ami
        .simplicity, the aecond of the Curies' dlacoverlei
        seem*- destined to replace Hie coatly and com
        plicated X ray aj.jmratus In the realm of
        surgery
        one important dlatinctlon is t,, he noted be
        tween the behavi-.r of the "rookes tube md
        that trait of radium which Is now for th?- tirst
        time being exploited in thla country. Tha prac
        ticabillty ??f deriving one form f .*n??i*u'.? beat,
        light, electricity ?,r chemical action fn,m som,?
        other na? long been recognised, hut it is axiom
        ntlc that none ,,f them can ia- j.r?nl?i.1 except
        hy that method. Ii |s believed lhat the moat
        man can ?lo Is to tnnaform. Ii IS thought lhat
        h?* ?-.'innot, in any true ?.en-**?*, create Rtatgen
        obtained bli X rays uni.? by converaloB loree previously existing in the form txiclty. But a radium.? which will penetrate
        opaque b,??lies and act upon the chemicals on
        a photographic plate is secured fr??m radium
        without the apparent use of any known sjtecies
        of energy. The phenomenon may yet be ex?
        plahMd But at present It lookl v.-ry much
        like what has long, been regarded an impos
        sibiiity. the ipontaneoui leneratloii m. force.
        The la?t li not ..lti-gethiT Unique, however.
        Within the last two years an englishman.
        named Bussell, ha?; b??eii ?'ailing attention to
        th.- exM-edlngly tMrw bul well defined action en
        a photographic plata ?f several familiar sub
        Stancea, Itnong them printer's ink. of which ne
        regard! the rarnlah the ?potent factor. The pro
        tective covering which be placed n bia plate
        leemlngly ?*?redudcd any chemical action hy
        the ink. or any Invasion of Wa |?latehol?ler hy
        true light rays. Ami n* h." ?vas able to ob?
        serve UM efTect when he us? d l|.linens nf
        print over a century old. it Is hanl to say how
        long this mystariOUl ?power may continue to he
        exerted hythe ink. This fact, taken with the
        discovery of ii. and lime. Curie, "P'?s op n
        fas-,.mating, and perbapi fruitful. Held ??f specu?
        la H,,n u to the exl'itence and nature of yet
        unrecognized phyalcal forces.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 3 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-12-31/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=Curie+Curies+radium</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        TI-jE CATHODE RAY OUTDONE.
        WHEN the marvels of the cathode or X ray
        were made known to the world only a few
        years ago, it was believed we had reached a
        degree of photographic power that would not be sur
        passed for generations to come, and that for the use
        of surgeons in locating foreign substances imbedded
        in flesh or bone it would be of permanent value. Yet
        according to reports of experiments made by Pro
        fessor Barker in Philadelphia a short time ago, that
        wonderful ray is about to become a back number be
        cause of the potency shown by a newly discovered
        element known as "radium."
        The discovery of the new element is due to M. and
        lime. Curie and is the result of investigations stimu
        lated by the discovery of the X-ray. They were ex
        perimenting in 1898 with uranium and its salts, which
        exert a feeble photographic power, when they ob
        served phenomena indicating the existence of an un
        known factor in the mass. They at once directed
        their investigations to the separation of that element
        from the substances with which it was associated
        and found not one but two new elements. To the first
        they gave the name "polonium" and to the second
        '•radium." The first is believed to have a radiant
        power five hundredfold greater than that of uranium,
        but Professor Barker estimates the efficiency of ra
        dium at one hundred thousand times that of uranium.
        For this reason and because of its comparative cheap
        ness and simplicity the second of the Curies' discov
        eries seems destined, it is said, to replace the costly
        and complicated X-ray apparatus in the realm of sur
        gery.
        The most extraordinary characteristic of the new
        element is thus described in an account of Professor
        Barker's experiments by the New York Tribune:
        "The practicability of deriving one form of energy
        heat, light, electricity or chemical action— from
        some other has long been recognized, but it is axiom
        atic that none of them can be produced except by that
        method. It is believed that the most man can do is
        to transform. It is thought that he cannot, in any
        true sense, create. Roentgen obtained his X-rays
        only by a conversion of force previously existing in
        the form of electricity. But a radiance which will
        penetrate opaque bodies and act upon the chemicals
        on a photographic plate is secured from radium with
        out the apparent use of any known species of energy.
        The phenomenon may yet be explained. But at pres
        ent it looks very much like what has long been re
        garded an impossibility, the spontaneous generation
        of force."
        The discovery of unknown elements of such mar
        velous potencies at this late stage in the investigations
        of science is a striking proof of how little we know
        of the substances that lie around us or of the forces
        that act upon them. There is no telling wlrit wide
        and high uses may yet be made of radium, but it is
        probable the discovery will be one of the most im
        portant gifts which this century v:ill bestow for the
        guidance of science in that which is to come
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 4 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085421/1907-05-13/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Curie+Marie+Sklodowska</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        WomenWhoDo
        The First Woman Professor In the
        Famous Sorbonne University at
        Paris —Mme. Curie as She Ap
        pears When Lecturing
        A slender, youthfnl woman in deep
        mourning, ber fair hair swept plainly
        back from a remarkably broad, high.
        full brow, her head seemingly almost
        too large for the slim neck that car
        ried it. her manner so simple, so un
        conscious and sincere that it was child
        like—such was the appearance of Mmc
        Curie as she stood in a class room de
        livering the first lecture ever given by
        a woman professor to the students of
        the University of Paris. It was an
        event which should make women all
        over the world rejoice and take cour
        age, because at last the earnest, de
        voted scientific work of one of their
        MME. CLXIX LECTURING.
        sex has been fittingly recognized.
        Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie, discov
        erer of radium. Is by birth it Pole. Her
        father was a professor of sciences in
        the town where Marie spent her child
        hood, and she was interested in re
        torts, test tubes and chemicals at an
        age when girl children are expected to
        play with dolls. But little Marie never
        did play with dolls. She used to spend
        her time In tbe professor's laboratory
        and frequently amazed with her wis
        dom and knowledge grave, learued
        meu who called on her father. After
        finishing the scientific course in the
        school of her borne town of Varsovie
        the young girl went to Paris to study
        further. There she met Pierre Curie,
        student of chemistry, as enthusiastic as
        herself. They were at once drawn to
        each other and in time were married.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 5 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1910-05-15/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=Curie+CURIE+Marie+Sklodowska</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        MME CURIE, DISCOVERER OF RADIUM AND P0L0NIUM;!j
        I ji a I
        iJ T. j ToOTTLED at Nice, France, and made from I l
        I til The r i ti i e acquired some years ago bv 1M i hum mumnmi h ii ..n-... 7 7 Vlu I II
        J M,n., Marie Sklodowska Curie by her ffgfPf 1 U IS 1 ltl J f 1 T"
        i dis,.,,,7y of ra.uum 1;rom;Se3 to be a i g$M tr 5tl o absolutely sound, perfect olives. 1 his o r
        I equal,.!, ,r not surpassed, by the honor. 1 1 Jfe&amp; A X U1V I I
        I I 1 which have cwiie tt her as the diseov- jl ff'" ill 1 1 1 1 1 11
        I. 1 1 eror ,0 ,otbs a,o of the new, even !ygp Pw k is pure and unadulterated. It has a unique and l
        I R more wonderful, element polonium. It; .hiiy' 5wv f fegg Q 1VI I I
        5 AVas ;,s :i t-'oworker with her husband, I 'iSs rlPSX1 'fe" 'l5! 1 1 fl 1 1T 1 I
        f y the lat, Frofer Cune that thi8 bra. f gW' ilg I 2 delicious Havor peculiar to itselt. ratent spout. v
        I sj bant won an succeeded ia isolating ra- Frf JT B tn -SfeJ&amp; r 1 i
        f f I dium, and it is now with th. assistance PfM2 jKV 'Hp? Wj iSlSt, I
        f I I of M. de Bierne that she has succeeded lJB "pf WWM I
        I fl r'srir: ftJ Sfeiyf X Guaranteed under the Food and
        I 5OU0 times rarer than radium and tak- tijjf&amp;Hl WWi'fW f g!
        :.y pefeMi '10 Drugs Act of June 30, 1906.
        I iji ment of more than, five tons of pitch- iPflA" Et lllJil I U I
        f 111 blende with hydrochloric acid. Polo- .f&amp;s rip? i'MiW i Si A
        III niurn "wastes away" with preat rapid- e- -Sagll 'I
        1; ity, a thousand times quicker than ra- v.-t5 J3ff f k
        1! dium. Of course, the value of this dis- V iSW J' I
        ii j- 'SKr. 'JfU sold by an Grocers I
        S I II the Re-rue Scientifiqne Paris, Iro- i f asgj?gn JSS "f" 'J? A 1
        f lill fsor Lippmann, the French scientist, tpMj J
        If remarks apropos of Mine. Curie's two I fS 1' A W" SHSC II 1
        I discoveries: IIE WM t 'W?! LI I
        iff "Jtadio-activity, it must be remem- ri sSi 1 f I I
        I i 'ered, is a general property of matter. P SgSSSg? 1 K ?fef3K L CD O O O O O O CZ30 O f 1
        y If the theory of radio-active trans- -fV W 1 I
        j formations continues to inspire a grow- pf: 1
        I ;:1 ing degree of confidence it will re- f i I
        j"i suit, in an important consequence for pStij. .V-.i T V rTN I T- A I
        I M? geology. It will lead to a careful studv feVwV-y 'I i '11 III V. ft Y J J I I I f 0
        of the proportions of the elements oc- X '-51 K II II 111 V II J 1
        j I" I curring in rocks, with a view to the t'' fpk, Ai L W iV II I I I I m. I
        I f determination of 'their relative au- I -,.lJU---t5-J !L-J-l. Tr,,- -Jr J I U 0 I
        5 tiquity. Jt is manifest that the hy- T'ji t y
        pothesis of radio-active transformation MADAME CURIE IN HER LIBRARY. WK fcZT.U 4 s 5
        is well adapted to the present state of Vt t T&amp;&amp;JSCr Wtlff T Ton I
        the science of radio-activity. It was W0Iliaii ot science has devoted her life to investigating the subject of I V VJOlL 1
        J among those proposed by the late Pierre radioactivity. S5 v-i
        f Curie and myself at the beginning of V-'43u I
        "J. -f our researches into radio aetivitv, but one brought up in stove-heated rooms, j womanly. Put she lost her mother early ifetef,Si!B,'5 T K A l ir-Tlit- rl m gf f I
        1 it has received its perfect development! ashen, aud the lusterless hair unchang- and was brought up at her father's "".TTfe I D fl D- IL fl fl A i 1 CI TI CI iUTT I
        j I at the hands of Professors Putherford ed in all but a few silver threads. She i side, in his laboratory, and not warped fJ ''-WX ijk II I I ll II II V S J
        1 I and Soddy, to whom it ia for this rea- remains hard to read, a consequence from her true nature according to any f: fe-'"iin ii.ii-ntmil W jl II V If jl fL Slli 1 I
        son generally attributed. Jt seems to of being brought up at. Warsaw under j eonventional standard of femininity. jjg J m mUJ J llll I J
        -i nip, however, better not to leave the j the heel of the Russian boot and the She evolved from withiu according to t:j '"'--!i".S--
        domain of demonstrated fact, not to eyes of an ollicialdom jealous of all her opportunities and the tender f .'''itowl 'l jw ti.CJ-CTt -S
        i J lose sight of other explanations of radio- scientific investigation. Mine. Curie paternal guidance, and became on chem- mJk" WMWlJlTft-IlRfr A 1 11 S
        i activity which have been proposed. The spoke of the university in which her istry an authority in the miuds of the rklfl'9JrA jL J.XiX VOU Dllt cl DdrilCF UCtWCCIl 1
        j actual state of the science docs not father tilled the chair of chemistry university students who came to the mtfgc- flT5PfSl5 "20 i
        j I seem to nie far enough advanced to war. as liaving in all its corridors finger laboratory. The suspicious prying of r?' 1 Tjy ''La 11 1111
        a rant a positive conclusion." posts pointing to Siberia. As the police taught her how necessary it 8' LMSditlfMSijl S lUll CfOWn dFlCl cl DcliCl OF16
        Personally Mine. Curie is a very mod- a lecturer she closely confines herself was to hold her tongue. Reticence in k vySLiC-rLKiW
        I I est and undemonstrative woman. She to statement and demonstration, risk- speech became her second nature. Mme. SLj5 .VVwjnll 3
        t nas for years been one of the most ing nothing that is unproed, however, Curie is greatly hindered in her re- aw", "''wlV rifSi n .1
        i efficient original workers in the labora- strong cause she may have for divin- searches by t he" rapid rie in the price -V V --f It Will Kill tfl6 gGriTI It W-II ClGSfl thC f
        I -te tory of the Sorbonne. According to ing inference. She is completely in- of radium. It is to be hoped the fymm'-i g-wjTuj-Jf.'1''-"- I
        i a writer in London Trulh, she take" nocent under all circumstances of any French government will be able to bor- fclfc'.S teZj --t$ J s-Slr rtr.mnl'n ...i-l I
        I ,1 5 all the honors heaped upon her with wish to dazzle Jr show off. Her labor- row some grains of the Austrian on! J SCalP a"Q prOmOtC the grOWth WtlCfC j
        i 0 great modest v ami is "the most un- atorv is kept with apple pie. order, audi the basis of an insurance bond given -M A'-l-$t:1. I
        J 'l4 f obtrusive, reserved person possible." her note books show the plain, straight- j to the lender. Mme. Curie lectures LfeM A,1-J1L1 tilC germ IS Weakeflillg it. TfICrCIS I
        "ti ,4 The Knglish writer says: forward and scrupulously exact ob- J regularly before the Sorbonne explain- KS X Iff I
        t 1 she is a little better dressed now servat ion of a good seaman 's leg. Thev i tig the regress of her work and set- Ht. ;v:'igtifcia nn.hinr s cr a- 1
        i than formerly, but with extreme plain- bristle with notes of interrogation. ting forth what she expects to prove tllL:v S&amp;S7 S M3t K 1
        i ness. The complexion is still that of Mme. Curie is essentially j by her experiments. 
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 6 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1911-12-11/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Curie+Marie+Nobel+NOBEL+prize</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        NOBEL PIES ARE
        GIVEN MINERS
        Mme. Marie Curie Receives
        Nearly MO,oou for Her
        Work in Cfiemistry.
        STOCKHOLM, Dec, 10. King Gustav
        today presented the Nobel prises, with
        th exception of the peace prize, to the
        wihners. Mine. Afavrie Sklodowska Curls
        personally receix-od the prize for chem
        istry: The Nobel prize each amounted to
        nearly $4ft.''l,"",.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 7 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Curie+Marie+NOBEL+Nobel+prize+Prize+Prizes+prizes</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        WOMAN WINS NOBEL
        CHEMISTRY AWARD
        Mme. Curte, Discoverer o! Ra
        dium and Polonium, Given
        $40,000 Prize
        STOCKHOLM. Nov. 7.—The Nobel
        prize for chemistry has been awarded
        to Mme. Marie Sklodowska Curie of the
        University of Paris.
        Mme. Curie is the chief professor of
        sciences in the University of Paris. She
        was the discoverer, with her husband.
        Prof. Pierre Curie, of radium, and in
        1903 shared with him half of the Xobel
        pflze for physics, the other half being
        awarded to Prof. Antoine Henri Bec
        queret. Each of the five Nobel prizes
        awarded annually amounts to $40,000.
        Recent announcement was made of
        the success of Mme. Curie in producing
        polonium, "a new element possessing a
        radio activity superior to radium."
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 8 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1912-05-02/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Curie+DISCOVERIES+discoveries+Discovery+Marie+radium</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        MME. C URIE. NOTED FRENCH SCIENTIST,
        WINS NOBEL PRIZE FOR DISCOVERIES
        TheatreMme. Marie Curie.
        Ileie is ihe latent photograph of Mme Mane Curie the great French
        scientist, who, with her husland, discovered radium Mme Curie is
        without doubt the greatest of all women scientists She was rccentlv
        the recipient ot theJNobel prize for her wondertul scientific chemical dis
        co cries.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 9 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1921-03-13/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Curie+Marie</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Madame Marie Curie, discoverer
        0t radium and 46blest woman in
        the world, will visit this country
        in 14y. That interests you, and
        MW PROVE your interest.
        WOmen of America have un
        dertakes to raise a Madame Curie
        had of $100,000. The money is
        set for Madame Curie. Money
        does not Interest her now, any
        more than when she lived in Paris
        as young girl, washing bottles in
        a laboratory that she might con
        tinue her scientific studies on an
        Incom, of twenty dollars a month
        And a diet of black bread and milk.
        The $100,000 Madame Curie
        Fund will be used to purchase one
        grain of radium for the woman
        that discovered radium. And that
        radium will be used by Madame
        Curie in her scientific |studies
        the studies that have given such
        magnificent results to the world
        Of science and have never given
        one sany of profit to Madame
        Curie.
        At sixteen Marie Sklodowski,
        now Marie Curie, was graduated
        from the -Girls' Gymnasium, re
        esiving a medal of gold. She was
        then a well-educated scientist.
        Next she worked in the physics
        Iaboratory of the Industrial Mu
        mum. in Warsaw.
        On her father's death rhe went
        to Paris to continue her scientific
        studies. On an income of $20 a
        aonth she lived alone in one small
        room, her furniture an iron bed
        and one chair, her diet black bread
        and milk.
        She found work in a scientific
        laborator as a washer of bottles
        and contmiued her studies. Pro
        fessor Lip n, observing her
        ability, ealed her to obtain a
        free course in physics, chemistry,
        and mathnenatics at the Sorbonne,
        *where she now lectures and teaches,
        the first woman tq be thus hon
        ered.
        You have heard "proud man"
        guestion woman's mental power.
        It would do such men good to fol
        low Madame Curie's work as it led
        up to her discovery of radium, a
        discovery shared by her husband,
        Prof. Pierre Curie, but due chiefly
        to her.
        Everybody knew that salts of
        thorium and various substances
        emnitted rays possessing the qual
        Ity of radiation, discovered by Pro
        fessor Becquerel. Madame Curie
        and her husband learned that
        pitch-blend. also produces radio
        active force that will pass through
        any substance, lead and steel ex
        S That vague information satisfied
        others, but Madame Curie was de
        termined to know just WHAT it
        was that caused the radioactivity.
        For three years she worked stead
        Ily, intensely, using in experiments
        every penny above the actual cost
        Sof keeping herself alive. In her
        work she "reduced" tons of pitch
        blende.
        At last, in 1900, in Paris, a
        watchcase was exhibited contain
        ing a speck of the world's rarest,
        most extraordinary element. It
        was labeled "Radium-Discovered
        by Madame Curie."
        .In 1911 Madame Curie obtained
        the Nobel Prise for chemistry.
        When her husband was killed in
        1906 there was no one able to take
        his place at the Sorbonne, except
        his wife, and that ancient institu
        tion broke its rule of centuries and
        Invited a woman to the full pro
        fessorship that Madame Curie now
        ,holds.
        Madame Curie is admlitted to be
        asg the greatest scientists liv
        lag, net the great "woman" ecien
        a tMs, but among the greete'st scien
        tists whether men or women.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 10 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1921-04-05/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Curie+Marie+radium</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        AN IMMORTAL WOMAN
        The visit of Madam Marie Curie to this country in May
        will be celebrated by American women with the presentation
        of a thimbleful of radium to the distinguished scientist. At was
        a beautiful tribute to the modesty of womankind that Mine.
        Curie made when she discovered the element which has revo-
        lutionized physics, chemistry and some branches of medicine,
        and gave it an impersonal name. The courtesy of the labora-
        -tory dictates that the discoverer of a new thing under the sun
        may give it his own name if he wishes, and so perpetuate nia
        own glory. Mme. Curie called it radium, because it gives out
        HINTS TO GARDENERS
        More than sentiment attaches to the gift. Of course, it
        money value, something like $100,000, will have little weight
        with a devotee of science like Mme. Curie.: She will use the
        radium for scientific research. Although Mme. Curie knows
        more concerning radium and its potentialities than any living
        soul, she has not, because of her generosity, one grain with
        which to conduct experiments.
        The history of the discovery of radium is one of the most
        exalted romances that the world has ever known. The daugh-
        ter of a professor in the University of Warsaw, the present Mme.
        Curie was drawn to Paris by the magnetic pull of the renowned
        scientific schools there. In conjunction with the scientists
        Becquerel and Curie, she began a series of experiments with
        uranium which led to her discovery of radium. It also led to
        her happy marriage with Professor Curie. That the discovery
        was that of Mme. Curie alone was well established by a com-
        mission which awarded her the Nobel prize in 1903.
        The hope which radium holds out to the world is that it
        may be the means of fighting cancer, that malignant disease
        which has baffled physicians for centuries. Undoubtedly there
        are new fields into which researchers can go. And it is in these
        unexplored regions that Mme. Curie will venture. The women
        of America honor themselves by providing the means.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 11 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085523/1899-11-02/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=Marie+Curie</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <!-- article 12 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063592/1899-12-21/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Marie+Curie</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <!-- article 13 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92066979/1911-11-21/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Marie+Curie+radium+Nobel+Prize</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        MME. CURIE.
        Distinguished Scientist Who Was
        Awarded Nobel Prize For Chemistry.
        Mme. Curie, the chief professor of
        sciences in the University of Paris,
        who has been awarded the Nobel prize
        for chemistry. $40,000. is the foremost
        scientist in France, perhaps In the*
        world, and of course the greatest an
        thority on radium and radio-activity.
        She and her husband, the late Pro
        fessor Pierre Curie, in' collaboration
        discovered radium after toiling and
        experimenting through years of pover
        ty and depression. In 1903 half of
        the Nobel prize for physics. $40,000.
        like the other four prizes which the in
        ventor of dynamite founded, was
        f 1
        A
        MME. CUIUB.
        awarded to the Curies The other half
        went to Professor Antoine Henri Bec
        querel.
        Mme. Curie was the first woman to
        be so honored Now she is further
        distinguished by securing the whole
        prize for physics, which In to sav that
        she stands alone in that realm of sci
        ence Recently It was announced that
        she had succeeded In isolating poloni
        um. a now element possessing a radio
        activity superior io radium.
        The Nobpl prize Is awarded In the
        face «f the refusal of the Academy of
        France to elect Mme Curie to a va
        cancy in the ii'-ademy department of
        science ibout a year ago.</text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 14 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90060976/1911-11-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Marie+Curie+radium+Nobel+Prize</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CATHOLIC WOMAN
        SCIENTIST HONORED
        Nobel Prizes for Chemistry Awarded
        to. Madame Curie of Paris, the
        Discoverer of Radium.
        The annual distribution of the Nobel
        prizes which are given for distin
        guished work in several departments
        of scientific and allied studies took
        place recently at Stockholm. It is in
        teresting to note that the prize for the
        most important contribution to chem
        ical knowledge was awarded to Ma
        dame Marie Sklodowska Curie of the
        University of Paris, the well-known
        Catholic scientist and co-discoverer
        with her husband, Pierre Curie, of
        radium. This is not the first time that
        she has been thus honored. In 1903
        she shared with her husband half the
        Nobel prizes for physics, the other
        half being awarded to Professor Bec
        querel, the discoverer of radioactivity.
        Each of the five Nobel prizes which
        are awarded annually amounts to
        forty thousand dollars.
        Madame Curie is a native of Poland,
        where she was born in 1868. She
        studied chemistry in Paris with Pierre
        Curie, whom she afterwards married.
        Together they continued their chem
        ical researches in the School of
        Physics, their greatest discovery be
        ing that of radium in 1898.
        ST. PAUL, MINN.^ NOVEMBER 18, 1911.
        After the announcement ot this di0-
        covery honors and scientific recogni
        tion came to them. A few years later
        Pierre Curie was accidentally killed
        and his wife succeeded to his profes
        sorship. In 1908 she was appointed
        chief professor of physics in"the Uni
        versity of Paris.
        At the Congress of Radioactivity
        jand Electricity held in Brussels a few
        jnonths ago a signal honor was con
        ferred upon her by designating as the
        "curie" the unit of measurement for
        radium emanations. Her name will
        thus be perpetuated in the annals of
        science as are those of Ohm, Volta,
        Ampere and other pioneers in certain
        departments of science.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- article 15 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84045439/1899-11-30/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Marie+Curie</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>