<topics>
<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ellis-island</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1890-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>March, 1890 : Congress appropriates $75,000 to build an immigration station at Ellis Island.</time>
        <text>
          Springer introduced a joint resolution to
          retire N P Banks with the rank of major
          general Referred Adjourned
          Ellis Island ns a Landing Station
          WASHINGTON March 31The Senate and
          House committee on immigration have
          adopted a resolution approving the selec
          tion of Ellis island as the location for the
          immigrant landing station
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1890-04-06/ed-1/seq-13/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>March, 1890 : Congress appropriates $75,000 to build an immigration station at Ellis Island.</time>
        <text>
          A VOTE POR ELLIS ISLAND.
          THE HOUSE PASSES THK SEN.VTE JOIXT
          EE80LLTION.
          kBotnaxTB roa and agaixm tiif. tlacixo
          of tiii: immici.xnt i.andin.;-statiox
          ox tiii; ULAVD.
          Ifaahlngton, April _..*.The I! m-e to-iay, on motla*m
          nf Mr. lioutell ¦, ..f Malne, wm Intn .'.¦mnil.tco f tho
          \vi.,i.* oir. buttenrortk, -*f Ohio, !¦ tii* ekatrl n the
          aettate J'.iit ratohitloa lor tha rooao4ral "f thc naval
          oiagaslne Irom Bllla IsUnd, Kew-YoHi IImii..»r.
          i.n* Bnl lectlon authoriaea Um wteniory *f the
          Nnvy to take Imraedl-ate mea-Mtrc- -Jof Uaa raaMMnal ol
          fn* naval napulne Irom Bllla i-Umi. Tlaa omcmB
          .ection approprlatea 975,000 to pnrehaee, oe to ol.taln
          v rondcmnatlon, a aita nr, Mid for th er© Uon od o
          aeval magazinc, v. ith halldlnica tlwretor: aml tli-- tO-.
          retary ol the l-arj li authoriaed to -*l.* t ¦ itta at a
          -.if.- dlstence from popahma eltfee an.l trom the
          Jtlpping of the Harbor ol Bew-York. Tbaet to »l*o
          m appropriaUon ..f Bisjooo, t. eatble lha 8_er_tary
          f the Treaaury t. Improve Bllla latand lor ia_-_-__.
          Uo ii pnrpoaea.
          Mi*. lioutelle expUlned tbal tlu* reaotatkta ha**
          i»., _-«i the senate, bad rarelved H"- nnanl_nona r-T-.r!
          from Um Committee on Baval Affialra, and haat l**cn
          ,i I,*, the .i"i'it Committee *.n l-ninltraMon.
          Prompt artlon ahould be taken In order t" nmooo.
          ..,::¦:. ;.,:i. explosive* f-Oa IH" \i*:niiv ..f .N'.-w-Y.ir!-
          Ily, and to accure an Inimlgraut -tatlon, aa the l-ra_e
          **i I'u-t!.* Uarden would exptre In a len day*.
          Sr. Co'verl aaM thal there araa no objeetlon _»_-.
          arhere to the Dral part f the leaotattoo. provldlnj ht
          Um removal ol i in- poirder macailne. Bnl ii" iM ah-
          ;,,. in the proposlUon thal BUIa Manrt bhNM beeO-M
          ihe permanent, or even lemporery, alte "f th-* _______
          _i.it...n Itureau. if ..ll the l_b_nda In Bew-Y«_l
          llarbor, Ellln li-land waa the moat nntll f..r tiii- pnrj,,.-.-. n 4viu u i"". i""_ l-buad, a nalta and a ii-.n
          from Seu Vork, rontalnlnft onlj --ur or Ire aare-, aml
          le-tlUlte "f ii.Ii.i!,;l ,: -. Ue did OO- think. however,
          I, .1 any ..f tbe Ialanda ahould be Ml._L Thc im-
          ;.i_-r.it:*.n atatloll nhoi I'l be upon tli*' iii.tnilnnrt.
          Mr. ".it .if Alabama, favored the icao-rnl of the
          magazlne, but objected Ua tbe leteclloa ..f BUIa i-iar.d
          or ii,.. ImmlgranI atatlon. The latai wm
          i miihII one. and the dcepe_l water whi.-h eeaM
          '.talned nt it waa aeven ..r cu-iit laal.
          rhere wa* not room on Um l-laud tn eraet ¦ boepttnl
          i,..ii-*-. and the Uland would have ti ba
          -..l.u _¦.¦! bj Mvcral a. :-¦-.
          Mr. Brewer, ol Mlchlffan, favored Ihe aelecHon ot
          KHi, i! i*i.i. Ue dld ii"i iiniiii thal a proper Um "ii
          the m.i. ii.. *'i rouM b ».red lor l'-- than -18,000.000.
          Mr. ¦«_---. ii.'.v..! I- -*..;*¦ oul i.lauae provldlng
          ;,,, iho loi-Htl.f Um Inimlgraul station on Blili
          Ul md. i"-i I" '" ¦.".
          \l.. Cnvi-ri oifered an amendmenl provlding thal
          Lh«* ini-i.,-1 -N'"* ' '"'.¦'.
          i,i,,..i,!\ a, Uon. Uland  lt or fluteii
          Mr. C'iii nl '¦¦ Vork, ud that be would
          ,,i I., v.ite fnr th-- amend there a aa u**-
          -j, ¦, i;ji im it ta mn it. t'ongr-ea* bad
          the m retary of thc rre_i-*ury full power to wleel
          und in ii.*- e.\ei*..: ial power he had -elertcd l-wllow'-i i Und. i *--..t.¦ -1 - ut_ulii**t thi* el-*-
          tl,,n had n-ade ¦¦ the ritizena ul Seu Vork, and
          ii.i,i i, ,.i;_ ihul tli*- IIoum; had hcedrd theaa
          ii..* ,.um..-int:.ni . iiiiiin.il*-.- lo Sew Vork
          t.i ui-.i--ii_-.n** tho n.if-'i. iii.miiii-i''.- had t"!.a
          its work thiimiiuhlj and had reported I. favor of Ellla
          .|Hnd. H-¦:-. -"omeihli i y II i.'.'l in iim
          ir, iini-.ta.il *- he tll.1 no. - .. how he »uld .-"". ln any
          uj ,n *,.. u-taiii tha ;i* Uon ol Um ommittea.
          11.- '
          a ed, ua wax alao uu amendl.j Mr. Mi \. ol Sea .i**i*-.'v. pni-id-
          ,*,.- thal the po* '!"'. m--.!.'¦*- ahall he loeatod al taaal
          mlle-. t: *"i New ^ »i tl C'tj
          pi o ..*¦.'. aud tii- Jolnl resolutlon
          ivan passed, with an luilmportnnt amendment, whlch
          will i.. iry lu return to tho zMnale lor fkrihaf
          Uon.'
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1892-01-02/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>January 1, 1892 :	The immigration station at Ellis Island officially opens.</time>
        <text>
          Immigrants Will Hereafter Land
          at Ellis Island.
          Ni.w York, Jan. I.— Without anycer
          emoney or formal opening the immigra
          tion officials of this city today^settled
          down on Ellis island in the harbor and
          the barge office is known to them no
          more. The steamship Nevada was the
          first to arrive at the new landing place.
          Her, immigrants were put aboard the
          barge J. E. Moore, and amid the blow
          ing of fog horns and -whistles ap
          proached the pier.
          Charles M. llanley. private secretary,
          to the late Secretary Windoni,' who had
          i asked permission to be allowed to regis
          ter the first immigrant,- was at the reg
          istry deck when there came tripping up
          en-year-old Annie Moore and her
          little brother. -They had come from
          Cork -'to meet their mother, who lives
          here. Col. Weber greeted Annie and
          then presented her with a crisp new $10
          bill.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1897-06-15/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>June 15, 1897	: Fire destroys station and records of immigrants back to 1840.</time>
        <text>
          FEDERAL
          BUILDINGS
          IN RUINS
          Flames Sweep Over Ellis
          Island Doing Great
          Damage.
          EMIGRANTS RESCUED BY
          TUGBOATS.
          Thrilling Experience of Many
          Persons Just Landed in
          the Country.
          SMALLPOX PATIENTS TAKEN
          FRCM THE HOSPITAL.
          Exciting: Scenes During: the De
          struction of Government Prop
          erty Valued at Nearly a Million.
          NEW YORK, N. V., June 15.— A fire
          started in tue biggest of the Government
          buildings at Ellis Island at 12:30 o'clock
          this (Tuesday) morning, and, spreading
          with frigbtinl rapidity, was at 1 o'clock
          sweeping over the whole island, and it
          seemed almost certain that every building
          would be destroyed.
          Telegraphic and telephonic communica
          tion was cut off, but the tire had lit the
          whole bay and every tug with fire ap
          paratus on board started for the island.
          By the time the police had started a great
          crowd had gathered at Battery Park. The
          flames were then shooting a Hundred tret
          in the air, and by their light hundreds of
          people could bo seen on the island rush
          ing hither and thither.
          There are usually more than 1000 per
          sons, most of them emierants, who sleep
          on the island. The customs officials
          thought the number there when the
          tire broke out less than 1000, most of
          whom arr ved on three ships yesterday.
          The officials thought tbe boats and men
          Bent to the island were enough to handle
          the immigrants who escaped from the
          burning buildings, no matter how scared
          they might be.
          At 1:15 o'clock a great crash was beard,
          and a moment later there was another
          tremendous shower of sparks flying into
          the air. When it had cleared a little it
          was seen that two walls of the main
          building had fallen in.
          For two minutes after this crash the
          crowds that had been seen on the island
          rushing around were lost sight of, but
          when the smoke cleared away it could be
          teen that a hundred or more tugs had
          reached the island and wore taking the
          people aboard. At this time every build
          ing and every shed seemed to be burning,
          and there was absolutely no shelter for
          the people anywhere. The beat was in
          tense. The whole island is|ooly six acres
          in area. The unfortunates were forced to
          crouch, fur on the cater edge until the
          ho: f'iv J.
          At 1:30 o'clock thf ferry-boat John G.
          Carlisle arrive 1 from the island with 200
          emigrants and all the sick patients from
          the hospital there. As the boat got to the
          pier a crowd made a rush for her. The
          i police charged on the great crowd and
          fought their way to the boat, the officer*
          ot the boat standing on tiie upper deck
          screaming. "We've got sraa'lpux patients
          aboard Go back go bick
          The crowd retreated pre.uita:ely. The
          Carlisail the nurses employed on the ilund and
          by Mrs. Wtiite, wife of the resident phy
          sician. She said thnt when she boarded
          the boat she had not heart of any one
          being injured, and thought all the emi
          grants got out of the buildings safely.
          One of the oilu-ers of the boat said the
          fire originated in one of the lowers of the
          main building. At the time it started all
          the emigrants were asleep. The watch
          men sounded the alarms before they did
          unytuing towaid tiehting t: c fire, and in
          that way it :ot such a great headway that j
          by the time they could turn their atten- j
          tion to it it was sweeping through the ram
          shackle buildings utterly beyond con'.rol.
          Tfie tire was first -een In the northwest
          corner of the building, which is the de
          tention building, by Captain W. J. Burke,
          who is in charge of the night watch.
          Burke said all the rtoms in the building
          are connected by an elecric alarm, and
          that ;ii qu.ckly as possitle he rushed to
          the main ollice and rang the alarm in all
          the rooms.
          This alarm, he said, summoned the
          eleven men and two women under him.
          There were at the time 110 in
          the main building. Cv the time these
          people got out the whole building, from
          tower to tower and side to side, was a
          n.as.3 of swirling flame?, whi h shot hun
          dreds of feet in the a;r. Within a tew
          minutes after the fire started the miserable
          i water supply on the island was almost
          completely cv: off|v bthe bursting ol pipes
          which run along inside he main build
          i ing, so that when the first detachment of
          police arrived It was impossible to secure
          a stream of water with enough force to
          have any effeci.
          Just directly north of the main build
          ing stood the hospital in which were
          lifty-seven patients. Ihe admirable dis
          cipline of the nurses and medical staff
          i shov.-ed itself and the fifty-seven patients
          j were quickly wheeled or helped out of the
          building. One woman who was nursing a
          child suddenly lemembercd she had left
          her baby behind. She beat the air with
          her bauds and then tried to rush back
          into the flames. She was held back by
          tliree attendants. Presently the nurse
          came around with the baby in her arms.
          Every official a reporter saw on the
          i island said positively that no lives had
          i been lost. Ail the emigants were brought
          to the barge office lor tne night. Com
          missioner Seuner said he would person
          ally furnish a place for all sick emigrants,
          and the city hospitals would not be asked
          to take ttiem.
          Dr. Senner says the building* burned
          cost the Government $780,000. He does
          not know what accommodations can be
          arranged for the receiving of emigrants
          until they are rebuilt.
          U hrrtmrti llratin in tint War.
          ATLANTA, Ga., June 14. Colonel
          Cook's order barring ou; bicyclists from
          Fort McPherson has been approved .by
          the War Department, as has his defense
          of the sentry who bayoneted young Hop
          kins. Hopkins will swear out warrant
          lor the sentry's arrest, but Colonel Cook
          says neither the State or municipal
          authorities have any jurisdiction over the
          inmates of the fort except in case of
          murder, and that there is no way in which
          the gentry can be prosecuted.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1900-07-15/ed-1/seq-29/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>December 1900 :	The new and currently standing main building opens at a cost of $1.5 million.</time>
        <text>
          THE FINE NEW IMMIGRANTSTATION ON
          ELLIS ISLAND—TO BE FINISHED
          BEFORE JANUARY
          The new Immigration Bureau on Ellis Island,
          which has been in course if erection since August, 1898, is nearing completion, and in its
          present condition makes an imposing appearance
          from the New-York shore. Although this is a
          United States building, it has not been erected
          under the direction of the Government Supervising Architect's office, but by the architects who
          received the award In a competition which was
          open to architects all over the United States.
          When completed, the new building will furnish
          roomy and pleasant quarters for the immigrants, where they may be examined, "assorted."
          forwarded or detained, and will In- a great improvement on the present cramped and inconvenient quarters at the Barge Office.
          The building is about 300 feet long and 100
          feet wide. The base is granite, and the building
          proper is brick, with limestone trimmings The
          flat roofs are covered with tile and the sloping
          roofs with copper. The structure is elevated
          about fifteen feet above the landing pier, and
          the distance from the place where the immigrants are landed to the main hall is about one
          hundred feet. This space is a glazed porch
          which will serve as a protection to immigrants,
          as well .is baggage, when they are transferred
          from the barges to the bui.ding. From this
          light and roomy vestibule the newcomers will
          go up a large stone stairway to the upper floor.
          where the Inspections will be made. This room
          is about one hundred by two hundred feet In
          size, and its arrangement, the divisions by wire
          screens, rails an-J partitions, were made after
          careful study of the experiences at the Barge
          Office during the last ten years.
          On the lower floor all the baggage will be
          taken care of. There will be a number of dormitories on the third floor, and the wings of the
          building will be occupied by offices.
          In addition to the main building there will be
          a hospital, a building containing baths and a
          restaurant, a kitchen and laundry building, a
          boiler house, physici ins" house and ferry houses,
          and these will all be connected by covered and
          protected walks. The bull lings will all be uniform in style of architecture and material.
          The architects, Boring &amp; Tilton, have provided
          f rroof gardens in the construi tion of the main
          building These are not positive features of the
          new building, but the roofs are so arranged that
          gardens may b built with little difficulty,
          The contractors are making good progress with
          the work, and hope to have it completed before
          next January. Th •
          cost  the structure will be
          about §I.I.MM NM». which is only about "_ \u25a0
          \u25a0 per cent
          more than the cost •\u25a0! the wooden structures
          which wtre erected on the island a few years
          ago aad destroyed by lire in TUT
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-12-17/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>December, 1900 :	The new and currently standing main building opens at a cost of $1.5 million.</time>
        <text>
          iGAIN AT ELLIS ISLAND.
          IMMIGRANT STATION TO BE
          OPENED rOB BUSINESS TO-DAT.
          impression of th? way thinr* don In the
          /g\,,trs made upon the Immigrant who ar
          l'C here to-day Will a more favorable one
          that made npon his brother who arrived here
          li a k «po. He will pr this country I• the
          the new Immigrant station on Elll»
          t *2a ir.»teaa^, aKEeS tjve of an laclosure for animals than
          tat^ O etv\r.K station for prospective citizens of the
          rrfted Stales.
          %l c pew tulldlnc on Ellis Island, which la be
          "u^'J to-cay for the first time. Is a marked
          1 tT to the Barge Office, with Us dirty, dimly
          tT^ited. cramped, penllke quarters. In place of
          floors and board partitions. l— my and greasy
          c ccntct with the soiled hands and clothing of
          •°u?aofis of immigrants, there are concrete floors
          a irhlte hard surfaced plaster walls. Instead cf
          **rrov. gloomy passages there are epaclous, well
          lighted rooms
          ORNAMENTAL AS WELL aS USEFUL.
          Tb« architects, Borlnp Tilton. have tried In
          itt r.ew I'irildlng to fulfil every practical demand
          in RJC SI a teMhig. and give It besides, architect
          ural fffß*V- They have erected a structure that
          j, cot likely to meet the fate of the great "tinder
          j^j" that did duty m Its elte as an Immigrant
          station ur.ti: it wai destroyed -y fire three and
          one-*'* years ago.
          Th* building tugges:* an exposition hall from th»
          ¦»tw. It Is of re.l brlrk. the de«iirn being picked
          ml with Irnilar.a limestone and Maine granite. In
          «B«sc resr«-ct» the interior resembles that of the
          0 U itriKture which It replaces. The main dl-
          THE EXAMINATION ROOM IN THE IMMIGRANT STATION ON ELLIS ISLAND.
          tlslom are similar. As In the first building, the
          examination* are conducted on the second floor and
          the baggage Is handled on the first floor. The big
          examination room Is two rtorles high. It Is the
          largect room in the building. On a level with the
          third floor a railed visitors' gallery runs around It.
          It Is fringed with the offices of the Immigration
          o9dala, rooms for the meetings of the Hoard of
          Special Inquiry, for records, for the Contract
          Labor Bureau and for more minute medical and
          contact labor examinations. The chief rooms on
          The tMrfl floor are dormitories for detained Immi
          grants.
          GOOD 6ANTTARY CONDITIONS.
          .Extrezas rare has been taken to have th* sanitary
          condiUcr.s as close to perfection as possible. The
          floors are of asphalt, with raised edges around the
          walls, so that they can be thoroughly cleansed with
          water. The walla for seven feet above the floors
          are of X£eene cement. Above this they are of
          white, hard surfaced plaster. There are no cor
          ners where a hose may not be turned. The white
          walls and the dark green trimmings are refreshing
          to their suggestions or cleanliness.
          Everything has been so arranged that the Im
          migrant passes through the station very much
          after the faanlon of a roll of paper through a web
          press. Upon landing at the pier he enters a pas
          sage which leads to the entrance of the examina
          tion building. Once Inside, the passage leads up a
          flight of broad stairs, which turn before reaching
          the second floor, and discharges Its contents onto
          the broad, open floor of the great vaulted examina
          tion room. Here the preliminary medical Inspec
          tion Is made. Th* immigrants Into whose physical
          condition there should be further examination are
          here weeded out and turned Into a room near by.
          The others go forward through numerous narrow
          aisles. These are the parting of the ways. As the
          Immigrants leave them they a;e separated accord
          tag to their destinations.
          THREE PASSAGES FOB EXIT.
          A stairway opens before the Immigrants as they
          leave the aisles. It Is divided into three passages
          by wire screens. Those for New-York now have
          free access to the covered passage to the New-
          York fern* Flip. Those who are to go away by rail
          are taken bark through the building past the ticket
          oSees and the big ttggaga room on the ground
          floor, where the, baggage has been assorted Into
          two divisions, that destined for New- York in one,
          ar.a that going out on the railroads in the other.
          The baggage for the railroads is properly checked,
          and the immigrants are then taken to a steam
          boat landing adjoining the one where they landed
          *n? «-re transported to the railroad stations.
          Those who are detained are ushered into a large
          room to remain until further disposition Is made
          ""them Rccord:rif, to the merits of their cases.
          The char.pe from the old station to the new one
          be a welcome one to the immigration officials,
          l w?' l make their work easiex and pleasanter,
          ¦no give thrm more cheerful quarters.
          The hoppitfc!, the power house and the '.clan's
          nous* win not be ready for occupancy before Feb-
          cEumcm alliaxce service.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1907-12-16/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>December, 1907 : Ellis Island has peak number of immigrants arrive.</time>
        <text>
          In a discussion of the new Immigration act Com
          tnisriiiiii 1 Sargent strongly urges that advantage
          V-« taken of a provision it contains for calling an
          international conference on immigration and emi
          gration. In hi* opinion, now is the time to act.
          lie cays:
          Ther* nssar has be*n a. period when all the prin
          cipal countries of the world v.ere to deenly Inter
          «-st~d in the subject. Several of the leading Euro
          pean countries' have recently either parsed or in
          troduced In their legislatures immigration laws.
          astne of whifh are modelled practically after our
          cum, Some of the jsovernn-.ents are utking noti^
          the idea of adopting measures to discourage
          the *raS£TaUon of tbeir citizens or to indue* their re
          turn others are solicitous lest their subjects should
          lorpet tb*ir allf dance; and altogether th. r. should
          b- »jo Jifflculty in appealing to this BWgkened gen
          *r%\ interest with the object of accomplishing some
          international arrangement and understanding lhat
          -ill work for the general good.
          T Commissioner points out further that, either
          through such an international conference or
          through amendments to this country's law*, ade
          quate provisions thould be made for the issuance
          '-•iaj»rica. By this means s=uch organizations as
          Black Hand Society could not gain a foothold
          Imbk, because the passport would have to bear the
          isccrd of the alien. It would do much, too, the
          Commist.oner believe*, to put an end to the "white
          »4*v*- traffic." although that even now Is under
          j reasonably good control by the immigration of
          ■sMb.
          The financial statement of the bureau of imml
          .fration Fbows that, eft- r the. payment of all ex
          penses;, including nearly J7£0,000 for new construe
          lion, there ■was a net balance on hand on July 1.
          of $3,079,513. The total expense of the execu
          ion of the immigration laws, exclusive of pay
          ments on account of special construction work,
          «as 51,645,373.
          Among the recommendations made by Commis
          inn" Sargent, many of which are administrative
          j in character, are the following:
          i That legislation should be enacted to check vio
          1 iHtion!= of the law by professed seamen.
          i nat marine hospital surgeons be stationed at the
          principal ports of embarkation abroad to examine
          aliens before th v start for America.
          i n surgeons and inspectors, male ani female, be
          placed on vessels of the principal steamship lines
          to examine incoming aliens.
          That arrangements be perfected for the detection
          or members of tho criminal classes who seek to
          come, to the United States.
          That a treaty be negotiated with Mexico respect
          ing immigration through that country: or. if that
          cannot hi- done, that the Mexican border be close.!
          to all except American citizens and bona fide resi
          dents of Mexico.
          That a harmonious arrangement be made with th«
          Canadian government respecting the enforcement of
          the immigration laws of that country and the United
          States.
          That immigration stations be erected at Boston,
          Philadelphia and Baltimore.
          That appropriations be made for improvements
          at Ellis Island. New York Angel Island, San Fran-
          Cisco, and Honolulu.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016244/1954-11-15/ed-1/seq-9/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>November, 1954 :	Ellis Island ends immigration operations.</time>
        <text>
          Ellis Island
          Ends Operations
          NEW YORK, l^i—Ellis Island is
          closed after serving as the gateway to America for millions of immigrants during the past 62 years.
          The tiny island in New York harbor in recent years served chiefly
          as a place to keep deportees. Immigrant clearance abroad reduced
          the number detained on the island j
          to almost nothing.
          Last Friday the last of 50 persons
          still detained on the island were moved to the mainland and Edward J. Shaughnessy, district immigration director, said: "Business
          is closed.”
          The immigration service will
          keep a skeleton crew on Ellis. If
          New York City or some federal
          agency does not take over within a year, the island will revert to
          the governments General Services
          Administration.
        </text>
      </result>
      <!-- 5 additional topics -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1941-06-17/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Island&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.213,-0.071,1.427,1.427,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87075213/1901-04-06/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Island&amp;r=-0.835,-0.112,2.671,1.433,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026897/1895-11-27/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Island&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.28,-0.078,1.56,1.56,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel><time>January 1, 1892 :	The immigration station at Ellis Island officially opens.</time>
        <text>
          ELLIS ISLAND.
          UNCLE S AM'S G ATE WAY FOR THE
          ADMISSION OF IMMIGRANTS.
          Lively Scenes When the Living
          Freight of Several Ocean Steam
          ers ls Landed-A. Lightning
          Money Chaager.
          LTHOUGH a great improve
          ment on the nightmare ar
          rangements that need to ex
          ist for the recep.ion of immi
          grants who landed at Castle Garden,
          Ellis Island, says the New York Recor
          der, is far from being a gateway that
          .would prepossess arrivals from Europe
          in favor of their adopted country.
          The island is tied around from dook
          to dook with miles of red tape. It is
          a fearfully tedious matter to land in
          America and a most unnecessary
          amount of fuss and feathers seems to
          accompany the entrance of a new ar
          rival into the land of freedom.
          A visit to Ellis Island, when the liv
          ing freight of two or tbree ocean
          steamers is being sifted through the
          various avenues leading to the boat
          that trasport8 ir to the Battery, pre
          sents so many phases that it is well
          worth braving the trip in an immi
          grant ferryboat from the Barge Office
          to see the sight. Around the big room
          in the centre of the principal build
          ing on Ellis Island where the sifting
          THE DETE
          process goes on rans a gallery, and
          from this a view of the whole interior
          can he obtained.
          The first stage through which the
          new arrivals pass iii the scrutiny of
          the medical oi?ser.s und the Ellis Isl
          and matrons. Having proven that
          they are free from physical defeuts
          the immigrants are o riven into fenced
          in passages leading io the registration
          officials.
          Through these fe aced avenues the
          unfortunate steerage passengers,
          wearing every variety of eccentric
          and un-American head-gear, and car
          rying as much portable baggage as
          they can stagger under, edge their
          way along foot by foot in the direc
          tion of the gate of hope through
          which alono they caa get to liberty.
          The procession slouches forward at
          the rate of about a foot in ten min
          utes, the delay being caused by the
          laborious attempts of the uniformed
          official tu extract the necessary infor
          mation regarding the incomer's birth
          and .parentage, etc
          Fortunately the official speaks an
          almost infinite variety of languages or
          tho task he has in hand would bc a
          well nigh hopeless one. AB it is, ow
          ing to the nervous condition of the
          immigrant, it usually takes an almost
          interminably long time to drag out
          an answer to the simplest question,
          j Everything has to bo repeated several
          times and explained in the minutest
          J detail and then occasionally the ques
          tioner has to give it up and turn the
          obtuse foreigner over to au assistant,
          j But somehow or other the line
          moves on. Each man and woman
          IMMIGRANTS AT TE
          hitches the family belongings along
          as the space betw?sn them and the
          man in the brass buttons decreases,
          and the hope that springs eternal in
          human breast buoys them up to be
          lieve that some time they will be able
          to pass the official who so jealously
          guards thc-entrance to the open space
          beyond. Ttn their hands the immi
          grants clutch the doouments handed
          to them on boar! ship, for all this
          questioning and registration at Ellis
          Island follows a preliminary cross-ex
          amination before the steerage passen
          gers are allowed to leave the ship.
          The immigrants are ticketed, too-a
          very necessary precaution, for there
          are several steamship line\ all landing
          passengers in a promiscuous mass, and
          without that ticket it would be a Her
          culean task to sep irate one lot from
          the other. So, ticketed and registered
          and served with documents and cross
          examined and pushed and jostled into
          place in the line, the hopeful refugee
          from monarchy-riciden Europe travels
          slowly into thu premised land.
          When the immigrant has passed suc
          cessfully through the ordeal of an
          swering the sharp catechism of the j
          official at tho top of the laue, he is
          handed to the mercies of tho crowd on
          the outside and thenceforth becomes
          common property at tho mercy of
          hotel and boardinghouse runners, rail
          road agentd, well meaaing but offi
          cious missionaries, restaurant keeper*,
          and if he ba lucky enough to have
          theni, relatives nu I friends
          He is u luckies* wight during this
          period of his transition tocitizeuhood.
          First of al, ho must change hit
          money. This can bo clone at the
          island, -where a firm of money brokers
          his purchased the solo right to money
          changing. The immigrants* savings
          are brought from all sorts of extraor
          dinary biding placee, sometimes from
          the depths of stockings, from the* in
          side of waists, where nothing short ol
          a knife or a pair of scissors CHU secure
          its release, from shoes and belts, and
          even from the mouth.
          To watch Money Changer Scully at
          work is one of the most interesting
          sights on the island. The rapidity
          with which he changes into current
          coin of the republio Russian roubles,
          Italian lire, German marks, French
          franc?, English sovereigns and Aus
          trian florins is marvelous. Only one
          glance seems necessary, and the band
          goes down into oue of tho well-filled
          cash drawers. Two or three eeconds
          later and the amount of exchange lies
          before the immigrant with a paper
          showing how much has been exchanged,
          and the bewildered foreigner is told
          to stand back to make room for the
          next applicant. He might as well
          take it for granted that the amount is
          correct (as, of course, it is) for, if he
          looked at it with that air of stunned
          stupidity for au hour, he would not
          know anything more about tho strange
          money than before. Occasionally one
          holder than the rest will make an at
          tempt to challenge the accuraoy oi
          the amount given him, upon which an
          attache of the money changer's office
          unios PEN.
          will take the coins from the immi
          grant's hand and explain the value ot
          each as he drops it baok again. It is
          wasted time, however, as the owner of
          the money is left in as bad condition
          of dense ignorance a*3 ever.
          Money will buy things on Ellis
          Island and the proprietors of tbe
          lunch counter?, where bologna and
          bread appear to be the staple articles
          of food, aro at liberty now to cuargo
          on the mob made hungry by the long
          wait in the lines. The scouts for
          these lunoh counters are indefatiga
          ble workers and certainly earn their
          money. The wonder is, from thc way
          in which the immigrants are almost
          dragged to the bologua counters, that
          some one does nob get hurt in the
          scrimmage. If the greenhorn gets
          through the experience all right and
          survives the bologna, lot him brace up
          to resist the onslaught of the railroad
          agents, who will bear him off bodily if
          he does not keep a sharp look out.
          In this neutral ground at Ellis
          Island the scene ou a busy day is be
          wildering and distracting. The offi
          cials do their be3t to keep the mixed
          mass of humanity in something liko
          order, but with so many nationalities,
          with excited men and women running
          around looking for their baggage and
          for each other, children crying and
          relatives and friends all chorusing a
          welcome together in various lan
          guages, it is no wonder that the scene
          looks like a pocket edition of pande
          monium.
          As fast as possible the immigrants
          are hnstled into the ferry boats and
          transported to the Battery, and grad
          [E LUNOH COUNTER.
          nally the island is deserted by all save
          tho tired offisials and tho detained im
          migrants.
          A sorry-looking orowd is this last.
          From the detention pen they watch
          the fortunate ones who .pass the bar
          rier with envious eyes, looking eager
          ly at every stranger who approaches
          them to see if there is not some hope
          coming from ?some where. In all the
          driven and badgered crowd that passes
          to the boats there is none which is not
          light-hearted, for tho red tape ordeal
          is over. The prisoners in the deten
          tion pen have nothing to buoy them
          up. After eoming all this way to reach
          this land of promise, they get only a
          glimpse and are sent baok to the wil
          derness again.
          One ol the queerest personages on
          the island is the barber. It is hardly
          correct to call his place a shop, for it
          is merely a corner of the big room
          where tho barber has placed a chair
          and hung up a mirror and a towel or
          two. Judging from the condition of
          tho majority of tue immigrants, the
          barber is au institution sadly needed
          at Ellis Island, but few seem to utilize
          his services, advertised at the prices
          of twenty cents for a hair cut and ten
          cents for a shave.
          The crematory at Ellis Idand is an
          other very necessary acsos?ory. Jt is
          not intended for the cremation ot hu
          man bodies, but merely to give the
          clothing of suspicions arrivals a thor
          ough chance to shake ott any disagree
          able associations with infectious dis
          ease or obnoxious insects.
          Fairly good arrangements appear to
          i have been made for the bonsivg cf
          i immigrants who are compelled to stay
          i on tho island over night, tue old pow
          THE BARBER'S CHAIR.
          der magazines having been converted I
          into comfortable sleeping rooms.
          One of tho worst Bourses of annoy
          anoe to the officials are the crowd of
          relations that flock to Ellis Island to
          meet incoming passengers. They are
          always in the most intense state of ox
          citement and it is all that the gate
          keepers can do to prevent them break
          ing down the barriers in the mad rash
          to get inside of the enclosnre.
          There being no police on the island
          it is necessary for the officials to take
          the law into their own hands and
          maintain order by force. It wonld
          be a decided improvement if some of
          the strongest and most reliable mea
          on the island were sworn in to act as
          special policemen.
          An old landmark of the island is
          gradually yielding to the infirmitses
          of age. This is the historical tree on
          which the pirates, Hicks, Wormsley
          and Gibbs, were hanged when the*
          place was known as Ellis Island. The
          tree was damaged during tue storms
          of last winter, and has recently been
          broken off short by the wind. All that
          is left of the tree now is about seven
          feet of bare trunk, and this the Eliis
          Island gardener is making every effort
          i to preserve.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063952/1902-08-09/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Island&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.289,-0.079,1.577,1.577,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93050700/1901-03-11/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Island&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.361,-0.086,1.721,1.721,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>