<topics>  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-harry-houdini</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-01-07/ed-1/?sp=43</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-09-29/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>1</rel><time>September 29, 1906 : Houdini escapes from a piano box.</time>
	<text>PIANO BOX FAILED FAILEDTO FAILEDTO
TO HOLD HOLDHOUDiNI HOLDHOUDiNIMter HOUDINI HOUDINIAlter
After flftyaeven minutes confinement confinementIn
t f In a zinclped imcaped box prepared prepared by em employe employ employes
ploye ploy of the William Knabe Kn1be Piano PianoCompany PtanoCompany PlaneCompany
Company Harry Houdini Jail breaker breakerand breakerand breakerand
and indcuff iidcuff king kln who wa waaUeci was tied band handamljt band1H1 band4i
amljt 4i 1H1 1 to a chair with a rope rop before beforeentering beforefntetn beforeentertn
entering fntetn the case reappeared rea ed on the tbestage thelitage theatae
stage at Chases Chaae last night J just 6n the thestroke thetroke thettroke
stroke troke of midnight midnightlioudioi mldnltrhtHoud101 midnightIloudlot
lioudioi went Into tbe box wearing an anImmaculate an1mmaculate anImmaculate
Immaculate stiff Uff shirt high h collar and anda
a wellpressed evening suit When he hev hewas hewas
v was as next seen hi his collar and tie were weremissing weret wererising
missing t i 5iDg hi hlB hiashirt shirt was wringing wet his histruuscr h hI hisI hisruU5era
I truuscr stuck to him and his h l face faceeh facebhOWCd
I eh bhOWCd owed wtCI plainly that he had fad been en through through1iore throUlh1l through1re
1iore 1l 1re re than he had expected Before B4 Beforeg fore foreging I j jteeing
teeing g sing to hi hY dressing dJealn room HoudinI Houdinlstated HoudinItated loudintstated
stated that fiftyseven minute mInutes wa w was the theIt1l1gest
1 It1l1gest mgest time lie had ever been confined confinedin
in any wooden box boxThe boxThe boxThe
The box waa brought on the stage staget IiItageby stageby
t by y the employee JIUlo and Houdlnis assist assistj1t 18t 18tant 1 1ant
ant j1t and thoroughly inspected by 900 900jf JOOIprsonll 300Jrsons
jf Iprsonll rsons who were compelled to take takeeats taketatB takeats
eats ats on the stage e because standing standingroim atandlnKHllm standingau
roim au rn could not be procured on any anyJloor anyror anytkor
Jloor of the th playhouse playhouseThe playhouaeThe playhouseThe
The committee on holding Houdini Houdinias
v as composed of Chairman J W Clouse ClouseI Clou
1 Iee Anderson Charles Birth Charles CharlesVollmer CharlesVoilmer
Vollmer Y nllmtr William llIIam Ziegler Earl Sanders Sandersand Sandera111 Sandersad I
and Wilt Butler Chairman douse e de dec deCJdld docided
CJdld c id id to put a few more screws screw in the thelX thebx their
lX ir and for fifteen minute his W fellow fellowmmitteemen fellowmmltteemen
4 mmitteemen straddled the case and andimvHl andIIlv and1i
imvHl IIlv 1i CI j screw 8CreW screws into the box as fast a aiwdrivers as aswdrlven asI
iwdrivers I could work worktlouoinl workt worklifluOlni
tlouoinl t 1 nualnl discovered tbe box was wa air airt air1t
11 1t t and asked that a a few small holes holesnored holeshtr holestred
nored htr 80 o a as to allow him to breath breathAt breathAt breathAt
At iu45 1o4 oclock Houdini seated him himself himselfn elf elfin
1 in n a chair cha on o the tJte platform above the theand thei
i S O and announced that he was r ready readylouse ady adyClouse adyJ
J louse and one of the theater em emi emtook
i vesf V e took twenty yard yar s of t brand nw nwe
I e half an inch in diameter and tied tiedi I IMnidini
Mnidini i 5 alinl in a way which the trickster trickster1ilinits trlckstetImits trickstertiiijts
ilinits Imits he b wa w was never bound befor beforeliairman beforc beforIjairman
c liairman Clouse and his men then thenI
I I if fd M d Houdini chair cha Ir and nd rope inside the theshowed theI
S showed everyone thut he was Iili there thereiiiitl tberei
i iiiitl lid u then prepared to put on the lid B Bi Be BeI Be BeI
i sir if J doing this he handed Houdini a astai atal ata1
stai tal card written by a skeptical in iniiKtual inliiiual
iiKtual 11 olual who claimed Houdini had a aml aI aS
S tS ml iOlo I assisting aamUft him At 1100 Houdlnis Houdlnisi
i I plush IU5 spook house was placed placedfr placedfr
I 5 fr f the box This being done the the or orI ortra orplSYed
I atra tra played at a a furious rate and the theiti theliUtne thesettied
iti liUtne Jien e settled down to wait waitJiut waitJt
Jiut as the hands of the stage clock clockjointed clocklinted clock1Inted I
jointed to midnight Houdini jumped jumpeddown jumpedoft
down oft the platform His HI appearance appearanceindicated appearanceindicated appearancelnhcated
indicated that he had a strenuous time timeiusi timethe I
iusi 1l1SIIIe le the case Hi H His arms were scarred scarredny
hy b ny the rope and nd there were blisters on oni onSis
tis i Sis is hands hand Houdini handed the postal postalt
t Mr Close took his hi coat from the thephuiorm theJII1ttorm
phuiorm 11 1 LI Oflfl and andleft led the stage He reap
l pired ired a moment later and assisted the
Knane j nlbe employee in removing the cover coverl c cwertu ver verto
l to tf thft that the box was empty
Houdini congratulated ihe manufac
titer tl ter l of the box box and said it was one oneof onef onet1
of f the th hardest Jobs he had ever under underIt undertlkfn underttkfl
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1907-09-01/ed-1/?sp=36</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-09-23/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
	<rel>1</rel><time>January 7, 1906 : Houdini escapes from a Washington, DC jail.</time>
	<text>WIZARD TOYS
WITH POLICE
HOUDINI HAS FUN AT JAILERS
EXPENSE
EASILY GETS OUT OF THEIR
HANDCUFFS
Man Who Releases Himself from
Crushing Weight of Manacles
Defeats Cleverest Men
on the Force
Houdlnl again baf
fled the police and of
ficers and escaped
from their most dif
ficult hardware last
night at the Orphe
um. Officers Gardner
and La Niece, assist
ed by Jailer Gllpln,
fastened nearly one
hundred and twenty
pounds of shackles
and handcuffs on the
wrists and ankles of
the handcuff king,
from which it took
him exactly eight and
one-half minutes to
escape.
This is the second
attempt made by
these three officers to
defeat Houdlni. On
Saturday evening they
handcuffed his hands
behind his back and
drew the chains of the
leg Irons through the
iandcuff chains. In this difficult posi
tion, which compelled him to crouch upon
his knees, it took Houdinl fifteen min
utes to release himself.
Gardner, La Niece and Gllpin say that
they are not through with Houdini. and
Houdlni says that if it gives them pleas
ure to shackle him they are welcome
every evening. He offered one of the
trio a years salary— Houdlni s, not the
officers— to repeat one of the simplest
of his tricks which the rtflcer had boast
ed of doing. Up to date the offer has
not been accepted.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>1</rel><time>September 29, 1907 : Houdini leaps into a lake heavily handcuffed and shackled, escaping death. He writes about his life and career in a full page spread.</time>
	<text>CROWD HAS
WILD THRILLS
HANDCUFFED MAN LEAPS INTO
THE LAKE
REMAINS BENEATH WATER AN
INTERMINABLE TIME
Harry Houdini Gives Throng of Spec
tators In Westlake Park Two
Minutes of Suspense While
Submerged
Five thousand spectators held their
breath in sympathy with Harry Hou
dini at Westlake park yesterday after
noon when the handcuff marvel did a
Count of Monte Crlsto stunt by leaping
into the lake heavily manacled.
OOoo! I bet hes drowned, said a
small boy in awed and shuddery tones
when the man remained what seemed
an interminable time beneath the shim
mering water of the lake.
A small line of bubbles came to the
surface. Then larger bubbles arose
and a little cloud of mud drifted to tho
top. Five thousand shivers ran down
5000 spines.
Oh, why doesnt he come up? asked
a nervous old lady who had waited
HOUDINI, AS HE APPEAED WHEN
HE LEAPED INTO LAKE YES.
three hours for the opportunity to
worry about the fate of the misguided
youth.
Hes unlocking the shackles. Ho
will be up in a minute or two, said a
high school girl.
Oh, dear, a minute or two Is enough
for him to drown In, was the dismal
reply.
Aw, hes stalling, shouted an Irre
pressible urchin.
No hes not. He has to get them
shackles off first. He cant swim with
them on. This from a bright lad with
a wire bridle on his teeth who waited
two hours and went home with an
autograph which read: Harry Hand
cuff Houainl.
A man on the landing threw off his
coat and ran to the edge of the planks
looking intrntly into the water.
Hes going to jump, shouted the
throng.
Hes stuck In the mud. Someone
has got to rescue him, shouted a wise
guy who had seen Houdini Jump from
a bridge thirty feet high into 300 feet
of water or 300 feet high into thirty
feet of water. The crowd never got It
straight.
More bubbles. More mud. Then
Houdini canre slowly to the surface
feet first!
I told you hed stuck his head into
the mud. said the wise guy. Then the
feet disappeared. A second later Hou
dinis head bobbed to the surface. He
made it dramatic and shivery enough to
satisfy even the small gamin who had
half hoped to see a drowning or at least
aTthrllHuK rescue scene.
Laden with heavy chains and hand
cuffs enough to restrain the county
road gang Houdini leaped from the
roof of the pavilion at Westlake park.
His hands were shackled behind him.
TbTM biff uatrolmen attended to that
little detail. There are some members
of the force who would have liked to
have defeated the handcuff king even
beneath the water.
With no free hand to guide him in
the headlong dive the mans body shot
forward in an almost horizontal posi
tion. With an indescribable midair
kick he righted himself and made a
pretty but dangerously vertical dive.
The shutters of 800 cameras clicked In
unison and the awful suspense began.
The horror only ended when the mans
smiling face appeared above the water
of the lake.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel></rel><time>July 16, 1914 : Shackled Houdini escapes from a box after being thrown into the water.</time>
	<text>CROWD OF 15.000
WATCHES HOUDINI
Handcuff Expert, Shackled and
Boxed. Is Thrown Into Water
Rises in a Minute.
Fifteen thousand people in Battery
Park yesterday noon, cither saw or
tiied to sec Harry Houdini, known a?
the ?handcuff k,r.j.r. thrown into the
water from the tug J. A. McAllister.
The cro\?d surged back aril forth
the water fronl with such force
that those in the front row alonn the
???a wall eed ab? tit miI, aided by po?
licemen, ri: I ack into the
park
pu-heI into I n .or.
In the meantim? Houd ?vas having
all hard t ?me .?ii\ inu a**:
nioir, picture photographers who in-
sisted upon reeling off his font di
id thai he had his 0?vn staff of
film-makeri on hand.
All these little troubles being I
tied, the newspapermen put the leg
irons and two pair of handcuff on
He ?va- then p;i: ii a pack?
ing box, the cover was nailed down and
boui ?tl steel tape, the whiatli
the tugboat end the P. D, 7 I
rerboard ?vent the box, Houdini
and -dl.
In about one minute he appeared al
the surface. He had done it once be?
fore a-id had lived to hear the crowds
cheer him The spectator
r ting, some sr.ying that he k.-pt
the ke; s h ick hair, other? thai
art genius.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1916-04-18/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel><time>April 18, 1916 : Houdini is set to perform his legendary straitjacket trick 100 feet in air.</time>
	<text>Houdini to Be Hanged
In Strait jacket at High
Noon Here Tomorrow
Handcuff King to Dangle 100
Feet In Air Before Crowds
At 12:30 oclock.
WILL .EXTRICATE HIMSELF
Expert Knot Tiers Will Superin
tend Exhibition, to Which All
Are Invited.
Harry Houdlnl has heen cordcmned
to be hanged! i
Ho will bo hanged at 12:30 tomorrow
In front of the Munsoy building In plain
view of all of tho thousands of Wash
lngtnr.tanu who can gather on Pennsyl
vania, avenuo.
The Handcuff King has escaped
from ovciythlng tho pollco or saVty
llrst artists of all sorts havo designed
to confine a vicious criminal and now
ho will reach tho end of hit rope!
Tho end of tho rope will danglo 100
feet In mldnlr from the front of tho.
Munsey building -and Houdlnl will bol
attached to it by tho feet with, all tho
Ingenious knots the police or anybody
elan can devise
Arms To Bo Rigid. I
Ho wil also havo his arms securely I
bourn, to his body and his body made
rigid with the most approved type of
straltjacket. All of these things will
be done to Insure the thorough hanging
of tint worker of magic.
And Houdlnl doclarea he will hang
only long enough to loose himself from
His lncumorances!
He laughs at tho proposition to hang
him. and declares those In charge of
the operation can go as far as they
like. He guarantees that he will free
himself. And It Is agreed that he shall
go fieo If ho docs get loose.
Tho rrocidura to be followed will bo
to confine Houdini in a regulation
straltjacket. A Jacket and two
husky attendants have been secured.
The men are experienced In restraining
dai.gcioiudy Insane patients. They havo
been instructed to use the most ap
proved Jacket a tvpo from which no
escape has ever been recorded.
Houdini hasnt seer, the Jacket that
vlll bo used apd will not see it until
they put It on him The two attendants
will see to It that tho Handcuff King
Is placid in tho Jacket In a way they
havo of putting men in Jicketa of the
samo kind for keeps. They state they
will put Houdlnl in the jirket for keeps,
as no ono they havo over put into one
of them has ever gotten out.
In Air 100 Feet.
Then a rone will bo nttached tn Hon.
dlnls fet so that It will not come oil
ana tacKlo will bo attached to this
rope with which Houdlnl will be hoist
ed up about 100 feet and will dangle,
head down for
The exact length of time he will dan
gle Is all up to Houdlnl. Tho men
In charge will do It so well that they
Insist he will dangle until they let
him down. Houdini thinks otherwise.
He claim ho will be thero long enough
for an average person to wriggle an
oyellu about three times in deliberate
succession.
Ho wants Just a minute or two and
then ho claims he will free himself,
throw off the straltjacket and when
he wave his arms, tho tackle men
aro to let htm down.
Put he will not be lowered until ho
hns relvnecd himself ibsolutely from
thn straltjacket.
Tho tltnn Ih M-30 tomorrow.
Thu pluca Is In front of the Jlumey
building.
r.veniody In Washington Is Invited
to cheer Houdlnl or thu policemen
and nsylum attendants who think ho
cant get nway.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1918-01-06/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-12-28/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090862/1958-10-10/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1951-11-16/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1952-10-03/ed-1/?sp=9</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88063294/1944-08-27/ed-1/?sp=89</id>
	<rel>0</rel><time>BLNK</time>
	<text>VAUDEVILLES GREATEST
What act was vaudevilles greatest attraction?
None other than Harry Houdini, The Handcuff
King. Some of the escapes” Houdini staged for
publicity purposes were better thin his act. For
example, Ins escape from a packing box tossed
into a river. Abo his es ape after being thrown
into a river heavily shackled. Also his getting out
of a strait jacket and h: many escapes after being
locked in supposedly escape proof cells. Nobody
has ever been able to successfully imitate Hou»
d:ni. However, Harry didnt accept all challenges.
A Gloucester, Mass., fisherman said he would tie
Houdinis thumbs behind his back and then bet
a thousand dollars the Handcuff King couldnt
get out of the knot. Houdini wouldnt try it.</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024808/1920-07-19/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
	<rel>1</rel><time>December 28, 1919 : Houdini preserves his tricks on film for prosperity.</time>
	<text>Houdini Is Baffled
by His Own Trunk;
Locksmith Called
Special Dispatch l Great Falls Dally
Tribune and Chicago Tribune.
Now York, July 18.— Harry Houdini
who gets out of locked trunks, wrig
gles free from handcuffs and lets you
tie him with knotted ropes only to
prove he is superior to all these
things met his match here when he
tried to unlock his trunk for the
customs officials* He bent over it, in
serted the key and twisted it. The
result approximated those of the
John W. Davis boom at San Fran
cisco. There was none.
The customs men smiled tolerantly,
being glad to humor the worlds
greatest non-finger-printed jail break
er in his little pleasantries. Mr.
Houdini smiled, too, ventured a
jocular remark about the weather.
Then he twisted it the other way.
Nothing doing. He sat on the trunk,
kicked it, tried the key again. A lock
smith was brought and he put a key
in the lock and the lid popped open.
Hühl said the locksmith.
Huh! yourself, said Houdini.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic></topics>