<topics><topic>
  <!-- topic 2 -->
  <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
  <results>
    <!-- article 1 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>March 4, 1897: Escaping gas in Boston Subway during construction creates havoc; many killed by explosion; half a hundred injured.</time>
      <text>
        Escaping Gas in Boston Subway
        Works Great Havoc.
        HALF A HUNDRED INJURED
        PnsHlng Electric Cnr "Wrecked and
        Adjoining Ituildiiigg Itadly Dam
        aged Partial Liht of Dead and
        Disabled Accident Occurred ut
        Treuiunt and lloylbtoti Streets.
        Boston, March 4. An explosion lias just
        occurred in the subway excavation at the
        corner of Trcraont and Ooylston streets.
        Three electric cars that were passing
        at the time were wrecked and one ot
        them was burned. Several bulldingsin the
        vicinity were more or less damaged.
        The explosion was caused by escaping
        gas.
        Among the buildings damaged are the
        Hotel Pclliam, the Knickerbocker and
        Head buildings and the Masonic Temple.
        Window glass in buildings within 200
        feet of the scene of the explosion were
        shattered.
        At least twelve persons were killed.
        Four bodies have been removed to un
        dertaking' rooms.
        Forty-two persons arc at the Emergency
        Hospital.
        Among the dead are:
        Rev. W. A. Slack, professor at Tufts Col
        lege. G. I). Bigclow, conductor.
        Unknown man and woman.
        The injured include James Reardon, John
        J. O'Conuor, Thomas F. Ford, Mrs. J. R.
        Wilson, Nellie Jackson, Lucy Dolan, F.
        W. Tceling, and Mrs. F. A. reck
        There seems to be no doubt thatatleast
        eight persons were immediately killed.
        The explosion came Jutt as the streetcars
        were almost in the ceutcr of the space at
        the corner.
        The first car was In the center when the
        explosion came. The whole of the wood
        work, which is used as a bridge over the
        subway, was lifted into the air, carrying
        the first car with it and taking along the
        two horses of the second car. The other
        Tehlcles were lifted straight into the air,
        but came down on the tracks. Instantly
        the air was filled with flying debris.
        The firat electric car, the one in which
        most or the killed were riding, no sooner
        reached the track than It broke in hair,
        and the whole portion Immediately burst
        into flame. Then someone sounded a fire
        alarm. This brought a large rescue force
        to the scene, and almost immediately calls
        were being sent out hurriedly for the am
        bulances. It was an awful Eight that met the gaze
        of those who were first on the scene. In
        the center was the long blazing electric
        car. .Close beride this were the bodies ot
        the two horses killed instantly, and about
        ten, twenty, thirty feet away from where
        the woodwork of the car was blazing lay
        the dead and wounded people. Those who
        wore not injured in the cars on Boylston
        6treet were Incapable ot action
        at first, and people in the buildings and
        stores surrounding did not know what had
        occurred, but it did not take them long
        to secure their senses, and almost imme
        diately there was a rush to the assistance
        ot the wounded.
        It is stated that there was not a person
        on the three cars who was not injured, and
        all the wounds received were severe. Im
        mediately stores and offices were con
        verted into temporary hospitals until am
        bulances could arrive. 1 1 was a gruesome
        spectacle to see these bodies exposed on
        the sidewalks.
        Hose carriages were pressed into service
        as ambulances, and immediately they were
        started on their humane duty or getting the
        maimed to the hospitals.
        It Is supposed that-one of the dead women
        at Jones' undertaking rooms Is Mrs. A. M.
        Bates. She was out wlth a sister this
        morning and has not returned. The sister
        returned home slightly injurcd
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 2 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>March 4, 1897: Escaping gas in Boston Subway during construction creates havoc; many killed by explosion; half a hundred injured.</time>
      <text>
        UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
        T1IK BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COM?
        PLETED AND IN OPERATION.
        A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
        TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
        TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
        The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
        of whli h has Ju il b >a op? n? -i for at rvlce. is an
        em.???? of more than local Interest The ne
        eesslty for some relief t? the i rowded thorough?
        fares above it can besl be appre? lat? d, of course,
        by H lonlans; but tl?.- Modem Aib.n.s is i?; no
        means th.ily cltj In this countr) which is
        beset with problems of the same character.
        ThofO who :ii" familiar v.iih "!h&lt;- lay of tiie
        land" in Bosl? n remember thai Tremont-st. runs
        In a ajenerall) north-and-aonth direction and
        forms ihe istern boundary of th.- Common.
        Ii i-; intersected by Rovlston-st., which consti?
        tutes Ihe southern boundary of thai historic
        parle On the Boylsl m and Tremonl st edges
        of the Common there is a broad promenade.
        known as the Mall. The main part of the sub?
        ira. li. h Is w Id nough to a? commodate four
        tracks, passes under ihe Tremonl st. Mall, and.
        niter passing under Park-st, which lies along
        the northern side if ine Common, extends mr
        will extend, when completed) to Scollay ?Square,
        thence eastward to Adams Square, ami finally
        up northward again to Hayraarkel Square.
        This terminus Is close to the great union rail?
        way station .it the North End.
        Ft en th.- oin, r of Tri mont and Boylston sts.
        there are two extensions, wldn enough f>?r only
        a double track. Boylston st. Mall for about '.k"> feet, and then
        ascends an Incline through an op? n ul for ,'il*
        feel The terminal station for this branch la
        situated In th- Public Gardens. The other
        branch reaches away to the southward, and. on
        nearlng th&lt;- Junction of Bhawmul ave. and Tn
        mont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline
        leads up into each of those streeta
        Including th? Inclines, ihe subway has a total
        length of about a mile and a half, und will con?
        tain about five miles of track Al present the
        branches from th.rn.-r of Boylston and Tre?
        monl Bl.-. and th-- main line up to Park-Si. an
        In operation. A great >l&lt;-.il o? work has already
        been done on the northern portion of the route,
        arid it is h? i I thai everything all) be finished
        within th> n \t eight months. Hi und wats
        broken for the subway in April, 1805, twenty
        Bine month- ago.
        The depth of this underground passageway Is
        1 I f. t. The Width IS L'i feel for I WO T.|. l(S, .11,d
        18 feel f.-r f? ur. Al Int rvala of sis r- et, along the
        side.-, si--. I posts are b&lt; t up on at.1 foundatl >nB,
        and from the tops of those on one side there
        r? rn h a? n i to the top ..f o, i th? r
        stul roof beams. Where there arc four tracks
        there is a c? ntral lia.f posts in the turn I, In
        addition to those along the sides, From one
        ro i am t.? the n&lt; sl th? re cxl nd an ai h of
        ma t.ry. These su&lt; Iv? ai hi f. mil I hi
        roof, an covered with coni-rete; ind th?
        mat? lal HI th? pace betWi'.-i
        the Bides. A waterproof I
        i In es iding from I .....a, wat&lt; r that
        other? leak n fi ml ill. Th? m i
        ?onry floor is d, like an Inv? rted ar. h,
        an l al ng II ?rural line iher? r in i a dra n At
        Int? r\ ala the train a pit, from
        which, whem ver the wat? r rises to a
        level, the contents arc withdrawn bj auti i il
        ally con troll? I 1?. :r,,- pumps
        V? ntllatlon Is ff? '.-l by hui i ?l irj ran
        establish? d in masonrj it thi or four
        pointa along the i ne. The air Is suck l out of
        the subway, and forced upward thi ugh the
        op nfnga to Ihe level of ihe ?trei-i, ll u dr&lt; I of
        Im and? m i ctrlc imi and scores of an
        Hghta ai i advanl ig? i al ?ng Ihe in
        terl? r. As clectrlelt) i>d for th?
        propulsion of the i ara hi? h i il
        th? r.- la i. smoke lo a? umulat? i n the -Mings,
        and no foul gases to offend the fa i rv?i
        Tin-re is no reason why th? pla h ..-1 n I r?
        main lean, sweet and bright for years.
        AI th? und? rground r irse, the
        subway is broaden? I A high Air? fenc? runa
        lengthwise In the middle, irallng the two
        noi thboui -1 tr u from the tw?i soul hi un I.
        The tra- lu of e.i., t, p.ur are Ivided i rial n
        gineers call an "island platform." saj feel
        wide, and 300 or IfSJ feel long. Ace? i.m tie
        had to on? platform from the ??(her onlj b) pro
        Ing down a low flight of ita ai i through a
        narrow bul brightly Illuminated pas age undei
        n- ath, oi i going up i the street and rosslng
        iv? r.
        The cara v. hi, h run Ihn ugh the tunnel ar- oi
        ("..i irj li lej cars, but, iik.- many which tra-.
        i other rout? In t!:-- i ty, th? y are all con?
        trolled by one ror|ioratliin, Ihe West Knd Street
        Hallway Company, to which, by the way, the
        subwaj la- lieen leased by th? Tran t Commis
        i neri 'iii fact partially explains some of the
        pri au ?i taken al the stations. Then one
        buys a ii ki t In lure h >a riling i.u or Hing a,
        rhan? e to do o, are) thi ndui lor on I h? car col
        lecta Ihe Ll? kets, Kill fn m th? i tatlon i lat
        Is effected Ihrouul lun les, wbi&lt; b a.. >w
        a person to pa In onlj ?in dh i ion.
        in. id, easy stall rid d n n from Ih I reel
        r? the und und statloi 'i i
        more than thirty Btej In a (light Th ai
        two flights for He northbound tracks, ind two
        f ?r the Bouthl ?ui I The h ud of a li
        i.; in loa d by a neat oni tory, gla
        granite b ill lin Glazed white i?i i. i&lt; and i I? lit)
        ?,f whit.- paint Impart to ihe station interlora
        a fresh and the r> appearance. At present t?..-
        BOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE PUBLIC GARDEN.
        ?nly stations in use underground are at the cor
        ner of Boylston and Tremont sts. ami at Park-st
        A temporary loop at the latter point permits
        the northbound cars to return without switch?
        ing. When the subway is completed, however.
        there uiii i.ther stations at Si o lay Square,
        Adams Square and Hay market Square.
        miy an engineer can begin to understand
        th.- difficulties of an undertaking lik?- this
        Count leas sewers, a ater-plpcs, gasplp? s and tele
        phon? -Air.- conduits have been laid close to the
        route, and Bom of ih.s,- have been bared dur?
        ing the prigresa of the necessary excavation.
        When ihelr position was at a higher level than
        the r..of ,,f the future subway it was not neces?
        sary to do ne re than lo protect them carefully
        f.r the lime. Bui if the) were lower than the
        roof, and higher than the Boor, the situation
        was root, serious. Two great water mains, one
        thirty Inches In diameter and the other forty
        BOSTONS NEW SUBWAY FOUR-TRACK SUBWAY UNDER TRKMONT-ST.
        Inches across, ?ere encountered at that very in
        invenlent level, It became necessary to con
        utru t siphons, bending down under the subway
        and up agiln on the other Bide, in order to ad
        ju-t these conflicts of Interest. Kor the happy
        solution of all th.-:- difficulties great credit is
        ,'-j to th? t'ity Commission Intrusted with the
        work, to their 'hlef ngli.r, and, in some meas?
        ure, t. the engine, rs of the West End Company,
        An Incidental l j: I mi orlant f. ature of tlie
        plan of construction Is the avoidance of grade
        i rossinirs. In the four-track passageway the
        Iloylston-st. ears have the two inside tracks,
        and the Tremont-st and Bhawmut-ave. ears use
        the two outer ones in common. Accordingly,
        at th" southeastern corner of the Common, the
        westernmost track (southnound) is carried down
        Under the two central ones, by a special one
        track tunrnl which soon emerges With another
        one-track tunnel carrying th>- up-track. At a
        point still further south a similar plan Is pur
        sued in th.- separating of the Bhawmut-ave. and
        Tremont-st. cars
        Tie- cipa. Ity of the subway is ninety cars
        per mit,ute. Inasmui h as th" facilities thus af?
        forded :ir.- Buppli mentary to th.me already af
        forded on Tremont-st., and an- not a substitute
        for the latter, a distinct increase In the number
        of punes, as well as freedom from blockades,
        bas been secured
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 3 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>
        THE BOSTON SUBWAY
        SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE
        STREET CAR PROBLEM.
        Contention of Trafllc In tli? Iluny Streets
        of the Uub Relieved by Underground
        Trolley Lines?Tunnels Tlmt Am Light,
        Clean uud Attractive.
        It is now possible to cross Tromont
        street, Boston, at any point opposite tho
        Common and at any time of day without
        loss of life or limb. Tho new subway has
        brought about tho change.
        It 1 s an old tradition that tho fathers of
        Boston, when thoy laid out tho city, let
        the. streets follow the winding cow paths.
        At any rate, the streets ius thoy exist today
        urc very crooked and must of them aro
        very narrow. This was all right in Revo?
        lutionary times, but when the city grow
        miles beyond tho Common und spread it?
        self out to tho south and west; when busi?
        ness centered itself along tbu lower ends
        of Washington and Trentont streets, and
        when dozens of street car tracks usurped
        tho narrow roadways, then the Bostonlans
        wished their ancestors bud not stuck so
        closely to the cow paths.
        Probably no other city on the continent,
        was ever so badly allllctcd with a conges?
        tion of trnllic as tho Hub haslieon for
        many yea: Some of tho most important
        street ear linen skirt tho south and east,
        cornets ol the Common on Boylston mid
        Tremont streets. When I he chango was
        made hum hoc. epov.vr to trolley, matters
        grew worse. Then tho poles and the tan?
        gle of overhead wires made that historic.
        breathing spot look liko a pieco of dingy,
        green billiard cloth which had become fray?
        ed and tuttered around the edges. So after
        much wrangling in tho legislature and
        courts it w;ls decided tu build the subway
        and put the trolley cars underground.
        A large portion of the work bus already
        lieen accomplished and Boston is delight?
        ed with the result. The first thing a Hus?
        ton man asks a visitor from Now York,
        Chicago or elsewhere is:
        "Been through tho subway yet'/ Let's
        see?you huven't one in your place, have
        you?"
        It is, in fact, a triumph of engineering
        anil well worth a visit. Then! arc throe
        open cut.s where tho trolley curs enter the
        subway. One Is out on Tremont street
        whore Shawmut avenue comes in. Hero
        the tracks from each of those jmorough
        fares dive into the tunnel. Another is In
        the Public gardens, where the cars com?
        ing down Boylston street take tho under?
        ground tlip. The third is at tho northerly
        end of the subway, just beyond-Hay mar?
        ket square and in front of the new Union
        terminal railroad station into which the
        Fitchburg, Hoston und Maine, Eastern
        und other roads run. Theru is u. loop hern
        DOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE Plin
        LIC ns most of the t rolley lines inako it their
        terminus, and, the subway being four
        tracked, they disgorge their passengers
        and take the back track up town.
        Including the inclines or open onto, tho
        subway has a total length of 1 miles and
        will contain about live miles of track. At
        present the branch down Boylston street
        along the Common side and the main line
        down Tremont to Park street are in oper?
        ation. The Shawmut avenue branch and
        tho northerly end of the main lino will be
        finished within the next eight months.
        Ground was broken for the subway in
        April, 18115. The sum appropriated was
        $7,ii(?0,000 and, wonderful to relate, tho
        transit commissioners say that it is proba?
        ble the cost will bo about $1,000,000 less
        than that sum.
        No groat difficulties have been encoun?
        tered thus far in digging this big liplo In
        the ground. Of course there were count?
        less sewers, water pipes, gas pipes, electric
        wire conduits and the like und some -III
        inch water mains at an inconvenient level
        proved rather hnrxl to handle, but n? un?
        expected conditions arose to delay tho
        work. The main trunk of the subway
        runs under the wide walk or mall on tho
        east side of the Common, anil when the
        excavations were being made the bones of
        hundreds of old Puritans were disturbed.
        This raised a bowl of righteous Indigna?
        tion,and the sncredness of the long forgot
        burying ground was harped upon for
        weeks. Hut the commissioners quieted
        the reverent patriots by collecting nil tho
        bones and roiuterrlng them in the holy
        ground of the Common, with a nice monu?
        ment to mark the spot.
        The tleepest jioint of tho subway is on
        Boylston street, where the south bound
        t racks are laid lit) feet lielow the surface,
        but the average depth is 14 feet. The tun?
        nel itself is a giant bore with ribs of steel
        mid casings! of cement, asphalt, concrete
        and masonry. The roof is a series of
        arches und the floor Is concave, with
        drains at the bottom. As tho drnins are
        below the level of the sewers, jilts have
        been established at Intervals, and when
        thev are filled with water automatic elec?
        trical pumps are started, which empty
        them Into tho sewers above.
        Perhaps yon imagine that Boston's sub?
        way is a tlark, damp, ill smelling place. It
        is nothing of the sort. The entrances to
        the stations aro handsome structures of
        stone, with glass roofs. The only fault, to
        be found with them is that thev remind
        cs?blc. It makes food shortened
        it i3 uahcaltb.ru! and filled with
        icd by every medical r.::d culi- B
        1
        vegetable oil is nutritive, digest-
        i
        coil. Itisnu
        :d with or fried
        armful results.
        md yoll^w tins,with
        u((nM-/ililii( urc.il??
        way. lladounlyby
        1 PAN Y,
        Montreal. ^?-?n?? _^ff* fa
        you or an olo Urccinn tomi)?ft" least that
        is what I thought of the first time I saw
        one. Put then you go down an easy (light
        of wide stone steps to n cheerful, brilliant?
        ly lighted station. Everything Isdazzllug
        ly white. The bricks lining the entrance
        art? of glazed white porcelain, the mason?
        ry arches are painted white and the iron
        pillars and supports arc covered with im?
        maculate white; enamel. Incandescent and
        are lights Hash everywhere, and the vista
        nhead through tho stretches of the subway
        is far from u dingy one. It. Is about tho
        cleanest und neatest holu In tho ground in
        existence and no doubt will be kept so.
        Already lifo tralllo on Tromont and Duyl
        ston streets has been much decreased, ami
        when tl;e subway is fully completed Bos?
        ton foil: may get about their town with
        comparative ease und safety.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 4 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>
        BOSTON'S UNUSED SUBWAY.
        ft) H' VMDBnOltOVSD TBAXBITA TAILURE
        j jjv oxvU x. rjtA otice.
        Ij aYeople Reniie ta L'se It. Jot as Thfir Wonld
        .1' the Hot la tbo Cronna Transit rropwed
        J'v fbr Wew .rk Only Keren Per Cent, ef the
        M Total Tronic Credited ta the flatmar The
        j rreniable rnney TraDI o Lost to It Entirely
        Jf Vat tba Condlllem Are nl Farorablr
        BbS. Beaten Want, an Klevatrd nallraad Hon,
        'sflf "H Before any farther attempt la mado to com'
        i V Bait tbli eltr to the building of the proposed
        jH underground system of rapid tranalt it would
        H be well for every ono Interested to learn somo-
        ll thing of the experience which Boston Is now
        I lusTlng with Its subway. Boston's subway Is
        li'H New York's proposed underground railroad In
        L S miniature, excopt that It was constructed for
        I H the use of the trolley car lines Instead of being
        I V equipped with cars, motors, and power of Its
        I H own, and mnnlnir two sets of trains one express
        tf( I and one local.
        The Boston subway short. That part now
        jkVM tense Is less than ft mile In length, and the
        KS farts which are under construction or proposed
        R M Would add only about another mile to the tun
        Hk wr Bet, There lr, perhaps, no finer specimen of
        Jl&amp;B passenger tunnel work any whero In the world,
        aBfYS n ls doubtful -f anymore perfect tunnel
        HtjH could Deconstructed.
        B9p The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and
        HHk Its extensions are to go under Cornhlll, Han
        JJ. oxer street, and Washington streot, passing
        i right through the denso business and shopping
        districts, and thus securing every advantage
        I that a road might have If It ran through Broad-
        jf Tray, Fourteenth street and Twenty-third street,
        i and part of Sixth avenue. And yet. In the face
        j ef all these advantages, three months' experi
        ence has shown that the Boston subway is not
        popular, that people will not go Into It ex-
        cept when they have to, and that the subway Is
        lv a failure, save so far as It was a necosslty to re-
        i'i Have the congestion of traffic on the street.
        V XEED OF TUB BUDWAT.
        A Bostonlans are proud of the subway. They
        ri take strangers to see It, just as they take them
        h to see Bunker IIIll Monument; make them ride
        vM the length of It back and forth, and call alien
        s' I tlon to all its fine foatures and then they keep
        I away from it themsolves. Just as thoydofrom
        if the monument. That this result ls of tntorest
        I V to New Yorkers there can be no doubt. Tho
        building of tbo subway growoutof a publloneed
        Tfhloh was as absolute and pressing as the need
        v ef this city for some addition to Its trafllo
        in. facilities.
        Hien, about ten years ago. the West End
        oet Railway Company began to transform tho
        horso car lines of Boston Into electric trot
        lines the narrow streets In tho heart of
        iton were already choked with tho dally rush
        vehicles. Boston has to-day tho most ex
        stve and comprehensive electrlo car system
        the world. The added cars which wero re
        red for tho now service fairly filled
        i streets of the little central city
        ere they were all concentrated. These
        lines eorvo a suburban population of
        trly a million persons, and it is possible to
        ;e a car for any part of the territory covered
        .hoot going more thai a quarter of a mllo In
        i city. Under a special act of the Lcglsla
        e the Boston Transit Commission was ap
        nted to devise a suitable means to relieve the
        Station.
        THE OrERATIVB COWTnAOT.
        fader this commission tho subway wns
        nned and is being built. Tho city of Boston
        s for it and leases it to tho West End Street
        llway Company for twenty years at an an
        il rental which is not to be less than 4Ts per
        it. upon the net cost of the tunnel, or more
        ,n .Ts per cent, upon tho sum of $7,000,000,
        he tunnol should cost so much, and tho com
        ly agrees to pay. in llou of interest, a toll of
        nts for each car that passes through the
        way. In caso the aggregate of tolls should
        :eed the interest charges. The railroad com
        ly cares for it, lights it, ventilates it, ana
        ips It free from wator. i
        fork was bosun on the subway on March 28,
        13, and on Sept. 1 of this rear the first scc
        o was put Into use. A second socllon was put
        o use on Sept. 30. The main part of tbo sub
        y now in use lies usdor Tremont street, bo
        sen Park street and Boylst:n street. This
        lion 'Is 1,700 feet long and contains four
        cks. At both ends aro stations, built
        nmodlously under ground and approached
        m the surface by wide, easy stair
        ye. wulch are protected by small or
        mental stone buildings. At the BoyI
        in street station the tunnel divides into
        o two-tracked sections. Ono of these con
        ues under Tremont street for about 1,200
        it, whon its comes to tho surfaco and empties
        cars upon the tracks in Tremont street and
        awmut avenue, which hero diverge. The
        ler branch turns sharply to the wostward,
        asunder the edge of tho famous Common, to
        Public Oarden beyond Ohnrles street, where
        comes to tho surfaco, 1,200 foet from the
        ylston streot station, and its cars goon tholr
        y down Boylston street,
        man standahd or coxsTitucnos.
        The tunnel Is kept almost as light as day
        im end to end. At the stations It ls lined on
        sides with enamelled white brick. Through
        t its length and on tho codings at tho
        itlons It Is pnlnted white. At tlio su
        ns and through the tunnol electric
        hts aro hung In abundance, and to make
        re that these shall not all fall at any ono tlnio
        5y are divided nnd fed by two scparato clr
        Its of wire, resides these lights, fixed In the
        itnel, are the lights In tho passing cars, which
        kept lit In making the tunnel passage. As
        oorthreocarsaro passing In each direction
        ery minute almost all the tliuo, their lights
        me would keep it fairly well illuminated.
        People doclare that they found the tunnel ro
        ishlngly cool during the warm woather In Sep
        nber Just after it was oponed, and In cold
        lather they find It warm. No winds penetrato
        and the moraont a porson gets to tho stairs at
        itatlon he Is out of rench of storms. Only ono
        jrce of discomfort has yet developed In tho
        e of the tunnel, and that. It U belloved,
        11 be remedied. This was, for the tlmo
        lasted, a very groat trouble. It occurred
        it month, when there had been a sudden
        ange of 25 or 30 degrees in temperature,
        oweathorhad been cold for thrco or four
        ys, and the ground and tho Inside of tho tun
        Ibadgotchillod until It was pretty nenrly as
        Id under ground as on the surface. Thcncume
        isoln tlio general teniperaturo of 23 or 30
        grees. Tbo warm air. drawn Into tho tunnol
        the ventllnting fans, struck against the
        lllod roof and sides, and Immediately every
        log began to weep. The cold roof and sides of
        e tunnel condensed tho moisture In the
        irraer air, and In a short tlmo the
        jole Interior glistened with molsturu.
        the stations tho condition was worst nnd pro
        ced much discomfort. Here the air entered,
        dof course gavo tin the greater part of its
        ilsture. Most of tho moisture collected on tho
        ling nnd dripped dnujion thn waiting passen
        rs. People who had loft pleasant neathar
        stairs found themselves exposed to trick
        m streams below. It wns so bad that tbo
        llroad company sot men to work scrnp
        K down the roofs and Bides with riihbcr
        urezers to gut rid of tho moisture. Even
        this troiiblo cannot bo cured, tbo mil
        sd officials do not believe that It would prove
        serious consequence, bcciuso thero aro not
        aro than thrco or four duj s In a year when
        angrs of tetnpernturo uro wldo enough to
        oduco tho drip.
        REFL'SALOr THE run MO TO I'BK IT.
        rho portion of (ho Bubnnyi use nt tlio pros
        tllmo Is open fortrnvel from OoYlocl; A. M.
        12 midnight cturlni; cwli day of tlio Muck.
        lorenro at present 1,302 trips per duy being
        n through ttio subway.
        Vet hero Is the Bignilleaut fact; n study of tint
        lly travel In tho Hiibnn-.. hour by hour and
        y by day for months, Khiincd conclusive!)-, In
        o judgment or tho,o who arc mont closely cou
        nted, that the sub.va) U nut piipulnr.nm! that
        Vf porsons tuo It, except w hen thev hnotn.
        'esldcnt Littlo declares that this is aiiuuli
        oro serious mutter than It would upniar to tliu
        Initiated,
        j THE KAKOV TIIAKKIO AVOIIIH IT,
        B "In tho rush hours," he said, recently, In ills
        jBA cussing tho matter, "I hit people in list tnke
        HI every means of coiio)nnco that I here is at
        t I hand. In these hours they Dock Into tlio sub-
        Fii way as freely us they do In tliu ears i mining on
        K, the surface, and during these hours nn carry
        eH'-l about as many In the subway as It U possible
        tJi for us to handle Iheront tboprnsotit time,"
        Mf Then Mr. Little made a ntntument of which
        iKmt. every street railway must reioi;nUo the truth,
        lyK'l!, and which should bo inrrfiilly lonn.dered by
        I M I.', every capitalist who maybe Invited to becomo
        H I interested in building and operating the pio-
        IbH posed rapid transit line In this city, provided tho
        scheme ever gets so far as inviting contracts,
        Thlsrushbourtraftlc,"Mr.Llttlocontlnued,
        HkLSF "Is, however, not the business which wo mako
        mv' tar money out of. If we had nothing but this
        ntmi y other strlotly business traffic, it would
        m
        UK
        b?id.1l!!,eH!.tA?i1B,lko Win business. Boring
        nil tho middle part of earn day wo should bo
        iu'inlf.,lSttsri!w "na (rotting nothing for
        doing It. The fancy trnfUo 1s what wo want
        and rely upon tho poople who ride bocauso Itls
        V..VH nt to o, not bocauso they have to.
        M? nTa. lhe People, our statistics show, who
        will not go Into tho.subway. Wo know Just
        how mnny persona tako tho cars In thn subwar.
        becnuso wo sell tickets there beforo the peoplo
        go upon tho station platforms, and these tickets
        nro i-pllectcrl In tliocnrs. The sales of subway
        car tlckcta show that thn tunnol gets a fixed
        portion of the general trafllo, but docs not get Us
        share of tho fluctuations,
        Dlfll.tKK OF TIIF. 8UIIWAY IK ntiUItKS.
        Wo carry nearly 200,000.000 pass-liners
        every yoar. In September wo tarried 18.310,
        (MX) passengers. Tho loop to tho Public Garden
        from tho Park streot station was tho only ono
        inon through tho subway during that month.
        Tho atibwny trrtvel then wan 0.0 per cent, of
        our wholo travel. In November, with tho Tre
        mont streot and Shnwmul avenue toop open,
        theMilnvnytraUIo reached 7.1 per cent, of tho
        vtliolo,
        "Sw His ft curious fact that although our
        total number of passengers was Increased 111
        October by 238,000 over the September figures,
        tho number carried In tho subway was Increased
        by only 7.000. Thfct great general tncronse was
        nlmo-it entirely marto up of tho sort of fancy
        riding 1 spoko of. Theio aro the peoplo who
        Jump on n car nnd rldo downtown, ostensibly
        to buy a spool of thrond or a skein of silk or
        ynrn. hut really bocauso tho car Is handy and
        the rldo pleasant. Theso pooplo won't go Into
        the subway. If for no othor reason than becnuso
        thoy won't walk down tho stairs.
        On rainy days ono would suppose that tho
        subway would get n bigger proportion of trafllo
        than in flno weather; but this ls not true. I
        mot Mr. Dalton. ono of tho Transit Commission,
        the other day when It wns mining, at tho en
        trance to tho Park street station.
        '"Isn't this chnrnilngl' he exclaimed as he
        got In out of the storm.
        "I admitted th-it It was; but when I camoto
        look over tha tables of daily receipts and com
        pare thom with the total tralllo I found that
        although tho general trafllo had fallen off less
        than 0 per cent, because of tbo rainy dny, tho
        subway traffic had lost 30 per cent. This Is the
        rooro significant from tho fact that one
        half the former number of cars nro now oft tho
        streets above."
        A reference to tho dally tablos showed how
        tho travel In the subway fell off In unpleasant
        weather. On Nor. 2, when tho usual dally
        Irrffllc was 22,000 or 23,000 persons, only
        14.000 went through tho subway. On Nov. 2a
        tho number roll to 13,000, while tho next dny It
        roso to 24,000. On Sundays, when tho tratllc
        on nil parts of tho system ls fancy riding prin
        cipally, tho number of passongers who go
        through tbo subway falls as low as 0,000.
        FACT8 FOR NEW YORK TO 1-0NDER,
        These aro tho facta. If It wcro possible to
        build tbo long tunnel proposed for this city nnd
        mal.o all parts of It ns perfect ns tho Boston
        subway, which is at least doubtful, what would
        be thn effect of an oqual Indisposition of Now
        Yorkers to using it upon tho chances of Its pay
        ing I Tho proposed road would have enough to
        contend with through tho location of its main
        linos out of tho way of tho short-ride local
        business, out of which alone profit ls to
        be made; but If the fancy traffic avoided It, ns
        It avoids the lloston subway, tho result would
        bo ruinous, Tho contractors would find them
        selves with no ono to carry except tho people
        who wanted to ride to Harlem and far above
        or to Klngsbrldge, all for fire cents, and. what
        ever forfeit they had to make, they would soon
        abandon tho lino for thn city to operate at a loss.
        CACHES OF rUPLIC PREJUDICE.
        Why the peoplo avoid tho subway Is a ques
        tion much discussed. Perhaps as good nn ex
        planation ns anr Is to bo found in a conversa
        tion which took place between Tun Sun re
        porter who gathered these fncts nnd the pretty
        &amp;lrl who Owns the news stnnd at one of Boston's
        est hotels.
        "Ilavo you beon through the subway yet I"
        ho asked enthusiastically.
        "Yes," the reporter nnswored.
        "I have just been through It, Isn't It grand!"
        she exclaimed.
        "l)o you go through it of ten I" asked tho re
        porter curiously.
        "Ob, no!" Bho answered. "I think It's beau
        tiful, so light, and dry, and comfort bio: but I
        always take a surfaco car. I think I hate to
        walk up the stairs, although I am not lazy. I
        walk clear out to ltoxbury and back almost
        ever' day, and have lost slxteon pounds by
        doing so, but, somehow, I don't llko to go up and
        down stairs In tho subway."
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 5 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Boston+subway</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 6 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42&amp;q=BOSTON+subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>June 21, 1903: Boston’s historic landmarks obliterated by Boston Subway and other innovation.</time>
      <text>
        THE MARCH OF IMPROVEMENT IS FAST OBLITERATING MANY OF BOSTONS MOST FAMOUS OLD LANDMARKS
        OLD STATIC HOUSE, BOSTON.
        To be transformed Into a tunnel station for the subway
        BOSTON IMPROVEMENTS.
        Historic Landmarks and Crooked
        Streets Disappearing.
        Boston, June 20.— Within three years the
        crooks and turnings and devious wanderings of
        Boston's most honored highways and byways
        will be nothing more than a memory of the past,
        and many of her ancient landmarks will be
        wiped out or so altered as to be unrecognizable
        to the oldest inhabitant. Slowly and surely the
        ancient thoroughfares are being widened,
        straightened and bent into the rulerlike lines oC
        i rosscut New- York. Philadelphia and Chicago.
        Boston is undergoing a transformation below
        arid aloft that would cause Benjamin Franklin.
        John Hancock, "Warren and Paul Revere *.o rub
        their eyes and stare in amazement. Million dol
        lar buildings by the dozen, elevated roads, tun
        nels and streetcar lines beneath the streets and
        under the harbor, swamps and mud Hats filled
        for piers and excavated for docks that ac
        ':;iinodate giant steamers these are the things
        they would see.
        Along State-st., beneath the spot where the
        Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the his
        toric old State House, a tunnel is eating its way
        from under the harbor to Scollay Square to con
        nect with the present subway by means of
        (lights of stairs and elevators, and thence out
        side to the busy world. The old Slat- House
        itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station
        connecting with a subway line also. The re
        modelled building will soon be crowded with
        people hurrying back and forth, intent on busi
        ness, with never a thought of its old associa
        tions. Little do they think, as they hurry past
        where tunnel workmen are digsing seventy feet
        beneath, of what has happened In that quaint
        old edifice. On this site the first State House
        was built in 1G57. Destroyed by fire in 1711. it
        was rebuilt In 1712, and rebuilt again in 1747,
        when destroyed a second time. The building
        has been in turn Town House, Courthouse. Prov
        ince House, State House and City Hall. &lt;>n the
        NEW-YORK TRIBUNE ILLUSTRATED SUPPLEMENT.
        PAIIK STREET CHUUCR, "RRIMSTONE CORNER," BOSTONT.
        It is to make way for a skyscraper.
        first floor in the early days was the merchants*
        walk, or exchange.
        During the Stamp Act excitement the stamped
        clearances were burned in front of its doors.
        The British troops were quartered within the
        building in 17'J.S, and the Boston Massacre oc
        curred about fifty feet away on March 1770.
        The next day Samuel Adams stood in the coun
        cil chamber and made his successful demand
        upon the royal representatives fur the immedi
        ate removal of the British troops from Boston.
        In this same room Generals Clinton, Howe and
        Gage held a council of war just before the bat
        tle of Bunker Hill. In 17N'J, at the western end
        of the State House, Washington reviewed the
        great procession in his honor on the occasion of
        his last visit to Boston. Here, also, in lSi>s,
        William Lloyd Garrison found refuge from a
        mob which had broken up an anti-slavery meet
        ing, and threatened his life.
        The Park-st. station of the present subway
        handles I!7,course of its trolley traffic, but the number of
        passengers who will pass through the old State
        House station will far exceed this number.
        The march "f progress does not stop here,
        however. Down Washington-st., to connect with
        the tunnel and present subway, will be another
        subway, this a double one for elevated trains
        after they leave tli" surface at the Broadway
        extension. It will pass beneath the Old South
        Church, the Old Corner Bookstore and other well
        known landmarks. Through the tower of the
        »lil South Church, which juts out into Washing
        ton-st., it is planned to cut an arcade, in the
        g&lt; neral scheme of widening and straightening
        Washington-st. Surrounding the Old South
        Church on three sides, a new $1,000,000 office
        building eleven stories high is going up rapidly.
        The Old South Church has been called the
        'Sanctuary of Freedom." The ground on which
        it stands was formerly the site of Governor
        John Winthrop's home, where he died in
        Itri'.t. The land was afterward owned by Mine.
        Mary Norton, wife of the Rev. John Norton,
        who gave it in trust "forever, for the erecting of
        a h"use for their assembling themselves to
        gether publkjuely to worship God." The first
        meeting house was a small cedar building, built
        IB 16701 where Benjamin Franklin was baptized.
        The present structure was built in I. When
        the British occupied the town they desecrated
        the place by using it as a riding school and cav
        alry drill hall. In 187»J the "Old South Preserva
        tion Committee" was formed to buy it for a loan
        museum, at a cost of $4r,0.000. and saved it from
        being torn down.
        Further down toward the old North End a
        syndicate has bought the old Hancock Tavern,
        in Corn Court, and upon its site, with the ad
        joining lots.'will build another eleven story office
        building. Tenants in the Hancock Tavern have
        already received their notice to more.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 7 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023296/1906-06-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=bomb+Bomb+Boston+explosions+FIRE+subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>June 6, 1906: Fire and Explosion on the Boston Subway for unknown reason, women dragged to safety; high fear of electrocution.</time>
      <text>
        FIRE IN SUBWAY.
        Lives Impcrilled in Boslon's
        Underground Railway.
        Terrlflc Exploslona Caused by 8hort
        Clrcultlng of Heavlly Charoea uiec
        trlc vyirea Hundreds of Men and
        Women Thrown Into Panlc Three
        Persons Injured.
        Boston A dull, low ronr, llko tho
        blast of n chnrge of dynnmlte under
        tona of grnnlte, nnd clouda ot black,
        Blckenlng smoko belchlng fortli,
        threw hundreds of men nnd women
        into a panic nnd paralyzed trnfflc ln
        the subwny nt the Boylston street
        statlon at 5.30 o'clock, Wednesday af-
        ternqpn
        No one know the trouble. Elevatcd
        road employes and offlclals were allke
        confused, and fearful of what mlght
        come next, fla tho smoko raphlly fllleil
        tho stntloim at Boylston and Park
        streets, nnd passengers wers rushed
        from tlie cars to the surfacc.
        Tralnmen nnd statlon pollce at
        tempted to call the flrd departmont
        and found tho telephones so charged
        wlth clectrlclty as to be useless.
        Mnny of the women reachlng the
        subway by the Boylston street cars
        were overcomo by the smoko, falnted,
        nnd had to be dragged to the surfnce.
        Several becanio hysterlcal and woro
        controlled wlth much dimculty, the
        danger belng constant of Bomeono
        falllng from tho platforms overcome
        by tho smoko and becomlng electro
        cuted upon the deadly thlrd rall.
        Tralnmaster Benjamln wns the flrst
        offlclal to reach the Boylston street
        statlon and to brlng some sort of or-
        der out of tho cliaos. Enterlng the
        subway along the llne of the north
        bound cars he made hla way some 100
        feet to the south of tlie statlon and
        found the cause of the trouble.
        The feed cables for the thlrd rall,
        runnlng between the ralla and en
        closed ln four-inch wooden box con
        dults, were found grouuded and
        throwlng off flashes of electrlclty,
        whlch llluminnted the subway for
        tnany hundreds of feet. The electrl
        clty had jumped to other cables run
        nlng parallel, and even charged the
        wnlla of the subway. Ten powerful
        cables felt the lnftuence of the crosn
        nnd were cracklng nnd throwlng off
        flames and flashes of llght, threaten
        Ing death to any who cnme near.
        Tho wooden box condtilt, black and
        greasy and very Inflammable, was
        burnlng rapldly. A north bound traln
        whlch had passed over the spot got
        nflro nnd wna inillod bnnk lo Waont
        street, hlnzlng flercely underneath.
        Tlie terrlfled passengers were hnnied
        ntt nt Plpnsnnt Rtreet nnd tlie flro be-
        nnivth tho. Kttn"gulshed by'road
        employes before serlous damage was
        done.
        Three persons were hurt, nnd all of
        them were on the surface. The nccl
        dents whlch caused thelr Injurles were
        the dlrect result of the trouble In tbo
        subway. The Injured wero all near
        the Pleasant street entrance to tho
        Biibwny and were hurt by the explo
        sions in three mnnholes at tliat polnt.
        Tralnmaster Benjamln ordered all
        tralns Into statlons, and then the cnr-
        rent on the thlrd rall and feed cables
        was shut off.
        Chlef Mullcn and the flre depart
        ment hod been notlfled before tho
        power was shut off and entered tho
        nubway nt the Boylston street sta
        tlon, although there was great danger
        for anyone, however famlllar ylth the
        subway, to enter ln tlie dense smoke
        whlch flllcd every foot of space be
        tween the walls.
        As Chlef Mullen's men toucbed the
        walls thoy felt a shock at once. The
        brass nozzle of the chemlcal hose
        Ihey carrled became charged, and wlth
        electrlclty runnlng up thelr arms the
        men hcsltated for a mlnute for orders
        from thelr chlef.
        rlsk It," shouted Chlef Mull
        en, and he dashed Into the smoko
        filled subway. Hla men followed close
        behlnd, thelr hands on the shoulders
        of the men In front. A few darlng
        newspaper men brought up the rear.
        Half an hour was consumed ln put
        llng out the flames whlch had fol
        lowed nlong the box condults nearly
        300 ynrds.
        Both Chlef Mullen and Aaslstant
        Chlef Brady termed It one of the
        most dangerous flres they were ever
        called upon to hnndle, not from lts In
        tenslty but for the dangers of electro
        cutlon that surrounded them and the
        thlckness of the smoke.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 8 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>
        ANOTHER BOSTON SUBWAY
        Eat Ilpnlon Tunnel Junt Openti
        IllliiM Under Itnrbor
        Boston the pioneer city of America
        In subway construction now boasts a
        subway Maid to be the greatest single
        boring yet completed under the enter
        of a river or harbor It Is tho EnSt
        Boston tiinnl extending from tile
        zing UA8T JtOSTON TUNNEL
        city proper under the harbor to
        Maverick square East Boston It Is
        the second subway to be opened In
        Boston wns begun In 1000 has cost
        3000000 and has Just been turned
        over to tint Boston EIu rated Rallwny
        company for operation It Id about
        one ones twofifth miles In length and
        has an exterior diameter of nearly
        thirty feet thoilgli the thickness of
        the walls bring Its Interior diameter
        down to about twentyfour feet
        The East Boston tunnel nets to n
        depth of more than ninety feet below
        tho waters of Boston harbor through
        n blue day sediment It Is fov the
        use of regulntlpn trolley cars which
        come to the surface at the suburban
        end of tilt passage nnd continue their
        Journeys over tliestrce trucks Kven
        trashy the tuba Vlll be connected di
        rectly with the present Ruiwny In Ba
        tons congested dlflUlct
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 9 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87078082/1910-12-07/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Boston+Subway+subway+suicide+SUICIDE</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>December 10, 1910: John F. Donahue commits suicide by jumping in front of moving train.</time>
      <text>
        JOHN F. D0N0HUE A SUICIDE.
        Thomas
        Lawson's Confidential Man
        Dies In Subway.
        Boston, Dec. 1. John F. Donohue,
        many years the confidential man of J.
        Edward Addicks aud of Thomas W.
        Lawsou, committed suicide by throw-!
        lng himself before a fast moving train
        in the subway. Deatli was install Ui- i
        neous.
        For about fifteen minutes Mr. Dono
        hue had been pacing the station plat
        form, walking to tho edge and looking
        down at the rails and peering up and
        down the track. Just before a north
        bound train drew up Mr. Donohue
        dropped a light cane lie had been car
        rying and jumped into the train pit
        His family furnished no explanation
        for the act. Friends say he had been
        suffering from stomach trouble about
        a year. He was sixty years old and a
        native of Ireland and for a time was
        engaged lu shoe manufacturing In
        Lynn, Mass.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 10 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90005351/1921-12-23/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>December 23, 1921: Main power line of Boston Subway explodes right during Christmas holiday.</time>
      <text>
        EXPLOSION SCARE IN
        BOSTON SUBWAY
        BOSTON, Dee. 23 Tratìic wa
        panilyzed for two hours an
        thousands of commuterà and
        Christmas shoppers friplitened in
        underground traina when a mr.in
        power cable in the Cambridge -''ub-way
        prounded and exploded, lhu-5
        rhutting ofF the current. Con
        fusion broke loose in the vicinity
        between Chauncey Street r.nd t'a.
        South Station when volume: i f
        black smoke poure.d through the
        tube and permeateti to adjoin'ii
        subway systems. The offici:!' o'
        the road dcclare that there were
        no injuries resulting from the ac
        cident.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 11 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1902-06-28/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=Boston+Subway</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 12 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023058/1897-03-05/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Boston+Subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>March 4, 1897: Escaping gas in Boston Subway during construction creates havoc; many killed by explosion; half a hundred injured.</time>
      <text>
        Boston, March s.—An accident, by far
        the worst of its kind ever known in
        Foston, occurred at a few minutes be
        fore noen yesterday, when an explo
        sion of illuminating gas, in the subway,
        at the intersection of Tremont and Boyl
        ston streets, caused the death of six
        persons and the injury to a score or more
        of others, although not more than 10
        were severely hurt.
        Buildings for hundreds of feet in all
        directions were damaged by the concus
        sion, and several electric cars, which
        were passing at the time, were wrecked.
        One of these caught fire and was burned
        to the tracks. The property loss will
        amount to thousands of dollars, includ
        ing not only that sustained by real es
        tate owners, but also that resulting from
        a general demolition of geods in several
        of the steres in the vicinity.
        The corrected list of killed is as follows:
        Rev. W. A. Start, D. D., Medford, bur
        sar, Tufts cellege.
        Willlam L. Vimal, Salem, Mass.
        Miss A. M. Bates, Boston.
        Guilford B. Bigelow, driver, West End
        sf:'w\:: rallway.
        Ednjamin Downey, herdic driver, Bos
        ton.
        Delane M. Sibley, cab driver, Boston.
        The most serieugly injured are:
        Fred Deeley, Boston, dislocated elbow,
        lacerated wound across the eyes and
        head and centusion of back. May die.
        B. R. Sargent, Boston, compound frac
        ture of skull; expected to die.
        Willlam Maybour, Boston, fracture
        base of the skull.
        Paul Hackett, Bosten, both legs brok
        en, head cut.
        Mrs. Horatio Bigelow, Boston, 80
        years, injured back.
        Miss May E. Stone, Waltham, frac
        tured thigh, scalp wound.
        W. Richardson, Newark, N. J., cut
        face, head.
        8. D. Nickerscn, Boston, secretary Ma
        sonic Temple, head and face cut by glass.
        famuel Morton, Detreit, scalp wound,
        five inches long, clear to the bone.
        John Gill, Boston, bad wound in shoul
        der.
        Mprs. Sarah A. Peck, 233 Everett street,
        Allston, severe injuries to back.
        Nellie Jackson, 35 Marlboro street,
        Boston, serious injuries to back and
        arms.
        Mirs Sadie M. Brown, Regent street,
        Roxbury, a reporter, spine injured.
        Charlotte N. Nair, 371 Center street,
        Jamaica Plain, fractured thigh.
        Miss Aliee Richardson, 9 Falirfield
        etreet, Boston, fractured thigh.
        Sarah Fleming, 19 Marlboro street, in
        i juries to head and back.
        Thirty-five others received minor in
        juries, which were dressed at the Emer
        gency hospital and the police station,
        and all returned to their homes.
        The explosion is thought to have re
        sulted from the ignitien of gas from a
        leaky main, eitherj by a gpark from a
        CASTORIA.
        passing electric car or from an improp
        erly insulated wire in the subway. An
        investigation to determine just what
        was the cause will be held by the city au
        thorities. Mayor Quincy, who was
        promptly on the ground, stated that
        there would be no delay in looking ints
        the matter. y
        The street was crowded with pedes
        trians and vehicleg, besides the cars.
        Suddenly the earth and planking which
        comprised the roof of the subway at
        that point burst open with a terrific re
        port, and, while the ground trembled,
        the air wag filled with dust and smoke
        and flying debris. Cars and carriages
        were tipped over and their occupants
        thrown out into the midst of the wreck
        age. Flames leaped from the opening
        in the street and seized upon the splin
        tered woed of the cars which had been
        torn apart, and seon a brisk fire was
        burning. An alarm was given and a few
        moments later the rushing engines add
        ed their din to the confusion. The fire
        men went to work promptly and the
        flames were soon put out.
        Meanwhile a vast crowd gathered and
        scores of ready hands began the work
        of rescue. It took congiderable courage
        to approach the scene, for, besides the
        tangled and twisted rails and lronwork
        which supported the roof of the subway,
        the live trolley wires, which had been
        broken apart, dangled dangerously in all
        directions.
        The West End emergency men shut
        off the power as soon as possible, and
        the rescuers suffered less obstruction.
        The first bedy taken out was that of
        Rev., W. A. Start, an aged man, and
        bursar of Tufts college. He was about
        to board a Brookline car when the explo
        sion occurred. Both of his legs were
        blown off, and the bones protruded from
        the flesh.
        The car which he was about to take
        was directly over the spot where the
        gas ignited, It was raised bodily frem
        the track by the force of the concussion,
        and, dropping back, it split in two, and
        then the tlan.es seized it. Near this car
        was another, a herse car of the Back
        RBay line, of which Guilford Bigelow was
        the driver. Moth horses attached to the
        car were killed and mutilated in a sick
        ening manner. Bigelow’s body was
        taken from bencath the car, which was
        badly wrecked. ESeveral other cars in
        the vieinity were also badly shattered.
        William L. Vinal, a passenger in one
        of the cars, was found dead. Delano M.
        Sibley, a herdic driver, was also picked
        up dead. Benjamin Downey was alive
        when rescued, but he died on his way tc
        the hospital.
        Miss Bates, who was also killed, was
        driving with her sister-in-law. The ear
        riage was overturned and its occupants
        thrown out. Miss Bates was taken up
        dead. Her compaion was hurt.
        The dead were removed to an under
        taker's reoms nearby, and the injured
        were promptly taken to the hospitals.
        Every ambulance in the city and every
        police patrol wagon in the vicinity were
        impressed into service. The work of
        rescue was accomplished in remarka
        bly quick time, and the coolness of a
        large squad of police who were sent to
        the scene soon allayed the excitement.
        Fortunately, no men were at work in
        that section of the subway, as that part
        is nearly completed, and the gas main
        in which the leak occurred was between
        the roof of the subway and the surface
        of the street. The leak which caused the
        trouble is said to have been noticed sev
        eral days ago, and, it is stated, the
        proper officials were notifled.
      </text>
    </result>
    <!-- article 13 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1901-06-18/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Boston+Subway</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 14 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023058/1897-03-05/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Boston+Subway</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <!-- article 15 -->
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028490/1897-10-07/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Boston+Subway</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>THE BOSTON SUBWAY
        SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF
        THE
        8TREET CAR PROBLEM.
        Congontlon of Traffic In tlio llny Streets
        of the Hub Itrlloreil by Underground
        Trolley Uncs Tunnols That Are Light,
        Clcnn and Attractive,
        It Is now possible to cross Tromonfj
        Street, Boston, nt any iKiliit opposlto tlio
        t'ominoti nnd nt nny tlino of day without
        loss of llfo or limb. Tho now subway has
        brought nbnttt tho chntiffo.
        It Is an old trmUtlon that tho fathers of
        Doston, when they lnld out tho city, let
        tho streets follow tho winding cow paths.
        At nny rate, tho streets iw they exist today
        nro very crooked and most of them nro
        very narrow. This wn all right In Revo
        lutionary times, but whon tho city grow
        miles beyond tho Common and spread It
        self out to tho south and west; when busi
        ness centered itself along tho lower ends
        of Washington nnd Truiiiont street", nnd
        when tlorcns of street car trucks usurped
        tho narrow rondwoys, then tho Bostonlutis
        wished their nncestors had not stuck so
        closely to the cow paths.
        rrobably no other city on tho continent
        was over so badly afflicted with n conges
        tion of trnlllo as tho Hub has been for
        many years. Homo of tho most important
        street ear lines skirt tho south and east
        corners of tho Common on lloylston and
        Trcmont streets. When tho change was
        mndo from horsepower to trolley, matters
        grow worse Then tho poles and tho tan
        glo of overhead wires mado that historic
        broikthlng spot look like a ploco of dingy,
        green billiard cloth which hod bocomo fray
        ed and tattered around tho edges. So after
        much wrangling In tlio legislature and
        courts It was decided to build tho subway
        and put tho trolley earn underground.
        A lurgo portion of tho work has already
        been accomplished and Boston is delight
        ed with tho result. Tho first thing a Uos
        ton man asks a visitor from New York,
        Chicago or clxowhcro is:
        "Been through tho subway yctf Let's
        boo you haven't ono In your placo, have
        your"
        It is, In fact, a triumph f engineering
        and well worth n v lslt. There aro threo
        open cuts whero tho trolley cars cntor tho
        subway. Ono is out on Trcmont street
        where Shawmut nvenuo comes In. Hero
        tho tracks from each of theso thorough-
        fares divo into tho tunnel. Another Is In
        tho 1'ubllo gardens, whero tho cars coin
        ing down Boylston street tnko tho under
        ground dip. Tho third is at tho northerly
        ond of tho subway, Just beyond Haymnr
        kot square and in front of tho now Union
        terminal railroad station into which tho
        Fltchburg, Boston nnd Maine, Eastern
        and other roads run. There is a loop hero
        BOSTON'S NEW bUDWAV IKCI.INE IN THE rUD
        LIO 0A11DKN.
        as most of tho trolley lines mnko, it their
        terminus, and, tho btibway being four
        tracked, they disgorge their pabscngcrs
        and tako tho back truck up town.
        Including tho inclines or open cuts, tho
        subway has a total length of IX miles nnd
        will contain about Hvo miles of truck. At
        present tho branch down Boylston street
        along tho Common sldo and tho main lino
        down Tremont to Park street aro iu oper
        ation. Tho Shuwmut avenuo branch and
        tho northerly end of tho main lino will bo
        finished within tho next eight months.
        Qround was broken for tho subway In
        April, 1805. Tlio sum appropriated was
        $T, 000, 000 ond, wonderful to relnto, tho
        transit commissioners soy that it Is proba
        ble tho cost will bo about $1,000,0U0 lot.8
        than that sum.
        No great dltlicultles havo been encoun
        tered thus for In digging this big holo In
        tho ground. Of course thcro wcro count
        less sowers, water pipes, gus plinjs, olectrio
        wire conduits and tho llko and somo -10
        Inch water mains at an incomenlcnt level
        proved rather hard to handlo, but no un
        expected conditions arose to delay tho
        work. Tho main trunk of tho subway
        runs under tho wldo walk or moll on tho
        cast side of tho Common, nnd when tho
        excavations wcro being mado (ho bones of
        hundreds of old Puritans were disturbed.
        This raised a howl of righteous Indigna
        tion, and tho sncretlness of tho long forgot
        burying ground was harped upon for
        weeks. But tho commissioners quieted
        the reverent patriots by collecting all tho
        bones and rclntorrlng them in tho holy
        ground of tho Common, wlthnnico monu
        ment to mark tho spot.
        Tho deepest point of tho subway Is on
        Boylston street, whero tho south bound
        tracks aro laid 80 feet below tho surface,
        but tho overage- depth is 14 feet. Tho tun
        nel Itself is a glunt boro with ribs of steel
        and casings of cement, asphalt, concrcto
        and masonry. Tho roof is a series of
        arches and tho lloor Is concave, with
        drains at tho bottom. As tho drains ore
        below tho lovel of tho sowers, pits havo
        boon established at Intervals, and when
        they aro filled with water automutlo elec
        trical pumps aro started, which empty
        them into tho sewers abovo.
        Perhaps you Imagine that Boston's sub
        way is a dark, damp, 111 smelling place. It
        Is nothing of tho sort. Tho entrances to
        tho stations nro handsome structures of
        etono, with glass roofs. Tho only fault to
        be found with them Is that thoy remind
        you of an old Grecian tomb at least that
        is what I thought of tho first time I saw
        ono. But thou you go down nn easy flight
        of wldo stone steps to n cheerful, brilliant
        ly lighted station. Everything is dazzling
        ly white. Tho bricks lining tho entranco
        nro of glazed whlto porcolain, tho mason
        ry arches nro pointed whlto and tho Iron
        pillars and supports nro covered with lm
        maculato whlto enamel. Incandescent and
        aro lights flash everywhere, and tho vista
        ahead through tho stretches of tho subway
        Is far from n ding' ono. It Is about tho
        leanest and noatcst holo In tho ground in
        existence and no doubt will bo kept so.
        Already tho trnlllo on Tremont and Boyl
        ston streets has been much decreased, and
        when tho subway Is fully completed Bos
        ton folk may get about their town with
        comparative caeo and safety.
      </text>
    </result>
  </results>
</topic></topics>