<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chinese-exclusion-act</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	    <id>www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053040/1882-05-13/ed-1/</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
        <time>May 1882:	Congress passes the Chinese Exclusion Act and President Chester A. Arthur signs it.</time>
	    <text>
            The Chinese Bill.
            The bill signed by the President on the
            8th inst., entitled "An act to execute cer
            tain treutv stipulations relating to Chinese,"
            provides In the first section for the suspen
            sion of the immigration of Chinese laborers
            to the United States for a period of ten
            years, counting from the expiration of
            ninety days after the passage of the act,
            that is for to years from the 30th dav of
            July 1882. The second section provides
            lor" tiie punishment of masters of vessels
            who shall land in the U. S-, Chinese labor
            ers in violation of section first, bv u fine of
            $500 for each immigrant and imprisonment
            not exceeding one year. Section third pro
            vides tor certificates of identity tor Chinese
            laborers now in the country, who may
            wish to visit China and return. Section
            twelve makes it the duty of the President
            of tiie United States to cause to be removed
            to tiie place from whence they came, and
            at the cost of the United States every Chi
            nese person who shall have unlawfully en
            tered this country by land or water, after
            being brought before some justice, judge or
            commissioner of a court of tiie United
            States. Section thirteen exempts diplo
            matic and other officers of tin; Chinese
            Government and their body and .musehold
            servants from the provisions of the act.
            The two following sections are the ones
            against which so much opposition lias been
            shown by Republican Congressmen.
            Section' 14. That hereafter no State
            court or court of the United States shall ad
            mit Chinese to citizenship; and all laws in
            conflict with this act are repealed.
            Section- 15. That tiie words "Chinese
            Laborei s" wherever used in this act shall
            be constructed to mean both skilled and un
            skilled laborers and Chinese employ ed in
            mining.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-22/ed-1/</id>
	    <rel>1</rel>
        <time>November 21-23, 1901:	Chinese Exclusion Convention “demands” re-enactment of Exclusion Law to protect labor.</time>
	    <text>
            CHINESE EXCLUSION CONVENTION OPENS
            FIGHT IN DEFENSE OF AMERICAN LABOR
            PRESIDENT WILL URGE RE-ENACTMENT OF EXCLUSION LAW.
            D. C, Nov. 21, 1901. Hon. James D. Phelan, San Francisco, Cal.; I have seen the President. I have the best authority for saying that he will not only recom
            mend in his message the re-enactment of the Geary law, but will go further and urge that it be made stronger. J, c. NEEDHAM.
            CHINESE QUESTION ONE OF" RACE
            TyTy E are the warders of the Golden Gate; we must stand
            y y here forever in the pathway of the Orient, and if there
            is any danger or trial it is for us to sound the alarm.
            I regard the Chinese question as a race question. I regard
            it as an international question; and above and over all, a
            question involving the preservation of our civilisation. The State
            of California, with its sezrn hundred miles of seaboard facing
            the Orient, is entitled to speak on this question for tlie people of
            the United States. Excerpt from Mayor James D. Phelan' s ad
            dress at the Chinese Exclusion Convention.
            Leading Citizens Gather to Urge
            Re-enactment of the
            Geary Law.
            IT was a distinctly representative
            gathering of business, professional
            and laboring men that packed Metro
            politan Temple yesterday afternoon
            when Mayor Phelan called the Chi
            nese Exclusion Convention to order.
            Xearly every seat in the large auditorium
            •was taken, the lower floor being devoted
            to the use of the delegates from all parts
            of California, while the gallery was given
            up to the general public. All present
            seemed to be animated by one impulse,
            that of doing their utmost to secure the
            re-enactment of the Chinese exclusion act
            and thereby prevent the threatened In
            vasion of Mongol horclee to the peril and
            degradation of American labor.
            The gathering was of that character
            which lends weight to any public move
            ment and the conclusions of which are ac
            corded respectful consideration In legisla
            tive halls. The convention was not the
            outgrowth of political or partisan senti
            ment, but of the fear of the people of the
            State that the danger which menaces
            their advancement and prosperity might,
            unless strong measures were taken, be
            actually realized. In order that the peo
            ple of the East might understand how
            the communities on the "Western confines
            of the continent feel concerning the un
            restricted immigration of Chinese into
            their midst, the convention was decided
            upon, and it is needless to say that the
            memorial which is to be adopted to-day
            will prove to be an unanswerable argu
            ment to those of the East, who, without
            the slightest knowledge of the blight-
            Borne characteristics of the Chinese, have
            df-clared open sympathy for the coolie
            hordes which are only awaiting the ex
            piration of the exclusion act in May next
            SENATOR PERKINS WOULD CO FURTHER.
            /T is our people who pay the taxes that have built up our splendid institutions, and we should
            draw the line furtJter, only this is not the time nor occasion. I would permit no one to come into
            this country unless he felt as he approaches these shores as Moses did when he approached the
            burning bush that he stood upon sacred ground; and the voice coming out of that bush from the
            American people is "Unless you love freedom, unless you believe in republican institutions, unless you
            believe in the free public schools, you cannot come into this country." Excerpt from Senator Perkins'
            address before the Chinese Exclusion Convention.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-23/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>November 21-23, 1901: Chinese Exclusion Convention “demands” re-enactment of Exclusion Law to protect labor.</time>
          <text>
              THE Chinese Exclusion Convention
              completed its labor? yesterday
              after the adoption of one of the
              most important as well as vipor
              ous memorials on the Chinese
              question ever addressed to the
              President and Congress of the United
              Elates. The attitude of the people of Cal
              ifornia and of the entire Pacific Coast to
              ward the problem of unrestricted immi
              gration of Asiatics to these shores as rep
              resented in the convention was distinctly
              outlined, and its language cannot fail to
              he understood in the East as being the
              Fpontaneous outburst of a united people
              n the imposition upon them i f a
              grievous wrong.
              The delegates gathered in force yester
              day morning and listened with enthusi
              asm to many speakers. Only one theme
              was discuss-ei, only one idea advanced,
              namely, unalterable resistance to the pro
              ject of unrestricted Chinese immigration
              to America. Tie danger of a Mongolian
              invasion In the event of the refusal of
              :ess to re-enact the exclusion law
              wae pointed out in forceful language by
              all the speakers. The delegates choc-reel
              heartily at every patriotic sentiment
              voiced by the orators, and particularly
              when the necessity o* protecting Ameri
              can labor against foreign competition was
              urged. The members of the convention
              .6howed by their zeal t^at they were in
              accord with the speakers, whose senti
              ments they cordially indo-f>ed.
              The report of the comir.ittee on perma
              nent organization was tae first matter
              to engage the attention of the delegates
              et the morning session. The recommen
              dation that the temporary officers be
              made permanent was adopted amid
              cheers. It was expected that the memo
              l rial committee would be abl* to file its
              report, but the announcement by Chair
              man Geary that further time was re-
              Quired by the cotimittee resulted in the
              desired action beltg taken. There being
              sm> definite bufiinesi before the convention,
              The San Francisco Call.
              speechmaking was indulged in. Assistant
              Tnii^rj States District Attorney Duncan
              E. McKinlay was introduced by the chair,
              and that gentleman delivered an able ad
              dress in which he reviewed the Chinese
              question from the standpoint of the Dis
              trict Attorney's office. The legal aspects
              of the issue were capably presented, the
              peakcr's remarks at times evoking
              hearty applause. So favorably did he im
              press his hearers that at the close of his
              speech he was honored by a Tote of
              thanks for his brilliant oratorical effort.
              The Rev. Dr. William Rader followed
              with a witty address, in which he re
              viewed the Chinese question from the
              standpoint of morality and religion. His
              allusions to the vices prevailing in San
              Francisco's Chinatown, and of their ef
              fect upon the whole community, were im
              pressively advanced, and his remark that
              the proper place in which to Christianize
              the Chinese was in China and not in this
              country, evoked cheers. The address
              was replete with statistical information,
              and it was listened to with profound in
              terest by all present.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-11-26/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>November 21-23, 1901: Chinese Exclusion Convention “demands” re-enactment of Exclusion Law to protect labor.</time>
          <text>
              COMMISSIONERS ABE NAMED.
              Chairman Geary Appoints Men to
              Chinese Exclusion Committees.
              Thomas J. Geary, chairman of the Cali
              fornia Exclusion Convention, announces
              the following appointments:
              Commissioners of California to "Washington—
              Andrew Furuseth, ex-Governor James H. Budd,
              Truxton Beale, James D. Phelan and Edward
              J. Llvernash.
              Press committee— P. Bufflngton of the Jack
              son Republican. E. A. "Walcott of the Ex
              aminer John McNaueht of The Call, Edward
              F. Adams of the Chronicle, Charles punbar of
              the Santa Rosa. Press-Democrat.
              Additions to executive committee— A. Sbar
              boro George Stone, Jeremiah F. Sullivan,
              James H. Wllklns, Henry H. Taylor, Thomas
              F Barry, M. H. de Young, James H. O'Brien,
              Arthur G. Fisk. J. C. Kirkpatrick, George A.
              Ross. Eugene E. Schmitz, Ed Rosenberg. J. S.
              Parry, George H. Knight.
              VOTE ON CHINESE EXCLUSION.
              Merchants' Association Takes Boli of
              Members on Important Question.
              The returns from a vote of the mem
              bers of the Merchants' on
              questions pertaining to the Chinese ex
              clusion act are as follows:
              Do you favor the extension of the present
              Chinese exclusion act? Ayes, 425; noes, 208.
              Do you favor a modified Chinese exclusion
              act? Ayes, 243; noes, 376.
              Do you favor sending delegates from the
              Merchants' Association to the Chinese exclusion
              convention? Ayes. 638; noes, 91.
              Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged for
              Chinese exclusion act Ayes. 11; noes, 0.
              Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged
              against Chinese exclusion act Aye-, 7; noes, 0.
              Affirmative answers to No. 3, if pledged for
              modified Chinese exclusion act— Ayes, 5; noes, 0.
              Affirmative answers to No. 3, If pledged also
              for Japanese exclusion Ayes, 1; noes, 0.
              Parties desire matter to be left to board of
              directors' discretion— Ayes, 4; noes, 0.
              The delegates who were appointed by
              the Merchants' Association to the Chi
              nese Exclusipn Convention, are Prank J.
              Symmes, Marshal Hale and Andrew M.
              Davis.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/46032385/1901-12-06/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>November 21-23, 1901: Chinese Exclusion Convention “demands” re-enactment of Exclusion Law to protect labor.</time>
          <text>
              The Yellow Peril.
              It will be necessary for the present congress
              to. take acjtion upon the Chinese exclusion act
              which expires by limitation May 24, 1902. The
              Kjansas City platform contained the following
              plank on the subject:
              We favor the continuance and strict en-
              forcement of the Chinese exclusion law and
              its application to the samo classes of all
              'Asiatic races.
              This plank was unanimously agreed upon by
              the platform committee, and there was no dissent
              from it among the delegates. It is to be expected,
              therefore, that the proposition to extend the
              Chinese exclusion act will receive the support of
              all the democrats in the house and senate. The
              editor of The Commoner received a letter a few
              days ago from a democrat who complained that
              the laboring men of the Pacific slope had ignored
              the. Chinese question in the last campaign and
              suggested that it would only be a merited punish
              ment if the republican party refused to extend the
              exclusion act. It is not unnatural that some
              resentment should be felt toward those who sup
              ported the republican party in spite of the dangers
              which republican supremacy involves, and yet no
              one can justify himself in either supporting a bad
              policy or in failing to protest against it merely be
              cause the policy would punish .some who ought to
              have exerted themselves to prevent ij:. That
              many of the republican leaders are in favor of a
              ..policy, Jfcat will flood the country with cheap
              Chinese labor, is true, and that an imperial policy
              tends to lend encouragement to the cheap labor
              proposition, is also true, but the failure of the
              laboring men' to see these dangers in advance
              would not justify .democrats in remaining quiet
              on this subject, although the republicans are in
              "power and are responsible for legislation.
              The Chinese question is one that effects the en
              tire country, not the Pacific Coast alone or the
              laboring men alone. It is true that the Pacific
              Coast would feel the evil effects of Chinese emigra
              tion first, and it is also true that the laboring men
              would come into immediate contact with oriental
              labor, but in its ultimate influence the subject
              touches all parts of the country and reaches all
              classes. The question is whether we are going to
              build up a strong, independent, upright and pa
              triotic people and develop a civilization that will
              exert a helpful influence on all the world, or
              whether we are going to be a greedy, grasping na
              tion, forgetful of high ideals and concerned only
              in the making of money.
              Chinese emigration is defended by two classes
              of people. First, by those, comparatively few in'
              number, who believe that universal brotherhood
              requires us to welcome to our shores all people of
              all lands. This is the sentimental argument ad
              vanced in favor of Chinese emigration. There Is
              no more reason why we should construe brother
              hood to require the admission of all people to our
              country than there is that we should construe
              brotherhood to require the dissolution of family
              ties. The family is a unit; it is the place where
              character and virtue and usefulness are developed,
              and from the family a good or evil influence ema
              nates. It is not necessary nor even wise that the
              family environment should be broken up or that
              ill who desire entrance should bet admitted to the
              family oircle. In a larger sense a nation is a
              family. It is the center for the cultivation of na
              tional character, national virtue and national use
              fulness. A nation is under no obligation to the
              outside world to admit any body or anything that
              would injuriously effect the national family; in
              fact it Is under obligation to itself not to do so.
              The influence of the United States will bo much
              more potent for good if we Temaln a homogeneous
              nation with all citizens in full sympathy with all
              other citizens. No distinct race like tho Chinese
              can come into this country without exciting a fric
              tion and a race prejudlco which will mako it moro
              difficult for us to exercise a wholesome influence
              upon the Chinese in China, not to speak of our in
              fluence on other nations.
              Let us educate tho Chinese who desire to learn
              of American institutions; let us offer courtesy and
              protection to those who come here to travel' and
              investigate, but it will not be of permanent benefit
              to either the Chinese or to us to Invite them to be
              come citizens or to permit them to labor here and
              carry the proceeds of their toil back to their own
              country.
              The second, and by far the larger class, em
              braces those who advocate Chinese emigration on
              the ground that it will furnish cheap labor for
              household- and factory work. There is no force In
              the argument that is made by some that it is diffi
              cult to secure girls to do housework. If domestic
              service is not popular as compared with other
              w.ork, it is because the pay is not sufficient to mako
              it attractive and the remedy lies in better wages.
              Labor can be secured for any and every honorable
              -position-when-the'i'4sufflcienfc-to'attratitr'
              and the demand for Chinese servants comes with
              poor grace from those who often spend on a sin
              gle social entertainment as much as a servant'3
              wages would amount to in an entire year. At this
              time When skilled and intelligent American labor
              is able to compete in foreign markets with the
              cheapest, labor of the world, it is absurd to talk
              about the necessity for cheap factory hands.
              The increase in Japanese Immigration, or rath
              er importation (for large numbers of them are
              brought for specific purposes) has been referredto
              in a former issue of The Commoner. IWwas there
              suggested that the Japanese government would
              doubtless, if asked to do so, place restrictions upon
              Japanese emigration that would make it unneces
              sary for us to deal with the subject by legislation.
              This matter should at once be brought to tho at
              tention of the Japanese authorities, and unles3
              sufficient and satisfactory action Is taken by the
              home government the Chinese exclusion act should
              be made broad enough to extend to Japanese of
              the same class.
              The subject of oriental emigration cannot be
              discussed without giving some consideration to
              the danger of cheap labor from the Philippine isl
              ands. It will soon be necessary to legislate on
              this subject. If the Filipinos are permitted to
              come here there is danger that the Philippine ques
              tion will become only second in aggravation lo
              the Chinese question. If, on the other hand, the
              Filipinos are prohibited from coming here (if a
              republic can prohibit the inhabitants of one part
              from visiting another part of the republic), will it
              not excite a just protest on the part of the Fili
              pinos? How can we excuse ourselves if we In
              sist upon opening the Philippine islands to the In
              vasion of American capital, American speculators,
              and American task-masters, and yet close our doors
              to those Filipinos who, driven from home, may
              seek an asylum here?
              TIio democratic party should take a strong
              and aggresslvo position on this question. It can
              afford to'oppoBO Chinese emigration and insist
              upon tho unity and homogoncousness of "oiir
              nation. It can afford to Insist that Japanese la
              borers shall be treated the samo as Chinese labor
              ers and excluded, by agreement with tho Japanese
              government if possible, by congressional legisla
              tion if necessary.
              The democratic leaders should further point
              out that the Philippine question involves tho samo
              menace to our country, and that as wo can neither
              afford to admit tho Filipinos nor yet mako a dis
              tinction between different parts of tho republic,
              we should at once declare our purposo to give the
              Filipinos independence as soon as a stable govern
              ment can be established.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-04-17/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>April 16, 1902:	Senate passes bill continuing Chinese Exclusion laws, extending Geary Act to 1904.</time>
          <text>
              The Senate failed to substitute' the
              enacting clause 'of the House bill; for th'e
              Senate measure, so that the bill 'now! will
              go to the House as an "original measure
              and from a" parliamentary standpoint will
              have to he acted on and "treated the same
              as though- the I louse ;had not. passed a
              Chinese 'exclusion bill already.
              pThc vote' by which the substitute took
              the .place of the originalwas ayes 48 to
              noes 33. Once the substitution had been
              made air the Senators joined in its sup
              port, with the single^ exception of Hoar,
              the substitute being passed,. 76 to 1. The
              friends of the^ 1 substitute .'showed their
              strength throughout the voting on amend
              ments .that preceded final action and; sue-,
              ceeded in preventing any 'material change
              in' its features. Some minor, conditions
              were made, admitting Chinese persons
              connected with national expositions^ arid
              providing for certiflcates\of Identification
              of /Chinese l in our insular, possessions.
              Otherwise, 'however, the. substitute was
              adopted substantially in "the 'form thit
              Platt presented it.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065462/1905-06-21/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1905-1907: Widespread debate over effect of Exclusion Act on U.S. economy and possible omission of certain “classes” from the law.</time>
          <text>
              President Roosevelt is reported
              to be very indignant because the
              Chinese Exclusion Act is being
              vigorously enforced, says the New
              York American.
              n..ia a. T 1 L i
              irresiueui jiuuBe veiii uugui uui
              to complain of vigor, because he is
              the national exponent of the stren-
              .nous life.
              h Also, President Roosevelt has
              nnaAil a a favftrinrr thn vifnrnriR An-
              j o
              forcemeat, of all laws regardless of
              the feelings and interests of indi
              viduals. There is no Iaw on the statute
              books of the United tates more
              Important to the wellbeing of the
              citizens of this conchy than the
              Chinese Exclusion Act.
              Despite the great vigilance of
              the officials, the law is constantly
              being eluded and broken even to
              day. It has been found almost impos
              sible to protect the two thousand
              miles on the Pacific Coast frontier
              against the invasion1 of Chinese,
              j Trho employ every device known
              to human ingenuity to pass the
              Hues.
              Before President Roosevelt gets
              .r.Jignact about the vigorous en
              forcement of the Chinese Exclu
              sion Act, he might better consult
              with the Federal judges andoffi
              Jala of Pacific Coast ports.,
              Juflga Morrow, of San Francis
              co, for instance,' could tell him
              that perjury, forgery of firtiS
              stes, forgery of photographs and
              Vernation of purgery are nni
              cr?:il in Chinese cases.
              Iumigrant Commissioner North
              culi tell him that, despite the tit
              nost precautions, cm Chinese la
              ulatituteil for another, and that
              rca now tl.rre is trlcrethade
              itrscct tLs exar:.:Eitica cf r.any
              i wLcra CLir- af t,!avP3
              ira L:en Ban:!: I i. '.3 W.i caun-
              11.2 CLiiese lit-: i Act b
              c 1 1
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1905-06-30/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1905-1907: Widespread debate over effect of Exclusion Act on U.S. economy and possible omission of certain “classes” from the law.</time>
          <text>
              THE CHINESE
              EXCLUSION ACT.
              One of the big questions which is
              agitating thit country at tho present
              time is the Chinese exclusion act, and
              the effect its rigid enforcement has
              now and may have in the future, on
              American commerce and trade in
              China. The exportation of cotton and
              cotton goods to China has grov-n from
              almost nothing to $40,000,000 in a few
              yca-s. Other lines of exports to the
              celestial kingdom have shown very
              large gams. The American manufac
              turer is clamoring tor an open door
              to the trade of China. The American
              manufacturer has always been solf-
              ifsh and in most instances, been ready
              to sacrifice the good of the people to
              his own profit and selfish ends. It
              matters little to the manufacturer of
              cotton goods in New England or the
              south if the Pacific coast and adja
              cent territory is overrun with cheap
              Chinese coolies, the lowest strata of
              Chinese life. 5f he can find a ready
              and a profitable market for a few
              more millions of dollars of cotton
              goods and other products of his shops.
              7"he cry for more liberal immigration
              Jiws for the Chinese comes wholly
              Irom the manufacturers. Tne people
              of the Pacific coast don't want the
              aan at any price. He is a men-
              ace to this country and his very pres
              ence exerts a contaminating in
              fluence. It is impossible for him to
              amalgamate with the people of this
              country. He can not become a citizen
              and ho has no desire to make this
              land of the free his home and reside
              here permanently. Personally he Is
              as objectionable as tho negro of the
              J south and if we must have cheap labor
              1 let us give the negro a chance. "We
              lave him with us and while he is not
              .as skillful as the Chinaman or as In
              dustrious, he Is by far the best cheap
              laborer in the world.
              The Chinese exclusion act has been
              in operation for more than twenty
              years. At tho time of its passage a
              perfect horde of orientals were
              streaming Into this country, over
              running the Pacific coast states, and
              drifting far back into the interior. The
              exclusion act stopped this unholy in
              vasion at once and the flow of China
              men began to go the other way. There
              were at that time more than a quar
              ter of a million Chinamen In the
              "United States. During these twenty
              years this number has been on the
              gradual decline. Death has thinned
              tho ranks of the yellow skinned sons
              of the east and a large proportion of
              the Chinamen who were in this coun
              try have made their "stake" and re
              turned to China to remain. In San
              Francisco. Los Angeles, Portland and
              Seattle the gradual decrease in the
              number of Chinese has been most
              notable. It is doubtful if at the pros
              sent time there are 50,000 Chinese in
              the entire country, and the country
              will be infinitely better off when
              these, too, "have folded their tents,
              like the Arab, and silently stolen
              away."
              The manufacturers, for years, have
              kept an outrageous tariff on all
              classes of manufactured goods by
              their cry of "protection to American
              labor," and they have filtched mill
              ions of dollars from the pockets of
              the people under the guise of a tariff
              to enrich their own. It matters not
              to them how heavy the burden on
              the shoulders of the people, just so
              they get their pound of flesh. Now
              they wo ild throw wide open the doors
              to the Chinese in order to get a few
              more dollars of trade.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1905-07-21/ed-1/n</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1905-1907: Widespread debate over effect of Exclusion Act on U.S. economy and possible omission of certain “classes” from the law.</time>
          <text>
              CHINESE SCORES
              EXCLUSION LAW
              OPPOSING THINKERS IN A
              HEATED DEBATE
              'UNJUST/ SAYS NG POON CHEW
              Noted Oriental and Rev. William
              Rader of San Francisco Argue
              Right of Exclusion
              Acts 7
              "Chinese exclusion as a measure of
              protection for, American labor Is a fal
              lacy. American labor needs no protec
              tion and the anti-Chinese crusade
              amounts to nothing more than the op
              pression of a set of foreigners without
              votes by, a set of foreigners with the
              voting power."
              jvNg Poon Chew, a noted San Francis
              co editor, was angry at the wrongs done
              his people and hurled his defiance at
              Rev. William Rader. In thel^ great de,
              bate before the Venice assembly last
              night. if"
              *j'Ng Poon Chew had' the negative side
              ;of^ the question,: "Resolved, that Chl
              'nese exclusion Is reasonable and neces
              sary, while Rev. William. Rader, also
              of San Francisco, upheld the offtrma
              ,'tlve.yW
              'As the first affirmative Rev. Rader
              the subject, outlined the ex-
              I lstlng conditions and the stand taken
              ;by T the present^admlnlstratlon.
              Rev. Mr. Rader Argues
              i-^ln'.part Rev. Rader said: "The exclu
              sion^ of the Chinese la not urged upon
              the .'grounds of prejudice. We have -no
              [objection to their religion. Joss is 'as
              free as "Jesus. No apology Is made for
              the 111 treatment of the exempt classes,
              ;but T ;l;'stand ..with i the. administration
              when It declares for coolie exclusion.
              A'V.'The question Is not a sentimental
              one. It is a question of national mean-
              Ing, f. We, should have uniform emigra
              tion, laws. More foreigners landed on
              our shores last year than there are peo
              ple* In Los 'Angeles and San Francisco;
              Sentiment' goes down before such facts.
              -"'"I maintain that it is within the.prov
              lnce of the state, to restrict' emigration
              If It so desires: Exclusion is practiced
              In; nature, in very home..,-;
              l.' "Chinese exclusion is reasonable and
              necessary for at least two great rea
              sons. .v
              "First, because of the effect that un
              restricted Immigration would have upon
              our civilization.: America cannot digest
              China. Chinese do not j assimilate: ■My
              opponent— an -exception— proves^., the
              rule.'| There is not another Chinaman in
              California who has reached the posl
              !tlon|thls -.man has j reached. We can
              make servants of the Chinese but not
              citizens and soldiers. They bring with
              ,lAein"; customs and vices which: add to
              bur disorders. They bring sanitary con
              ditions", which are a menace to the pub
              lic health.; In San' Francisco there have
              been 1 more deaths, ln' the Chinese quar
              ter] than"' In -the city 'proper. Li.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1906-01-10/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>1905-1907: Widespread debate over effect of Exclusion Act on U.S. economy and possible omission of certain “classes” from the law.</time>
          <text>
              EXCLUSION LAW IS VALID
              COURT OF APPEALS DECLARES
              CONGRESS HAD POWER TO
              EXTEND STATUTE.
              Cincinnati, Jan. 10.The case of
              Hong Wing against the United States,
              involving the Chinese exclusion act,
              was decided in favor of the United
              States circuit court of appeals in this
              city, the court holding that the act of
              .April 7, 1904, continued the exclusion
              act in full force, congress haying full
              potyer to dp so.
              Hong Wing is one of six Chinamen
              who had been ordered deported under
              the provisions of the Chinese exclu
              sion act and the cases being identical
              the one decision will apply to all six.
              Attorneys for the applicant main
              tained that the exclusion act was void
              and that their clients eould not be de
              ported.
              The decision was announced by
              Judge Richards, who said that the
              main point presented to the court was
              whether the act of April 7, 1904, con
              tinued the Chinese exclusion act in
              force and the court was satisfied that
              it did do so without reference to any
              existing treaties or regulations. The
              act was passed in view of the treaty
              expiring and it had continued the pro
              visions of the treaty. Congress has
              the power to modify, reject or concur
              in treaties and it had done what was
              wholly within its power in passing this
              act. The decision of the lower court
              was, therefore, sustained and the ap
              peal dismissed. '-..hffam
          </text>
      </result>
      <!-- five additional -->
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076200/1901-08-03/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>November 21-23, 1901: Chinese Exclusion Convention “demands” re-enactment of Exclusion Law to protect labor.</time>
          <text>
              CHINESE EXCLUSION.
              Miners' I nlon Petition* tor
              enactment of the Present tow.
              The Sentinel publisher below a lettei
              from a oommittee of th# Tosoarors
              Miners' Union together with a petition
              which it to be presented to Congrast
              asking the re-enactment of the Chinese
              Exclusion Act. The petition should be
              generally signed as the question ia one
              which appeals to the people of th ie
              State. The more against Chinese immi
              gration has been started in the right
              quarter—by the labor unions—aa the
              laboring people will be the greatest suf
              ferers ahonld the Chinese be permitted
              to again invade this country
              To the Kdltor of the Bxstinxl:
              The within petition will in a measure
              explain itself. The Chinese Exclusion
              Aot will expire by limitation in May,
              1902. As labor it the first to feel the
              evil effects of the importation of cheap
              labor and degraded workers, organized
              labor baa decided to appeal, through
              petition, to the people for a re-enact
              ment of the Chinese Exclusion Act, with
              mendments that appear in the petition.
              We do not deem it necessary to argue
              the question with the people of Nevada,
              for we think they folly understand the
              evils of Asiatio immigration and only
              want the opportunity presented to act.
              lienee we would ask you to be kind
              enough to give our letter and petition
              apace in your valuable paper to the end
              that the people may folly understand
              the purport of the petition when pre
              sented to them for signature. This com
              mittee will send petitions to every post
              office in Elko, Eureka, Lander and Hum
              boldt counties. From this you will see
              that our work ia large, but the stake
              played for—the Amerioan home—it
              worth it. Wa would respectfully urge
              every mao and women to act promptly;
              delays are dangerous. Any assistance
              through your valuable paper will be ap
              preciated.
          </text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025308/1892-01-30/ed-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <time>No timeline found</time>
          <text>
              Numesaous li gned' Petit ia. Asbklnll Con
              srqps to Pasil a stringent ExclusIon
              Act Agattist the, lioallants.
              The meeting at Assembly hall last night
              to discuss the 'Cbloese question was well
              attended by workingmen of Helena, J, E.
              Boncher presided and J. Y. Bennett was
              secretary, Chairman Boucher stated that
              all were no doubt aware that the Chinese
              exclusion act expired in May, and that a
              measure would be introduced in congress
              to continue the restriction. "It is a matter
              of interest to us and to the business men of
              Helena," bhe said. "I am surprised that
              there are not more basiness men present,
              But because there are eot more of them is
              no reason why we should not express our
              opinions."
              L i. Glidea said the meeting had been
              called by him to take action on the peti
              tions to congress for the exclusion of the
              Chinese, and for the election of senators by
              the direct vote of the people, both of which
              were suggeted by T. V. Powderly. The seo
              retary stated that he had petitions on the
              Chinese question prepared for the signa
              tures of those present and for other work
              ingmen's organizations. It was decided to
              allow five minutes to each man to talk on
              the subject. As this was announced one mani
              present began a rambling speech about the
              uselessness of the Chinese to the mer
              chants, the doctors and the real estate men,
              and was proceeding to state that China had
              44,000,000 people and the United States but
              17,000,000, when the bhairman called him
              down with the remark that this was a
              meeting to discuss a serious problem, and
              not a "josh." The culprit took his seat,
              and, the discussion was taken up in a seri
              ons strdin.
              John Finn suggested that the working
              men would have to come out and let it be
              known to the politicians that whoever was
              not on their side could not get thir votes.
              F. A. Adrian said they could nothing un
              less they all stood together and refused to
              patronize the Chinamen or those who em
              ployed them.
              Adolf Halest thought the question a grave
              one, not only because the Chinaman worked
              for less than a white person, but because
              what money these people got was with
              drawn from the already inadequate circulr
              tion and taken back to their native land.
              Besides that there were the vices the Chi
              nrmen brought here, such as the opium
              habit. While it was impossible to get rid
              of all the Chinamen now here, it would be
              well to keep others from comine. Those
              now here would soon die out. He said the
              working people had to patronize the Chi
              namen for their garden truck because no
              white man raised any, but that would not
              be enough to keep them here.
              Chairman Boncher said the solution of
              the problem was a difficult one. It might
              do to take the almost unprecedented step
              of sending all the Chinamen back, but as
              that was well nigh impossible, the next
              great question was how to mitigate the
              evil and reduce it to the minimum. The
              exclusion -act did nrot remedy the disease.
              it was not heroic enough. It was wonder
              ful how, when congress passed a law, it was
              so easy to evade it. The people of the
              United States were most considerate of
              evil doers. It would seem that when any
              great wrong was committed it was neces
              sary for a certain class of people to get out
              and roar, and all the others called them
              agitators. Perhaps Dennis Kearney was an
              agitator, but he had a kick. No attention
              was paid to him, but when the trouble be
              gan to effect the upper classes, then congress
              took action. There were certain stores on
              Broadway occupied by Chinamen as mer
              chants. If the Chinman ever vacated the
              places the stores could never be rented to a
              white man for the same sum. That had
              been found out in Portland and San Fran
              oisco. But the Helena business men knew
              it all; they would not learn by experience.
              When the merchants began to feel the effect
              of the presence of the Chinese then the
              legislators would act. He feared they never
              would act on the appeal of the workingmen.
              "I he only way I see is to pass an exclusion
              not that will last forever." he continued.
              "We must say to our legislators that this is
              the one thing we insist upon. The Knights
              of Labor have a clause in. their declaration
              of principles that no creed or color shall be
              prohibited from being members. The same
              is found in the constitution of the United
              Statee. Yet Jefferson and the other fram
              ers of the constitution never meant a lot of
              vampires and bloodsuckers should be ad
              mnitted who come because we have some
              thing they want, aeni who, when they get
              it, go back home to enjoy it. Our only way
              is to impress on the minds of the people
              who are in office and those who want to get
              there, that their present and further safety
              depends on the passage of an exclusion act
              that will last forever."
              When the petition to congress was being
              passed around for signatures Mr. Gildea
              suggested taking up the senatorial question,
              but Michael Corbett thought that it would
              be bad policy to drop the Chinese matter at
              this point. He favored continuing to hold
              the meetines, but in a larger place. He
              also suggested withdrawing all patronage
              from the Chinamen. The quickest way to
              get rid of them is to lot them alone, Mr.
              Gildea said the Chinese question had been
              effectually disposed of so far as the present
              meeting was concerned. The question of
              electing senators by direct vote of the peo
              ple was eof as great, if not greater import
              ance than the Chinese question. The
              Chinese exclusion noact had been in force ten
              years, but it was a prohibition that did not
              prohibit. The other question was one of
              bringing the senato s closer to the people,
              where they conld,bo dealt with better and dic
              tated to in stronger terms than they could
              be now. Chairman Bouocher wanted
              another and a larger meeting with the
              business men present. liecretary Bennett
              did not have much faith in the business
              men attending. "As an example of their
              duplicity, or policy," he said, "you will re
              member that the council unanimously
              passed anti-Chinese resolutions. Four of
              ths men who voted for them employ China
              men in their houses. One told me it was
              because better service could be had from
              the Chinamen. The other said he would
              talk about it when the Burlingame treaty
              was rescinded." Mr. Gildea then moved to
              take up the senatorial question.
          </text>
      </result>
    </results>
</topic>