<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-eiffel-tower</id>
    <results>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1889-04-02/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.058,0,1.116,1.41,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1889: The Eiffel Tower opens as a part of the 1889 World’s Fair in Paris. The tallest structure in the world at the time, it is to be taken down after 20 years.</time>
            <text>THE EIFFEL TOWER
                A Msht and Sensation for lisitor to
                1arls
                In view of the assurance of a
                creditable representation of Hawaii
                both in productions and person
                agesat the Universal Exhibition of
                this year in Paris a few facts rela
                tive to the EiffeUower culled from
                a late English paper may be of local
                interest
                The tower is named after its pro
                jector Mr Eiffel now President of
                the French Association of Engineers
                He is famed in part -for the design
                ing of a great bridge at Bordeaux
                Although the Eiffel tower was orig
                inally the conception mainly of an
                ambition likened to that of Ameri
                cans by the English paper referred
                to for having the highest structure
                in the world it was also early as
                sumed that it would have uses in the
                interest of science It is claimed
                and anticipated that it will be very
                raluable for observatory purposes
                owing to the perfect clearness of the
                air at its summit
                The tower is to be one thousand
                feet in height At the date of the
                description here drawn upon it had
                attained an altitude of 738 feet or
                162 feet higher than any other build
                ing on earth There were 180 men
                employed then in its construction
                100 preparing the lifts at the base
                and 80 riveting the perfectly fitted
                parts at top To avoid fatiguing the
                workmen aloft in descending several
                times a day for food a restaurant is
                fitted up at a height of about 400
                feet There are to bo four perman
                ent restaurants for the refreshment
                of visitors on the first stage of the
                tower
                A spiral stairway runs from the
                ground to the summit of the tower
                but it is believed that few if any in
                experienced heads will be able to en
                dure the strain of going round and
                round or looking down from the
                giddy heights Therefore there are
                to be mechanical lifts to the top
                four to the first stage two to the
                second and thence one to the sum
                mit the crown of observation The
                final lift will have a capacity of 65
                persons I1 ares will be 6 francs to
                the first stage and 5 francs to the
                top to be reduced on Sundays to 1
                franc and 3 francs respectively No
                visitors are allowed during construc
                tion except on Sundays owing to
                danger of accident from a hammer
                or bolt falling from aloft Mr iffol
                pays a weekly visit to thoworks The
                workmeu have to endure severe cold
                at the summit whore the thermome
                ter sometimes registers several de
                grees below zero
                The panoramic view to be obtained
                of the beautiful city of Paris and
                environs froin the top of the Eiffel
                tower must be loft to the readers
                imagination until assisted by ac
                counts from the Hawaiian Commis
                sioners Col Spalding and Hon J
                A Cummins or unofficial visitors
                from these isies or descriptive writ
                ers in the foreign press after ex
                periencing the sensations of the
                sublime ascension and prospect
                UHfrnisMuaii</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1889-04-26/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+Exhibition+1000+Feet+High+France+French+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.335,-0.303,1.669,2.11,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1889: The Eiffel Tower opens as a part of the 1889 World’s Fair in Paris. The tallest structure in the world at the time, it is to be taken down after 20 years.</time>
            <text>NEARLY 1000 FEET HIG&amp;
                The Great Eiffel Tower at the
                Paris Exposition.
                How the Colossal Structure, Just
                Completed, was Erected.
                The great Eiffel tower at the Paris Exhi
                bition has just been completed, and a de
                scription of the colossal structure, with an
                account of the way it was built, and a sketch
                of its constructor, will bo appropriate at this
                time. It is scarcely necessary to say that the
                U
                mm

                Cologne
                Cathedral,
                511 ft.
                The Eiffel Tower,
                9S4 ft. The Great
                Pyramid,
                480 ft.
                Eiffel tower is by far the highest structure in
                the world. It presents a decidedly unique ap
                pearance, too in general outline not unlike a
                stack of four gigantic muskets with their
                butts well and solidly spread and their bay
                onets joining at their tips.
                The Eiffel tower stands in the Champ de
                Mars, almost on the left bank of the river
                Seine, just in the rear of the Quai d'Orsay,
                and in fact a part of its foundation is sunk
                through an old arm of the river, which lias
                been filled in these many years. Its base
                covers a plot of ground 328 feet square, or
                nearly two and a half acres in extent.
                GUSTAVF. EIFFEL.
                It Ls really at the base a group of four tow
                ers, each nearly fifty feet square, placed at
                the corners of the plot of ground, and in
                clining toward each other as they rise at an
                angle of fifty-four degrees. Each tower con
                sists of four columns, bound together by
                trusswork, and each column rests on a
                masonry pier which is so built that the weight
                of the column rests upon it squarely and not
                at an ancle.
                As the tower is 0S4 feet high. it will be
                seen that the matter of providing a solid
                foundation was one of great importance.
                There was a lot of boring and digging befon
                the spot upon which the tower stands was
                finally selected.
                The foundation rests upon a thick stratum
                of sand and gravel. It may be well to say.
                for the benefit of those who think sand is a
                rather treacherous sort f ground, that a bed
                of sand and gravel, away under ground, is
                pretty solid stuff. One of the towers of the
                Brooklyn Bridge rests on that sort of base.
                The foundations of the two piers of the Eiffel
                tower farthest from the Seine rest on sand
                and gravel about twenty-five feet below the
                surface of the ground. These foundations
                were laid in open excavations, and consist
                first of great solid platforms of beton, six
                feet thick, and next of four stone piers which
                rise to the surface to receive the iron col
                umns. The foundations for the two piers nearest
                the river were not so easily laid. It was
                necessary to go thirty-five feet below the
                surface of the ground, end this was sixteen
                feet under water. So caissons had to be
                used, as they were in building the Brooklyn
                Bridge piers.
                A caisson is in effect simply an enormous
                iron box, without any cover, turned upside
                down. The method of using it is to dig the
                earth out from under it and allow it to
                gradually settle as the excavation pro
                gresses, meanwhile building the pier on top.
                When the required depth is reached the cais
                a .n itself is filled up with the beton, and it
                forms the bottom layer of it a foundation.
                A shaft is left running through the pier
                auove for entrance and exit as the work goes
                on, and the air in the caisson and shaft is
                compressed to whatever is necessary to keep
                the water out of the bottom. It is the prin
                ciple of the diving bell modified.
                Work on the foundations was begun on
                January 28, 1887, and at the end of June they
                were completed. Then began the labor of
                setting up the innumerable pieces of iron of
                which the tower is composed, and it went on
                at a vapid rate, for each individual piece
                came from the works of M. Eiffel, at Leval-lois-Pere
                cut to its exact dimensions, fitted
                and drilled, so that no modification was neces
                sary at the place of operations. Up to a
                height of about fifty feet the workmen re
                quired no scaffolding to work upon, as each
                pier supported itself, although each leaned
                toward the others. Then an artificial support
                had to le provided, as above that height, un
                til the first platform was reached, the center
                of gravity of each pier would fall outside of
                the base.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1889-05-07/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Expo+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.038,-0.005,1.195,1.611,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1889: The Eiffel Tower opens as a part of the 1889 World’s Fair in Paris. The tallest structure in the world at the time, it is to be taken down after 20 years.</time>
            <text>Pxitia, May At 3 o'clock Sunday after
                noon, M. Carnot, presidont of tho Ropublic,
                soaompaniod by a number of ominont states
                Mat, proceeded to .the Champs do Mars and
                formally declared tho exposition open to tho
                world. Thoro was much music and but lit
                tle speech making. The city is profusely
                Adorned with flags and banners; after dark
                gut lights, oloctrioity and fireworks blend in
                splendors noTor before equalled; and for
                meatus to come Paris will be the Mecca of
                th sightseers of the world.
                MAcm.tniiT nxLL.
                Xilherte, in 18GT and 1678, she has had
                world's fairs, which wers at those times the
                greatest yet held. The third, thich was
                pasted Sunday, far oxceeds them in inagni
                tod importanco and splendor as human
                MtaeremonU of the present surpass those of
                cto tho proximate past. In 1878 there
                ware displayed inventions that in 1807 would
                bars been esteemed chimorical; this year, in
                tarn, soos an array that scarcoly the wildest
                omthusiast had dreamed of cloven years ago.
                Tho Actual physic.il oxtont of tho present ex
                hibition correspondingly goes beyond that
                f its prcleceior. The exposition covers 103
                acres.
                The gardens of the Hotel des Invalided
                contain the exhibitions of tho French
                colonies, of tho several ministers and of
                social economy. At the Quai d'Orny aro
                tho halls of agriculture, viticulture, INhorios
                and general food products. The Trocudoro
                gardens are given up to fruits and flowers
                in tho open air and in glass houses. Tho
                principal buildings aro clustered on the
                Champs de Mars, where a century ago, somo
                of tho great oponing scenes of the revolution
                wero ouacted.
                At tho ontranco, spanning the gateway
                witu the vast archways of Ite base, rises tho
                gigantic Eiffel tower, 'MO metres high. Pass
                ing underneath it tho Central gardou is
                i cached. This has a monumental fountain
                BASE OF EIFFEL TOWER,
                ia tho middlo, and is surrounded by build
                ings containing exhibitions of flue arts,
                boUos lettres, tho liberal arts, and various
                departments of industry.
                Those buildings stand on parallel lines and
                ore crossed in their axis by a high gallery
                manaounted by a doma which leads to th
                hatt of machinery. Tho cost of tho build
                ings in tho Champs do Mars, exclusivo of tho
                Mffel tower, has been about (4,000,000, and
                it is intended that they shall remain as per
                aaaent structures. The total outlay author
                ised for tho entire exposition U 38,600,000, of
                wttch $000,000 is hold aa a rcerve fund.
                The earthworks required a removal of
                700,000 cubic foot. Tke drains and water
                pipes of the Camps do Mars were lengthened
                hf about two miles, and more than 40,009
                ems of iron and steel wero u&amp;ed by the
                holders. The hall of machinery is 1,309 feet
                long and 150 feet high, covered with a roof
                f iron, wood and glass, having a span of
                380 feet in tho clear, the greatest ever at
                tempted. A gullory extends around tke in
                terior for the display of tho lighter classes of
                machinery and from end to end run four un
                ferofcen linos of shafting for distributing the
                Beotivo power. Tho powor is dorived from a
                proup of steam engines placed in one of
                the touts, tho bollors of which transform
                into steam forty tons of wator per hour.
                The total energy is about 400 horse power.
                TJio chief architectural feature of the ex
                position is, of course, tho Eiffel tower, as
                wore the Crystal Palace at London In 1851,
                the iron lighthouse at Paris in 1807, tho groat
                THE EIFFEL TOWZ&amp; VBOX THE BEINK
                rotunda at Vionna in 1873, and the Trocadero
                palace at Paris in 1878. This is the loftiest
                structure eyer rahedjjy Iman, being about
                064 feet high. The Washington monumont
                now stands second, 55.5 feet. The Cologno
                cathedral is 501 feot. Tho tower of Babol
                was probably CS0 high. Moro than 7,000
                tons of metal were us?d in building tho
                Eiffel tower. Tho first sod was turned in
                excavation for its foundation on January
                28, 1887, and the whole work was completed
                on March 31, 1889.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032018/1894-01-31/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+1900+Exhibition&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.304,-0.08,1.608,1.608,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>The World's lair in 1900.
                Already the air is' filled with rumors
                respecting the exposition of 1900, says
                a Paris letter in the Philadelphia Tel
                graph. Already are the moans of the
                Parisians rending the air beforehand,
                for it is a Parisian peculiarity to detest
                world's fairs in general, and those held
                in their own city in particular. Quoth
                a miserable native in heartrending ac
                cents: "Whenever there is a great ex
                hibition all our taxes go up-rtempo-rarily
                we are told, but never by an ac
                cident do they go down. I paid three
                hundred and eighty francs in '77,
                and for the same premises my taxes
                are now three thousand and odd. We
                are overrun by tourists; we are crowd
                ed out of all the theaters; the cabmen
                all go on strike; the cafes all put up
                their prices. For several years before
                all the streets one wants to go through
                are closed to the public because the ex
                hibition is being prepared, and for at
                least a year after the same streets are
                closed because the exhibition is being
                demolished. All your country cousins
                come to town and expect to stay with
                you in an apartment you have always
                found too cramped for the require
                ments of yonr own family; and if I am
                not lucky enough to be dead I shall
                certainly move away before this large
                misfortune falls upon this unhappy
                place."
                tj Happily all Paris is not so pessi
                mistic as my friend, and the architects
                are busy with their plans. All the
                ground comprised in the exhibition of
                '89 is to be included, as well as the por
                tion of Cour la Heine that will inclose
                the Palais 1' Industrie and its surround
                ing gardens. We are to have an addi
                tional bridge across the Seine which
                will open a vista from the Place de la
                Concorde straight through to the palace
                of electricity, which is to be the cen
                tral feature. Our rulers are greatly
                bored about the Eiffel tower; but as
                the concession was granted for twenty
                years it has got to stand; but the arch
                itects say consolingly that the 7 will
                try and hide it as much as possible.
                The sight of it vexes poetio souls,
                and Francois Coppee, the author, who
                is, by way of being, sthetio, wrote
                a formal protest to the government at
                the time of its erection to request that
                the plan should not be carried out on
                the ground that the Eiffel tower, being
                ugly and ungainly, and furthermore
                being visible from his windows, inter
                fered with his flow of inspiration.
                However, the tower was built never
                theless, and, although we are deadly
                tired of seeing it about, Coppee con
                tinues to write, so evidently his flow
                ol inspiration was only impeded and
                not permanently plugged up. Further
                more, we are to have a branch exhibit
                at Versailles, which will rouse that
                sleepy little town from its chief ou
                pation of listening to the grass grow
                ing in the streets. In the splendid
                park of Versailles, on either side of
                the grand canal, is to be the retro
                spective history of gardens throughout
                the ages.
                The Hanging Gardens of Babylon,
                that were counted among the wonders
                of the world, are to be reproduced in
                miniature; Japanese gardens, Persian
                gardens, the Italian garden of the
                renaissance and French and English
                gardens of different epochs. The
                Grand canal itself is to be used for the
                exhibition of one of the floating gar
                dens cultivated by the Aztecs in Mex
                ico before the Spanish conquest of the
                country. The center of the canal is to
                be occupied by a large island built on
                piles, with bridges connecting it with
                the two shores, which is to have
                aquaria, grottoes and cascades, with
                cages for aquatic birds, and the great
                sheet of water is to be additionally or
                namented, by an exact reproduction of
                the little fleet of elegant boats that
                Louis XIV. launched on its surface
                when Versailles was first built All
                this sounds most imposing; but we are
                devoutly thankful that the time for it
                has not yet come. It is like the 6tory
                of the philosopher who was to teach
                the king's donkey to speak in a year's
                time, on pain of death, and never
                bothered about the penalty on the
                crowd tMt the kin? mLrht UJ
                the "doSkey "might' die, or ha
                himself might die, and whatever hap
                pened he had a year to the good. So,
                as we have seven years before us, we
                do not yet as a rule wail about future
                contingencies.
                POLANDCHINA PIGS AND SHORT
                horns, bred by J. H. Taylor, Pearl, Eas.
                MEGGlNCUBaT0nS0rilY$1Q
                F.M.CUEYlA,Boxl51,Lincoln,NebV I v
                AGE
                Wanted. Liberal Salary
                AthotneortotrTl. Team rural, hrd
                free. P. O. VICKKBY, AaoiU, He.
                AND TUMORS aolan tlfUally
                I treated and cured. No knife.
                Rook ft. Dr. L. II. tiralla-ay.
                1 SO SkMIU A, Clarlaaali, Ohio.
                FOR LADIES ONLYJXTi
                Valuable Secret that cost me 15.00 and a Rubber Shield for SOetSi
                Mia f ft.ftTlAN tX!.,ofi KlVMSyiHUIAflfX, fTfo
                BH0RTHAND gong raSIkBMkataklapiB. Sum
                ptoat tat an Tm, eoqaM to iha tuuatiaaa ewun4
                rtuMM W BatM,Titarrpt m Shunt DrartraM. ft. H.
                lira (art, laoaai dtf Bartrnai UoMtntv. iaaaw Utf. at
                Permanently Cured
                Home treatment. 0 to t35.
                Bend stamp for hook.
                jno. B. Harris, Port Payne, Ala.
                ftr A MnNTH"i"!!I"i!f"7;
                MU a montn to dUtfiMM circular,, warypwu momuij. omii
                U oar modi and contract free. Send 10 cti. for pottage, packing,
                f.'.,. Wi MtinKwim VSWS SUI'PI.Y CO.Cmca.ia In.
                $COC Agent's profltspermonth. Will
                J Cm J prove It or pay forfeit. New arti
                cles juat oat. A L60 sample and terms free. Try
                us. Chideater Son, 38 Bond at, N. Y.
                MICROBE cause disease; Microbe Killer
                kills microbes. Cures all diseases. Write
                for agency. Big money: exclusive control. If
                sick write for pampnlet. Try our granules;
                finest laxative In the world; 250 postpaid.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1899-02-03/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair+Ladder+Clouds&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.241,-0.074,1.483,1.483,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1889: The Eiffel Tower opens as a part of the 1889 World’s Fair in Paris. The tallest structure in the world at the time, it is to be taken down after 20 years.</time>
            <text>A LADDER FROM THE CLOUDS
                Bach Will Be the Appearance of the
                Eiffel Tower of Parts When
                Painted.
                The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
                of esthetic temperament, must go.
                The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
                who know the law, must stay for some
                years yet. The Eiffel tower, say the
                esthetes. Is ugly, discouraging to the
                eye and an all-round nightmare. "Scaf
                fold I cries the carper. "Down with it
                It has no place in esthetic Paris,"
                "Impossible! objects the law. "When
                the company took a lease of it they
                got it for a term of 20 years.. You
                can't break the lease, and the time is
                nowhere up.
                "But, urges the esthete, "look at
                the shape, look at the size, look at the
                color! Is not the whole thing hideous"?
                If we can't destroy it we can at least
                improve it and lessen the offense to
                our senses."
                And so the Eiffel tower is going to be
                metamorphosed. It has. been in color
                a reddish brown, and it is the color to
                which the gentlemen with the fine ideas
                have long objected. They have called
                the tower a shameless creation and re
                peatedly ridiculed the commonplace
                tone of hue. And now they have pre
                v ailed, and the lower is going to be a
                thing of beauty, so far as that goes.
                Silver white is the color agreed upon,
                and it is urged that when the army of
                workmen have finished their painting
                the huge structure will look really not
                so bad after all. Ilalf a hundred men
                will be employed on the building, work
                ing hard every day for two months.
                And 50,000 kilogrammes of paint will
                be used up before the Eiffel tower has
                finally lost its brickdust coat and finds
                itself arrayed in the poetic covering
                which the esthetes have advised. Two
                coats of paint will be applied and the
                brushes will be busy.
                It has been objected that the tbwer
                has always had the appearance or hav
                ing been cast up in inartistic form by
                a careless earth. The tower has seemed
                to rise awkwardly from the ground,
                the critical have said. Why not give
                it such an arrangement as would sug
                gest the idea of dropping from the
                clouds? That would be a pleasing fan
                cy, and if the huge tower were lighted
                at regular intervals it would present a
                picture as of a brilliant creature of the
                clouds, and all the world would be lost
                in admiration. These plans were sug
                gested when the exposition of 1900 were
                tinder discussion, and they have been
                adopted. A ladder from the clouds.
                That was tbe idea. 'And with that the
                esthetic taste, was forced to be sat
                isfied.
                The Eiffel tower has long been the
                universal bed lamp of Paris. The great
                candle in the top would be sadly miss-d,
                even by those who have fought agair.&amp;t
                the continuance of the structure. That
                ever-swaying lantern is one of the won
                ders of the French capital. Y. Her
                aid.
                Kicked All Around.
                A correspondence is being published
                In the Times on the subject of "French
                Feeling Toward Englishmen." A Mr.
                Jackson has written to that paper to
                repeat that at Caen recently a student
                went out of his way to publiely insult
                Great Britain. As a boy I was first for
                some years at school in Paris. I -was
                then kicked for being an Englishman;
                later I was transferred to a school in
                England, where I was kicked for being
                a Frenchman. Comment is unneces
                sary. London Truth.
                Bis Only neeoorie.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1903-10-25/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Doomed+Rocks+Wind+Paris+France+French+Gustav&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.216,-0.072,1.431,1.431,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1903- 1913: Gustave Eiffel’s successful experiments with wireless broadcasting and communication convince the City of Paris to let the Eiffel Tower remain standing.</time>
            <text>THE Eiffel Tower must come down.
                The authorities of Paris have so decreed.
                This iron spire, the tallest structure in the
                world, and the engineering feat of the last cen
                tury, \.i regarded as a dangerous plaything.
                When a high wind blows from the south the great
                ribbed structure trembles like a frightened horse.
                But let a stiff breeze come bowling down from the
                north and the tower vibrates until the china rattles in
                the cafes, and to those in the observatory at the apex the
                sensation is that of a ship fossed by heavy seas.
                The fact that the tower is more'sensitive to a wind
                from the north than from the south is regarded as proof
                of the structural weakness, and from this springs the
                theory of danger of collapse.
                It is almost twenty years since Gustav Eiffel began
                the work of building his sky-scraper. The mark of com
                pletion was set for 1889, Exposition year, and on March 31
                of that year the tower was thrown open to the public. It
                wa« the leading attraction of the big show, and it has
                not since ceased to attract attention and coin.
                The cost of building the structure was more than
                $1,000,000. Of that amount the French government appro
                priated $29L',000. Eiffel supplied the remainder, trusting
                for his reimbursement to the receipts from admission fees
                and other sources.
                In this he was not uisappolnted, as the profits of the
                first year were almost sufficient to make him whole.
                The lease held by Eiffel will expire in next March, and
                then, if the present plans of the city fathers are realized,
                the work of razing the unique structure will be started.
                The plan is to sell the tower to the highest bidder, the
                purchaser to be given a certain time in which to remove
                what Paris regards as almost a public menace.
                Except as a curio and an Investment for its builder,
                the tower has been somewhat of a failure.
                Much was expected in the scientific world from the
                metaphorical observatory, with its physical and biological
                laboratories, all 954 feet above ground. But little has
                come of this, the enterprise having taken on a rather
                commercial aspect.
                The Eiffel Tower will ever be considered a colossa*
                feat of engineering.
                Tlhese Stria! Ihxean F®ds ire nsudhes hM
                .'v_V- Ir 'mJf.A?j -i?'^^t Vk^T*i^*v*
                THE beanstalk up which Jack, the Giant Killer,
                climbed to fame has been sung and pictured until
                even little Emma and Annie and Jeannette and
                Joe, sprawled there on the nursery floor, can tell
                of its sturdy trunk, of its stout, ladder-like branches, of
                Its leathery leaves, which the eager hands of their hero.
                Jack, could not crush, though he clutched them ever so
                tightly.
                They can tell you that this fabled beanstalk was so
                tall that "Oo! you jest couldn't see the top uv it, so you
                couldn't."
                DRINKERS IN TWO CLASSES
                ==Mlsery and L,Mxtuiry==
                BOTH CLAIM THEIR VICTIMS OF LIQUOR
                LONDON, August 17.
                WOMEN who drink are classified by the experts
                into two sections—misery drinkers and luxury
                drinkers.
                Speaking broadly, the misery drinkers come
                from the very poor, the luxury drinkers from the rich.
                But whatever the cause which first sends them to drink
                the ultimate results are the same—a falling birth-rate, a
                rising death-rate among infants and the physical degen
                eration of the race.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-04-23/ed-1/seq-5/ocr/</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>Paris. Stars and stripes hung be
                side tri-color on Eiffel tower Sunday,
                afternoon, while formal salute of 21
                guns was fired in its fconor. It was
                United States day in Paris and Amer
                ican flags -were everywhere.
                New York. Local newspapers
                adopt resolution criticizing press
                censorship provision of espionage
                bill "assault upon very foundation ol
                our free institutions, freedom ol
                thought and freedom of speech."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
                https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1907-05-18/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=Dangerous+Painting+World+Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Republic+Gustav&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.149,-0.412,1.111,2.36,0</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1903- 1913: Gustave Eiffel’s successful experiments with wireless broadcasting and communication convince the City of Paris to let the Eiffel Tower remain standing.</time>
            <text>The Trocadero m Seen Through the
                "Lege" of the Tower.
                Height of the Great Tower
                as Compared to Some of
                the World's Tallest
                Structures.
                Special Correspondence of The Star.
                PARIS, May A, 1907.
                A painter has Just fallen from the Eiffel
                Tower. Four more men must fall to make
                the awful average of the most dangerous
                painting Job in the world?repeated every
                six years only.
                They are repainting the Eiffel Tower,
                and all Paris is concerned about the color,
                on which depends whether the gigantic
                mass of iron shall be the eyesore or the
                glory of the capital.
                Its first shade was "dead leaf," In 1889.
                When the sun lit it up to hazy golden with
                an unreal effect of Jeweler's fragility, even
                the artists who now corse it admitted that
                the Eiffel Tower had its nobility.
                In 1896, after immense discussion, they
                repainted It orange, magnetic currents
                even more than light and weather having
                turned it to a dingy chocolate, heavy and
                obtrusive. In strong sun the orange
                showed gleaming copper or red gold. Oscar
                Wilde declared It magnificent. Puvis de
                Chavannes threatened to blow It up with
                dynamite. From this period dated the bad
                name the tower acquired as a colossal
                piece of engineering vulgarity, usurping
                the artistic note of Paris.
                Then, for the exposition, they painted it
                "sun color." In bright lights the tower
                became a thing of glory once again.
                "All Depends Upon the Faint."
                "All depends upon the paint!" declares
                the city's architect, Bouyard, "a fact
                which shows the utter inartistic character
                of the Titan 1^3 intruder. The pyramids ol
                Egypt were originally cased with gleaming
                marble; but its present lack does not
                detract from the artistic appropriateness
                of the pyramids to their situation!"
                The tower gleamed sun color seven years
                agoi But the atmospheric electricity received
                every hour since then by such an
                unprecedented mass of iron reaching into
                the air so high is Incalculable. Conducting
                tubes a foot and a half in diameter
                lead it down the four niles to flftv feet be
                low the water-bearing stratum; but the
                effect on the paint la there for every one
                to see. It does not crack the paint off.
                The paint simply disappears, leaving the
                ugly chocolate, the dingy brown of the
                oxidising iron.
                It Is the tower's way of "calling for new
                victims. Fifty painters, working continuously
                together, take three months to do a
                ingle coat Few tourists realise- the immense
                proportions of the tower, but
                Parisian!, by experience, show you a peculiar
                phenomenon of Its deceptive symmetry.
                They take you In a cab close to the
                tower. It looks heavy and chunky. It
                seems sinking into the earth from lU
                weight. Half a mile distant from that
                oab the tower grows higher and slenderer.
                It seems to lift Itself from the earth, like
                a person rising from his knees. "Why, It's
                bigger than before!" you say. At a mil*
                distant-It seems quite as near. The river
                boats ttmt flit beside It now look tiny. The
                buildings round about are growing small.
                But the tower grows! Then at two miles?
                from the heights above Passy?It appears
                A 4kin? A# litfhtnMa hl alAn^nrAf
                Efc IIIIUB Vi u fc?v? gutiUVBWi ?and
                more open In Its lacework than when
                you gaped at its foot almost disappointed!
                In a country town thirty miles from
                Paris I have sat at night and watched Its
                leaxchltsht!
                Some Comparisons.
                Tou think Niagara Falls are high? They
                are 105 feet, and St. Paul's Cathedral, Lon- 1
                don. is 404 feet. Niagara Falls could de
                scend from below St. Paul's dome. Now
                place St. Paul's beside the Eiffel tower. It
                reaches only to the second platform of the
                tower?the real beginning of its slender
                shaftl
                Place the Eiffel tower beside the greatest
                buildings of the world. The great pyramid
                does not reach to Its Intermediate platform.
                Neither does the spire of the Cologne 1
                Cathedral.
                Only one 'set of buildings, nevertheless,
                are higher than the Cologne Cathedral
                Bplre. They are the sky-scrapers of American
                dtles, the tallest actually existing being,
                say, 6S6 feet high. It would not reach to
                the tower's intermediate platform, either.
                The loftiest masonry construction In the
                world is to be the Singer building extension,
                at the corner of Liberty street and
                Broadway, New Torlc. Beating any other J i
                American sky-scraper by 57 feet, it will i
                stick 612 feet into the air. And yet even j
                It will not reach to the Eiffel tower's inter- i
                mediate platform 1
                You can easily detect this intermediate i
                platform half way up the slender shaft of 3
                the Eiffel tower. In the nearer photographs j
                It shows for what it is?a mere platform
                for styftlng passengers from one set of ele- t
                vators to another, built In the center of the 1
                the time you git left. This yere man. Bob
                Hampton, Is my prisoner, an' I'll take him
                to Cheyenne. If I have ter brain every tough t
                in Glencaid to do It. Thet's me, gents." 1
                "Oh, come oft; you can't run your notions j
                igin the whole blame moral sentiment of c
                this camp." c</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1912-09-14/ed-1/seq-23/ocr/</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>IParis
                fV
                Birdseye View of Paris Taken From the Top of the Eiffel Tower. In the Distance
                May Be Seen the Arc de Triomphe, Around
                Which Is Situated the Most Fashionable and Aristocratic Residential Quarter in
                Paris.
                (PHOTOGRAPH BY COURTESY OF NEWMAN TRAVELTALKS.)

            </text>
        </result>
    </results>
</topic>