<topics><topic>
    <id>
    https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-motorcycle-mania
    </id>
    <results>
       <result>
           <id>
           https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042591/1869-01-22/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=0.262,0.46,0.524,0.273,0
           </id>
           <rel>1</rel>
           <time>1869: An article reviews the history of the “velocipede” (self-propelled, wheeled vehicles).</time>
           <text>
           THE VELOCIPEDE. “Nothing is at once invented and perfected,” says an old Latin maxim, the truth of whose application was made manifest in the early history of the velocipede. Like all things on earth it was forty years in the wilderness. It first made its appearance in Paris and received notice of the following effect in the Courier de Paris. The date of the extract was July 25, 1789: “It was stated that a certain vehicle, invented by M. M. Blanchard and Massaurier—the former the celebrated aeronaut—was exhibited in rapid motion in the Place Louis XII. on July 27, 1789, in presence of many members of the French academy and a large concourse of spectators. At the front of the machine was the head of an eagle with outspread wings, to which was attached the apparatus with which the driver directed its movements. Behind him was seated an individual who gave an impetus, more or less rapid, to the machine by pressing his feet alternately on the ground. He sat down or stood at discretion, with his legs half concealed in a sort of box, where the springs that communicated
           movement to the machine were evidently placed. The vehicle was subsequently transported to Versailles, and exhibited its capabilities in presence of Louis XVI, Maria Antoinette and their court. There is nothing to show why this experiment failed, but it is to be supposed that it had its defects.” The second appearance was also in 1808, and public exhibitions were made of its workings in the Jardin du Luxembourg, but without success. At that time it was mounted on very low wheels, and the rider had to support himself by placing his feet directly on the ground. Such a mechanism was of course rudimentary, and the result was that the invention was extensively ridiculed and caricatured, and in these archives only do any traces of the first experiments made with this machine in the garden of Luxembourg exist. But the modern railroad locomotive was also sneered at and caricatured, and so was the modern steamboat. And the early inventors, who sought to make the world wiser, were called disciples of the black art, and friends of the devil. And more, they were socially 
           ostracized; they were hooted at and stoned by the mob, and sometimes burned at the stake. But they never ceased scheming and planning, nor was the velocipede to stop here. Twenty years after its first exhibition the velocipede reappeared in Paris. This time, a public functionary, one M. Dreuze, perfected the machine of twenty years before, and again exhibited it in its improved form. M. Dreuze secured the rider’s point of support upon the axletrees to the two wheels instead of the ground, and thus created the actual modern velocipede. The inventor, who belonged to the administration of postoffices, also formed the further idea of proposing this machine for the use of rural postmen, as being of greater availability in the matter of speed and promptness, and at the same time causing them less The plan was adopted, but unfortunately, just in the winter season, when many difficulties existed in the way of locomotion. The wheels slipped about in the mud, and plans were frustrated, and the enterprise was again considered a failure. At this late date, it would have 
           been suggested that it was only necessary to iron the wheels or suspend the use of the velocipede during the winter; but the French Government lacks invention and dropped the velocipede. “Three times and out,” is the old saying, but not so with our subject. A few years on, and, undiscouraged, the velocipede appeared a third time, and again in an altered form—this time being a little carriage upon three wheels and propelled by the hands of the rider. This machine did not succeed on account of the difficulty in guiding it and the fatigue it caused the guider. It is a well-known fact that the muscles of the legs can be used much longer than those of the arms, and, acting upon this hint, all good velocipedes are so arranged that the action of the arms is merely complimentary to that of the legs. This failure was the result of not attending to this fact. “The mills of the gods grind slowly, but they grind exceedingly fine.” Science and improvement move like the tortoise, but still, they move, as Galileo said of the world. When a pebble is dropped in the water your 
           eye loses the ripple. But that little splash has displaced every drop in the stream, and the water you see before you has been completely changed. The velocipede as it has been exhibited thus far was an idea dropped into the mud, and that idea must grow, and the mind must be revolutionized before its work ends. In the presence of success who is so bold as to laugh. Ridicule falls harmless before the iron armor of prosperity. And the velocipede succeeded. Paris, where it was hooted at and frowned down, now lifts up the prostrate work, and the thing despised yesterday is the idol worshipped to-day. It is the poetry of justice, and the two share the triumph. The thoroughfares of Paris are thronged with countless riders on the strange creature, and the public have warned the velocipede votaries that they must carry their lanterns on their vehicles to avoid accidents. The mania has spread to all classes, and to the suburban cities of the capital. In St. Cloud, Vincennes, Engheim, Pantim; in Bordeaux, Marseilles, and the other principal cities, the people are all 
           riding this economical species of iron horse, which requires no feed, harness, stable, or groom to care for it. The velocipede and velocipede mania has reached America. It struck New Orleans many years ago. But the inhabitants of that benighted burg thought it might be the "yellow jack" in disguise, and gave it the cold shoulder. Time passed, and all Europe was ablaze with enthusiasm and astride of their favorite Philadelphia, stand and quakerish, has adopted the velocipede with but little less enthusiasm than New York. Jersey is practicing, and so are the swells and the broadcloth fractions of the rectangular city bid fair to rival New York in their exhibition of the new order of equestrianism. Chicago, as in all things, rides velocipedes are becoming a matter of every day occurrence on our streets. Our tradesmen and mechanics are beginning to lay them in for sale. The fever is catching, by the time the season opens we will see them coming among our regular institutions. If they are to prove a success, there is no city and surrounding country better adapted 
           for them than this is; a city perfectly flat, and a surrounding country equally flat, are elements for the use of this machine best calculated to test its merits. Chicago, as is her wont, is not to be beaten even in velocipedes, and comes to the rescue with a machine which differs from any other extant, not only in its general appearance, but in its motive power. This Chicago velocipede has three wheels, two behind and one in front. The hind wheels are considerably the largest, being four feet and two inches in diameter, while the front wheel is only two feet and one-half. The front wheel is for the purpose of guiding the machine, and is connected by a lever with the body, and reaching within convenient distance of the seat, a straddle runs up from the axle of the front or guiding wheel, about a foot from the tire, which surmounted by a lamp. This velocipede is propelled by spring-power, which works as follows: On the axle of the hind wheels is fastened a pinion, which is operated upon by a cog wheel, five times its size in diameter. Fastened to each side of 
           this large cog-wheel is a dog, which works into a ratchet, upon the hub of which ratchet is fastened the center of the springs. The other end of the spring is fastened to a rod of iron, which runs through the body of the velocipede. These springs are made of the very best English spring steel, two inches wide, one-tenth of an inch thick, and nine feet long, and when wound up their power is estimated at over 3,000 pounds each. Immediately outside of the spring, and in the ratchet hub, is fastened one of the treadles. The large cog-wheel and ratchet work loose around the shaft on which they are placed. The treadles are two feet long, and reach from the ratchet shaft to within convenient distance for the foot of a person occupying the seat. On the end of each treadle is a slipper to keep the foot from being shoved forward. By an ingenious contrivance the wheels can be thrown out of gear, so that the velocipede, even under full headway, can be turned around within a space of fourteen feet. The seat has the appearance and general characteristics of a buggy seat, 
           and can carry two persons with ease. It was designed for the use of ladies only, but can be used by anybody. The grand feature of this Chicago velocipede is, that it is worked by spring power, and that the springs can be perpetually wound up by simply using the treadles after ately. It only takes one-fourth the power to wind the springs that the springs exert in unwinding. By pressing upon the treadle with the foot the ratchet is turned, on which is placed the spring, which of course is thereby wound. It differs from the Alton invention in this, that the springs are being continuously wound by the alternate treadles, and this can always be kept in motion; while the Alton invention runs only a mile and then stops to be wound again. This Chicago invention has been tested and all who have seen it are sanguine of its success. The cost of one of these machines will be about $100. Velocipedes are of various kinds. Some have two, and others three, and even four wheels; all have either pedals or rests on which to place the feet, and usually either brakes or levers to 
           regulate the speed.THE TWO-WHEEL VELOCIPEDES. The two wheeled velocipedes, or the bicycles as they are styled, are intended for the male sex only, and are by far the swiftest machines. They are usually of wrought iron, and have pedals or reels attached to the front and large wheel, and the working of these gives a light movement of the feet and the requisite impulse to the vehicle. The saddle is placed upon a bar of iron, suspended four inches above the top of the fore wheel. The hands rest on a handle in front of the machine, which, working on a pivot, serves as a balancing pole, and equilibrium is preserved by exercising a slight twist to this handle. By this means the rider stops the revolving motion of THE THREE-WHEEL VELOCIPEDES. The three-wheel velocipede, or tricycle, is easier to guide and safer to use than the bicycle. Its speed, however, is less rapid; still, it can be made to pass a carriage at full trot. As the fair sex largely patronize the tricycle, the seat is more commodious than that of the bicycle, having sides and backs of wicker, and a horse 
           hair cushion to sit upon. The hind wheels, though large, are light, and revolve with facility. The fore wheel, which is smaller, serves to guide the machine, being acted upon by means of the handle, which causes it instantly to turn in the direction indicated by the rider. The pedals are shaped like slippers, which facilitate the movement of the legs, and at the same time admit of the foot being disengaged instantaneously. The movement required to impel the machine is a perfectly natural one, analogous to that of walking. That is, it requires but the slightest pressure of the foot, and produces no unusual fatigue to the leg. In addition to these advantages, the largest three-wheeled velocipedes have carriers attached to the pedals and fit on the axles. By this means the speed of the vehicle is considerably increased, and the pressure of the foot is relieved by transmitting the motion to the driving apparatus of the machine by means of impulse and a brake.
           </text> 
       </result>
       <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015104/1895-11-16/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>Mid 1890s: Races and endurance tests of vehicles called “motorcycles” begin to take place.</time>
            <text>
            ROGER MOTORCYCLE. It Left New York Yesterday on Its Journey to Chicago. NEW YORK, Nov. 15.—At 12:15 o’clock today the new Roger motorcycle left on its 900-mile journey to Chicago. The motorcycle is the same as the horseless carriage, which has caused so much interest all over the country. This is the longest trip that has ever been attempted by a motorcycle in this country. The carriage in which the trip is being made is patterned after the phaeton and is run by the Benz naphtha motor. The carriage has no baggage other than the two men who are attending to it and forty gallons of naphtha. The carriage will run during the daylight hours, and at night the travelers will rest wherever darkness overtakes them. It is expected that the carriage will reach Chicago next Saturday evening.
            </text>
       </result>
       <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-11-02/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=0.29,0.215,0.767,0.4,0
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            SPORTS AND RECREATION THE WORLD OF SPORTS. POLO—CHESS—ATHLETICS. R. G. Betts’s Services to Motorcycling—The Kennel Show. One of the most active workers among motorcyclists is R. G. Betts, the president of the Federation of American Motorcyclists. Mr. Betts was recently elected to this office. The purpose of the organization is to "encourage the use of motorcycles and to promote the general interests of motorcycling; to ascertain, defend, and protect the rights of motorcyclists; to facilitate touring; to assist in the good roads movement and to advise and assist in the regulation of motorcycle racing and other competitions in which motorcycles engage." He became interested in motorcycles while living in Boston in 1900, his first experience gained on a rented tricycle. In August of that
            year he sought to organize the first motorcycle club, and issued a call to bring together some fourteen interested men. The group, away from its stated purpose, and, against Mr. Betts’s protest, resolved itself into a national organization styled the Associated Motorcyclists. Mr. Betts is a native of New York and has been connected with bicycle journals for many years. He is now the editor of the motor and motorcycle publications published by the Goodwin Company. He is a member of the New York Motorcycle Club and the Alpha Motorcycle Club and was one of the founders of the Metropolitan Cycling Club. He is also a delegate of the Associated Cycling Clubs. There is much interest in the Election Day races to be held at the Meadow Brook Club, on the Hempstead Plains. There will be five races,
            gentlemen riders competing. Some of the best steeplechase horses owned at the Meadow Brook and Rockaway hunts, the Great Neck Club, the Genesee Hunt and the Country Club of Westchester will enter. “Larry” Waterbury, the poloist, will ride some of the Gould entries, and Rene La Montagne are expected to carry the colors of Harry Payne Whitney. A steeplechase entry of August Belmont’s son, August Belmont, Jr., will have the pick of the horses.
            </text>
       </result>
       <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1904-07-20/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=-0.006,1.045,0.363,0.189,0
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>1904-1905:	Police departments begin to organize motorcycle units.</time>
            <text>
            MOTORCYCLES FOR POLICE. Machines Now Being "Tried Out" for Selection for a Squad. Through certain motorcycle riders and dealers it is reported that New York, or at least Manhattan borough, is to have a motorcycle police squad. Inspector Smith, it is said, has become a convert to the idea ever since the general adoption, about a year ago, of the "grip control," which enables a rider to start and stop and regulate his speed on one of the power cycles with one hand and without removing it from the steering bar. A number of members of the New York Motorcycle Club and several dealers have been interviewed by the inspector, with a view to selecting the best make of machine, and several varieties have been tried out on the road by officers. Two patrolmen are now covering posts on motorcycles, 
            Patrolman Ennis, on Riverside Drive, being one of them. According to Inspector Smith the only thing that stands in the way of an immediate formation of a motorcycle squad is lack of funds. He considers the machines necessary for chasing automobiles and runaways, and he hopes to be able to get the money for them before long.
            </text>
       </result>
       <result>
        <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1908-09-09/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=-0.091,0.644,0.837,0.436,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <time>No timeline found</time>
        <text>
        MOTORCYCLISTS AFTER RECORDS. FAST MACHINES IN RACES AT AGRICULTURAL PARK. DE ROSIER, THE INDIAN RIDER, NOT ENTERED TODAY. Derkum on Thor Reeled Off Miles Close to 56 Seconds Yesterday, in Tryouts—Breeze Goes in 58 on Indian. BY FREDERIC PABST World's records will be shattered at Agricultural Park this afternoon when the crack motorcyclists of the west meet in fourteen different events. The speedy little two-wheelers have been tuned up to the second and will be out today to cut down existing records, and judging from the time made yesterday the fastest miles ever seen on a local track will result. All of the events are well filled and much interest is being shown in the races. The following is the program of events: Race No. 1—Five miles, fully equipped stock machines, single cylinder, 
        under 50 cu. in. Prize, $30, $15, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 2—Five miles, fully equipped stock machines, twin cylinder, under 60 cu. in. Prize, $30, $15, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 3—Five miles, Club challenge cup for single cylinders, for club members only owning machines 15 days old. Race No. 4—Five miles, Club challenge cup for multiple cylinders, for club members only owning machines 15 days old. Race No. 5—Man against motorcycle, 100 yards. Prize, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 6—Five miles, free for all, single cylinder machines. Prize, $20, $10, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 7—Five miles, free for all, multiple cylinder machines. Prize, $20, $10, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 8—Fifteen mile limit, Australian pursuit race, free for all, single cylinder machines. Prize, $25, $15, $5 in merchandise.
        Race No. 9—Fifteen mile limit, Australian pursuit race, free for all, multiple cylinder machines. Prize, $25, $15, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 10—Ten mile professional, open. Prize, $25, $15, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 11—Ten miles, open, stripped stock machines, single cylinder, under 50 cu. in., for private owners not connected with the trade. Prize, $25, $15, $5 in merchandise. Race No. 12—Trials for world’s record, both professional and amateur. Race No. 13—Five miles, Riders challenge cup, for multiple cylinder machines under 60 cu. in. Race No. 14—One hour race, free for all. Prize, beautiful cup. The track was alive with speeding machines yesterday and the trials went off without an accident of any kind. A force of police kept the people off the course to prevent a repetition of the unfortunate 
        occurrence of the day previous. The fastest work yesterday was done by Paul Derkum on a “Thor.” He went close to 56 seconds for the mile, and says he will reach that mark in the contest today. Ben Brees did some fast riding on an Indian. He went around the circle in 58 seconds. Others who went close to the minute mark were John Derkum, W. Hose and G. Blaylock, these latter on single cylinder machines. The track is in the best of shape and there is every reason to expect the fastest time. Jake De Rosier, the well-known Indian rider, will not appear. He was talked of on all sides as Derkum’s one opponent to be feared, but he has not been entered, and C.W. Risden, the local Indian agent, says he never expected him to be here for the contests. The statement that De Rosier would race here was unauthorized, according to Risden.
        Risden said last night that his fastest Indian machine was put out of commission in the tryouts Monday. Brees had gone to the track without sufficient oil, and a piston stuck, putting the car out of the running. There are fifteen entries in the five-mile free-for-all for one-cylinder machines. Four Thors, a Merkel, three Indians, two Reading Standards, two Ives, and H-D's, a Harley Davidson and Peugeot will do battle. All the crack riders are entered to ride, including Derkum, Wilson, Hoag, Knapp, Richardson and Seymour. The one-hour race will be a hummer. Twenty-one are named to go, and the skill of the riders and the stamina of the machines will be thoroughly tested.
        </text>
       </result>
       <result>
       <id>
       https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn98047754/1911-09-01/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=-0.158,0.047,1.385,0.721,0
       </id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <time>1910-1915: Motorcycles are gaining acceptance as an economical means to accomplish many tasks.</time>
       <text>
       The Motorcycle on the Farm. If one is to believe the statements of the leading motorcycle manufacturers of the day and their statements seem logical, it is cheaper to make a trip to town on a motorcycle than to drive or walk. A manufacturer of one of these motorcycles (his particular make holds the world's record for economy) states that while the machine that made the world's record traveling fifty miles at a cost of less than one-tenth cent per mile over country roads was operated by an expert, it is nothing unusual for this particular make of motorcycle in the hands of an amateur to travel from six to eight miles on one cent's worth of gasoline. In comparison with the private riding horse the expense per mile is naturally much less and if one figures that while the driving horse must be fed daily, the motorcycle only 
       consumes while in use, the difference is still greater. The limit of a horse for continuous daily driving is probably thirty miles, while that of a motorcycle is over two hundred. Good traveling for a horse means four miles an hour; good traveling for a motorcycle, twenty miles a motorcycle from thirty to fifty miles per hour. In this age of scarce hired help, time, at some season is extremely valuable to the farmer. His ability to cover the distance to town and back with a motorcycle in one fifth of the road driving horse time and with no time wasted harnessing and unharnessing, is a factor to be considered. Most all the good motorcycles are now equipped with tandem attachments and luggage carriers, if desired. By means of this tandem attachment two can ride as well as one. The luggage carrier permits the carrying of 
       small freight, not exceeding 200 pounds. Many a farmer, as well as his children, have rebelled at their inability to go to town, to the swimming hole or the fishing grounds in the late summer evening, for a horse cannot be worked all day and be driven on the road at night. To these the motorcycle fills a long felt want. It is ever ready, costs nothing when idle and will last for years. It is really more expensive to be without a motorcycle than to own one, just as it is more expensive to plow with a hand plow, cradle the grain and use the flail instead of the modern appliances. The best makes of motorcycle today can be had for from $225 up. A motorcycle like many other pieces of machinery, can be built too cheaply to be good. There are, however, several well-established makes, which have years of successful manufacture
       behind them and one will not go amiss in choosing any of these. The motorcycle of today has come to stay. Already in the cities it is being adopted extensively by business firms because of the great time-saving its use assures. Repair men, inspection men, etc., can accomplish triple the work possible with their former horse and carriage. The saving of time as well as the great pleasure to be derived from its use has given the motorcycle a lasting place in the home of the American farmer.
       </text>
       </result>
       <result>
       <id>
       https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1915-02-07/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=motorcycle+motorcycles+vehicle+street+race&amp;r=0.054,-0.036,0.686,0.357,0
       </id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <time>1910-1915: Motorcycles are gaining acceptance as an economical means to accomplish many tasks.</time>
       <text>
       MOTOR CYCLES INVADE ALL FIELDS OF ACTIVITY. Preacher, Doctor, Policeman and Soldier Now Use Two-Wheeled Vehicles. Hundreds of daily demonstrations are proof of the utility, speed, and economy of the modern motor cycle. There is scarcely a field of activity that the two-wheeler has not entered and proved its value. The motor cycle carries the minister to reach his patient in less time than ever before, making it possible to eliminate many hours of human suffering. The motor cycle carried the minister of the gospel on his missions of mercy. The motor cycle is a part of every progressive police department, carrying mounted officers to the scene of crime or accident, and enabling them to run down violators of the law. The motor cycle aids the forest ranger in protecting our great timber lands from fire. The motor cycle 
       carries mail and delivers telegrams. The motor cycle rushes the important prescription to the bedside of the suffering. The motor cycle hurries the pulmotor to the beach, where every second counts, in the effort to restore life. A motor cycle mounted guard accompanies the President of the United States in his trips about the capital. Motor Cycle in War. Uses of the motor cycle in the army are almost unlimited. Motor cycle dispatch riders and scouts have won great fame for themselves in the present European struggle. Machine guns mounted on motor cycles are carried to their positions on the battlefield; motor cycles with side-cars hurry supplies to the Red Cross workers who are seeking to relieve the injured soldiers to the hospitals. "The motor cycle has revolutionized signaling on the battlefield," says Henry Beach 
       Needham, a war correspondent. It has practically done away with wig-wagging on the field. It is economical, efficient, and speedy; it is everywhere and nowhere as much as the front. For pleasure too, the motor cycle has made a definite place for itself. The ease with which the two-wheeler is operated, its reliability, and comfort make it an ideal vehicle for touring. Club sociability and endurance runs are enjoyed by thousands of riders all over the country every year. And more and more we hear of the long-distance tourist, riding from ocean to ocean, from gulf to lake, around the United States or circling the globe—for pleasure. Many of these long-distance tourists are women, who find as much pleasure in the sport as do the men. King "Eight" Car Arrives. The new 1915 eight-cylinder King touring car arrived last night, 
       and will be placed on exhibition at the local salesroom of William P. Barnhart &amp; Co., 1712 14th street northwest. The car has been on display at the national automobile show, and is making its debut in the National Capital. Awarded First Honors. William P. Barnhart, local distributor for the King in this section, has been awarded first prize in the contest for November and December on the sale of King motor cars. Mr. Barnhart is in receipt of a check for $350 and a gold Swiss watch as the result of the contest. He competed against the branch houses in Chicago, New York, Philadelphia, and Boston. Argo Roadster Purchasers. Purchasers of Argo roadsters during the past week included H. K. Morgan, W. Rukites, H. E. Burwell, W. E. Rouse, and G. E. Gallion. Pullman Touring Car Sales. During the past week 1915 Pullman Junior 
       touring cars were purchased by Charles E. Shank, Z. V. Dark, F. N. Hampstead, William D. Randall, Jr., W. Baker, and D. B. Cannon. Purchase King "Four" Cars. Purchasers of 1915 King "Four" tour cars delivered during the past week were Dr. Claude E. Cooksey, E. E. Jones, and R. P. Morris. MOTOR CYCLE NOTES. The Capital City Motor Cycle Club of Sacramento, Cal., is making an effort to secure the 100-mile championship for its annual meet. It has been decided that the national motor cycle, bicycle, and accessories show will be held in the museum in Chicago, September 20-25. Sanction has just been issued by the Federation of American Motorcyclists for a 100-mile motor cycle meet to be held at Galesburg, Ill., July 5. The Wheeling (W. Va.) Motor Club is planning to have a big reunion of motorcyclists during the coming summer.
       In planning for the coming season’s events, the Worcester (Mass.) Cycle Club has set Patriots’ Day, April 19, for the opening run, which will go to Concord, Lexington, and return. Though less than two months old, the motor cycle club of St. Paul has reached a membership mark of 150. It is the purpose of the club to raise this to 250 by next fall. A new motor cycle club has been formed in Cincinnati, Ohio, known as the Queen City M. C. It has 12 charter members. The officers are yet to be elected. Order Eight-Cylinder Kings. Orders have been placed with the local representative for King “Eight” touring cars as follows: H. S. Thompson, D. Scott Thompson, and D. M. Gamble. Purchasers of Cadillacs. During the past week seven-passenger 1915 Cadillac touring cars were delivered to W. E. Montgomery, Mrs. V. F. Isenberg, and Col. A. Whedon, U. S. A.
       Mexican Embassy Buys Hudson. Mexican embassy has purchased a 1915 6-40 Hudson touring car, fully equipped. Delivery was made a few days ago. On Territory Trip. Walter L. Smith, local representative for the Argo and Detroit car lines, is spending several days in Virginia in the interest of these cars. He left Thursday night and is expected to return Tuesday night of this week. A New Franklin Owner. The latest purchaser of a 1915 Franklin 6-30, five-passenger touring car is Charles D. Sager, delivery being made during the past week. To Represent Acme Tire. The Pollock Car Corporation has closed a contract to represent the Acme red letter tire in the National Capital.
       </text>
       </result>
       <result>
       <id>
       https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053043/1940-06-21/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=motorcycle&amp;r=-0.006,0.847,1.126,0.587,0
       </id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <time>No timeline found</time>
       <text>
       Billings Motorcycle Club Has Thrived Since 1913. Throughout most of the years since 1913 Billings has had an active motorcycle club. In those 27 years the city has watched [motorcycling] grow from a fad in which few cared to risk their necks, to the modern streamlined sport it is today, with scores of enthusiasts. Motorcycling has always had its thrills but the modern, high-powered machine goes further and combines all the speedy action of aquaplaning and flying, yet offers the pleasures and comforts of motoring. The city’s first motorcycle club in 1913 was a novel and, if it may be said, a noble experiment. It worked, and about a score of dashing young daredevils went in for motorbiking. Officers of that early club were George Bott, president; August Trutnau, vice president; Clarence H. Lauson, road lieutenant; E. J. Robb, activities chairman; 
       and Martin Curtis, racing chairman. With the horse and buggy era on the wane, young road demons, astraddle explosive two-wheeled gas burners, awed the town with feats of speed and daring. Motorcycling came into its own as one of the most popular sports of the day.Motorcycle racers thrilled thousands at the Midland Empire fair during the years from 1915 to 1920. In 1915 and 1916 races also were staged on a track at Joliet and hundreds of Billings fans traveled there regularly to watch those thrilling contests in which the more daring riders would sometimes hit a breakneck pace of “60 miles per hour.” State Racing Circuit In addition, there was a state motor-cycle racing circuit to coincide with fairs at Bozeman, Great Falls, Helena, Miles City, and Roundup. Several Billings riders competed in these early meets. They included Pat Curtis, Martin Curtis, 
       Bob Robb, George Tur-ner, Frank Boyd, Don Rieger, Fen Garvin, Johnny Thomas, Clar-ence Lauzon, Buck Engelhardt, Grant Lam-port and Fred Olsen. Favorite per-formers on the old Joliet racetrack were the Curtises, Turner, Robb, Nelson Wells and Frank Boyd. "Those were the good old days," it was the motorcyclists who braved the stretches of open road on which no operator of a horseless carriage would dare to tread. They tackled bridges across streams, stretches of deep sand, oozy gumbo and miles of mud to go on where some of the difficulties surrounding even these early circuits sub-dued the timid. The city's first motorcycle club maintained active membership until 1917, when several of its members entered service for the World War. Between 1918 and 1921 there was a lull in activities. The Billings club was reorganized in 1921 and has been a functioning organization since. 
       In the years 1914 to 1917 Ira S. Dille, Harry Williams, Frank Boyd, E. J. Robb, Alec McLeod served as club presi-dents and Robert E. "Bob" Cooke was secretary-treasurer. When reorganized in 1921 C. M. Lauzon was elected presi-dent, A. Nicolas, vice president, and Frank Polesek, secretary-treasurer. New Popularity Peak Motorcycling today has hit a new peak in popularity and the Billings club has a large active membership. There are approximately 100 of the two-wheeled machines registered in Yellowstone County. The Billings Motorcycle Club promotes a full active program each summer, highlighted by such events as gypsy tours, reliability runs, and hill climbs. The club has been affiliated with the American Motorcycle Association since 1929. Endurance or reliability runs of the Billings club date back to 1916, when a 126-mile trip was made to Miles City and return. Dirt 
       roads, turned to mud by heavy rains, tortuous hills, and ruts made this endurance test live long in the memories of the riders who participated, including R. E. Cooke, Clarence Lauzon, Pat Curtis, Martin Curtis, E. J. Robb, Johnny Thomas, Frank Hayes, Carl Aurich, Don Rieger, and Fred Olsen. Other riders who took part in events of the early motorcycle club and who still reside in Billings were Dr. C. H. Nelson, C. G. Gans, Jimmie Noyes, Horace Noyes, Bob Freeman, Glenn Farrell, Gus Wanderling, Eddie Eichenhard, Dan Davies, Walter Fultz, Bob Mitchell, and Peter Yeegen Jr. The club today is headed by Charles Lasher, president; Herman Judd, vice president; Andrew Dukes, treasurer; and Fred Olsen, secretary.
       </text>
       </result>
       <result>
       <id>
       https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024808/1919-04-26/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=motorcycle&amp;r=0.164,-0.028,1.025,0.534,0
       </id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <time>No timeline found</time>
       <text>
       HARNESS RACING FOR MIDLAND FAIR Association Puts Out a Card of Events Which Reads Like Old Times Special to The Daily Tribune. Billings, April 25.—Through the organization of a harness racing association in Montana, the Midland Empire fair association of this city has been able to secure an attractive racing card for the local fair next September. The program for the four-day meet has been arranged by Secretary Lawrence and the purses decided upon. The circuit includes Bozeman, Forsyth, Billings, and Miles City. The card for the fair here is as follows: Tuesday, Sept. 16: 2:30 trot, 3 in 5, $250. Running race, $200; running race, relay race, men’s professional, $1,000. Relay race, cowboys, local, $500. Motorcycle race, $75; motorcycle race, $50. Wednesday, Sept. 17: Running race, $200; running race, $150. Relay race, cowboys, second day. Relay race, professional, second day.
       Motorcycle race, $75; motorcycle race, $50. Thursday, Sept. 18: Running race, $200; running race, $150. Relay race, professional, third day. Relay race, cowboys, third day. Motorcycle race, $75; motorcycle race, $50. Friday, Sept. 19: Free-for-all pace, 3 in 5, $400. Running race, $200; running race, $150. Relay race, professional, finals. Relay race, cowboys. Motorcycle race, $75; motorcycle race, $50. Harness race entries close Aug. 15. American Trotting Association rules; five per cent to enter; entrance fee refunded to all horses starting and not distanced. No deductions from money winners.
       </text>
       </result>
    </results>
</topic>
</topics>