<topic>
<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ouija-board</id>
<results>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028296/1886-04-29/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch+Talking</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        THE NEW TALKING BOARD.
        Tfce
        MjitarlMS AaBaaeaaeat Which la
        raeelaattBt; Okls reettltk
        Many of our readers will still remember
        planchette, the strange little heart-shaped
        board with a pencil at its point which used
        to walk over yards of paper and write no and
        of tenie and nonsense if the finger tips of two
        persons touched the upper surface of the
        board.
        Planchetts had Ka day, and mostl died
        out But the same mysterious force which
        used to impel it it moving now another kind
        of little board, and setting whole eommuni
        Uet of eminently sober and respectable Ohio
        people on their heads.
        You see how it it made. A bit of board,
        say 18x30 inches, is lettered, rather large,
        with the alphabet, A, B, C, D, etc The
        letters are put a small distance apart At
        the upper corners of the board are written
        the words "yes" and "no," the "yes" on tha
        left, the "no" oa the right On tha left and
        right hand lower corners respectively are
        written "good evening and "good night
        Underneath tha letters of the alphabet are
        the figures in a row, the whole arranged like
        thit:
        t'esV no.
        j ABC OS VGH I JKL MIf
        ibPQBSTUVrVXVK.,
        1334T8V0 i
        Good-eve.
        Good-night
        Hen a tiny table it made with four legs.
        It is three or four inches high and very thin
        and light Two persons tit opposite each
        other and take the board upon their knees at
        in the picture. The little four-legged table ia
        placed upon the board. The two persons
        grasp tightly with the thumb and forefinger
        the comers of the table that are next to them.
        TBS TAXKXJfQ fJOABDb
        The two sit down and become quiet, asking
        rtioml" After a few minutes the little table
        begins to move over the board, It is an In
        tel lig nt, or at least, a semi-intelligent force
        that guides the table, for it answers
        questions. Bomettmes It talks utter nonsense
        and again it will write real information.
        The table spells out sentences in this way.
        When a question is asked, the table moves
        towards the tetters, and the foot stops upon
        the first one of the sentence to be written out
        Then it passes to the next one and the next
        and so on, with more or less rapidity, a
        gentleman, who hat experimented with the
        thing, says: "Sometime the table will cover
        two letters with Its feet and then yon hang
        on and ask that the foot be moved from the
        wrong letter, which will be done,"
        One man who tnougnt nit lamiiy was
        spending too much time over the talking ma
        chine burned it up. Then he left noma on a
        Journey. When the talking board could not
        be found some one made anotner, ana tne
        amusement went on. as before. To tho qu
        tion what had become of the other board the
        answer was given, "Jack burned It up,
        which somewhat astonished Jack on his re
        turn.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016373/1890-12-21/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Mysterious+Talking+Wonder+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        "HE
        Nineteenth Century
        This most interesting and
        mysterious talking board has
        awakened great curiosity wher
        ever shown.
        It surpasses in its results
        second sight, mind reading, or
        clairvoyance.
        It consists of a small table
        placed upon a large board con
        taining the alphabet and nume
        rals. By simply resting the
        fingers of two persons upon
        the small table it moves, and
        to all intents and purposes be
        comes a living, sensible thing,
        giving intelligent answer to
        any questions that can be pro
        pounded. Wonderful as this may seem
        the "OUIJA" was thoroughly
        tested at the United States
        Patent Office before the patent
        was allowed.
        For sale by all first-class toy
        dealers and stationers.
        MANUFACTURED BY
        THE KEMARD NOVELTY m,
        220 SOUTH CHARLES ST.,
        BALTIMORE, MD.
        de21-lt,'i
        THE WASHINGTON
        Loan and Trust Co.
        Temporary Oillccs: Cor. 10th and
        F Streets N. W.
        Under Act of Coiiki-cbh Approved October
        1, 1890.
        Subject to supervision of tho Supremo Court of
        the District of Columbia and tho Comp
        troller of tho Currency.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1893-11-14/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Weird+Writings+Craze+Unseen+Forces+Talking+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        THE MORNING CALL, SAN FRANCISCO, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 14, 18*3;'
        WEIRD WRITINGS.
        The Planchette Craze Has
        Broken Out Again.
        UNSEEN FORCES AT WORK.
        Some Uncanny Pranks of a Little
        Instrument That Once Held the
        Attention of the World.
        There Is a planchette fever in San Fran
        cisco.
        Clubs of patient sitters, anxious to hold
        communion with the dead and distant liv
        ing, have been formed here and in Oak
        land. Daily and nightly seances are being
        held.
        Plancbette is old, so old that it is almost
        new again. Early in the fifties the weird
        little contrivance was invented and ten
        years later nearly the whole civilized world
        was teaming with a recital of its wonders.
        The most uncanny tales were related of
        the marvelous doings of the instrument,
        and for a time the greatest scientific minds
        of the world were interested iv its queer
        pranks. Such men as Tyndall and Faraday
        were drawn Into controversies pro and con
        over the merits of this occult agency.
        Exhaustive essays were written and
        learned lectures delivered to prove that
        planchette was a fraud and to prove that
        planchette's powers were supernatural.
        But it all ended where it began. The
        deepest study and the most careful analy
        sis of the wiles and ways of planchette
        developed nothing of scientific value either
        to the student of the occult or the natural
        forces.
        And so the planchette fever died as
        quickly as it had grown. Men and women
        went back to their workaday world or con
        tinued their occult studies unuer different
        auspices. Planchette had it« little day nnd
        then died a natural death. Or, if it did not
        i die entirely, it lapsed into a slate of coma
        j from whicn it is only now being resur-
        I rected. To-day, in San Fraucisco aud in
        j Oakland, and perhaps In other parts of
        ihe world, great numbers of men and
        women are bent on solving the mysteries
        i that still cling to this little contrivance.
        And it is all because of that irrepressible
        j desire of man to penetrate the mysteries
        j of the future. f ,v
        What does to-morrow hold for me.
        That is the question nearest the heart of
        most men to-day. lt is a very part of the
        commercial spirit of the age. And as yet
        science has made no advances toward
        placing the means within reach of answer
        ing it. So planchette comes again to fill
        the gap between the known and the un
        known.
        What started the fever no one seems to
        i know. 'Hint it has been started and has
        already interested hundreds of intelligent
        men and women no one doubts, for the evi
        dence is clear.
        You know what planchette is, do you
        j not, and how it operates? Some have
        thought there was a hidden secret in its
        I construction, but this is wrong. Never
        was a wonderful device more simply con
        trived; There is first a heart-shaped cedar
        board. Pendant from the points of the
        angle are little legs with metal or wooden
        castors. At the end of the board is an
        aperture for the insertion of a lead pencil.
        Those who fit to planchette for communi
        cations from this world or the next place
        a baud each on the surface of the board,
        then wait till the "spirit moves." And
        the spirit has been moving pretty rapidly
        in these parts of the world for the last
        few nights. Dire things have been fore
        told and timely warnings given.
        Ordinarily planchette will write out
        what it has to say if time be given i\ but
        the quicker way is to write the alphabet
        and the simple negative and affirmative on
        a large sheet of white paper and let plan
        chette spell out its messages by pointing to
        tbe letters.
        It was this method pursued py a party
        of well-known clubmen who began as
        i skeptics Friday evening and went home at
        I daybreak firmly convinced that there were
        i at least many things that they had little
        j dreamed of In their phiiosophy. Only two
        members of the party placed tbeir hands
        on the instrument at one time. The others
        j looked on and scoffed.
        "We were all unbelievers when we sat
        down to that table," said the member of
        the party who told the story to a Call
        man yesterday. "For a while planchetie
        refused to move and we were almost on
        the point of giving it up for the night,
        when, without un Instant warning, the in
        strument gave a sudden jerk and almost
        flew from uuder the fingers of Jones and
        Smith.
        "Roth the men turned pale at this and
        in order to rally themselves they accused
        each other of having moved the planchette.
        On their honor both men denied this, but
        since neither had believed his own accusa
        tion the denials were useless.
        "I think it was a wife or a sister of
        Jones that came first. I bave forgotten
        the name of the spirit or influence, or
        whatever it was, that purported to move
        the instrument, but the information it im
        parted can be easily verified or disproved
        when the next news from Samoa arrives.
        "It spelled out 'Apia' first, very clearly
        and unhesitatingly. Then it went on to
        say that a terrible hurricane would sweep
        over the Samoan Islands on the 10th of
        November and that two vessels would be
        lost In the storm. And touching this
        event it would say no more, though we
        plied it with queries for a long time.
        "Another influence came. I remember
        tbe name, but shall not give it.
        'Dead or living?' asked Smith.
        'Living,' came the answer, but Smith
        knew this already, for the name it gave
        was the name of his sweetheart.
        'What have you to tell me?' queried
        Smith, and then he wished he had not,
        for the answer that came distressed bim
        sorely.
        "Twill not marry you,' it spelled out
        with painful accuracy.
        'Why not?', was the natural question
        that followed when Smith had recovered
        his presence of mind and bad determined
        to face it out.
        'Because I like D— letter,' came the
        answer.
        "Then two men glared at each other for
        a moment, for D— sat at the opposite end
        of the table waiting bis turn to try plan
        chette.^^StHß^^B^o96iQH''SK^
        "Now, if It were not already notorious
        that D— hail been a little soft on Smith's
        sweetheart of late we would have passed
        over this little incident as one of the
        vagaries of plancbette. But Smith couldn't
        take it in this light. He was crushed, and
        Invited D— to take his place. 1 needn't
        tell you that D— declined the invitation,
        but I would stake a small sum that" D—
        has his bands on a plancbette this moment.
        a,\*'l look Smith's place at the planchette
        and presently the' thing began ;to move
        again. This time it discarded the use of
        the alphabet and gave its message in writ
        ing.
        "Now, I am not going to place any reli
        ance on this thing till I see how it turns
        out, but the message that came to me is
        Important if it is true.
        '"I am an enemy,' it wrote.
        '"Are you going to thrash him?' asked
        Jone?, who likes to be facetious when
        there is the least call for it.
        ."'No!' said planchette. Then after a
        pause it carefully wrote out, '1 am going
        to harm him. He is my enemy and I will
        be revenged.'
        "Well, all this meant nothing without a
        name, and no name had been given yet.
        Again I asked for the name and ■it not
        only wrote oat the name of tbe man who
        happens to be smarting under a very just
        punishment that i Inflicted upon, him, but
        wrote it in bis own handwriting. a
        ''You should have seen some of the faces
        of the men who sal about that table when
        they recognized the handwriting. One of
        the men who bad laughed loudest and
        scoffed the most when we first sat down
        found it necessary to go outside for fresh
        air." There was no more laughter tbat
        evening. i
        "Then it came into my bead to ask plan
        chette something about itself, but before
        we put the questions both Jones and my
        self were blindfolded. This precaution is
        unnecessary, for it is simply impossible to
        move planchette as it does move without
        exerting a physical force that would be
        readily detected. However, we did this
        more to convince ourselves than others.
        ".'Are you inspired?' asked.
        "'Yes,' came the answer.
        'By a good power?'
        "The instrument fairly flew to the word
        'no.'
        'By the devil said Jones.
        'The devil,' it spelled out without the
        least hesitation. s:
        'Who are you?' I inquired.
        'An agent of the devil,' replied plan
        chetie, and this time in writing.
        "And after that there was not a man in
        the room brave enough to put bis hand on
        that instrument."
        The above questions and answers can
        be vouched for by -more than one man
        whose word in the commercial world is as
        good as his bond, and many similar dia
        logues might be cited to prove— prove
        well, to prove that plancbette has a strong
        hold on the people of this city once more.
        Whether the craze will die out before it
        reaches any great proportions again re
        mains to be seen.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1915-12-11/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=Marvelous+Mysterious+Messages+Talking+Patience+Worth+Curran+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>1915:	Pearl Curran claims to have made contact with a 17th century author whom she names Patience Worth; she begins publishing written work.</time>
    <text>
        Tho oulja board Is coming back
        tnto favor and has been taken up
        I quit extensively by society women
        v In New York, Boston, Chicago, St.
        Louis and various parts of the coun
        try. Perhaps tho most remarkable le-
        Iccnt experiences with it arc those of
        Mrs, John Curran of St, Louis. Sho
        has been in communication, she says,
        with the spirit of Patience Worth, a
        woman beliovcd to have existed in
        lhe Colonial days and who not only
        has sent philosophical axioms that
        are characteristic of tho Puritans
        but even has gone to tho extent of
        sending outlines of plays and es
        says and has gone extensively Into
        the dictation of poetry. More than
        300,000 words havo been received
        from this supposed spirit in ihieo
        years.
        Patience Worth talks In a strange
        t English that is archaic and not
        J 1 found in the best authors and yet
        j may have at one time been the
        tongue of Inhabitants of this coun
        try. Long condemned by religious as
        the direct agency of satan and by
        i skeptics as the toy of the supcrsti-
        tlous, the ouija board is being ro
        f stored to its own former popularity
        I through the curiosity of society wo
        men. In many parts of the country oo
        clety women are devoting their timo
        to "communicating" with spirits in
        tho other world.
        Many sti'ango results of such com
        munications are reported and a ao
        t clety woman is unhappy indeed if
        she hasn't at least one good spirit
        i in tho world of mystery who is al
        B ways ready to send a message at her
        m, control's pleasure.
        Ill Even in staid St. Louis where so-
        lit! cIety women arc supposed to bo
        1$ very conservative, tho ouija board
        il has been, restored to favor whilo
        HA
        in New York and In various
        cities of the east it is quite the
        "rage."
        In St Louis Mrs. John H. Curran
        has gotten into touch with one Pa
        tience Worth of Spiritland and has
        transcribed more than 300,000 words
        thiough the ouija board, all of which
        will be published at some future
        date.
        Patience Worth is believed from
        her peculiar choice of words and
        phraseology to be a Colonial dame,
        who has been wandering about In
        space for a long time, burning to
        send her messages back to the mun
        dane sphere yet finding no source of
        communication until Mrs. Curran
        bought a ouija board and com
        menced taking messages.
        THROUGH
        CURIOSITY.
        The board Avas purchased through
        curiosity. There is something fas
        cinating about the tales told of tho
        little board, whether they be- true
        or false. It is known that a num
        ber of people have asked the board
        to tell them in what land their dead
        iclativcs liugercd and were shocked
        considerable- when the naughty Utile
        hoard spelled out a word starling
        A ith an H and ending with an L.
        Many have thought that the words
        written bv the board were the result
        of the mental influences oC the per
        son opeiating it. while others have
        credited it with supernatural pow
        ers. In tho use of tho board at the Cur
        ran home, Mrs. Curran always is one
        of two whose "hands are on the
        board. The latter is arranged on
        two wheels and has a pencil at the
        end. As the vibration of the fingers
        of tho holders develops the pencil
        moves over a sheet of paper and
        prints numerals o'r letters of the al
        phabet, While Mrs. Curran operates tho
        board her husband transcribes tho
        message as sho reads it to him.
        The "Patience Worth" matter be
        gan to be transcribed in June, 1913.
        Since that time Mrs. Curran has
        made public as the products of Pa
        tience Worth a six-act play entitled
        "Red Wing." a novel called "Tclka"
        and numerous verses, essays and
        bits of philosiphy.
        The quaint language of these writ
        ings has probably attracted more at
        tention than their literary merit, tho
        latter being a matter of some dis
        cussion. They are in an antique
        language, not the English of Chau
        cer, Spenser or any other well-
        known classic English writer, but
        possibly more like the common
        speech of the English people of an
        early day.
        It is known to travelers that an
        antique, almost archaic, form of
        English still Is spoken in remote
        communities of England. Theie are
        districts of England whose inhabi
        tants have great difficulty in under
        standing or in making themselves
        understood by the coster-cockney
        class.
        Mrs. Curran, however, says sho
        has no personal acquaintance with
        such speech and that she has not
        gone farther in her study of classic
        English than other well read per
        sons. The language used' by Patience
        Worth, she explains, is as strange
        to her as It is to others.
        Mrs. Curran recently gave to the
        Fapyrus Club of St. Louis some of
        her messages from Patience Worth,
        one of them being a special messago
        that Patience had sent the club. It
        read:
        PATIENCE WORTH'S
        MESSAGE.
        Good Dames and SIrrahs At the
        board thou hast sat and cat of
        earth's grow. Aye, and now do ye
        cat o' the grow thou knowest not the
        looting place of. Yea, thou shalt
        hark unto the woid o' MEN, and jet
        they do to prate o' DAME. Ayca,
        and methlnks 'tis a word aspoke'
        amany, that be not the word that
        hid 'pon the lung, lest the Dame be
        offended I
        Aye, then come thou and ait 'bout
        the board, and thine cars shall hark
        tmto the words o' me, and thou shalt
        sec the cloth o' me the hands o' the
        loves o' mc did to fashion out for
        me. Ayea, I then shall sit me meek,
        and thread mc up a bobbins full for
        the next o' put.
        Ayca, and 'tis frocked that I shall
        to be, and nay dame shall see!
        Awoe! Nay, this be a piddlc-put-tlng,
        good folk!
        Athin (within) thy heart shall set
        the me o' me at thy go ahence. And
        'tis nhope I be 'tis a loving wampth
        'twill find. And so dost thou to
        smile, 'tis Bweets and love 1 cast
        thee. And doth thy heart to shut it
        up, lo, then shall I to knock till thou
        dost leave me in.
        A night o' cheer. A heart o' love!
        A God's wish o' loving 'pon thy day.
        Anight! Anight!
        HOW IT
        BEGAN.
        Mrs. Curran told her audience of
        her first experiences with tho ouija
        WW
        w
        board and of the puzzling messages
        received. Later sho used the'board
        together with Mrs Emily Grant
        Hutchings and began to receive
        sentences which foimcd maxims and
        philosophical paragrapbs. Then
        came the announcement:
        "Many moons ago I lived. Patience
        Worth, my namo. If thou shalt live
        then so shall I. I make my bread by
        thy hearth"
        The word "bread." Mrs. Currau
        later learned, lefeired to the literary
        products embodied in the messages.
        Mrs. Curran said she would not at
        tempt to say whelhcr Patience
        Worth was a spirit, but spoko of ,ber
        as a beautiful personality, which had
        come to seem not a mystery but a
        fellowship.
        She said the messages came to her
        in daylight as well as at night and
        that there is no trance connected
        with them.
        "The words come in sort o a
        rhythm," Mrs. Curran explained,
        "and I record just what comes
        whether I understand it or not."
        Pnticuce has been tested by rnoro
        than 200 persons and her messages
        have never varied. A professor from
        the University of Indiana visltod
        Mrs. Cunan to investigate her com
        munication with Patience Worth.
        William Marion' Reedy, editor of
        the Mirror, and Caspar Yost, editor
        of a SL Louis newspaper, became ac
        quainted with Patience Worth and
        both declaic her genuine. Yost has
        described her as a "spinster of un
        certain age; a writer, but a poet by
        preference. White the average spirit
        stalks dismal and wailing lugubri
        ously through the flnito world, Pa
        tience comes with a laugh, Yost said.
        She remarks. ''I be no sorrj' singer,"
        and proves it by many witticisms.
        EDITOR
        DESCRIBES HER.
        Reedy calls Patience's doctrines
        Pantelstic.
        He describes her as follows: "She
        fs a little woman, dressed In gtaj;
        with a little bonnet, ribbons coming
        down and tied under her chin. There
        are lines in her face, not the re
        written wrinkles of the smiles or
        her youth, but the results of ex
        perience Her eyes are biown liico
        autumn leaves after a rain. She Is
        -between 45 and 50 years old, spright
        ly, dainty, delicate.
        "Sho has stood beside the stock
        ade helping a good man load a gun,
        while he defends the settlement
        against the savage horde of In
        dians." Reedy said the theory was ad
        vanced that she was filled in an In
        dian massacre and this question was
        askcu of her. Sho intimated that
        something of this sort had happened
        to her and she was asked if she had
        not been taken captive oy the In
        dians. "Nay, something worse," was her
        reply.
        '.'She speaks an English almost
        pure and undefiled," Reedy said of
        her "There is an absence from it
        of all the derivatives of France and
        Rome, and sho rarely uses a word
        of more than two syllables. Her an
        swers are- diredt and almost invari
        ably in parables. She has respect
        for her interlocutor's intelligence."
        Reedy said sho is not another
        Sappho, or George Elliott, or Mrs.
        Humphrey ward nor a Sara Teas
        dale,' but rather echoes of all of thct
        poets. He said theie runs a consist
        ent character through her works and
        in two years she has not gotten "out
        of chaiactcr." Sho never has used a
        modern word or expression and he
        illustrated the seeming significance
        of this by pointing out how difficult
        it would be for a man trained In
        Irish or negro dialect to make a 30
        minute talk without breaking out of
        the character.
        "She has nothing lo tell, in my
        opinion, "Reedy said, "but she com
        mands my admiration and reverence.
        She tells nothing- that we have not
        heard from tho old masters and
        bards."
        "What of the divinity of Christ?"
        Kcody at one time asked her through
        the ouijd board. She answered, "He
        bought thee of his loving."
        "What of love?" he asked. "Tho
        love there is but tho o'er drip of lovo
        here" came the respou&amp;c of tho
        board.
        "Describe tho place where you
        are?" sho was asked. "Think you
        "Patience Worth," Mythical
        Character, Startles Literary
        World With Her Quaint I
        English In Essays, Plays and H
        Novels Noted Writers Are H
        Puzzled Over the Output of H
        This Woman Supposed to H
        Have i Lived 300 Years Ago H
        there Is bottom or top; this is a
        walless country."
        "Can you do anything you want
        over there 7" The answer was:
        "When you put the will you put the
        limit."
        "Put" in Patience's vocabulary re
        sponds to the modern verb "to do."
        "Patience may be a second person
        ality of Mrs. Curran," -Reedy sato.
        "but she teaches a lovo that is
        greater than we can conceive and
        that death is the keeper of unknown
        redemption."
        LITTLE COLONIAL
        DAME.
        Mrs. Emily Hutchings, who -was
        one of the first to receive 'with Mrs.
        Curran the messages from Patlenco
        Worth, said the first glimmering or
        the quaint personality of the little
        Colonial dame came in the maxim:
        "A busy saw gathereth no rust."
        One of the sentiments expressed
        by Patience Worth is: "A blighted
        bud may hold a sweeter message
        than the lovllest flower; for God
        hath kissed her wounded heart and
        left a promise there."
        Of the seances, Mrs. Curran says:
        "I sit with a friend, our hands up
        on the board, which I havo come to
        believe is nothing more than a con
        centrator. There is no trance. Ev
        erything is quiet with the exception
        of Patience Worth. The only
        definite part is that while I put my
        thoughts awhither, as Patience
        would Bay, and immediately the sto
        ries, poems, plays., parables, or
        whatever her work for the sitting IH
        may be, is shown to mo in tiny pic- JH
        lures, beautiful and distinct a3 IH
        though my eyes saw them.
        "The characters move and speak H
        and my hands fly over the letters jH
        much too fast for me to anticipate- H
        even one word. J
        "I cannot account for the langu- jH
        age. The words seem to be spoken ilH
        to me. though I cannot 'say 1 hear llH
        them In the sense that we hear tho iH
        voice that speaks aloud to us. The H
        words come m sort of a rhythm. I lH
        am not familiar with old Euglish jH
        and yet even the conversations -are H
        in this archaic tongue." jH
        Psychologists recently havetakcn ,H
        up a" study of Mrs. Curran and tho M
        Mvstcrlous Patience Worth. Some jM
        believe that Paticnco Worth is Mrs. jH
        Curran's sub-conscious self. Others jH
        have departed in doubt and without jH
        expressing an opinion. iH
        The ouija board has been con- JH
        demned by various religious bodies, iH
        but society is taking it up beside il
        these prohibitions. The Catholic tl
        church has condemned it as a super-
        stitlous practice. H
        Other religious bodies havo u- H
        clarcd that the devil is in hc boaid H
        and employs it to send his messages. H
        Whatever the truth may be, so-
        ciety has gone into the mystery of lH
        tho board, not so much with the ob- iH
        jeet of definitely deciding if it really jH
        is the medium of communication H
        with the other world but to,gratlfy H
        society's chief attribute Curiosity. H
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96076839/1920-06-25/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Invented+William+Isaac+Fuld+Baltimore+Dispute+Talking+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>1920:	After a 19-year court battle, courts declare only William Fuld can manufacture boards; Issac is ordered to pay court costs.</time>
    <text>
        WHO INVENTED OUIJA
        Brothers Ask Baltimore Court to
        Settle Dispute.
        Brothers, Apparently Lacking Falfh
        In Talking Board, Ask Judge
        to Decide.
        Baltimore. At the moment that the
        oulja board, which some years ago ex-
        cited the country and then virtually
        disappeared, has again come Into the
        Umellgbt throughout the world, two
        brothers are engaged In litigation here
        over the ownership of the patent, t
        The trial Is now In progress of the
        suit of Isaac Fuld, trading as the
        Southern Toy company, who I ask
        ing for an Injunction to restrain his
        brother, William Fuld, from deriving
        pecuniary profits through the sale of
        the oulja board.
        The plaintiff asserts that In 1904 he
        originated, manufactured and placed
        upon the market the board under the
        copyright name of the oracle 'and
        that later William Fuld started the
        manufacture of ihe oulja board.
        William Fuld asserts that he and
        Isaac Fuld were In business together
        years ago, and that the oulja board
        Is the original talking board, and
        claims that tlie oracle talking board
        manufactured by Isaac Fuld Is a
        copy of the one placed on the market
        by him.
        The Fulds about 28 years ago were
        In charge of a wooden toy factory
        known as the Kennard Manufacturing
        company, and the oulja board was one
        of the devicesthey made to entertain
        the young. It quickly won tremen
        dous popularity nnd so overshadowed
        the business of tho concern that the
        plant was largely devoted to the mak
        ing of. the oulja board.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1920-01-25/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=Baby+Ghost+Spectral+Messages+Curran+Patience+Worth+Talking+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        These entertaining and ravther well written novels
        War? dictated by the spirit of "Patience Worth" to
        Mrs. John Curran, of St. Louis, Mra. Curran solemn
        ly Ms?trta. Mrs. Curran says aha wrote every word of
        that? novels and many poem* on a ouija board word
        fttr word as the spectral voice of "Patience Worth"
        whiipered them in her ear. t
        shit theae spooky novel? ?ire not what this page
        deals with to-*lay. ?A nor? oaereet?ng thing to being
        done by this spook, .vccortllng to Mra. Curran and
        her friends. 'Patience Worth" oommividtTsd Mra.
        Curran, who ia childless, to seSarch for a certain rad
        head*id, blue eyed infant "with dark linea in than."
        whoee father was English and mother waa Scsotoh.
        Such a baby waa found and adopted by Mra.
        Curran
        And thia child, embodying to-day features and
        parentage similar to "Patience Worth," who tited 200
        years ago, is being brought up by ita spectral god
        mother Day by day "Patience Worth" gives Mra.
        Curran an ouija board message of advice about little
        Patienoe Worth Wee whenever il to U4&gt;?*mI4mL
        Three-year-old Patience
        Worth Wee, iron* re
        cent photograph of tho
        ghost-guided lituo ono
        ia Forest Park, St.
        Louis, She is wearing
        tho clothing ordered by
        hot "spirit mother."
        SIX years ago Mrs. John H Curran, of St. Louis, a
        peculiarly healthy-minded, normal young woman,
        who is the wife of the former Immigration Commis
        sioner of Misitvouri, began for amusement to experiment
        with the ouija board. This peculiar instrument for receiv
        ing meaaages foom the beyond" consists of a flat wooden
        board, about two feet long by one and a half wide, on
        which are th? letters of the alphabet, the numerala up to
        ten and the words ''Yea," "Mo," "Don't know" and
        "Good-by." A little heart-shaped table on three legs is
        placed on top of the board. The sitters place the board
        upon their knees, the finger tips of both hands lightly upon
        the heart-shaped table. After a while an "influence,"
        "apirit" or "spook" begins to move the heart-shaped
        board, whose narrow end then points to the letters, spell
        ing out the words of ?ta* message. A third person, an
        observer, acts as amenuensis, taking down the letters as
        the pointer indicates them.
        The "mestages" are accounted for by non-spiritualista
        as an expression of the sub-conscious self of one or both
        of the sitters; the mysterious movement of the table is
        supposed to be due to unconscious muscle rhythms of the
        hands of the sitters.
        Whatever the explanation, Mrs. Curran began to hear
        from someone who signed herself "Patience Worth" and
        who spelled out upon the board sentences in remarkable
        English?archaic, a forgotten dialect. This ghostly per
        sonage speedily developed into the strongest kind of a
        personality. She had been, she wrote, a maiden of Dor
        setshire. England, who lived about 1650. She was a
        weaver's daughter, an only child. She wrote that "my
        thumb is thick from twisting flax" and speaks of deliver
        ing fine linen to the "castle folk." Her father left to
        come to America, and after the death of her mother.
        Patience says she followed him to the new world. ?She
        was then thirty-five. Her new home was in the vicinity
        of Martha's Vineyard and Nantucket. Near there she
        tv a? buried, and now, she says, "a tree grows out of my
        grave."
        Soon she began to dictate stories and poems with ex
        traordinary rapidity and facility. The first book pub
        lished was "Patience Worth." The "Sorry Tale," a
        story based on the episode of the impenitent thief on Ihe
        cross, came out in 1916 and "Hope Trueblood." the last
        book, was a story of old England.
        The remarkable literary excellence of these writings
        attracted widespread attention. Their dialect
        passed every teat of experts. It was proven that
        Mrs. Curran had no previous knowledge of them,
        nor had she the education displayed by the com
        munications. Dr. Martin F. Prince, the famous
        neurologist, diagnosed Patience "asa sub-conscious
        personality of Mrs. Curran and offered to rid her of it
        by hypnotism. Mrs. Curran refused to have "Patience"
        banished by this means or any other, and scoffs at the
        sub conscious theory. Other distinguished scientists
        studied her case, but with no better results.
        For three years the "ghost" of Patience Worth?or
        whatever it is that responda to that nam?2?had been dic
        tating to Mrs. Curran by means of the oirija board as a
        concentrator. One book had been printed, another waa
        on the way to the printer. The first book was already
        promising an excellent sale. Reviews had been flattering
        and the publie was becoming interested
        Then one evening, after the Currans had been' dis
        cussing this materialistically agreeable result of the.man
        ifestations, Patience Worth exploded a bombshell. In
        the quaint old English words which she uses she an
        nounced that inasmuch an there "seemed to be some
        money in sight." and since it did not belong to the Cur
        rans. "but to God," that they should seek "a wee babe
        that had nothing, nothing and take it and care for iti"
        This was. indeed, disconcerting. The Curran house
        was a well-filled one. There was a grandfather, a mother
        in-law, a stepdaughter and the husband and wife. Be
        sides, they had counted upon using the money for thorn
        selves.
        Patience, however, was determined and explicit. Sho
        caustically called attention to the fact that the emolu
        menta of her bock did not belong to those who simply
        took down her dictation, but that as the author and main
        spring of the volume the returns from it were hers to do
        with aa she Dleased.
        "I am a weaver of cloth," said Patience on that night,
        in the curious imagery she loves to use, "and this cloth
        weave is not for him who hath. Thou ehalt seek a wee
        one who hath naught, and thou shalt deliver the goods
        of me unto it? hands, and ye shalt speak ita name
        ?Patience Worth."*
        This was an order, not a request 1 And to it when the
        first shock of surprise had worn off the Currans gladly
        bowed.
        ??L?ook ye.'' the '^heat** went on, "this shall be one
        who is sorely in need, mind ye Ye ?hall whisper sweets
        unto it. even unto the wee ear that knoweth not thy
        words, and tell unto it of a fairy dame who shall minister
        unto it and of Him who sent her And she shell be the
        love of all who love me and shall smile sweeta unto
        them.*'
        "But why a girl instead of a boyt" the Currans aaked
        anxiously.
        "Ye aee,'* answered Patience cryptically enough, "a
        man laddie hath man'? cunning, but the wee dame??ah,
        I know I"
        The Curran? quite naturally asked about the parent
        age of the child, ita legitimacy and many other important
        things, not the least of which was a description of it so
        that they might know when they bad found tbe babe
        Patience had in mind
        She gave them certain directions???rather vague; told
        them "not to mind earth's law but God's"?referring
        unquestionably to the matter of parentage and to watch
        close if there were any blood taints, but not to go back
        further than the grandparent?.. She wanted the child
        dressed simply, she concluded, and asked thai "about its
        neck thou ?halt hang a sign of Him." The Curran?, and
        rightly it, turned out later, construed this to mean
        cross."
        "Ye shall be upon tbe path! E'en now the wee one
        is waiting," she urged.
        So the hunt began for a child who wouid answer the
        description. The entire "Patience Worth" clan was sent
        out on the seareh. Two physicians were selected to ex
        amine it when found for blood taint! Much ground wa?
        covered in the next month. There were handicaps?an
        interesting one the refusal by a certain large St. Louis
        foundling institution to allow any baby to be taken from
        there because "Mrs. Curran wrote on a ouija board."
        During this search "Patience," who seems to have a
        strange sense of humor at times, remained silent. Then
        one night, according to Mrs. Curran, she directed them
        to cease, telling them there was no use in looking for
        "one that was not whole," and that in due time certain
        signs would be given them whereby they would know
        what to do adding that if they did continue it would be
        "like a wolf seeking for a fat fowl to feed well upon
        when the bird was still in the egg." After this, other
        weeks passed by without any reference being made by
        "Patience Worth" to the matter.
        Then one morning Mrs. Curran met an old friend
        whom she had not seen for years, and in the course of a
        ride together told some of the details of the quest for the
        baby. The friend, in return, told of a young wife who
        was about to become a mother, who was practically home
        less and friendless, and whose husband had been killed
        some time before in a mill accident. That night g mes
        sage from "Patience Worth" indicated that at last the
        Curraros were on the right track and that which she had
        prophesied M'as about to occur.
        The next day Mrs. Curran went to see this woman,
        who was very ill. A fever of preparation began imme
        diately. Layette cradle, perambulator, lawyers, adoption
        papers?everything was made ready just as though the
        thing were already settled. Seemingly the possibility
        that the expected child might be a boy was never for a
        moment considered.
        The mother-to-be signed the adoption papers, but held
        them under the agreement that if she lived she was to
        keep the expected child, but that if she died, then the
        Currans were to have the baby.
        Six weeks later, as Mrs Curran was writing with
        "Patience" upon the now well-known "Sorry Tale," the
        "ghost" stopped the dictation at exactly nine o'clock.
        "This be enough," she wrote, and the board became
        quiet.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1920-02-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Revelation+Lawsuit+Albert+Yost+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        REVELATION OF OUIJA
        FORMS BASIS OF LAW SUIT
        Lockport, 111., Feb. 24.An Ouija
        board and its uncanny revelations
        form the basis of a $10,000 suit here
        against Albert Yost. Recently Yost's
        home was burglarized. An Ouija
        board was consulted to solve the mys
        tery surrounding the robbery. Answ
        ering the question "Who robbed my
        house?" the board is said to have
        replied "Frank Walter." Walter is
        Yost's neighbor. They have been
        lifelong friends. The board is also
        said to have implicated Mrs. Walter.
        The board's accusations became
        known to Mrs. Walter, who called at
        the Yost home. She was told the
        Yosts had nothing to retract and
        forthwith filed suit for $10,000
        against Yosts, alleged slander. The
        Yosts deny the charge and insist they
        have uttered no word which might be
        interpreted as defaming the charac
        ter of the Walters.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-11-14/ed-1/?sp=70&amp;q=Invades+Britain+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        Ouija Board Invades Britain
        LONDON, Nov. 10.
        THE ouija board has invaded
        Britain! It masquerades un?
        der the pseudonym of "plan?
        chette," but it is the familiar
        alphabet and flatiron device that has
        helped to while away the tedium of
        prohibition in the United States.
        And apparently it has landed in
        force, because even now officials of
        women's clubs are debating as to
        whether the planchette is a game,
        or, if it isn't, what it is.
        "If it is a game." argued one club
        secretary, "it should be played as a
        game In the cardroom and during
        the regulation card hours. As it is,
        the planchette enthusiasts are busily
        occupied with their favorite pastime
        from early morn to dewy eve."
        Although she waxed poetic at the
        end, it was evident that the official
        was really disturbed about the exact
        status of the planchette. F-&gt;r it is
        said that the fascinating business of
        receiving messages from the spin*
        world?not the s?ance which was w
        popular following the war, but the
        more informal question-and-answer
        of the ouija board?is quite ousting
        the card games.
        If no regulation planchette is at
        hand a substitute, consisting of ?B
        ordinary inverted tumbler surround?
        ed by cardboard letters, is CtB*
        into play. The fingers are pl??*11
        upon the bottom of this glass, j^*
        as they are upon the little triant"
        lar device of the real ouija boaru.
        and it skips lightly from one letf*r
        to another spelling out its message*.
        And the planchette is less ex?
        pensive than bridge, because no on*
        yet has thought of betting on tM
        spirits! -?j
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1921-10-26/ed-1/?sp=22&amp;q=Mental+Troubles+Phenomena+Mystisms+Ouija+Board+Planchette+Alphabet+Witch</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        Mental Trounble i
        Washington?
        By BILL PRICE.
        Whether there is truth in a statmmnt that the ouija
        board is adding patients to Wasinta asums
        through disturbing infinenoes augon District mentalitin,
        students of mental phenomena will be inteAsted in the
        fact that the board takes its name from the French
        word oui (yes) and the German word ja (yes). Its
        origin is somewhat obscure. Both the planohette and
        ouija, somewhat simila in appearanes, date back to
        about 1855, and for a while were objects of consider
        able superstition. The planchette is a small board
        fitted with a pencil and two casters, made to move
        easily over a sheet of paper when the hands rest lightly
        on it. The dictionary says the ouija "is a form of
        planchatte used in spiritualistic seaness or the like.
        It consists of two parts, a board containing the al
        phabet and other characters, and a planehette, with
        a pointer substituted for the pencil."
        Investigation of automatic writings fail to find that
        the two boards have any origin in the mysticisms of
        Egypt. One writer is of the opinion that the iret at
        tempt in ouijaing was made by a man on his wife's
        breadboard. The skeptical refer to the board as
        wholly a modem trick afair which has no connection
        with Eastern or other metaphysics.
        Some of the noted spiritualists of the world make use
        of the ouija or planchette and carefully study the
        results. An able group of psychologists regard the
        ouija as a dangerous deception. Their theory is that
        the subconscious mind of the operator directs the
        fingers in such a way as to convey the information
        hoped for. The operator, they hold, is as innocent of
        this subconscious process as a sleep-walker is of what,
        he is doing, and naturally puts a supernatural con
        struction on the outcome.
        Leading spiritualists and other believers in higher
        agencies than natural ones, confident that communica
        tion with the other world is not only established but
        is developing into an understanding that will glorify
        humanity, are willing to accept the ouija board or any
        other method of transmission that will add ti the in
        formation they feel they now possess. Those of ma
        terial minds, who deride all supernatural beliefs and
        theories, hold to the opinion that after every great
        war there is a wave of the occult in some form, and
        say that right now the ouija board happens to be the g
        most popular man-made medium of bringing together
        terrestrial pinds and celestial beings and thoughts.
    </text>
    </result>
    <!-- 5 Extra Documents -->
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064187/1917-09-26/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;q=ouija+ghost</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        ALARM IS GIVEN
        BY OUIJA BOARD
        OF MAN IN ROOM
        Ghost May Testify in Unique
        Indiana Case.
        rVANSVILLK. Ind -Hire a gW to
        warn yuu of danger and jruard yoa
        from injury!
        A spirit protector, speaking throaffb
        the onija board, warned two F.varts
        ytlle women against a man's attack.
        The intruder lay three feet away, under
        their bed, and listened to the alarm
        message he waj powerless to prevent.
        May Prore Existence In Court.
        The Evansville ghost expect to
        prove his existence in court hy law.
        lie w ill not remain a creature of hear
        say, to be believed in or scoffed at ac
        cording to whether meti are credulous
        cr skeptical about the reality of the
        pi rit world.
        And all F.vansville asks this
        "What kind of a witness will a ghost
        make when the ouija board puts in its
        first recorded appearance in court?"
        Mrs. Martha Place and her daughter,
        JAargarrt, 811 John street, lonely, took
        up thair miija hoard to find they were
        nt as much alone as they had thought.
        "l ook out for Nat and Harb," spelled
        the board.
        A htrec blew back the curtains of
        Ihe bedroom where the women sat.
        "It's a little cooler," said Mrs. Place
        go her daughter.
        Board Repeats Warning.
        The curtains, an they billowed in,
        touched the bed beneath which lay the
        man. He held his breath as he heard
        the ghost messenger warn the two
        V"ien against him.
        "Is this Henry?" Mrs. Place asked
        the board.
        "Yes! Look out for Nat and Itarb!"
        repeated the board
        Henry is a son of Mrs. Place, electro
        killed ten years ago.
        "I have told vou before, Henry,"
        fcaid Mrs. Place, shaking a reproving
        linger at the tripod Vhich had spelled
        out the warning message by darting
        from one letter if the alphabet to an
        other, "not to talk that way,ahout the
        Moxleys." Nathanial anil Barbara
        Moxley, living .across the street, were
        the "Nat and Harb," of the ghostly
        Warning.
        Nothing Use Sail
        The board would say nothing further,
        kxcrpt repetitions of its ghostly alarm.
        The two women put the board away
        RihI went to bed.
        Mrs. Place heard a noise, like a
        leratching on the matting under the
        led. It was the cat, she and her
        daughter thought.
        Again Mrs. Place heard the noire. It
        ras not the cat. She leaped Trom bed
        and i an into the kitchen for a match.
        Margaret screamed. Trrere was the
        sound of a body falling.
        "I inn back toward the bedroom."
        Mrs. Place told the police later. "A
        man dashed past me through the kitch
        en into the garden. I followed. It
        was Nathaniel Moxley.
        Paper round on Floor.
        "We found a paper on the floor. He
        must have dropped it crawling from
        beneath the bed. It was a summons
        to Nathaniel Moxley to appear in court
        as witness in a divorce case. We Rave
        it to the police. They arrested him
        "When everything was quiet we took
        gmt the ouija board again.
        'I told you to look out for Nat and
        ttarb,' Henry spelled. And there the
        man was, under the bed within reach.
        While we were warned."
        Nathaniel Moxley has been bound
        giver to the grand jury.
        If the ouija board is asked to he ex
        libit in the grand jury room a new
        era in court procedure will be ushered
        The cross-examination of a ghost is
        judicial novelty.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076201/1920-03-27/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=ouija+ghost</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        Ouija-Board Silliness
        It has been said that the average newspaper reporter is
        just as honest and reliable as the average person that he inter
        views. We accept this as true so long as the person inter
        viewed is present in the flesh, but when it comes to the honesty
        and reliability of those persons who communicate with the de
        parted spirits, we draw the line. There we halt. An inter
        view with a pencil and pad as the mediums is something reason
        able, but when the pencil and pad are thrown away, and a
        table or ouija board duplicated, then the thing begins to look
        spooky. And—just think—you could quote the poor spirit
        anyway you wanted to, and yet he, it, or she, would have no
        recourse, except possibly by haunting you. And anyone hav
        ing the nerve to hold a telepathic conflab with a spirit would be
        above fearing a ghost. Senator Sorghum in the flesh could
        scare the editor into making a correction, or a retraction, but
        how could a spirit institute libel proceedings against anyone?
        There is some credulity behind even the most serious scien
        tific facts, especially in the earlier stages of their development.
        But there is considerable difference between a speck of credul
        ity and a great expanse of human gullibility. Any violent dis
        turbance, like the great war, tends to distort people’s emotions
        and reason, even more than it does their action and will. This
        must be the explanation of the tidal wave oi spiritualism that
        is now sweeping this country. The revers >n to the belief in
        the existence of ghosts is simply the bringing into pronounced
        relief of the state of mind that our ancestors exhibited. The
        burning of witches at Salem was of its fruitage. Spiritualism
        is superstition curtailed by law. As its disciples no longer
        have access to the stake and the guillotine, they must amuse
        themselves as best they can with table-rappings, ouija boards,
        and other such paraphernalia.
        The fact that such men a3 Sir Richard Crookes and Sir
        Oliver Lodge are converts to spiritualism gives little support to
        the hoax, for even a layman can find serious flaws in their evi
        dence, and such men as Joseph Jastrow and Sir Edward Clodd
        can veritably tear their tenets to shreds. From its inception,
        spiritualism has been founded on trickery and frauds, and no
        proof has yet been brought forward showing that the present
        revival is not concocted of the same ingredients. Even if such
        were not the case, we have our hands full of problems as it is,
        without giving heed to the imaginary gibbering of disembodied
        ghosts.
    </text>
    </result>
    <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1950-05-31/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=ouija+ghost</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <time>No timeline found</time>
    <text>
        Ghost of Highworth Rd.
        Returns After Exorcism
        BRISTOL. ENGLAND. "Mrs.
        It," the ghost of 13 Highworth rd.,
        is back again—with a playmate.
        Only recently the haunt was ex
        orcized by a Church of England
        vicar in a religious rite to drive
        away spirits taken from early
        Cristian records.
        The peace of No. 13 was short
        lived. Mr. and Mrs. William Ba
        ber, who live in the house, say the
        ghost now does a nightly routine
        up and down the stairs with an
        unidentified partner. Sometimes
        it sounds like they're dancing,
        sometimes like wrestling.
        The Baber theory is that the
        original ghost—which they named
        "Mrs. It"—is that of a woman who
        died in the house 18 years ago.
        "Mrs. It" first began prowling
        around the place in December.
        The vicar, the Rev. Francis
        Maddock, went through a rite of
        exorcism after a month of nightly
        uproar at No. 13.
        One night the Babers called in a
        spiritualist. All they found out is
        that "Mrs. It" (1) speaks a foreign
        language—possibly Russian and
        (2) is an atrocious speller.
        A ouija board was used to see
        if she had any message. What
        came out was "EEHFHMEV."
        Try Dancing if Putting
        Child to Sleep Difficult
        Gene
    </text>
    </result>
</results>
</topic>