<topics><topic>
  <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-roller-skating-craze</id>
  <results>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86089977/1905-04-01/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Revival+Roller+Skating+Rinks</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>April 1905: Cities in New England and New Jersey open roller skating rinks, reviving a sport that was last popular two decades prior. </time>
      <text>
        Rovival of Rollor Skating
        Forty or fifty roller skating
        rinks have been built and opened
        to the public in New England
        New Jersey and other states with 1
        in the year All are well patron
        ized and their promoters believe
        that this sport neglected for 20
        years will again become popular
        In the late 70s and early 80s roll
        er skating almost attained the dig
        nity of a national amusement No
        person was too oldior too young
        to use the rinks The hockey
        games endurance races and exhi
        bitions of fancy skating arranged
        bv rink owners attracted big aud
        iences for four or five years be
        fore the popular appetite was sat
        isfied Then and almost in a moment
        roller skating fell into disfavor
        Only children clung to it and on
        them it has never lost its hold
        This sudden loss of popularity
        was due simply to the fact that
        the pastime was worked to death
        for although a good many harsh
        charges were made by solemn
        moralists against it these never
        could have killed it Now it is re
        turning as a novelty with another
        gene ration of pleasurcscekers to
        appeal to but it is improbable
        that it will ever regain the glory
        it once had The outofdoors
        cult has made great progress since
        1885 and roller skating is an in
        door game</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1905-11-12/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=roller+skates+skating+rinks+Young+Enjoys+Fad</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1905: Roller skating is favored over dancing and other forms of amusement. Health benefits are also linked to the craze.</time>
      <text>YOUM ST. LOUIS ON KOLLEE SKATES ENJOYS FAD SO INTENSELY THAT
        DANCING AND OTHEE FOEMS OF WINTEE AMUSEMENT AEE NEGLECTED
        An Expert in the Art of Gliding on the Little Wheeled Shoes Gives Some Valuable Pointers to Tyros Desirous of Becoming Adept Too Enthusiastic Followers
        of the Pastime Compelled by Rules to Take Needed Rest.
        CrfA5 FRANKS.
        Ar jIjv VW KbMHdV-.ft?aif?. r noil film If- .iiiNSmjK 1
        WSSLUCfUE CAMPBELL
        the roller-Vaunt f.id )n
        upo- brlnrlns a Krrat
        Fr ii HrwOclvn bridle- to fir Go den
        tlate J the hre of the Ore it 1-lke. J
        to s- !.i .f thr MIss.;ippt. It rVrry
        l"ii w v rn them I, .i h-itl litrip1 enough j
        it if r slick nouicti. 'oclfty folk anj
        ollf a tak 11 to whils
        N t fiMwr-tlm! hl tht itu;;xrt.
        t -iant motor r. although automo
        Mii ro r:i!l popular, riot the li.cv.-Ir-
        i arc I'ltis stn.-o out of il.t. nor tin
        "bnu ro'iim' n'jr llut3-l to u inatprtal
        in I toj n )t rart f th liarn.an nnit
        mj, or. In other. orJ. wheel in the
        tiwil Non of thetx-.
        Tlip litttr h-s tint nuk up thr ma.'or
        tart 4-r t' roller U: ni- th ihlni
        ta-. 1 ij Too comi'ry haj can" m.il
        utrr ro lrr fi.utr. and S' lul 1 In thr
        t ror t rank of th Jrotr" to thl latr.t
        rjlilcn of an oM fad
        TIk ir'ai ho uc-c-,J la thr :mplr
        and uralthful pii'im of rl.rr i-kitins
        trn rar ai nould Rnd thr nr katr
        ai' ditTTent frvci thr old articl' I.U'il
        rr k-tr.. tr li""i IcjtoaJ of ooJn
        onr rnj tn-arii.S' Inslrad of pin
        xxir rciar tlr infjirn rolKr ikatr
        luu r r-rifort!nc and favtnatln;:
        O un f.t5 Vatr on l no lonr a
        vulrr ph ir in to ftnart Wnt Kad r
        Catwnnr tn onr roller Katr. en
        St Ij1 hit
        t-n-. ITOfe-
        flonal. who had brconr rjprrt with th
        rollrr. Thry wrr rnsaK'd at b'c talarj
        tu h-lp 'mart thr motrment Datrs with
        th hlch-prlcrl performrr r- canrrlrd
        afirr two fk. for thr rrnidrnta of thr
        V. Knd rrr a!rrad trampllnc upon
        nr .mothrr in th'lr rffcrt to co throact
        rr cur. iraainc to ir.r niny r.oot.
        WHiAt a thr o-r of costly ttrattlon j
        hri all thit tbr popV ftntrd wa an j
        i -pro r'ur.lty to i.atT Tft bump nl hrl i
        kno-ki t'; fall to t brcir.r.rr Jtdn t
        friiMrn anv of tr-r rol!rr-ttlnt novlc.
        horn havr boom o profl
        t that trrv arr now cl?tr.l I
        Ji qujtr thr pror-r thiu No fad tfct has j ha,dr,j,
        xr comr to St. Lo-x ia cauxht on a j ln twr
        haa thl onr j ,n, fojjn.-i bt.
        So lnttnn la thr tn'.rrt In rojlrr .at- ri-AT TO CAPACITT
        nt tJ inc parti" that naturally j -rt.,r, ar. t0 rlr,k, ,n St 1riul, thl.
        CO wtth It. that tr automotl" h almort r.a Arv nxj.1.. ,bo:t Vatrr It 1
        tconi rc3dary It lil iur;ty tak an r4r. tdrr.1 whan ltrr of thr rlnka
        obacurr pUe- a f wwki Utrr. when th- 4ee0 -rl,y to .jirj,ctr j crjn:r.1
        Jrt toB'i and th case ln thr thT ia CTo! trccmr at tlrr. tkat a r
        rnotaetrr drops In th vflnlty of tr t,J34Cjr 4anounCrr t-i blur urlfom- wnrid
        fralr. rotnt. It wtU thn b too cofcd A c(c m -j,. j, ju. ,ura t J
        to "auto. waUr thr "ra-hratrd skatlns j ordr thr mm or tr-t wernn. aa IN
        rlnka will b- at th p4nc: of thrir .j. ta v.-r rrcm t:vr arrna and clro
        I th nni
        XriuViar ar rouiai i ti,t:r
        Iory proSt.
        Tnciuvand ef St
        r.htly th lrt-sr miser tn thrr
        !raa3 rUKs. whc ar rcd to rip?
        tty whtr.r tt'raln er hiaN a thr M
        tcc would ay
        Tt rirsr-aU' fcatsrr of It? lr.nTa
        Uon 1 thr suns.- tn wafcrfc th tcp .otch
        :racst na taken to thr rirt. Out on IV
        Bajv.rr avenue ee caa r autcasobi.ea
        liatt! up fcr a bXv'a Itr.C aiot a
        raT IMrate kat-.C r-r?le a.- b
        comic tr;3tit, and St ta ejta to that
        a uc waen the aatcrcotllr part! cu?t
        It a !ta areclnr wten. after a ioeg
        w ti et-usty redr. wtth lt acnpa
        imett of rvputy Sheriff asd ht!t; If
        halt tta't sada t the rtsk aed aa hor
        r two (ttvn to tie rrCrr idi-att-v.
        A atwa-iB. aka fctlped. to introduc
        rr ptrtru!ar "T tS
        :r-rro:
        Ftftren nslnut w-lU
        HOW TO LEARN ROLLER SKATING.
        In
        allowrd the
        wersrn. 6en aftrrn mlr;utr arr allotro
        to the rat then Sftrrn ta'r.utra ar civets
        to tto want to kate In plr In
        th! war the earful rrsacajretsent farcw
        ra trpon tfc. who rsav b too n
        thu.iatr it thlr loyalty to the port.
        and Incidentally h rlrra rrryycnr
        chase to kte Is oro ecrcfert
        to rraon that I n to thr V riled
        rmpt tan evrry yrar ali yoorB
        nn." l that I don't dancr Tier rr o i
        nvasy at te V r that t:ter ceer lack
        for rcsM rompr It t different at tk
        rak hower Evrrjer. or. h 2 .a cr:3al fall here and therr brine th
        .n to akate and tN trouble J that c3jr treak la what U In all other rpecls
        t eerer ksow ten tn quit It fcaa tb aa rea picture
        aA (Sect tiat roZaws lha rH iaa I Ttm akatcrm so r ta alnlea and d3-
        II V AX IIXI'KHT.
        'earn th art of roller knt-. should, hut r..i fnrr.
        tnot 1'jn'i- J- t rollrr knf Th! Is renti:tl.
        Af?rr pur. h..!c a pair of flu'e... thr tt.drnt houl 1 fa to a katlr.)t rink
        and. after paying hi tdmlsslon. hou'.l Irmi.tli.itrly rMIre to the uriinc
        roarai. he-- t- will met a number of ri.unc mn. who will make him fr.l
        koi by triic him of thr nrifvo. thry had liTini: tl:- earlv t:iscs of
        their rollrr--S..itjni; eduratlon Aftr rri-i: th'r tcr!-- thr itu.rnt will
        th'nk of brok-n nrrke. arm and suddi i d-ath. Lut h ,houId b fr.arl.-j and
        tva-1) to catnr If ned be
        A -tulTt cm. If hr d!rr. Co on thr rioor r.ra-ins enly thr roller knte
        ai.d tu. ordiran raiment, but It l advisable to arrRuatd 3 bit l.v wrapping
        j-erral ard- of autorr.ob!l tire around thr waiit and chv. Th adju-t-nent
        of an automatic euMon t jlv ron!derrd a cxxl sugcstlon. a th
        tudrnt trae not lon- want to lt down. But he may ImoUnMrily it down
        whrn hr IrAUt rjrftl I.
        No or.r car teach th- tud'nt how to ka on roirr katr. but It I well to
        hmr an intruetor for two potent rron One that tlsr intructor act
        a ort of a pirltual aid Ar.othrr rr.iaor. u th-t thr sntruetor n-ed the
        monrj-
        Oncr on thr fl.xir. thr tudr.t hnuld re etTth!nc to thr kat !-t
        thrm do th wcrk After hr ha fall-n to thr -nor which -UU occur oon aftrr
        hr h,. madr hi, nrn e-rld-. hr nhould rir ,:owly anj look around to if
        anyon .aw hin fall Kwryonr w-sll har .rn him fall, to br ure. and thr
        student houkt not feel chagrined In ordrr to -hrrk thr temper thr f:dent
        Jhould rprat oer and oer ataln th. word Kverj bejy work, but father'
        The tudent will diorr. aftrr h ha falkn the f.r-t tine, that .lerr.
        mlnatlon ha arl'en within him Hr will mrntally reolv- to learn thr nm( or
        d'- He will the- mak- arother trtdr. and fall ar.Ia After arislr. and
        line ivuanc ar win rnaar anotr.rr tnIr and fall arain Uy thl tlmr :l
        reel aeccitoc.r.j :o itmtt ie wjh airo rrri ,ore. doubtte. but hr hould not
        let thl deter Mra Kep r!(ht at It. Kockefeiler ays that hard knocks never
        hurt any mat and he cujh: to know A
        I all No fer of ridicule, however They
        have ail b. en In the early stage of the
        roller s-rirnce Urmelvea
        The ?t !ul, promoter of the skating
        rclcr.cr are thinking yeriousty of perleet
        lr.c Romr sort of a pnrumatlc protector for
        the :afety of brlnnera Jwicli a p-i.tfetor
        would nrcesatl!' louk like an e"cagerjtd
        t itnpjr of a crlillrcn oiirit If adoptel It
        would undiubte'ly trove a ourcr of profit
        J t. f-.e k.itirc rink, for a man r'KRed out
        In thr b sinner" rra-alls would no doubt
        br thr funnlet thin? ever en flti th!"
        earth and vrvn.i n ul 1 want to i hits
        It 1 e.t!tntril that til l-i than J."1"
        I perroni paitltpatr in the new fad In St
        4) I Iul -ry night. The matlneaa are pro-
        j tr. almost a popular the nlrht
        j ion Student of Hotrrr Hall, thr .r
        a e,t Park Arilcw and l.r Intll r.rr
        ROLLER SKATING AN AID TO HEALTH
        ANO BEAUTY, DECLARE DEVOTEES
        A I dodsi-c thr theater nowaday and lnte.l
        meander down to the rwa". ti.ere to in-
        Ire f trie iat- aou t ,t aenaiionti
        Aid rrrreat'vr ;or'j
        tnr c if tnax aii
        about to.ler kat
        Thr r.tnirtr I
        I
        :i
        Why wn tt i T
        KTon la talklr. j
        havlnr hl harvest, i
        t ...n. I. AHa
        a f XOO. JCfl an ioere mr i-ji.u ikj nun i J
        i learn to dsn'r of tl.e.r own a.Tord, bt.t 1
        trf'- r teacher. Jut o are there thse t
        Ia a. w. ..a liamatt ala rrt enlla aaUtaawl
        n't iwiici aaaw-l-- k
        t. i -Aan--A -v art.,.., attaisM finer I
        who en t themlr on roller akat
        un'.e ther t omror.r to !lOW thejt hOT
        to do It Roller kal!n. Ilkr everything
        I in th' world. I !wrnd by hrd
        J I kr-oek The Inrtnwtor can't keep one
        apintiii aid to th beinner and aa b
        nee.! th- mor.ey no one blames him.
        Sorr.e of the meat prominent oety folk
        i I i..'rnir of the nrf of roJIr latins .i 'h
        lta!;t r, 1 1'r.uij They .iv thl, with ari'iii eoletinitv Th v itieiri It
        I.Ol.'et ,katmg ei tiex -rrv lr (.f III' 1mhI tliry ny. ami better
        till. It m C'r Kintl) Tlielr no! Mir Ml.UTirr of hurt bill! or tniril In allal-
        ln o tie rtllcr,. nor I thrr .in il.itK'r of Hie lii'rjliig th.it one meeta In
        fiutbuii
        llo'l. rkatlns M.rj .Tj-. l.rl a- the Siitli i.f healtl to the clierk of tti
        )omig lmly It iulrken the lilnml nml rimke onr frl "brund new
        llidle' Valine inaketr i, in nr.n-rful While the feet mm onl to be arriitnl
        arv 'r tiller katlng tl'r k:ieh lr,m the tlilta; Iti HiH Inntnn.-e. i.evettlielei.
        ep rtE trairialn that akntliiK rnIarillj' on the u,II r tenrlie one how to
        walk afttr the skate have let taken off
        While tl.c danrha'I jromoter look upon the ki'lur link manager aa hi
        ar-l. enetnv thr fact l fi.it roller rk.itlna; tn.tke bfter din.er of thoar who
        Ir.irn the former art In i.tliir word. kntltig on t tilti tearh onr how lo
        ue hi fet
        Holl"T "k.itlng taken In niMerat nuantllle. I helpful atnl healthful TI'H
        eoui.da like ih Ijiitruase of the tnedlrlne dvertlerm nte Mil It I ttue that
        the roller rr-ike the oM fel oun and the youna; tel great
        I.lnr all farinatlng jmtlme roller "katlnr nn be mnle 'too much of
        good thing ICniwIr.g when to fjult la un art to be acquired, ami riereaarlly
        ui on would enjoy fully all thr benefit and pleaatite of the Ort
        aa
        r.ew fml I an aid In
        aa44a
        I tn st I.oMi are getting up early In th
        mortiss to take private Instruction In
        the eentlemanly and lady-llke art of roller
        dec t know whn J ou've g-5t enough J much more arr.tlment and lnplritl9n In .katlng Other have ped the early
        Standing octIJ cc of tfcr st. Loite J th roller katr giHr than la th two- Ug of the game and ar no full-
        katlns rink thr eoucd of the gliding
        rcller frota Ithla remind ore cf thr
        rumbUcg of great wate-jfatL Co ir.lie
        ard one ee a thousand katera aaillag
        two-
        tp It i l..i tlrram-. aLv Tc-r 1 t f'ls1 PUei?nt.
        Skating rink trtU ar th rjle torn.
        ia.- wuir. ioo. .-so fuuijej saaiing v
        rink should t ralnua an orcheitra. The
        melody alto help to lean th vbock
        over th floor act ce of ttera ersir.R ta j wh,- .omeone U1U head over heel and
        exert a air.gl riue The .later iut i, or!j,a to craxnbl to tt -aide Ilr.e
        roll alosg In the even tencr of hi way. ;ar utr
        The crowd may roll around for an hour
        without a ml ha p. Then of a eudden there
        will t-e an awful crab. followed by peal
        of laughter, it u aoaneona faUI&amp;c that
        rhere are n ght partlea and matin par-
        tie The profit of the rink manager
        are of great conamueac1. however, and he
        can't give up ola apace ln th early vers
        ing o all cf th pr.vate gatfcermga are
        s'beduted to open at 11 p. m Aa a rule
        tny last until J a. tn Th early part of
        the everlrg l given to the theater or to
        a tour ta the motor can. and wvtwt gen
        erally It la the Utter.
        There ta ooe naaa In ft. taoat who leaka
        upon roller katea aa th rlt'ten of New
        Orlean look upon the fever-tnfretlng
        moaou.tn He i the owner .ml proprietor
        of th Ht IjI iltnr hall Th kalr
        hav ilnMi made h'm non t He l
        nearly uut of hiilne. Danca ar Infr
        quett Everyone who 1 moving hi feet
        th-e dar 1 d-lng o on ball bearing
        Isatead of dancing parti' It I kllng
        pertle. Not ha Tins the power cf Injunc
        tion, the dance. hall man ha about re
        algr.ed h!mlf lo h'a fate, and only hope
        that he may be able ome day to own a
        akattnc rtr.k
        In the roeatlme th wife promoter of the
        rlnka im Browing fat in th dollar,
        roll tn. for It et money to get on I he
        rink, erefl if nn dent hjow how tt
        akate. and lh popularity of th fad It
        ever Itvrreaalng Inatead ef b'ng on tk
        w ane. 1
        Another feature I moon lo be Introduced
        that will lend materially to lh luccea of
        the tyort. Tk fad ef roller akallac laa't
        confine,) tu mer katlng Other Ihlnga
        ran l don on th tntrnirtlk floor Home
        one hriv-ovri that about every known
        lame can be aicompllihed on th toiler a
        Poto la on of the moat popular It ta very
        like thr polo trnt U played en horae
        beck only In iead of being on a horae.
        the purer I rr wheel. The roller aelo
        plaer 1 thrown a lot more llmea than the
        man on horwhock. and the (port. It la
        e.d, I ito thrilling aa football, and
        lmot a, flangrrnua The roller aoJe
        player wear a gull that reeemblea the
        gear of a North fole egplorer, only the
        guoda ar firmr and heavier. Thr la
        bakrt bill ami Indoor t'nnla; too. aaaj
        ihe ar to 1- Introduced aa aaon aa the
        enthuila. tire of polo.
        No on I of the opinion that roller that
        Ing ha come to alay. but there lea atreaT
        belief that the Ht. Uule eagaewmaut f
        lb muni fail playing an Indefinite g
        gagetnent. and It to a pretty aafg hat tkM
        it anil laat all mm.
        .vi-w i, .v ---J.
        .s- I'
        -w.
        ll
        PI ?r.-r:$"'f
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1906-02-13/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=roller+skating+skate+craze+rink+rinks+skates</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>1906: The craze works its way into rural areas of the western United States. More roller skating rinks open in major cities along the Pacific coast and Hawaii.</time>
      <text>A Roller Skating Rink
        Will Open March
        Third,
        It has been a long time coming,
        many have thought, but it has arrived.
        At least the preliminaries havo been
        arranged for inaugurating tho "roller
        skating craze" in Honolulu,
        The Honolulu Skating Ilink Com
        pany hag been organized bv a number
        of young men. of whom Clifford Kim
        ball is the business representative. A
        skating boom has been in tho air for
        somo timo and this ontcrpriso is its
        culmination,
        Having taken the Union Feed Co.'s
        old warehouse at (jucen and Edinburgh
        streets for u rink, tho company
        will open it to the public on Saturday
        evening, March 3. Lumber is already
        on tho ground for tho skating floor. A
        supply of skates is on tho wny. They
        are or steel with ball bearings in fact
        the type of skate in uso on the Coast
        and in the roller skating rinks of New
        York and Boston. On tho inauka siilo
        of the building tho walls are to be
        opened up for admitting the cool
        breezes. This will make for comfort
        in tho exhilarating sport. A lean-to on
        tho Waikiki sido will bo fitted up. as a
        ftr.injlaf nnrl. aiu uvMrtfofn.. fliAvn a
        "Slsofjto be' a jiodnwator booth on the
        premises, but ,no spirituous, malt or a
        vinous liquor will bo sold. Arc lights
        will bo -installed, which will make the
        rink always brilliant.
        Of course an admission feo will be
        charged, as well as a skating feo. The
        riuk will be run on a first-class basis,
        in ehnrgo of a competent man. It is
        believed by the promoters that tho
        time for starling bucu a place of amusement
        is opportune. For a long period
        there has been' a dearth of popular entertainment
        other than theatricals and
        field Bports.
        To tho younger generation of Honolulu
        folks up to twenty-five years of
        age skating will ba an absolute novelty,
        for it is twenty years since tho
        previous voguo of that amusement
        here. And thero Is undoubtedly a
        larger population of tlnW hankering
        after that class of diversion, combining"
        exorcise with rollicking fun, In Honolulu
        now than then.
        The craze will bo a pastimo, moreover,
        for ninny onlookers of tho large
        class who take enjoyment from seeing
        others making joyful. At suitable intervals
        there will bo masked or fancy
        dress carnivals held for tho jollification
        of tho town. In the former craze
        theso wero highly successful features,
        No doubt Bandmaster Bcrgcr will meet
        me craze iiuiiwiiy aim uo prepared wmi ijn
        special stunts of music for gala</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1906-02-25/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=Roller+Skating+Skates+World+Takes+Wheels+Rink+Rinks+Craze+Skate</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1906: Newspapers begin running stories covering fashions related to the craze. </time>
      <text>WHEN THE WORLD TAKES TO WHEELS
        AD I been a visitor
        A^ j\T JI/T' Jk from Mars I am sure
        HE«f jj I would have thought
        y K| I was lookinr upon
        s 3!H |H the performance cf
        S Ha some solemn rite.
        fj] some mystic cere
        \u25a0 I mony, as the Person
        I] ally' Conducted •when
        I B seeking strange lands
        I if are? treated to the
        HI jl Snake Dance on the
        *Vf* I desert and the Whirl
        \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0*«™ ing Dervish on tha
        m sands f Afrlca at
        NnT/\y/Cl the usual,.very small
        kljf fcjf MZ\ additional' expense.;
        Surely nothing else 'could set adult
        human beings to going round and round
        and round like this, singly and in pairs.
        In a sort of speechless ocstacy.,
        Round and round and round thslr
        bodies swaying this way and that in a
        strange rhythmic motion.
        Round and round and round— sometimes
        faltering, staggering, clutching frantically
        at thin air. from fatigue or excess of emo
        tion, no doubt.
        Round and round and round— sometimes
        suddenly falling with a crash or a thump
        —according to the meagerness or ampli
        tude of the structure of the beings—mo
        mentarily overcome by exhaustion or
        fervor perhaps; then struggling to their
        feet again with wild gestures and frantic
        efforts, unheeded by the speeding throng.
        Devil-driven can they be, these madly
        hurrying, swiftly gliding beings?
        Round and round and round— urged ever
        onward when their spirits seem to flag
        and their limbs to las by the intoxicating
        plinky-planky-plunk of the piano that
        must be devil-played, even as the beings
        are devil-firlven. for no visible fingers
        press the keys that are uncannily lifting
        up and dropping down, striking the notes
        to which the hurrying throng; keep time.
        Round and round and round— the young
        and the old at»d those of middle life, never
        speaking, never smiling, never laughing,
        their eyes fixed In rapf gaze, perhaps
        of adoration, or. celestial" contemplation
        one or another now whirling and rushing
        backward, as if taken with sudden vertigo
        or touched with madness of despair or
        joy. then whirling again and going for
        ward as before, ever on and on and on.
        As I sit at one side, alone, upon a chair,
        among the tiers of empty chairs, alone
        and unheeded by the speeding throng that
        iaoks never to the right nor the left, but
        ever Into some dim beyond. I note that
        the" came beings flash past my vision
        again and again, -on an endless, :#mle33
        journey, some steadily like the planets
        ir: their orbits, others spasmodically dash
        ing In and out among the rest. In erratic
        course like comets.
        I note, too, that when indeed brtngs
        that have become familiar drop out, new
        beings appear and the throng hurries on.
        ever on and on and on, without diminu
        tion of members or of speed.
        Round and round and round they go
        youths and maidens clasping hands and
        swaying in unison; youths and maidens
        gliding singly and seemingly unconscious
        of each other; youths and maidens pursu
        ing each other, overtaking and capturing
        each other without losing one single
        rhythmic beat of the curious gliding mo
        tion.
        Roi:nd and round and round they go
        the beings of middle life, male and fe
        male, finely, with arms crossed behind
        then or hands thrust deep into their
        pockets, lost In meditation or the deli
        rious joy of motion; fla pairs, supporting
        each other In the onward struggle, mak
        ing mighty effort and but small and tor
        tuous progress.
        Round and round and round they go—
        even. the aged, the patriarchal males with
        ba!d her ?s or white beards, the females
        stout but determined, or those luckier'
        ones whose gray locks and wrinkles must
        be marked to belle the slendcrness of
        their waists.
        Round and round anG round they go—
        and darting In and out among them, with
        waving arms and legs and a port of stud
        led malice in their movements, are these
        imps .sent' to iotment them, to lmp«-de
        prnjrress and endanger limb and life, to
        afflict them and make their penance more
        real, or are they, indeed, as an extraor^
        dinary indulgence and toleration would
        fee-em to indicate, mercy the young of
        Ihtir kind the exub«rar»i. undisciplined
        male young?
        I note— irom my chair among the tiers
        of empty chairs— that a. strange rumbling
        accompanies the movement of these be
        inc?. Even as I reared the great build
        ing—can anything co hideous be a tem
        ple?—l noted It and wondered.
        Is it an undertone of groans and lamen
        tations?
        I look more closely.
        Surely these are little wheels, little sets
        of wheels s'-'ch as are used for moving
        about th&lt;; furniture indwellings, the. tittle
        t\ heels called casters, that are :fasiened
        to their feet, even as- they! are .to th*.
        icn oi beds and tables, and. desks and
        particularly heavy chairs. It is these.llttle
        wheels, 1 note, that make .the strange
        Tumbling sound, and send* the. beings on
        their eliding., curving dashes with which
        thty s,wrep along annihilating distance.
        Wonderful! Wonderful!
        What can thUs weird ceremony, this
        m; r stic rite be?
        Is ,It that these beings of all ages and
        conditions— for, I note the great and lowly
        mingling here, even clutching at each
        other— are doomed to glide In an eternal
        rc.ee? V, \u0084
        Is it expiation or adoration. that drives
        them round and round \u25a0 and round
        Could they slop if, they .would?
        Would they if they could r
        This I «ay, would have been the form
        my musings would nave taken, as I sat
        lonely upon my chair. In -that wilderness
        of «mpty chairs had I been a' visitor from"
        Mars.
        But— not being a visitor from Mars— l
        am, even as ycu are, "wise to the game,"
        and 1 know perfectly well that these, my^
        ordinarily sane,' sound' and 'pfactfcal" fel
        low beinre. somo of whom are the bank--
        ers we leave our .money with for safe-
        keeping, others of whom are the mer
        chants and. the merchants' .clerks, we
        spend our money with, are merely roller
        skaters, reveling in the latest," maddest
        f*d of a mad, mad world.
        lam ncit, I say,' a victor from Mars,
        yet so long as I remain on the side, stick
        ing to ray chair in that wilderness v of
        empty chairs— and it takes both hands to
        hold on and resist the tempiatJ6n of that
        vortex-this !s what roller, skating looks
        like to ny. and I haven't seest of It yet.
        1 haven't seen the Beginners' Pens!
        I haven't hung over the rail and
        watched the male beings initiated Into'
        the first degree.
        I haven't sat on! a footstool and peeked
        through the bars at the female novitiates
        undergoing the trials cf the preliminary
        ordeal.
        Why 'is roller skating?
        Now that th\> question is popped at you,
        you' can no more answer, it, I'm sure;
        than -you, can answer that other profound
        fjucry that Is' chiefly used to break .the
        fbc-ial ice:
        I Why Is an oyster?
        Acd" what It is is as great a mystery as
        why it is. \u25a0
        Roller skating in surely not a sport.
        This going round and round and round
        on little wheels In "a circumscribed, In
        clcscu area Is.no more .like ice skating,
        with Us freedom, and possibilities-, and
        surprises and tingling exhilaration,' than
        that mild nursery concoction. called "canv"
        brie tea is like the beverage that chee,rs.
        It surely. is not an athletic exercise/ for
        \u25a0 !t combines .the maximum of speed with
        *tbe. minimum of exertion-^xcept, of
        course, in .the initiatory stages, where the
        reverse i« true.
        It surely.'is not a social pastime, for it
        eeeins to even. the most unprejudiced 6pec-|
        tator a solitary pleasure, or at.best.a
        speechless ecstacy. for' two. '\u25a0'.\u25a0'•
        It may encourage sc^l communion,, but
        It certainly does not seem to be r a pro-
        inoter 'of conversation t for I have seen In
        the rinks the most susceptible beaux;- old
        and y'oung^ gb.\ round and round and:
        round, doing the^Dutch^ roll, cutting' figure 1
        eights'' and' other didoes, with their hands
        in their Dockets and their" eves rolled to
        \u25a0 \u25a0\u25a0-\u25a0•-. \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0•-\u25a0\u25a0. \u25a0'\u25a0:• \u25a0-.*:.\u25a0\u25a0 ,t, t \u25a0,• _, \u25a0-•.\u25a0\u25a0,"..«\u25a0\u25a0.\u25a0.\u25a0»;\u25a0..\u25a0:\u25a0 -_ *\u25a0: -\u25a0.-. V j- ;.\u25a0
        the-^san- era^gisgoS-sundXy;
        the rafterc, end never a glance for the
        distractingly praty.' girls cutting past
        '.Jhrrn. ,;v f' '\u25a0'-
        And to match them,; l've seen "the di3
        tractlngjy pretty girls, past mistresses -of
        the art of flirtation, \u25a0'_ glide' and sway- and
        sway and glide a'whole atternoon cr even-
        Ing away in aj moon-eyed 'abandonment* to
        the motion that can only be equaled by
        theinsfdious whiffs of opium or the sor
        ceries of hasheesh?
        That's it! \u0084".\u25a0
        If roller skating isn't a sport nor an ex
        ercise, nor yeta diversion. It Is an intoxl
        cant.iand that is why the whole world
        has taken -to it— perhaps.
        \u25a0 That Is, why the papa and the grandpapa
        'of .the .small bojr l who "makes a^perllous
        dash down-hill^ with one, roller-skate.un
        der the elbow of 'his; trousles; are. going
        round;ahd. round- and "round in the roller:
        skating rink, or taking surreptitious les-
        «6ns In secluded halls at a^dollar per, pre
        paratory to the round-and-rouhd d«but.
        That is why themamma and; the;auntie
        and the big sisUr— yes.Vand the physical
        cultured grandmamma— of the' -little girl
        who divides 'ber; pair *of roller skates with
        her chum; and becomes a'sldewalk'rnenace'
        to slow-moving,' shoft-"slghted r pedestrians,
        have alltaken to, the Beginners- Pens and.
        the dangerous fascinations \u25a0 "of
        instructors, who fascinate— no, I mean In;
        struct at'a;dol!arper. hour, v'!,u 1.
        There's no use Vdenyiiig "it, the /roller
        skating craze, ls' rampant, 1 and everybody."
        is r* either •skating "or learning -to skate,
        while rinks and schools," for "skating '-are
        cropping" out upon* th"e!city;s "surf i«" like
        chickeripox on a« schoolboy.; v \u25a0'; \u0084,\u25a0\u25a0
        Somebody has .called i it^a revival of
        rollerskatlng," but 'if isn't/ any more :than
        this year's' prairie fire Is', a revival *6f, (the'
        prairie fire of ten \u25a0 years "ago.v if* is *just" a':
        ;fresh°'outbr€akr.but' a "deal'; more virulent
        than it was before, attackiiuc ail raaka. j
        ages, and conditions, in no sense .a re-
        specter of persons. „...\u25a0
        Indeed,.soclety leaders, and belles and
        .beaiix, society; matrons'and society in-
        fants. have fallen vlctim-to it as readily
        as Ithe pretty^ girls in the rcandy stores".
        and the husky youths who .come up "out
        of i; the] foundries with'- their sweaters
        and' never-shovf-dirt S shirts to wrestle t
        \u25a0jwith: its Intricacies in the •Beginners'.'"
        Pen^: ••'\u0084'\u25a0".; vV-^ -.\u25a0'" \u25a0\u25a0. •'\u25a0,; \u0084" t\- \u25a0 \u25a0")'
        With '\u25a0 my.wn 'wondering. 'eyes l saw,
        leading^llghts" from the; lawTassoclatibh,'
        grave medicos, and \u0084> astute*;'',; financiers
        winding their way in and" oiit among
        \u25a0.grocery". clerk's;' and butcher j boys. v cdl-* t
        \\ege-- and "high^school Vstiidents. I,^1 giddy,
        gum-che wing and '^otherwise so-
        dateahd well-regulated on;
        the if asclnatinis">: little wheels. And', I
        HELEN DARE
        ,^aw-^^ould^you believe.'it-^one^ywun'g
        clergyfnani the very pattern of ;a young
        clergyman, .\u25a0 i,plnk and white, well
        groomed and 'decorously; coated, in
        black, who was tasting the 'incipient
        pleasures of this innocent; intoxicant,
        ?ln -fact, still waving his -arm's
        to 'maintain^: his": balance." -."swirnrnlh'
        rouii 1 i I he rI n k."; ast h e rude II t tie- boy s
        describe -it; '-"throw, actually throw, his
        clerical arms around' an unregenerate
        black T sheep \u25a0/' gambling] mjan, not .'to
        snatch Thhn.asia brand -fromt the. burn-.
        ing',";butj,to .keep from golng,;down: ker- y
        flump /himself; '\u25a0\u25a0- \u25a0 \u25a0
        ;>Such,a"iev^ler. is- roller skating/ \u25a0
        'The craze"' t hat'^it was t^v-enty- years
        •'ago^was* nothings to the .craze^ it is ion*
        t his r second^ visitation.*,'
        f Then Society 'frowned?:- it", down, and
        ska.ted, If it skated at all, surreptitlous
        incqg.. as it-were."
        was regarded as a cheap and some
        whnt.vulgar amusement.,
        But now. Society, perhaps. because it
        less strait-laced and more cheer
        fully constituted than it was twenty
        years ago, has taken to it with well, to
        he literal, wlt'i both feet.
        Any morning, if you will take the
        PROOF OF BILLY'S GENIUS
        a W- ~N ORDWELL. told me yesterday
        JJ-'iy tl at he was Boln8 olng lnto the
        JrV laundry business." said Hig
        i J: gins, as he and Perkins were
        ,^*T chatting in the elevated
        'jmoker. en their way, home.
        "Bord well!** ejaculated Perkins. "What
        ire you talking about?"
        "He claims," -continued Higgins, "that
        the' proprletcr of a suburban" laundry has
        jpleridid'; opportunities for paying off
        "grudges In ari innocent and unmaliclous
        way, 'but that they must be seized by a
        real genius In order to be made the most
        of." 3£&amp;83&amp;*&amp; l
        "But^l don't quite understand." said
        Perkins. "Pray elucidate." wmM
        "The] fellow, who runs the. mangling ap
        paratus patronize d-.by r Bordwell,'" said
        Hlsglns, 5 "drives one.* of his own wagons.
        is a:soclable chap with every one. gossips
        with h!s, customers freely and has 'come
        to be familiar, with _ their, likes and dis
        likes. ,The" r women. w^io see hlmj twice
        a week/ stand -for 'his chatter on account
        of^his^rare 'good nature: and confide in
        him to r such an i extent that there Isn't \u25a0 a
        private neighborly "opinion that Billy isn't
        custodian 'ot. '.'\u25a0'\u25a0\u25a0.
        :\u25a0» "There's a Tamilyi in Bordwell's block—
        I' 1 1 'call them the Van Sicklens-^-who have
        ver> artistic, ldeas of their own superior^
        it^. Bordwell- says they. are. a. lot of cads,
        and that-they j snort'an up to.date* auto
        mobile i and f.don'tjpay^ their bills. Their
        condescension has been 'maddening.; Re
        cently i&amp;l scries of sniibs \u25a0 administered to
        several iof i their plebeian neighbors made
        the*^ altuaUon V almost unbearable.^ when
        trouble, you may see Society in any on©
        of the Beginners' Pens of any one of
        the rinks persevering side by side with
        the hoi polloi. striking out as wildly
        .•with arms and feet, going down a3
        clumsily, all of a heap, grinning aa
        sheepishly when struggling to the feet
        that usually tread exclusive 'ways,
        "Mixing" democratically, too. and not
        a little selfishly, for one pretty bud go
        ing to her Pacific Heights home in a
        Larkin-street car artlessly confided to
        a friend, and the rest of us:
        "I've just had the loveliest time at
        the rink. I skated most of the evening
        with a riveter.* he called himself, front
        the Iron works. He's a splendid skater
        and his hands are as rough as as—
        bark. Tehee r
        "He said he'd look for me next time ha
        came.. Just fancy! Tehee!"-;"
        And it wasn't a snobbish tehe«»! at all,
        let me tell you, 1 but just of girlish enjoy
        ment, and we all teheed with her, at
        least In sDirit.
        What Is there in roller skating that
        makes its victims willing to endure the
        agonies of the Beginners' Pen?
        One can understand the perseverance of
        the boy in the' sweater who slides and
        joggles and spraddles .and sprawls his
        unruly way from one end of it to the
        other, for in strenuoslty is joy for the
        bor kind.
        But the stouV and studious Individual,
        professional by his spectacles and soft
        white hand 3. sedentary by his rotundity—
        what is there in this latest, maddest fad"
        that sets him to struggling with those
        fiendish little wheels that snatch his feet
        from under him. that bump him. Into wall
        and pillar and fence, that set him to wav
        ing his -arms like a windmill gone mad.
        that plump him flat upon the floor with
        an impact that jars his teeth In their
        sockets?
        What Is there in it that inveigles the
        matron out of her dignity into slipping
        and; sliding about on costers, clutching at men and women
        without the formality of an Introduction,
        remember whom she would scorn to put
        on her visiting list?
        Whatever it is. it's a very potent charm,
        for from its first dtvotees— the merely
        young and giddy and unclassified— lt has
        spreaJ until there is no safety in age or
        rank. From their first neadquarters,/ at
        the large and necessarily democratic Me
        chanics' Pavilion, they have overflowed
        until there's a rink in every quarter.
        Society, of course, cannot be democratic
        long, and having fallen victim to the fad,
        it soon organized itself into a club that
        ei: joyed the privileges of the Pavilion
        without the intrusion of the mob one
        nisrht every week. It was the Monday
        Night Club, with a membership of 500. and
        a list of patronesses that included the
        names of the undisputed leaders— Mrs.
        Kleanor Martin, for instance: Mr&amp; Dow
        ney Harvey, Mrs. Walter Hobart, Mre.
        James Follia.. The club was organized
        foi but four nights' skating, but so splen
        didly did the finances and the enthusiasm
        hold cut that its skating extended over
        nine nights, and it has disbanded reluc
        tantly oaly at the approach of Lent.
        So potent is its charm that it has be
        guiled not only the most unexpected
        victims into skating, but hard-headed
        business men into investing their
        money in leases, rink floors and skates.
        The pavilion is frankly democratic,
        advertising its masked skating carni
        vals unbiushlngly with prizes for "a fat
        ladles* race," "most comic lady's cos
        tume" and "most comic gent's costume."
        So. quite naturally. In the face of this
        there has sprung up a new and exclu
        sive rink on Pacific avenue. In the old
        armory, that was once upon a time in
        its history a riding school for fashion
        also. Here all sweaters and never
        show-dirt shirts are to be barred; no
        "fat ladles* races" are to be contested:
        no "genta" are to be on the list of eli
        gibles. It is to be small and highly
        select, and already its list of patrons
        reads like a chapter from the Blue
        Book.
        Jewish society has made for itself
        quite the most exclusive \u25a0 and hand
        somest skatlnfe rink in the city by turn
        ing the spacious, lofty, well lighted,
        beautifully floored ballroom of the
        Concordia Club from its original pur
        pose. There the 'club members practice
        of mornings" with skilled instructors,
        and there they have a ladies' night once
        a week that is as well attended as tha
        smartest dance or swcllest wedding.
        Quite as naturally rinks sprang up or
        are about to. spring up in the Mission,
        in the Richmond district, south of
        Market and— where do you think this
        last one Is? on' the Barbary Coast!
        Yes, even those freebooters of the night
        life are abandoning the waltz and the
        two-step -33 they practice it and are
        taking to the little wheels and going
        round and round and round with the
        rest of the World, fashionable and
        otherwise. CfcJK \u25a0
        What greater proof can there be of
        the lure of the roller skate when in this
        territory, already famous for its skates,
        the denizens take to the new kind!
        Billy, the laundryman. came to the res
        "Some green hand in his establishment
        made an awful mlxup and bits of the
        Van Slcklen wearing apparel were dis
        tributed throughout the community wher©
        they would do the most good. The dilapi
        dated condition of moat of the articles re
        joiced the hearts of the recipients. Bord
        well drew a dress shirt and a union suit
        which he says he would have been
        ashamed to send to a rummage sale.
        "Every piece was plainly marked "Van
        S..' so that there was no doubtabout It.
        Several returned their finds directly^to tha
        owners, and one aggressive lady aug-;
        gested a Joint note of sympathy and offe"r
        of pecuniary assistance.
        "It was evidently -most distressing to
        the aristocracy, and Bordwell avers: that
        the 'For Rent* sign now upon the Van
        Slcklen bouse \u25a0is the direct result. ";Ha
        says that Billy's talent is certainly mar
        velous, and in spite of; the laundryman's
        protestations, he Insists that it was a.
        beautifully worked out "plan from begin
        ning to end. as Billy acknowledges that
        the Van Sicklens .were three months be-,
        hind on his books.
        VBordwell says this la not the v only
        -.proof 'of Billy's genius. Some months ago
        the two had an argument over, prices, s and
        the next weok .Bordwell's pajamas came
        home' starchetl as stiff as .frozen flsh.
        Billy almost wept tears of contrition over
        'the incident, but Bordwell thinks it 1 was
        a case of getting back at him just the
        same. He says \u25a0 there is .no end of such
        opportunities in the laundry business, and
        the wonder is that more men ol hl*h abil
        ities don't so lato KIT
        Fit </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1906-04-22/ed-1/?sp=36&amp;q=Chinese+Diplomats+Joke+Roller+Skating+Skate+Skates+Craze</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1906: Newspapers begin running stories covering fashions related to the craze. </time>
      <text>CHINESE DIPLOMATS JOKEi
        i
        TOOK 11111 THREE WEEKS HUTHE
        HE HAD HIS FVXAmiiml
        Amused the Folk From the Other Legations
        Hall at the Holler Rink Jut OnoeThen
        Then Ho Set to Work to Learn theGame
        Game Made Them Open Their EyesWASHINGTON
        WASHINGTON April 21 Persons whobelieve
        believe that Chinamen have no sense of funare
        are invited to pay attention to this storyWashington
        1 Washington has had the roller skatingbug
        bug for the past three or four montlmIt
        Itis a revival of the roller skating craze ofa
        a couple of decades ago ConventionHall
        Hall which has been turned into a rollerrink
        rink late one of the biggest floor spacesInthe
        in the United States and the flooris lackedwith
        with skaters of all degrees at each of thethree
        three dolly skating stances Many of thetofflest
        tomcat people in town men and womenand
        and porno of them middle aged personawhorollerskatedbeforemout
        who rollerskoud beforemost of the presentgeneration Igenemtlon
        generation of roller skaters came into beinggyrate
        gyrate around on tho floor of this Washington I
        ton rinkThe
        The diplomatic hunchIlA Waslilngtonlans
        tonlans offhandedly call the legation poopie iplE
        pie patronize tho rink during the morningfpssion
        session from 10 to 12 noon None of theAmbassadors
        Ambassadors or Ministers Plenipotentiarylias
        lias yet been seen actually skating but tlwattaches
        attaches and the women folk of the legations
        tions have fallen for tills sport with a thudand
        and they cavort around on tho wheels wljilotho
        tho Ambassadors and Ministers look onfrom
        from tho berioliosAbout
        About a month ago one of the leadingsecretaries
        secretaries of the Chinese Embassy accompanied
        companied a crowd of the legation peopleto
        to the rink at a morning session He is ashort
        short rather fat Mongolian with an eversmiling
        smiling visage He took a seat with thestaid
        staid lookerson and watched the antics ofIhe
        the beginners with great apparent amusement
        ment A number of the young attaches ofother
        other legations begged him to put a pair ofskates
        skates on and have a try at the Americansport
        sport He shook his head over these suggestions
        gestions for a long time but finally heyielded
        yieldedWhen
        When tho other legation people saw theChinaman
        Chinaman being led out on to the floor byone
        one of the instructors they all stood byfor
        for fun They had the fun The Chinaman
        man on skates was a Joke The secretaryexhibited
        exhibited all of tho Chinamans natural lookof
        of agility as to foot and log work He wabbled
        bled like a rundown top and his legs refusedutterly
        utterly to support him even when he triedto
        to stand perfectly upright and still buthe
        he was game and hegavo tho thing a dozentrials
        trials Ho fell down every time on severaloccasions
        occasions dragging his obviously chagrined
        grined and tore instructor with him ThoChinaman
        Chinaman fell on every part and portion ofhis
        his anatomyHis
        His flowing green silk garments wore oftho
        tho color of oily mop rags when he finallyhad
        had the skates mood from his feet butthroughout
        throughout the whole performance thepleasant
        pleasant engaging smile never left the
        1 lL 9 j ii it f 7r
        r
        r
        f 0
        hiCOOKJRt7CZAsSM4NYOlZCHC
        eeWlfffG
        COOKJrff czwss jywwopraE xesv WWTTO SE CHEW wziMffG CARS iffo
        live to make the school a SUCCORS Therewasnt
        wasnt any doubt of this in a few weeksThe
        The school started with 200 pupils of nilages
        ages and wound up the term with 2000Next
        Next year it is expected the number willswell
        swell to more than 2000Even
        Even thorn who wanted to see the experiment
        periment made were hardly prepared forsome
        some of the things that happened Onenight
        night soon after the school was started awhite
        white haired colored man came along andput
        put his name on the rolls Ho said he wanor
        or All they askod him was what classbewanted
        wanted to joinI
        I want to write my name Bald the oldman
        man Im kind of late but Id just liketo
        to see how it looksGeorge
        George Braxtonthat was his namestraightway
        straightway became a member of the firstprimary
        primary class Ho has been going everynight
        nightWhen
        When the closing exercises were heldrecently
        recently he was kept busy writing his nameand
        and a lot of other words for a circle of admiring
        miring friends He was the oldest pupilin
        i
        Iin that or any other class but there weremany
        many whi had passed 40 Some of thesewere
        were colored women who went out scrubbing
        bing all day or bent over the ironing boarduntil
        until 0 oclock They were there learningto
        to read and write tooThere
        There were carpenters janitors andwaiters
        waiters men who worked hard all dayThey
        They sat side by side with colored boys andgirls
        girls in their toerwHundreds
        Hundreds came however not to loamto
        to read or write but to learn how to make
        a livelihood They werent asked how muchthoy
        they know They were just told to enterwhatever
        whatever class they wonted to
        Chinamans face If Chinamen ever arehard
        hard losers they rarely or never show itThe
        The legation people had a great lot of funover
        over the clumsy Chinese secretarys thumping
        ing falls They pretended to sympathizewith
        with him keenly but their winks and grimaces
        maces when he wasnt lookin g indicated howmuch
        much enjoyment they wore having Whenhe
        he had the skates taken off the ChineseSecretary
        Secretary of Embassy resumed his benchseat
        seat and benevolently watched the restof
        of them skate for the remainder of themorning
        morning stanceThe
        The Chinese secretary appeared at therink
        rink at 0 oclock on the following morningsought
        sought the proprietor of the rink introduced
        duced himself and announced that he wasgoing
        going to learn how to roller skate Hewanted
        wanted to loam while there was nobodyelse
        else on the floor he said and was willingto
        to pay for private instruction during theoff
        off hours He arranged for private instruction
        struction in the art of roller skating from
        8 to 10 in the morning 12 to 2 in the afternoon
        noon and 5 to 7 in the evening at whichperiods
        periods the rink la closed to the publloThe
        The proprietor of the rink detailed one ofthe
        the Instructors to attend the Chinese pecretary
        tary during these hoursWhentbeChlnaman
        When the Chinaman turnodup at the rinkon
        on the following morning he wore an American
        ican sack suit Instead of his Chinese officialrobes
        robes He had regular skating shoes onhU
        his feet and ho had n pair of brand hewroller
        roller skates the finest purchasable formoney
        money slung over his arm The wholeImmense
        Immense rink floor space belonged to theChinaman
        Chinaman and his instructor and they wentat
        at It The Chinaman practised roller skating
        ing for six hours that day six hours thenext
        next day six the day after that and everyday
        day for three weeks Ho was as prompt OHthe
        the town clock and there wasnt n minuteof
        of the entire time that his smile didnt lookto
        to be ineradicableOn
        On Wednesday morning last the Chinesesecretary
        secretary invited his chief the ChineseAmbassador
        Ambassador and all of the members otthe
        the Chinese official suite to accompany
        him to the roller rink for the morningsession
        session Whether the secretary let hischief
        chief and the others of the legation staffin
        in on what was going to come off doesntappear Iappear
        appear but the Ambassador from theFlowery
        Flowery Kingdom and every member ofhis
        his entourage down to the lowliest oopyUtof
        of official documents went with the secretaryto
        to the rinkAn
        An unusually largo diplomatic bunchIncluding
        Including a couple ot Ambassadors thirdto
        to look on had already assembled at therink Ihands
        rink when the Chinese party arrived AHhands
        hands gave the Chinamen a great reoebtion
        ties and a crowd of the young attachesecretary
        or olber legattons got around the Chinesesecretary
        secretary and pleaded with him tq put theskates
        skates on once more and try the thingagain
        again The secretary demurred quite alittle
        little but finally ho yielded again thintime
        time with more apparent rejuotanco thanwhen
        when be had put the skates on the firsttime
        time He retired to his Instructors cubby
        hole of a room put on his skating shoesand
        and his fine pair of roller skates and thenappeared
        appeared at the gate to the floor leaning
        heavily on the arm of his instructor hisknees
        robo knees seeming to snake beneath hiflowuK I
        1
        I Y
        Dressmaking was the most popular Theschool
        school started with one dressmaking classand
        and finished with six On the night theschool
        school closed choruses of exclamationscome
        came from these classrooms The coloredpopulation
        population of the district had turned outto
        to inspect what had been accomplishedand
        and gasped at what they saw There werecreations
        creations in blue in red in lavender dresseswith
        with lace and without lace princess gownsand
        and gowns for the ballroom And thecreators
        creators stood around giggling at the exclamations
        clamations of their friends Some of thepupils
        pupils were middle aged women who didwashing
        washing lii the daytime but their Joy wasthe
        the joy of childrenNext
        Next to dressmaking came the millineryclasses
        classes In point of popularity There werefive
        five of these There were classes for beginners
        ginners and advanced classes The crowdsof
        of colored visitors that surged throughthese
        these rooms saw hats of every kind andshade
        shadeSixth
        Sixth avenue has nothing to equal someof
        of them and Sixth avenue has been ablazewith
        with them ever since the school clowdfpr
        for thq pupils were allowed to take themhomo
        homo iorthofr own adornment or to sellthem
        them if they wished The city furnishedall
        all the materials and taught the pupils howto
        to make tho hat from the frame to the lastpiece
        piece of ribbon on itIf
        If the joy of those who had turned outthese
        these confections so dear to the race thatloves
        loves color in Us gaudier forms was great itwas
        was nothing to that of the pupils in thecooking
        cooking school City Superintendent Maxwell
        well happened to visit the cooking class ofthe
        the new school soon after it was startedTo
        To his surprise he found a lot of able bodied
        A titter of acute enjoyment went up
        from the crowd of Jogationpeoplo ou thifloor
        floor when they saw tho Chinaman witlthe
        the skates on again They huddled at oniond
        end of the rink to give the Chinaman althe
        the room hed neeThey had no intention
        tlon of Allowing him to knock them dowiin
        in sprawling around anti anyhow thejwanted
        wanted to get together so as to erijpy the
        fun momThe
        The instructor gave the man running
        the big orchestrion a signal and the orchestrion
        chestrion struck into a swinging Woldteufelwaltz
        waltzThen
        Then the Chinese secretary and theinstructor
        instructor holding each other by the handsand
        and facing each other at arms lengthshot
        shot into the middle of the floor and beganto
        to execute an extremely graceful rollerskating
        skating waltz The jaws of the watching
        legation people fell and they were struckdumb
        dumb at the sight The Chinaman and hisinstructor
        instructor waltzed gayly about the immensefloor
        floor pace for a few minutes reversing atwill
        will and doing all the other position exchanging
        changing stunts of the roller waltz w enl
        with a mighty shove the instructor puahedtho
        tho calm looking secretary into the middleuat
        or the floor The legation people huddledtogotherto
        togotherto watch he run tlintdlrlnt eventuate
        wotchJhe
        uate were amaze to note that tho Chinaman
        man was spinning all that long distance towhile
        tho centro or the sUppery floor on one I5katejWhllo
        while he held the other foot up under theshelter
        shelter of his robeReaching
        Reaching the middle of the floor theChinaman
        Chinaman brought the other foot to theground
        ground and started to skate curlicues oncult
        the toe wheels only ot his skatesas dlmcult
        cult a feat as any roller skater ever triesin
        Ho got away with It In great shape Thenhe
        he dashed forward on one skate wheclddIn
        in midcareer still on one skate and propelled
        pelled himself backward in a huge circleon
        on the one skate winding up by doing amost
        most perfect split on the heel wheelsunly
        only of his skates All the time the exhlmself
        pre slon on llla face was just such a one as
        he might have worn with cqualaJmropriate
        nllSll while engaged In plokJng wild flowers
        Then as a final stunt the CDlnamnn raised
        himself to the toe wheels of his skates
        began to revolve tfowly to the right and Ineight
        eight seconds he was spinning around onthose
        those toe wheels like an Indian whip topmaking
        making so many revolutions to ihomlnutethat
        that Ills features couldnt be dlstjngubuiedglanced
        The Chinese Ambassador sitting up on a
        high tier bench looked smlllrig and bdppywhile
        while the members or his oTclal suiteglanced
        glanced at one another and made low
        toned gurgling remarksThe
        The legation people huddled at the farend
        end of the rink and looked chapfallen butwhen
        when their nretiomozemont was over theyshowed
        showed that they were fair by surrounding
        the Chinese secretary and overwhelming
        him with congratulationsThe
        The Joke Is on us they all told himrather
        rather superfluouslyuFor
        For the remainder of the morning session
        the Chinese secretary skated around thegreat
        great rink arena with the prettiest girts of
        the legation crowd and taught them how
        to do the more simple rolloring stunts
        The Chinese secretary hasnt sold a word
        to any of the legation people as to how hlgroyereal
        reversal of form came about and mostfirst
        or thom believe that he fooled them the
        first time by pretending not to know how toskate
        skate professing to hold It Impossible
        for anylKxly to achieve the Chinamansrollerskating
        roller skating proficiency In the space of amonth
        month They dont know anything about
        the Chinamans six bourn of determined
        practice a day for a month and they say
        that he must have learned roller skating
        In Ban Francisco where he WM stationed
        before coming here but the facts ore as
        bore given
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093407/1906-09-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Latest+Fad+Roller+Skate+Skating+Skates+Craze+Rink+Rollerskate</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1906: Newspapers begin running stories covering fashions related to the craze. </time>
      <text>LATEST FAD IS THE
        ROLLER SKATE TWO STEP
        aBATTLE 18 JUST AS SUSY
        LEARNING NEW FORMS OF
        AMUSEMENT AS ANY CITY—
        THREE RINKS OPERATING
        J*TjE- ci t g|g|g|||-TJi|^|-gTgßSMaal*. ll'TaT'l t f laWjasSß 'I"
        AND ONE MORE ASSURED.
        tVdier skating baa ttrttck the Pa.
        in' itwat and struck It hard, tlred
        easSy working out from the it
        teaoaaw... It* si) through th* south.
        rrn.stat.-« t 9 i-,iiir,.ntta and then
        ssaili il northward. The fad atrurfc
        i l**rtsar rebounded t* the iburb
        st lawns. entered Washington at
        Vaisjonver, atruck Aberdeen a
        blow, and ended It* apectacular
        ■MM In thla city.
        lb Seattle tie growth of this I*l
        -e«t firm >.r amoaement la dtatlnctly
        evident. At first th* younger gen
        eration began etrapplng the roilera
        on their feet and skating around Ihe
        hails mn4 rooma of their bomea.
        The* law epi.nlit cement gaßtWalha
        and asphalt driveway* fern tb*
        new open-air res* of sport. A rink
        was ft.rmally opened and now Heal.,
        tie boaata of three flourishing roller
        Mia* Maud Coffin Shewing Differ
        ent Positions of th* Two-Step.
        I
        skating amusement place*, and
        fen Hi I* bring constructed nnd will
        he open lo the public by the it I.llls
        Of HI. month.
        Th* Two-Stop Now
        And now the rotlrr-iknte twu.step
        hi* "arrived" nnd tt.i. nrw fad I*
        raging. Just plain roller skating.
        despite lis delirious risk* and i. as.
        lUUrntlng danger In life and limb.
        It being relegated. To h* up with
        the times ..lid in with the »«tin on*
        inns' In nt this new Whirl o*l wheels,
        lh* |tt> at. tnaddett, wildest Inven
        tion of the roller sksllng rrnre.
        To ii. -i this new method nf
        courting death la the ambition of
        all th* tyros, and the bill, he, -pen*"
        af ell the link* along th* ...as! si.
        crowded with those eager to con
        quer 'I,a new d.tme on skates.
        Bump*, bruise* and broken headt
        count for nothing, and should an tar,
        CARMEN REFUSE
        tli II 01 II h KBII 1 IT
        TO ARBITRATE
        I if NnSafl I BlffV I &amp;a
        DANK CLEARINGS.
        Kr, I 1. I'Hlt 1i.32i.0nil
        h.'.i 1, m0i1,....., 7ll.til.it
        a'
        Incrrase over i:uin>
        dale last )*ar...l to:,r.3J II

        ..........a*.**.
        "I'M.MOT SHOT"
        SAID PRESIDENT
        OYSTER. HAY. Rent. I.— Wild
        minora that President It.ataen It
        whs shot, believed to hsve been
        rtsrled by curb brokers, sent news
        pa|H r mi to Hagamore Hill, raua
        tng Ihe country folk! lO Mill. thai
        a crura country run was In progress
        Tho icoclied, the prealJant'a house
        brealhlra* and were Informed by
        Ihe president personally that he
        had not hern shot. DII 'he
        forenoon Mir president -ii.'.. lo Iha
        vlllsgt. Thete am no Incident to
        give ihe smallest foundation for
        such a rumor.
        FIRST TO ADOPT
        NEW SPELLING
        WAHIIINITON. D. C f*ept. Ir—
        Th. Army and Navy Itrglster, aeml.
        .•ffi. I il, th* fiisi Journal In this city
        1., adopt the irfnrtned spelling.
        •ays:
        It should be adopted throout the
        country, tha the purtata do bate
        spasms."
        perchance, get sllcrd off by an un
        tamed wheal a hill ..1..- 1* prune upon
        lb* floor of Ihe pen. It I* of no Im-
        I portance—a mere Incident to the
        main leeue.
        Otily Stan**.
        At home. In the batementa *nd on
        the kitchen ft-., re. th* skater* are
        at the task. emittltrig alt' th*
        hitting Illtl* wheel*, trying to
        bring them Into lb* pretty but diffl.
        cult toot rin.Hie of the roller skate
        ""deui-tempa." In I'orlland and la.s
        Ar.aelea already there *re number*
        of expert tao-slep skaters among
        the female lel.tsts, the girls, st
        a rule, being quicker lo master any
        new til. on wheels tbsn the mas
        culine element of th* rinks. Now
        8. .ill!, wilt time h. artist*.
        Mia* Maud Coffin of Portland,
        who posed for hr accompanying
        pli lures, la an espert at the deux
        temp*, and ha* undertaken to •bow
        her i... fortunate staters, through
        the ratneru. Just bOW it it dune,
        iter* are her direction*:
        This It the Way.
        "Fir*!, own your own tkatrs, for
        no pair of skate* are alike, and
        constant changing Interferes with
        progress. If you are a rank ama
        teur, ii n to stand up on your
        ek.it.-s iti the kitchen at home, even
        li. t"i. venturing Into the slaughter.
        p*n, nnd always .-in. Mb to keep
        your knee ell h*llt If the funda
        mental rule. Don't undrilake the
        two-step until you have mustered
        Ihe gild ami Ihe swap and are Ihor
        oiighly al home on .kit.. If ynu
        ran dame the Iwo-slep ynu will
        klmw *hnut what strokes ate re
        •lulled, bul If ynu ciiniint dime It
        with ease, lake off tour aknii's and
        lake s dancing lesson. The move
        ment I* practb a'ly Ihe tame, rscept
        that It It l.rtlri mil to lift the fret
        from the floor nl any time—unlets
        o'he w.ii.ta a broken lierk. By fol
        lowing 11. movements n« shown by
        the umbel ci picture*, one will cx
        c, we ,11 the *trnke* of one revolu
        tion of th* dance, and the rat it
        •Imply repetition of the revolution
        nnd Inti tspriaiiig step* li not no
        easy to learn, and one take* a
        chance on one'a dignity st 111- begin
        nlng, but whtn ynu have learned It,
        It a th* grvatsst fun *\*il"</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1906-11-25/ed-1/?sp=35&amp;q=Costumes+All-Absorbing+Craze+Roller+Skating+Skates+Skate+Rink</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1906: Newspapers begin running stories covering fashions related to the craze. </time>
      <text>COSTUMES FOR THE
        ALL-ABSORBING CRAZE
        Feminine Tears
        Are Unbecoming
        V I V-l ls considered unbecoming by w*nen to
        a I shed tears when in trouble. They are
        SBS B •_« placing themselves on an equality with
        WOW O mei^ in all way«, and, hs men are sup
        posed, never to be guilty of such weak
        ness, women also must imitate this
        stoicism and develop hardness or Htrong-minded-
        QeM, whichever we may choose to call it. It is
        very questionable if this is good for women in
        any way; it is a relief to shed tears, and many a
        nun would be glad if it were not regarded as
        CowardiM for him to weep. It is Nature's meth
        od, or one of her methods, of assuaging grief, and
        the inability to indulge in tears leads many men
        to drink as a means of giving vent to their feel
        ings. .'._
        From another point of view, however, this stoi
        cism is certainly prejudicial;. that is, in the
        chances of marriage. Whatever men may say, it
        is inherent in them to like a tender woman; they
        tte in her one who will sympathize with them,
        and who will come to them for sympathy.' No
        man really likes to see a woman cry, for it hurts
        K irn and makes him uncomfortable until he can
        do something to relieve ,but all men prefer
        a woman who can and does cry. Not a foolish,
        faint-hearted specimen of humanity, who flops
        down at any trouble, however small, but really a
        tender-hearted creature who, although brave'
        enough, does not try to encase herself in a kind
        of additional outer skin, or suit of mail, that will
        render her proof against sentiment. A woman
        of that sort, they not unnaturally imagine, will
        be a very undesirable helpmeet in thia world of
        ups and dowus, and they look for one who has
        not lost the ability to weep in true feminine
        iushiou.
        In spite of their moral strength, Mien always
        want some one in whom they can eonfld| What
        encouragement can they expect fcoin a woman
        who knows not how to wet-p, amP regards it as
        undignified?
        T— ""IHE athletic Winter Girl is bubbling over
        with the buoyancy of her spirits.
        mjgWfl What's the answer? Guess.
        KSECq Another hygienic and beauty-wooing
        diversion has been added to her list of
        indoor winter sports, roller skating;
        before which throngs of enthusiasts willingly bow.
        And mcthiukn that morning tennis and croquet
        clubs, which were so fashionable last winter, will
        now go a-begging.
        This whirling through the air is a most invigo
        rating form of exercise, keeping the body in a
        good, steady motion (that is, after you have gone
        through the preliminary stages of proper balan
        cing, when your physical and mental forces some
        times woefully desert you).
        The exercise brings all the muscles of the body
        into play, stretching those the average woman
        seldom employs, besides stimulating the blood
        into healthy, vitalizing action.
        Not one woman in ten takes the proper amount
        of exercise; yet she wonders why she easily tire*,
        why her complexion is dull and colorless and her
        circulation poor and languid. Here's her beauty
        balm, packed down and running over.
        The benefits of ukating are materially increased
        when the fair whirler will make up her mind to
        take deep, full breaths, such a* can only be ac
        complished when the shoulders are thrown back
        and client out, in place of the atingy, little in
        halations that utterly ignore the upper portions
        of the lungs.
        ROLLER SKATING ABROAD.
        Heir, then, is au ideal exercise, that will keep
        you in good physical trim until the outing season
        intervenes. Let me conclude thin overture set
        ting forth the manifold benefits of roller skating
        by saying that Madame Heavyweight and her
        oliiu, aimeinir little sister will i-.ich deiive physi
        cal battarOMDt particularly suited to their indi
        vidual woe».
        We Americans are faddists at best with regard
        to our pleasures.
        T.OS ANGELES HERALD SUNDAY SUPPLEMENT
        We take hold of a new diversion, run it to
        death in six months, shelve it and take up an
        other. With the present advent of roller skating,
        however, it is likely that it will make good for
        a considerably longer time.
        In foreign capitals, London, Paris, Vienna and
        Berlin, roller skating is regarded quite as essen
        tial an amusement as theatres and music halls,
        and here the rinks are never closed except in
        midsummer.
        The costuming is usually elaborate, often fanci>
        ful, and the scene as a whole, a very picturesque
        and interesting spectacle.
        .mere is a wide difference between the charac
        teristic types of the skaters of the two countries;
        the sturdy, blonde-haired (Jerinun fruulein, and
        the dninty Parisian, with her perfect coiffure and
        chic toilette, are good example* of whut 1 mean.
        Fancy dress costumes, bal masques, as Paris
        calls them, are frequent occurrences, and many
        of these are given, both in private rinks, rented
        especially for the occasion, and in the large pub
        lic rinks. All manner of fancy skating is intro
        duced, and in some cases national dances are
        given on roller skates.
        In London, while the King, Queen Alexandra
        and Princes* Victoria do not actually indulge in
        the merry sport, they often occupy a private
        box on gali occasions, and saem to thoroughly en
        joy the merry spectacle.
        Pauline Chase, the original Pink Pajama Uirl,
        hat recently introduced a very novel skate dance
        in Ixindon that is making a great hit.
        But how boon, here in America, are we going
        to introduce our foreign cousin*' idea of a carni
        val on roller skates? Here's a chance for a wide
        awake manager!
        &lt;\KH ACCORDING TO HOUR OK lUY
        The Americau girl, as ever, has adopted l>rue
        i,,il and becoming attire for this indoor *p«rt
        that i.i in perfect taste for the- hour of day or
        uight.
        For the morning sessions the fair skater is very
        simply gowned in a rather severe tailored suit,
        with morning skirt of plaited linen or dainty ba
        liste, or fine French flannel, both styles being
        frequently hand embroidered.
        In place of the separate* waist, which is more
        practical and comfortable on account of its light
        weight, a waist is worn to match the skirt, mak
        ing a three-piece suit. The waist may be of the
        same material, or of silk trimmed with the cloth,
        r more fashionable combination this winter. The
        flannel waist referred to is not unpleasantly
        heavy, as it is the same quality used for outing
        wear in the summer.
        White or cream serge skirt worn with lingerie
        waist make* v pretty and attractive costume. The
        skirt and waist, too, may be kept in the locker
        or in care of the wardrobe woman and left there
        for a small sum each week.
        Roller skating seems to have captivated soci
        ety people. Especially in the morning do the
        girls make the largest showing, since there is
        less to do on the social program, and a string of
        automobile* and carriage* is always along the
        curb at thia hour of the day.
        GAY COSTUMES FOR AFTERNOON AND
        EVENING.
        Quite a stunning array of gown* is seen in the
        afternoon, many of which are typical matinee
        toilette*; short skirts, of course. A number of
        dressy bodices are worn, white or those in pale
        shades, harmonizing with the skirt*. A mlk or
        ahiffon blouse will top off a skirt of plain cloth
        or figured cloth. Many fetching plaid suits are
        worn, and in place of the small turban hats,
        larger one* are worn in the afternoon, laden with
        flowers, grape* and feather*. The surplice and
        fumpar with tfuimpes of lingerie, silk or
        shiffon! Mry attractive.
        Prime** and piiBMM corselet gowns aie worn
        for afternoon and evening, developed in a quan
        tity of fashionable materials.
        At night the scene presented is brilliant; white,&lt;
        pale and brilliant colors are worn, and the gown
        ing is often quite elaborate. A favorite style for
        evening wear is a silk or velvet Dutch dress
        (which is a princess, cut with low neck and
        shoulder straps), worn over a frivolous little
        guimpe of some sort, chiffon, lace or silk.
        A striking model of this description was worn
        the other evening; a wine-colored dress, panne
        velvet, "with self-colored chiffon guimpe, trimmed
        with bands of passementerie and silver buttons
        and a large cream felt hat with wine-red plumes
        shaded to pink.
        Another was of black corduroy, princess corse
        let (low) with bretelles of black velvet and baby
        Irish crochet waist over pale blue chiffon. The
        hat was a "magpie" model, narrow brim of cha
        mois-colored felt and crush crown of pale blue vel
        vet caught at the side with small black plumes
        and rhinestone buckle.
        I describe these costumes to show you how
        the fittingly well-dressed women choose their rai
        ment for hours of the day.
        CONFIDENTIAL VIEWS ON THE SIDE.
        Since Paris has taken up the no-corset notion, 1 1
        see girls experimenting with the fad during the
        morning, and undoubtedly the unrestrained exer
        cise will do them much good, but the same girls
        have small waist* in the evening. Feminine vani
        ty is a stronger force than self-preservation.
        Girl* who have long, narrow feet should choose
        shoes with wide, extended soles, otherwise the
        skates will not stay on, and when they slip off
        the soles a very nasty fall is sure to follow. For
        a 3tt-A shoe, a number 8 pair of skate* is re
        Short »kift| should be worn, those that touch
        or nearly 10, are too long aud are likely to throw
        you. U y° u have a pair ot bloomers, us
        this doe* aw »y wilh e*t«'a skirU, save the O i,g
        which makes your effort in skating mv.li
        easier aud you fuel several pounds lighter on your
        feet. MAKJOKIi;:
        Why One Actress
        Has Not Wed
        Y~" 01) ash. iv.ii i have never married?"
        queried a "star" of the theatrical nim
        _ ament, when frankly asked her reason
        for escaping Hymen's bonds. "Simply
        "■■■■■■a* because I never found a man I could
        honestly love," was the simple confe»-
        "Once I approached matrimony to the eitent
        of ordering my troußseau, but an incursion into
        the bower of matrimony was thwarted solely by
        myself, because I realized I did not love the man
        who had honored me by asking me to be his
        wife.
        "An actress true to her art should not marry.
        We women in dramatic art have all the virtues,
        the same ideals, the tutiue love of home, of par
        ents, sisters, brother* that belong to women in
        other stations of life. But we make our own
        roads. Having completed them, as we baliavt,
        we find often they are still rough, and we do not
        always succeed to our own satisfaction in making
        them ready. Why, then, hamper us with matri
        mony?
        "When two artist* of equal power, who htfl
        both achieved renown, both of strong will ;mil
        temperament, instilled with ambiiiuu
        still further, enter into a state oi wedlock, tin
        inevitable result is that their profossioaal instinct
        generates a temper that is distrustful and they
        disintegrate by their own artistic weight. It be
        cornea a burden which neither can .-urry and
        then they separate -that is professional]?.
        "In private life the conditions would be t>.
        same were women money producers like men,
        aflh in the same business and surrounded by n»
        soriations anil eondn oma to women
        of the dramatic profession.
        "One or the other must be tb&lt;
        Let it be the man woman'
        home. An actress' sphere is her .at a>4 the
        theatre When »ln
        a woman in the true oenoe ones inure und forget
        ■he waa ever an aotreaa."
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058246/1906-12-22/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=Roller+Skating+Craze+rink+Skates</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1906: Newspapers begin running stories covering fashions related to the craze. </time>
      <text>Roller Skating.
        The roller skating craze that has
        caught every ottior city and town In
        the country has Logan thoroughly
        within Its grasp. During the past few
        weeks the local rink has been crowded
        each evening and throughout the day
        many beginners may be found taking
        instruction. Roller skating Is most
        exhilarating and no sensation quite
        equals that of gliding through spaco
        swiftly on skates. The late roller
        combinations makes skating easy even
        for novices, and many In this city aic
        now Indulging In the pastime as
        healthful recreation.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1907-01-27/ed-1/?sp=37&amp;q=Beauty+Yields+Roller+Skating+Craze+Skate+Skates+Rink</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>January 1907: Washingtonians embrace the craze (now in the form of steel and ball bearing skates) both in rinks and on asphalt. </time>
      <text>ii l1tGtZIN zua ECTIOIV C ijUit a ftingto 6Jime ej NJ9AY rJ N2 07
        F i ii
        5

        i
        ASHIXGTON ASHI GTO Is In thes the thethroes
        t tblda 0 0throes
        s throes of a fad which whichbids a lirh lirhbids
        W bids fair to outrival outrivalthe
        1 e
        f the b4cyel fad of ten tenT tenyears J Jyears
        T years igo p Then It Itwas Itwas Itwas
        was two wheels to toride toride
        io
        ride en n Now No with the advent of theroper the thero theroer
        ro roer roper er skate It ta eight el ht wheels wheelst wMelaaU
        t all began with a few tn children childrenhating rhUdrentlng ebildrenskating
        hating tlng up ti at aM 4 down the sidewalks sidewalksearly aidewalkSearly Wewalksearlytist
        early earlytist Mat fall Finally 1111 high school schoollads 8hoollads schoollads
        lads and laaetes tea tried H and found it itHost 1tt108t itMost
        t108t Host inviting Then the older broth brothera
        4 l era and staler faactnaied by b the theport theII a asport
        II sport port took their turn at It and now nowit nowIt t
        it has actually actuall come co to the point pointwhere pointwhere r rtaere
        where taere the children cblld of a II larger Jar er growth growthshamelessly Xr growthshantelesety wth p paban1EIEHly
        shamelessly declare in accounting for fortheir fortheir iJ iJtheir
        their participation in the fan that iliatthe thatthe
        4 I the family lamll physician recommended reeotgx ended It ItSome ItSome II
        Some id tde Idea a of the popularity of roller rollerskating rollrkatlrg rollerskating
        skating in Washington tan be gained gainedfrom ai ri4 s sS sfrom
        from the fact that during durin tb the Ctiriat Ctiriatmas l Chrietmae rilt riltmlUil
        S
        mae holidays over 1W9 Jii OOI palm of akatps akatpswere akat akatw s swere
        were w re Mid The roller akathtg abattn tlnx 6 rink at atConvention atCURYentlon t J
        Convention Mall has a dally attend attendance IlttEndanCf attendante
        ante of from 9 9iIIf to 1NU1 lM I people jmopleThere PttOPIfThue peopleThere
        There are ttw cities dta in th the world worldtli worldthat orld k
        tli that t offer the t poaribiHti that Wash Waahingto ash r rInlftM h e eIngt9a
        ingto doe doer for roller aiwUng Ubl The ThejnileK TheHell ThenIIes
        jnileK nIIes Hell and mites of smooth m oth olean 4 an as asphalt asphalt
        phalt afford an outdoor rink rt k that can cannot cannot gra1 gra1phalt J Jnot
        not be surpassed ItU rpU Tbte fact lit at last lastbeing lastJwtng lasthetng
        being appreciated appreciatedhundreds IUI to shwn II by the thehundreds tV tVbundrecls
        hundreds of akaters who 00 each pleasant pleasantevening plea ant 44 44evening t teenl
        evening eenl whirl hlrt glkle 1I1k e and pirouette up upanJ upand t t
        and 8 n down the level streets or engage engage1r fna fnaawr
        1r 1 Iteree awr batth battles s of n roll skate sknteTliere te 00 00T1ure nThere
        There was as a tlwe UIo1 when hen Ice abating abatingwax IIktlnlIUI rkatingw
        w wax IUI the th princlpa 1 winter Inter sport of ofWaahington8 ofaahllIlon
        11 Waahington8 aahllIlon youtg people But for forthe torthe forthe
        the past few Ie year there ha has not been beenmore beenmore beenmore
        more than several weeks of o this thisshealthful thishealthful 1 1healthful
        healthful outdoor exercise A good goodsubstitute goodsubstitute goodsubstitute 1
        substitute has ha at laat been b en found In Inthe 1nthe inthe
        the present popular diversion diversionTitere dlver dtverslonThere lun lun111ere
        There ta no question as to the bene benefits hen hennts hcnefits
        fits derived from this form of exercise exerciseSome exerciseSome t tL
        L Some doctors are recommending roller rollerskating rotterakatfng i iskating
        skating to many of their patients patientsNervous pattentsKervous patientsNervous Ii
        Nervous trouble of all kinds rheuma rheumatism rheumaUsm
        4 tism and colds contracted from overheated over overheated oerheat8d
        heated heat8d houses hous are among the diseases dlseaaeeta diseasesfor diseasestor
        ta for which the physicians ystcJaas advise thetoiler the theroller theroller
        roller skat skate And whisper hlI r it gent enriv enrivlest nIJ nIJ1Mt 1 1beat
        lest the streets be blockaded with withskaters withx k kekattira
        x skaters roU roller r skating ia the tbebe beet t anti antifat antlfJlt antifat
        fat remedy Jfm dy n the world w rld One hour oa oaa o oa d
        a pair of roller skates Is worth more morethan morea I Jc Jcthan
        than all the nostrums oa the market marketfor marketfor
        a for the reduction of superfluous tissue tissueKor thlllueFor tissueFor II
        For a number of years ears it bus been beenthe beenthe iI
        the custom for the th CarinthUn and the theWashington theJ theneehlfRton
        J Washington boat cebs ch hbs bs to give an an an anaual ani
        ti i hunt Dual dance in Coi Comstlo4 ttin Hall This Thise Thillf2 Villeyear
        f2 year e r a rkate rkt wl1 w1l VI be heb h llelli In I l placo placoof lato latoof Ie Ieot
        of tbe 11 be usual IIn darce darceIt dance ute uteIt
        4 It wilt UI lwerawtjsinx be a aiWMttbmg r new to to see lan lancers IAnerll tansere
        sere erll and Cf qua4 tu drUl s being la lag danced da on onroJler onS
        S roller skates BkutesV IIkliLt There kere e la no doubt doubtthl1t doubtthl1tf doubtthl1tCqatlnued that thati t tr5n
        r5n 2
        f i Continued on Second S ecoad Page Pagei 2 2i
        i tnr t i
        i
        1
        t L V VEN EN B BEAUTY BEAUTY5A EA U r t ti AJ
        5A YI YIELDS E LDS TO f T THE mrz jfi 7 j f F r 3 3f t tRJ
        RJ itoiia l t 0 L L v SK 5KXN 5KXNt Z INIj Nf SqNf Sq e p 7 I r i 1i 1 Ii f i ip
        4 I lk</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1912-11-24/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;q=Hundred+Lives+Sacrificed+Roller+Skates+Skating+Skate+Craze+Rink</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>November 1912: 106 children in the Greater New York area are reported to have died in the first ten months of 1912 due to the roller skating craze. </time>
      <text>In the ten months of this year In
        Greater -New York VK young lives were
        sacrificed to the craze for roller skating.
        Sometimes the trouble came at the
        handa of automobiles or heavy trucks.
        and sometimes the boys and girls, going
        faster and faster on their down-nm-
        coast, fell and that ended It all. For
        they gain great speed as they get under
        way, and when an accident comes the
        blow is pretty heavy, and the little folk
        pay the price of their venturesome plea'
        sure.
        Worth While to Take Care.
        Probably those figures are not ap
        proached in any other city in the world.
        Europe cannot equal them anywhere,
        and surely our smaller cities and towns
        do not pay so oeariy tor tne cnuaisn
        pastime. But it Is worth wnile for
        fathers and mothers everywhere to take
        care when their little folk Indulge their
        fancy for the sport; and if they do not
        bar out the level spots they can stand
        guard over the graves
        A day or so ago when three little tots
        were seen speeding and coasting about
        on skates that fairly skipped over the
        giound. some passersby were heard to
        remark that there would be some broken
        heads or shattered bones before many
        days went by If that racing kept up
        much longer. The only reply was "Non
        sense," and as no direful reports have
        been heard presumably all has gone well
        with the loung racers, but tnose ios
        deaths In one great cit. Just from roller
        skating, make one realize that "Non
        sense" Is not all that should be said
        Whatever else those figures may em
        phasize, there Is the one great crying
        need thrt they bring to light the need
        of the children for playgrounds where
        they can gather together and play to
        their hearts' content. Just as nolslli or
        as quietly as they like
        Infnlr to Children.
        Few, very few of our cities, are fair
        to the children. They warn them that
        they must not do this and they cannot
        do that, they must not play ball for fear
        of broken windows and they must not
        play with roller skates for fear of
        broken heads Rightly enough they are
        scolded and threatened when they run
        ill iruiiL vi ma iu nco j ti uvo vi, .uc
        drivers and run the rlek of something
        worse They are told the 're a nuisance
        with their shouting, they run staid
        pedestrians down with their blcicles,
        they give them a shock with their skat
        ing, and the street Is no place for their
        I i.o. do not. In sufficient numbers, pro
        vide big open spaces where there Is no-
        tody to "call them down,' and do not
        make up for half the "don'ts" that are
        uttered. I
        Even once in a while we are eon-j
        fronted with some great demand that)
        we are told is a public necesslti vo
        must have this for the sake of the city's
        fair name we need that to show that I
        we are progressive, and there is some
        thing else that Is a common comfort,
        and of course that cannot go by the
        board
        The city wants them, the clt needs
        them, and money Is appropriated and
        space devoted to the Improvements that
        will make the city grow
        But the children They want more
        playgrounds and the need them too.
        for the sake of growing big and strong
        and wholesome like the blossoms that
        have light, air, and room a plent
        The bigger and more crowded the citl.
        the greater the need for playgrounds,
        but It Is only In the great open country
        that there Is no pla -problem at all It
        was In a little village this summer that
        a party of city folk saw scores of chil
        dren playing about In the streets. That.
        of Itself, was nothing, for they alwais
        will play there But the strangers look
        ed about them for the traditional "vil
        lage green looked for front lards, back
        yards, too. and they did not wonder that
        the boys and girls flocked out to the
        sfreets there was nowhere else to go
        The rich folk, the well-to-do folk, the
        comfortable even where, do not alwais
        think very much about pla) grounds.
        Their boys and girls can play In the
        open, and can keep off the busy streets,
        but of those 10b children killed while
        roller skating, most of them skated and
        played In the thick of traffic because they
        had no play space of their own and no
        big place where they could go.
        Children do not have to skate, do not
        have to romp and shout or play on the
        city streets, but nature made them want
        and need to, and cities should give them
        the space.</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://blogs.loc.gov/picturethis/2015/07/pictures-to-go-roller-skating-roundup/</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>When I think about roller skating as a kid, I remember fun Friday nights at the skating rink with friends, pop music and treats at the snack bar. There was the joy of going fast, and the occasional wipe out from going a bit too fast.  Not a problem for 4-year-old Betty Buck, since the caption for this charming photo states she is “equipped with bumpers fore and aft” and has adopted the motto of “safety first” as she learns to skate. People of all ages have enjoyed roller skating for well over a century.  Take a roll down memory lane through the following images from the Prints and Photographs Division’s collections.</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2021/08/pickleball-in-the-press/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/mss184240263/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/mss425490753/</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>GREATEST SKATE SPECIAL
        [illustration of a pair of skates]
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/mss382990069/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
  </results>
</topic></topics>