<topics><topic>
  <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wwi-planes/selected-articles</id>
  <results>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1917-08-26/ed-1/seq-20/#words=bombs+flying+great+machines+War+war&amp;tab=tab_search</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>April 6, 1917: The United States entered the war.</time>
      <text>A fine human being with a beau-,
        tiful head and not a thought in it
        would be very much like this mag
        nificent republic, with a beautiful
        Capital which is the nation's head,
        and not a vote in it.
        The Pictures on This Page
        Useful Fighting in the Senate, Horrible and Useless
        Fighting Abroad.
        For this page every Sunday we select pictures that
        stimulate and illustrate thought. For instance, you see the
        picture of war, fleeing in terror before the American flying
        machines. This picture will be a reality, if those in charge
        of American work can send ten thousand flying machines to
        France in time.
        The German soldiers will not sit in the trenches resigned
        because the people at home are safe, once American flying
        machines begin doing the work behind the trenches.
        The allies have not been able to go THROUGH the Hin
        denburg line. The United States will go ABOVE it with
        enough flying machines sailing over the trenches, trench war
        will end, and the whole war with it.
        The humorous genius TAD, with whose work you are so
        well acquainted, presents in his "Battle in the Senate" a
        picture even more valuable than ridiculous.
        It is a good thing for the United States that dis
        tinguished Senators fight occasionally. Much truth comes
        out in fighting. The grave statesmen are not physically as
        active as Tad shows them. But Tad's picture of their com
        bative bodies, represents fairly well their minds, when such
        men as La Follette, who thinks that wealth should arry the
        load, discusses taxation with the distinguished Mr. Simmons,
        who thinks that too big a tax on wealth might "make the
        war unpopular."</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1915-03-14/ed-1/seq-39/#words=aeroplane+AEROPLANE+AEROPLANES+aeroplanes+aviator+bomb+Bomb+BOMB+Bombs+bombs+flying+Flying+great+machine+machines+WAR+War+war</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>August, 1914: The First World War breaks out.</time>
      <text>OM.VILLE WRIGHT ON AEROPLANE IN EUROPE'S WAR
        INVENTOR THINKS
        ONE FLYING MA
        CHINE OUTVALUES
        SQUADRON OF
        SCOUTS.
        By EARL N. FINDLAY.
        THE most tremendous conflict In human
        history has reached a condition of
        stalemate because of the aeroplane,
        '.?verted by Wilbur snd Orville
        Wrigrit. at Dayton, Ohio.
        Man's eldest game, war. hss been checked
        by h^s '."'?vest.
        It was decided to try to interview Orville
        Wr.-'-t *t his home. A publisher recently of
        ..-- 1500 fcr 500 words on the stabilizer,
        but Mr. Wright did not accept. He has a most
        irrit?t:"??: trait wher? newspaper and magazine
        men are ^-?ncetned. To hirn it is more pleas?
        ant t.-1 experiment than to explain. One dollar
        a sot ! ?* ' not move him. Why. then, should
        he eonsenl to be interviewed, when all he could
        hope to get out of it was an interruption In his
        work?
        It ?a snother of those justly famous Wright
        my**''
        The originel Wright Mystery began in 1903,
        ?rid continued unabated on through to 1908,
        ifthough thrv were continuously flying. When
        ssked by their neighbors and by representa?
        tives 11 I -c;?n governments what they were
        doint in c d.iys they always told the truth.
        That is, they said they were flying?when con?
        ditions were favorable.
        That was the cue for Homeric laughter.
        THERE ARE QUIETER MEN, BUT, AS
        MARK TWAIN SAID. THEY ARE DEAD.
        If any one should ask Orville Wright if he
        enjoys being interviewed for publication he
        would ' ? tell the truth about it, just as
        he a- ther did in the early days about
        their flights. Hut no one is likely to ask him
        for the ti ilth?no one who has a job of inter
        ?, ?-.?. lo. It would be a poor interviewer
        who ? eed verbal confirmation.
        The v.: lei took out his pad and pencil once
        in Dayton. And then he put them back again.
        No one asked him to do this. Hope seemed
        to poinl ' at way.
        Asked for an expression of opinion as to the
        lyed in the war by the flying machine,
        Mr. Wright said:
        "If i had had aeroplanes and the
        cthe- Germany would have been in
        this. The country short on
        aerop!;?. c would have been in a nice mess.
        >n now fighting had been without
        nes when the war began she would not
        bel
        We were sitting in the office of the Wright
        company. Not far away was the Soldiers'
        Horre, lied with men who had known no
        stalematr because of motor-driven wings of
        gauze t tat carried scouts through the air at
        the rate r, I two miles a minute.
        WHEN .IKING ON AEROPLANES
        OME'S AIM IS OF NO CONSEQUENCE.
        Mr. Wright was asked what he thought of
        the t that the only fire effective against
        an aeroplane is that of a regiment of infantry,
        in wl there is a very large percentage of
        poor shore, the lesultant wide dispersion in
        creas.-ii* the probability of the aeroplane's be?
        ing hit in a vital spot, despite the usual error
        in estimating range. This theory has been ad?
        vanced in a recent book.
        "The time will come when they will learn
        to shoot at aeroplanes," he replied. "During
        the Ci**i1 War we would have thought it im?
        possible e.er to shoot at something we could
        not see. Now we have the range, and don't
        need daylight."
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1914-10-04/ed-1/seq-35/#words=Bleriot</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>August, 1914: The First World War breaks out.</time>
      <text>r1
        A PISTOL FIGHT BETWEEN A BRITISH BRISTOL BIPLANE AND A GERMAN TAUBE MONOPLANE
        Sergeant Werner, the first German to fly over Paris, had located the allied forces, and he had turned his monoplane to go back, when he saw a
        . . i . t t mi nt.f . . n J .It !. r . 1 . . - . I t. A ! n I CLt n 1 1 .1
        thousand icei or so aoove a urisioi oipiane pursuing, ine uriusn aeroplane new uown unui n was sua icci uuvc utnmn. n jjidiui ub" nti i t -A
        French Blerlot then joined in the attack. Presently German troops appeared below and fired at the Bleriot and the Bristol, whereupon they flew h H
        Copyrighted by The Sun Printing and Publishing Association by special arrangement with the JUusinUd London Newi.
        PICTORIAL
        MAGAZINE</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1913-04-29/ed-1/seq-20/#words=Birdmen</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>August, 1914: The First World War breaks out.</time>
      <text>France is by far the leader in air
        ship fleets. She has 838 aeroplanes
        which may be used during a war.
        Great Britain comes next with 244,
        and Germany is a clbse third, with
        214. Italy, with 175, is way ahead of
        the United States, the birthplace of
        PROVERBIAL
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96076839/1912-10-19/ed-1/seq-6/#words=aeroplane+aeroplanes+air+event+fly+Flying+flying+machine+Machines+machines+planes+stunt</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>lujuadron. Or, In other words, a squadron will
        consist of eight aeroplanes in charge of sixteen
        aviators, all of whom will be captains or lieu
        tenants of the regular army.
        "1-ach squadron will b in command of a ma
        "jor, who will have two commissioned officers on
        his staff In addition to tho aviators assigned to
        :no niaenmes. no win also nave uuuer nun a
        force of 48 aeroplane mechanicians, all enlisted
        oh" n, giving five to each machine, and an extra
        one for each company.
        'To ono field army of regular troops there
        will be three aviation squadrons, one asigned
        to each of the two divisions and one to the
        1h aeViuartcia of the'Ikld commander. The squad
        ron assigned to headpnrtprs will be equipped
        with aeroplanes of extra motor power for long
        distance reconnaissance. The field artillery will
        have special' machines and in addition there will
        be CI machines and 1T.2 aviators distributed
        among 11 of our coast defense stations.
        "Then the Philippines should have two squad
        rons, or sixteen Machines, and Panama and Ha
        v.nli should each havo ono squadron. This sky
        army will bo headed by two colonels under tho
        command of the chief cf the signal corps, two
        Jieutenant-colcncls and eleven majors.
        The aviation equipment should not stop with
        the regular army, but the militia must also bo
        provided with machines distributed among Its
        mobile troops at the rate of one squadron for
        ach division of men. The militia birdmen must
        .receive their diplomas from tho regular army
        Aviation schools, to be established throughout
        'the country.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1911-11-11/ed-1/seq-7/#words=aeroplane+AEROPLANE+aeroplanes+air+event+events+fly+FLYING+flying+machine+Machine+machines+MACHINES+plane+stunt</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>February 17, 1911: Curtiss successfully stops at U.S. cruiser with air boat.</time>
      <text>Mall carry inn; by aeroplanes uu a
        largo scale will be tin tcrtcken at At?
        lanta-, tin., on November to, 17 and lb.
        On those days Aylators Lincoln Beachy,
        C. C. Wltmer and Charles Andrews, ull
        Hying outside ol Atlanta, wfll take,
        mall to a point near the Atlanta, post
        office, whero It will be turned over to
        tho post-office employes. This experi?
        ment will be undertaken In connection
        with the convention of the Gcorgtu
        Postmasters, who will attend the meet
        In a body and witness the operation of
        the aerial mall service. It Is planned
        to carry somo 76,000 pieces of first
        class mall matter, eaoh ploce bearing
        a special stomp, showing that U has
        bean carried by aeroplano from the
        point of mailing to the Atlanta post'
        office.
        In order to make a test o( this ser?
        vice on a largo scale, Postmaater-Gen
        erai Hitchcock has Instructed the At?
        lanta postmaster to co-operate- with the
        Curtifs people, collecting tho mull from
        the boxes on the aviation lie id, putting
        it in bags and turning the bags over
        to the aviators, who will make or?e or
        more trips dally, according to the vol?
        ume of mall matter to be carried.
        General James Allen, Major George
        O. Squler and other Signal Corps offi?
        cers, are greatly interested in what
        the aeroplane Is accomplishing in the
        present war between Italy and Tur
        ! key.
        While France. Germany and England
        j have more aviators In the command
        of their armies than has tho United
        ?States, still it Is confidently believed
        j that In case of a struggle with these
        ! nations the aeroplanes of tho United
        : States Army and Navy would com?
        pletely outrank those of the foreign
        1 countries. This point of the discus?
        sion is taken because of tho splendid
        work of the army aviators In tho gov?
        ernment service. On a number of oc?
        casions the army and navy filers have,
        secured leave of absence and com?
        peted In aviation meets, where thn
        pick of the niera from foreign coun?
        tries wore contenting. The army and
        navy aviators havo come out victo?
        rious in the majority of events, clearlv
        demonstrating the fact that the United
        States has tho best and most reliable
        filers In the business to-day.
        Signal Corps officers also aro Inter
        I estcd In the report that the Turkish
        government has offered Gustavo Ha?
        ntel, the well-known English aviator,
        160,000 for his services In the war
        with Italy. At the samo tlmo tho
        officials here are puzzled to know how
        Turkey can use explosives from the air,
        when that country was one which sign?
        ed an agreement at the last peace
        congress not to use explosives from
        bolloons or other air craft until after
        the next peace conference.
        Italy did not sign that agreement,
        and by the aid of two aeroplanes her
        army has been able to stem tho tide,
        which seemed for a while as though
        It were going to turn in favor of the
        Turks. Thousands of Arabs and Turks
        have been killed by the dropping of
        explosives from Italian aeroplanes,
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025316/1911-08-27/ed-1/seq-11/#words=aeroplane+aeroplanes+aeroplaning+aviation+aviators+bomb+flying+great+GREAT+International+machines+WAR+war</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>February 17, 1911: Curtiss successfully stops at U.S. cruiser with air boat.</time>
      <text>st nothing--and
        so, naturally, when It suddenly became
        apparent that the aeroplane was to
        be the accepted type of craft for sky
        oaouting and attack they were In a
        position to qulckly shift their activities
        to this new branch of the field.
        However, in so far as Uncle amrn's
        place in the racer for aeronautle pres
        tige s concerned the situation bids fair
        to present a repetition of the history
        of the development of the submarine
        boat as an engine of warfare. It will
        be remembered that when, after cen
        turies of impracticable attempts, an
        American, John P. Holland, blazed the
        path to the modern dependable under
        water cruiser a number of European
        nations, notably France and E0ngland,
        grew excited over the subject and in
        augurated acitlvities in the field that
        bade fair to cast the United Stator.
        completely In the shadow. However,
        our inventors and naval officers-for.
        titled by the priceless heritage of Yan
        kee Ingenuity-kept pegging away and
        In consequence It has gradually come
        about that the United States has a
        England's Strike Troubles
        One of the eoeap liners tied up at an English port. The Right Honorable Dpvid Lloyd.George, leader in the
        movement for better laboring conditions for the maeso, and the man generally credited for having brought on
        the pre,.ni tiZ7i ii miore than any other individual, "Below, English troops who encamped in the streets of
        mony British prts.....
        submarine fleet that Individually and
        collectively lays it all over anything hbi
        yond the Atlantic. And at~rewd oh
        servers of the American aIy of do
        ing things-particularticully things that ne
        cessitate the exercise of nimble wits
        are not slow to predict that It will be
        the same story all over again in thr
        ultimate realization of the full pnssl
        bllltles of the military flying machines
        Uncle Sam's present activity In as
        sembling'and preparing for war service
        an up-ta-date aerial fleet is the direct
        result of the congrc-sslonal approplri
        ation of $125,000 for this new under
        taking. The national leaislature wae
        a trifle tardy in voting this initial al
        lowance, but there is reason to be
        Ileve that now that a beginning has
        been made there will be yearly addi
        tions to the flock of mechanical birds
        of war Just as there are annual ad
        ditions to 'our naval fleet. Gleneral
        James Allen, chilf signal officer of the
        United States army--mlltary aerorllu
        ties come under the jurisdiction of the
        signal corps-has predicted that with
        in a year or tao our war depatrtment
        will have a fleet of 20 aerial cruisers
        manned by not less than 40 officers
        specially trained in this exacting
        science. If this prediction comes true,
        Uncle Sam Will have recovered, at one
        bound as It were, his lead among the
        nations.
        Just at present the most interesting
        phase of this latest activity in behn't
        of military preparedness is found in
        the training of the military aviators.
        .'y he sure, the acquilsition. from time
        to time, of new flying machines is of
        interest also, for mlost every fresh ad
        dition to the fleet embodies some in
        novations or improvements that did
        not appear in any of the predecessorb
        of the type. At the same time all
        the characterisntes of the standard
        types of cloud-climbers have been so
        fully exploited In the press that they
        do not arouse quite the same curiosity
        that they did when they were more of
        a novelty. And just here It should he
        added that Uncle Sam in making up
        his aerial fleet is confining himself to
        the products of the American inventors
        of aeroplanes. This is not due to any
        billy., unreasoning patriotism, either
        for Uncle Sam is always out for the
        best-but to a sincere conviction,
        clinched by tests, that our home
        products are very much the best in the
        aeroplane line. The Wright and. Cur
        tiss models have the preference and
        are likely to continue to 'have, but th,:</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016413/1911-03-11/ed-1/seq-11/#words=AEROPLANE+Aeroplane+aeroplane+Aeroplanes+aeroplanes+aeroplaning+aviation+Aviation+AVIATOR+aviator+aviators+AVIATORS+bombs+flying+machines+STUNT+War+war</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>No timeline found</time>
      <text>w York, March 1 1. Clifford R.
        Harmon, the celebrated aviator, has
        completed his plans for al tempting
        the hazardous venture of flying in an
        aeroplane from Colon across the isth
        mus of Panama from ocean to
        ocean. He started from New York
        today on the steamship Moltke with
        nil his apparatus and assistants. His
        report will have important influence
        in determining tins attitude of con
        DOES BIG STUNT
        Carries Message When Im
        possible For Others to
        Cover the Ground.
        The War Department was kept, busy
        early in February declining all sorts
        of offers from aviators. It seems as if
        every man in tins country who either
        owns an aeroplane, or expects to do
        so, during the past few days has of
        fered to patrol the Mexican border for
        the War Department. If the services
        of every aviator who volunteered had
        been accepted the heavens along the
        Mexican border would soon be tilled
        with ncroplatii! or the ground in that
        vicinity strewn with the wrecks of
        flying machines. Very wisely the War
        Department decided to put this matter
        entirely under the supervision of Lieu
        tenant i.xF. Foulois, who Is at San
        A 1 1 1 1 . 1 1 i i with the only aeroplane own
        ed by the government. It is under
        stood 'that the State Department, as
        well as the War Department, feared
        that a large force of civilian aviators
        on the border might involve this gov
        ernment in International complications
        with Mexico.
        Unless the aviators were under the
        command of Lieutenant Foulois they
        would bo very apt to fly ovit Into
        .Mexico. There they might lie captur
        ed n spies, and it would be very dif
        ficult for tins government to extend to
        them the protection which Is nsked by
        every American citizen who gets into
        trouble in a foreign land. It Is fear
        ed by the olllcers of the War Depart
        ment that some of the amateur avia
        tors may become so enthusiastic that
        It. will be necessary to take steps to
        restrain them.
        Rut, despite all this confusion, nil
        vices were received at the War De
        partment 'if n lllglit which was made
        by Harry S. Darkness which Is re
        garded as a demonstration of the
        availability of Aeroplanes for war pur
        poses, (in Wednesday, February 8.
        I!l-i,r,,,ii,.,. I I A,. ..l,i,,r t,l,',l.,l
        '" '" (
        ottli er, received' u telegram from . ('.
        Collier, president of the Aero club,
        announcing Hint Mr. Ilarkness hud
        AVIATO
        PANAMA I
        MP ll . . . -nliiWl -w
        1 ; p GUIDE AVIATORS 4 CM , Vf
        ! m , i 5l prVKOHlGVELLCXltm RQZfyL
        U 1 SAFE LANDING tfWnOMS LOCKS" r
        3 ! v PLACES a 'BALBOA ots
        ' frV " 'V SiW'A,! ' "
        ARMY AVIATOR
        AND ROUTE ACROSS ISTHMUS OF
        WILL ATTEMPT TO TAKE IN AEROPLANE
        gress toward fortifying Hie Panama
        Canal, as his course takes him over
        the big ditch. Experts say aviators
        could destroy any fortillculions erect
        ed at the canal by means of dropping
        bombs from the sky. The topography
        of the hind over which Harmon will
        fly is such as ' to produce cross cur
        rents, and eddies in the lower air!
        strata, these currents parallelling the!
        configuration of the land and being'
        atmospheric disturbers for at leasti
        151! feet above t lie earth. Therefore. I
        In order to gain the more constant!
        air the aviator should attain a height,
        of from 4"i0 to 550 feet as soon as
        practicable after the launching, an al-j
        tit udo greater than would be neces
        sary under normal conditions in the
        I'liiteil Stales: liv Iho time Hie nav-1
        flown from the aviation camp on North
        Island, opposite Fort Itoseeruns, to the
        I'nitcd States troops on the Mexican
        border, near Tia Juami, a distance of
        forty-five miles, remaining In the nlr
        fifty-six minutes. The aviator deliv
        ered a message from Major McManus
        to Lieutenant Ruhlen in twenty-live
        minutes, covering an almost impassa
        ble road of twenty-one miles. Such
        feats as this are regarded by the sig
        nal ollicer as the most Important use
        to which aeroplanes can be placed. If
        the science of flying can be developed
        to. a point of prolicleney at which mes
        sages can be sent from one body of
        troops to another in such a short time
        under all conditions, aeroplanes will
        prove desirable In actual warfare.
        While the popular attention was cen
        tered upon the possible weight of
        aeroplanes, the Signal Corps was doing
        real effective work along the Mexican
        border. AYithin three days after the
        army had been ordered to the border.
        three companies of the Signal Corps,
        A, F and 1. had all the troops In the
        Held in communication through wire
        less telegraphy and temporarily con
        structed telegraph lines.</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1910-10-30/ed-1/seq-31/#words=aeroplane+aeroplanes+aeroplaning+aviation+bomb+bombs+Bombs+flying+great+machine+war+wars</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>July 15, 1910: Glenn Curtiss preforms stunt practicing dropping “bombs”.</time>
      <text>aking into consideration the comparatively brief
        time that has elapsed since the first heavier than air
        machine flew, and the marvelous strides aviation has
        made in that brief period, particularly within the last
        twelve months, we feel sure that whatever obstacles may
        remain in the way of the reduction of aviation to the
        safe and practical will soon be overcome, and that aeroplanes
        will be so perfected that aeroplaning will become
        as safe as automobiling.
        Need after need to secure automatic equilibration
        and stability of the flying machine in its unstable path
        is being discovered and met by men of the genius and
        cool-headed daring of the Wrights, Curtiss, Harmon,
        Hamilton, Paulhan, Farman, B16riot.
        Two things are evident,?that mechanical flight will
        be made safe and practical, and that the personnel of
        the sterling qualities necessary for reduction to practical
        utility is available.
        What, then, are the prospective uses of aviation?
        The paramount immediate use in times of peace is
        sport; but soon, even in times of peace, commuters will
        travel back and forth from suburban homes to large
        centers of population by aeroplane. The time that can
        be saved, and the sport coupled with business in such
        travel, will recommend its wide adoption.
        Cleared alighting areas or wide cleared avenues will
        radiate from large cities in all directions, over which
        aeroplanes may pass back and forth, with always a
        place for safe landing underneath, should anything go
        wrong.
        Since man first swung a club in combat, warfare has
        commandeered every invention it could utilize, and
        often a little lead of one people or tribe over another in
        some implement of war has meant victory for its possessor.
        Therefore, we naturally inquire of Mars what
        uses he holds in prospect for the flying machine.
        We have recently had demonstrations of the ability
        of the aeroplane to drop bombs on warships, coast fortifications,
        and cities, and we have also had our sham
        battles. A couple of aeroplanes from each of two French
        army corps meet and fight a mock duel over Paris.
        Little Danger from Bombs</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86081854/1910-07-15/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Air+AIR+air+aviation+AVIATOR+aviator+Aviator+aviators+exhibitions+FLIER+flying+machine+MACHINE+meet+meeting+meetings+stunt+stunts+Stunts</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>July 15, 1910: Glenn Curtiss preforms stunt practicing dropping “bombs”.</time>
      <text>Oaring Aviator Fell 100 Feet When
        Tailpiece Broke and Was Dashed to
        Death In Presence of Big Crowd.
        Hon. Charles Stewart Rolls, third
        son of Lord Llangattock, and noted for
        I his recent double flight across the
        English channel, was killed at Bourne
        mouth, England, at the aviation meet,
        In which Armstrong Drexel so distin
        guished himself several days ago.
        The tragedy occurred in the pres
        ence of n great company of specta
        tors, a majority of whom were women
        and children, and many of the per
        sonal friends of the young aviator.
        The Wright biplane on which he was
        flying fell suddenly with terrific speed
        from a height of 100 feet. It struck
        the ground close to the crowded grand
        I stand, smashed Into a tangled mass,
        ! and before the doctors and their as
        ! sistants could reach the spot Rolls was
        dead.
        The event in which Rolls was com
        peting was for a prize for the aviator
        alighting nearest a given mark. The
        goal was directly in front of the grand
        1 stand, where the spectators were
        massed. He had risen to a good height
        and then shut off his motor and was
        gliding in a broad circle toward the
        ! mark.
        Without warning the tail piece of
        the biplane snapped off. The machine
        gave a sudden lurch, and the frame
        work crumpled up in the air. When It
        struck the ground it was smashed to
        splinters. The doctors found that
        Rolls had sustained a fractured skull.
        The wreck of the machine and twisted
        stays surrounded the body so that
        there was difficulty in extricating the
        unfortunate man.
        Lord and Lady Llangattock. the par
        ents of Rolls, narrowly escaped wit
        nessing the catastrophe. They were
        yachting along the coast, and put In at
        Poole, near Bournemouth, intending to
        j attend the aviation meeting, but post
        i poned going until after noon.
        1 Audemars, the Swiss aviator, had a
        ; close shave while making a trial
        flight. His monoplane overturned and
        descended swiftly to the ground, but
        he escaped without Injury.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042242/1908-09-10/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Aeroplane+flying+machines+Stunts</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <time>September 9, 1908: Orville Wright preforms official trial in front of army board August,</time>
      <text>Two flights of approimately one
        hour each, and another flight in which
        two men were whirled through the
        air for upwards of si minutes -were
        the achievements of the Wright bro­
        thers aeroplane today. That these
        flights, record breaking as they were,
        %ill even be surpassed by Orvjlle
        Wright during his,trials at Fort .Mteyer
        Is confidently predicted.
        vf •'...""' ^!'UV-V'
        BISMARCK, NORTH DAKOTA, THURSDAY MORNING, SEPTEMBER, 10 190&amp;
        I's Aeroplane Bid |p
        'kable Stunts
        Air Traveler
        Two Trips of Over an
        Hour Each In Fast
        Time
        On Third Trip Took a Pas­
        senger Along and
        Flew High
        Washington, D. C., Sep. 9.—Orvllle
        Wright, in three phenomlnal flights
        at Fort Mayer today, established a
        new aeroplane record, that not only
        assures the success of the official
        trial before the army board, but in­
        dicates that real flight is now only a~
        matter of development
        War on land and sea will find in
        the aeroplane, it is now conceded by
        military men, a valuable means of
        reconnaisance and possibly carnage.
        In the first flight the maclhne cir­
        cled the drill grounds 57 times In 55
        minutes and 31 seconds. This was
        surpassed this evening when a flight
        of 62 minutes and 15 seconds was
        made.
        Not satisfied with breaking all the
        distance and time records for heavier
        than air flying machines, Mr. Wright
        took L/t. Frank P. Lahm, an aero­
        naut of the signal corps, for a spin
        around the drill grounds, and making
        a new record for a two-man flight
        All this happened so quickly and un
        ostensiously that the spectators,
        among whom were members of the
        cabinet, high officers of the army
        and navy, could hardly realize that
        history had been made and that a
        new era in the progress of the civi­
        lized world was begun.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://blogs.loc.gov/inside_adams/2010/11/world-war-ii-scientific-manpower/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/afc1945001_ms10138/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/21005304/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/gdclccn.14017171/?sp=2&amp;st=text</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83030193/1914-08-12/ed-1/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
  </results>
</topic></topics>