<topic>
    <id>
    https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-yoga
    </id>
    <results>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1904-12-18/ed-1/seq-30/#words=Vedanta+Vivekananda+yogis+Swami+yogi+yoga+Yoga
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            How to Practice Yoga Bright sunshine pours into the room in which Mr. Dulin practices yoga himself. Windows on three sides and a skylight help to make the room cheerful, which he says adds greatly to the effect. In one corner is a small skeleton chair which he calls his yoga chair. It is straight-backed and would prove anything but comfortable for library use, but there is little chance of anyone letting his attention wander so far afield while sitting in it that he would fall asleep, in any sense of the term. For this reason, the chair is all the more valuable for the practice of yoga. Seated on this chair or standing, the practitioner goes through thirty minutes of concentrated mental and muscular exercises every morning and afternoon. These exercises consist largely of assuming more or less strained postures and in regulating the breath. Standing straight as a soldier on parade, Mr. Dulin illustrated the exercises. 
            Placing one hand over his right nostril, he drew in slowly a deep breath through his left nostril, rising on his toes as he did so. When he had filled his whole lungs, he closed the left nostril too and still on tiptoe held his breath for about thirty seconds. Then, opening his right nostril, he exhaled slowly. This exercise is repeated seven times, and then the breath is drawn in through the right nostril and exhaled through the left. Another exercise consists of rising on the toes and at the same time placing the outstretched arms above the head with hands clasped and also drawing a deep breath, which is held for a number of seconds. Still other breathing exercises are taken while sitting on the yoga chair. Breathing Affects Mental Activity."I drive each breath into every part of my body or into such part as my will designates," said Mr. Dulin. "My attention is concentrated directly upon what I am doing. The motion 
            of the lungs has a very intimate relation to the activity of the mind. If we control the motion of the lungs, the activity of the mind comes more easily under control. Conversely, if we control the activity of the mind, we can also control the motion of the lungs. When the motion of the lungs is brought under perfect control, every organ of the body is brought under the control of the spirit. Have you ever noticed that at the time of perfect concentration of mind the rhythm of respiration changes and gradually becomes slower and slower; perhaps it will almost cease for the time being. It has been said by a clever and experienced thinker, Dr. Lewes, that to acquire the power of attention is to learn to make our mental adjustments alternate with the rhythmic movements of respiration. How intimately breathing is connected with life is apparent to anyone who stops to think of the so-called phenomena of living. As soon as 
            breath ceases, the very body itself disintegrates. When supreme control over attention is acquired by voluntary effort, it is possible to fix one's attention on any part of the body and experience strange sensations and wonderful phenomena. It is a well-known fact that one can easily experience pain in any part of the body by merely fixing the attention upon that part. By an analogous process, one can get rid of pain in the body. Mental healers, many of whom surround their practices with all manner of mysticism, are familiar with such phenomena, although they fail to understand the true inwardness of their cures. One can cure disease by fixing attention on the diseased part and sending an opposite current of thought. This method has become a common practice with Christian Science healers, and other mental healers under a variety of names. But one thing should be remembered in this connection. It is that each individual
            is born with this kind of healing power himself or herself. No one can give you that power. It is one of the natural powers of the human mind. It is far better to heal yourself than to go to some other person for a cure, which, at best, is only temporary. Do not let your mind be controlled by any other mind. Men and women who go to mental healers or Christian Scientists for help and who allow themselves to be influenced by the minds of others, do not realize that, by allowing themselves to fall under the hypnotic power of stronger minds, they are walking in a path which leads to mental degeneration. Many cases have been known where minds have degenerated into the slaves of other minds, losing all power of self-control. How pitiable is the mental condition of these self-deluded ones. "Because a yogi comprehends this danger he never allows himself to be influenced by the minds of others. And for the same reason he is careful 
            about attempting a cure of his fellow-beings. While through perfect concentration it is possible to cure an ill person other than himself the yogi rarely attempts this, knowing the danger to which he is submitting his patient. Vedanta teaches the power which is latent in every human being for self-cure. We do, however, at times, and have done so in extreme cases such as fever. I could reduce a high fever by means of the power of concentration."But if yoga is rightly practiced it should prove a preventive rather than a cure for disease. Anyone who is practicing yoga daily should be in perfect health. It gives immunity from disease. Since I have practiced yoga I have never been ill for a moment. It hardens the physical body to such an extent that it can combat with ease the so-called germs of disease. What are germs? Anyway but the creation of the human mind? The invention of a human mind would be willing to eat all the 
            bacteria you bring me and feel no evil effect.""If that is the case and the whole human race should take up the practice of yoga the average age of man would be greatly advanced, would it not?" Mr. Dulin was asked."Undoubtedly," replied he. "The effect of yoga upon longevity is marked. Man should live to be 125 years old." Mr. Dulin has picked the age which the Russian scientist, Metchnikoff, selected for the average length of life of man. According to the Russian, however, man can attain this great age by living largely on buttermilk and a wonderful bacillus discovered by himself. Four Divisions of Yoga. There are four grand divisions of yoga, and each division is suited to a different tendency of mind. The first division of yoga is called Karma Yoga. It is for the active man, for those who like to work, the busy everyday workers in mankind. It is largely the science of physical culture. By this means the true science 
            of physical culture is reached. depends upon the concentration of the mind upon work in hand as well as the mere going through with certain exercises. Karma Yoga teaches the secret of work, and shows how to turn the daily tasks into acts of worship. Thus man may reach perfection of life through work and work alone. Bhakti Yoga is the name given to the second division. It is for such as are of an emotional nature. It teaches how ordinary emotions may bring forth a spiritual unfoldment of the highest kind and lead to the ultimate ideal of all religions. It explains the nature of divine love. The third division is Raja Yoga, which has to do with the whole realm of psychic phenomena. By its psychic powers are developed such as have astonished the world since the beginning of history, and which have been termed miracles by the uninitiated. This division includes the evolving of the fine perceptions, the projection out of the 
            body of the power of life, the curing of disease, and all the physical powers displayed by Jesus, and are in use by the Christian Scientists today. These phenomena have been known and understood by the yogis of India since ancient times. While Raja Yoga teaches all these psychic powers, it does not fail to warn its students that they are not the end of wisdom nor a sign of spirituality. "Little brains and weak intellects easily turn away from the path of spiritual truth when some psychic power begins to manifest itself," said Mr. Dulin. "They think they have reached the highest state of spirituality because they have the power of curing a headache." Jnana Yoga is the fourth division or method. It is for the intellectual discriminative and philosophical man. Value of Yoga in Business. "Of what tremendous value Yoga proves to business men can readily be understood aside from its spiritual value," continued Mr. Dulin. 
            "In these days of competition it is the man who can concentrate upon his work and perform it, shutting out all other interests, who goes to the front most rapidly. The practice of Yoga demands concentration and Concentration before everything. The habit of concentration grows greater as the practice of yoga continues. For example, I can today accomplish in a few hours what would have a few years ago required several days of hard work. Vedanta explains the true basis of ethics. Why should we be moral? Not because it is written in a certain chapter of a certain Scripture, but because of the spiritual oneness of the universe. When you realize that you are part and parcel of the whole creation, you know that if you injure others, you injure yourself, and no one gains anything to himself under such a belief. Vedanta believes that for the time being, at least, this is for his good. No criminal commits a crime without thinking 
            that he is to benefit thereby. Vedanta shows that because of this same spiritual oneness, we should love our neighbors as ourselves since in spirit we are already one. "Thirst for enjoyment is the real disease in us. Its various symptoms are passions, ambition, pride, jealousy, hatred, anger, and all the rest. Tremendous mental exertion of will power is often necessary to control the restless mind from taking the forms of waves of passion and anger. Perfect self-control of a yogi is that state of mind in which no desires or passions of any kind disturb the peace and tranquility of his soul. Such a state of mind can be acquired more easily by removing the bubbles of desires before they take the form of passion; that is, by attacking them while they are in their incipiency. By concentration and meditation upon the supreme truths, the desires may be brought under complete control."
            Vedanta teaches that the soul never dies, that the soul of each individual man is part of the divine power usually termed God. It teaches also that the soul of man will return to this earth in various incarnations, which represent the different stages of advance toward that perfection of being which is the true goal. Mr. Dulin said that the practice of yoga is materially aided by a vegetarian diet.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1908-05-17/ed-1/seq-37/#words=yoga+Yoga+YOGA+Yogi+Yogis
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            MYSTERIOUS YOGA FAITH OF EAST INDIA WHICH HAS ROBBED AN AMERICAN CITIZEN OF A DEVOTED WIFE A Weird Religion. It is a weird religion, that of the Yogi, known in its generic form, but, in its many mysterious ramifications, regarded in awesome ignorance. That these fakirs do perform some wonders that not seem altogether inexplicable less, is attested by numerous reputable witnesses. But the power behind all this is still a mystery, clothed in the limitless shroud of occultism that only the East Indian can employ. To the Caucasian, the self-abnegation required to arrive at the perfect point that the Yogi assumes seems an impossibility of attainment. The marvelous concentration of will, it is said, makes the human brain capable of accomplishments. Yet the Yogi claims that they have gained mastery over this indomitable will forever, and, in this mastery, lies the power which enables them to govern natural laws, even to the 
            intangible law of gravitation. This power, which is in constant play, gives them control over the force of creation, the beginning of all being, and indeed, is a part of this faith. They believe that when man has gained his first purified form, and cast aside all grossness, he will return again to his original state. Belief of the Yogi The circle of existence runs unending and upon it rests the truth of all material and spiritual life. It is believed, therefore, that when their self-imposed trials of abnegation are performed stoically, they have gained their end, and are united in all respects to the Supreme Being, whom they worship. The main object of the Yogi is to establish a doctrine of a Supreme Being, and to teach the means by which the human soul may become permanently united with it. This Supreme Being is the reputed founder of the system, defined as a particular spirit who is untouched by affections, works the
            result of whose desires, in whom the germ of omnipotence reaches its supreme limit, and who is the preceptor of even the first because he is not limited by time. His appellation is Om. To attain the consciousness which leads to union of the soul with the Supreme Being, eight stages are taught. These are: moral and religious rectification, posture regulation of the breath, restraint, fixation, and profound contemplation. Self-Control and Religion. The first stage, self-control, consists in not doing injury to living beings, veracity, avoidance of theft, chastity, and non-acceptance of gifts. The second stage, religious observance, comprises external, as well as internal purity, contentment, austerity, muttering of the Vedic hymns, and devoted reliance on the Supreme Being. The third stage of Yoga, postures of various sorts, is regarded as essential to those following. The fourth stage, regulation of the breath, is three-fold,
            according as it concerns exhalation and inhalation, or becomes tantamount to the suspension of the breath. The fifth stage, the strength of the senses, means the diversion or withdrawal of the senses from their respective objects, and their entire accommodation to the nature of the mind. This stage is preparatory to the sixth, or the steadying of the mind, which means the freeing of the mind from any sensual disturbance by fixing the thoughts upon some part of the body, usually the tip of the nose. Meditation and Contemplation. Meditation, the seventh stage, is the fixing of the mind on the one object of knowledge, the Supreme Being, to the exclusion of all other thoughts. The eighth, or last stage, profound contemplation, is the perfect absorption of thought into the object, the Supreme Being; it is devoid of all thoughts and meditations. In such a state, a Yogi is insensible to heat and cold, to pleasure and pain; he has
            the same prosperity and adversity; he amends in ascetic reduction. The last three stages are generalized again, because upon their perfection depend the wonderful results which are promised to those who apply them to the extreme. Such results are, for example, the knowledge of the past and future, the knowledge of the sounds of all creatures, the knowledge of what has happened in one's former births, of the thoughts of others, and the length of the human frame; the power of levitation, the overcoming of hunger and thirst, death at will, and the creation of all that exists in the different worlds; and an analysis of the structure of one's own body. Their Eight Great Powers. There are eight great powers which a Yogi will accomplish when properly regulating his knowledge—the power of shrinking into the form of the minutest atom, of becoming extremely light, of becoming extremely heavy, of unlimited reach of the organs, of 
            irresistible will, of obtaining perfect dominion over everything, of changing the course of nature, and, lastly, of going anywhere at will. If the Yogi apply his knowledge to the contemplation of the smallest division of time and the successive order in which such divisions occur, he makes a discrimination which enables him to understand the subtle elements and to pass into the infinite. When his intellect has become free from passion he knows neither friend nor enemy, and no longer is subject to the result of acts performed, and when both have thus obtained the same degree of purity, the Yogi obtains eternal liberation. This is the religion that Mrs. Stead has adopted. But enough of technicalities. In practical demonstrations the Yogis have made their faith stand the world’s amazement. And their demonstrations are of remarkable puzzles and marvels. The existence of God, as realized by them, is a matter of absolute 
            demonstration—the forbidden fruit of the perfect man, and an element of life itself, as is oft witnessed frequently by foreigners. Yogi named Govinda-Swami, on the terrace of his own house. Being by no means credulous, Jacolliot took every precaution to prevent deception. Fine sand was strewn on the ground in order to make as even a surface as possible. The justice was asked to seat himself at a table, upon which was a pencil and paper. The fakir carefully laid a piece of wood upon the sand, and announced that whatever figures Jacolliot might draw on the paper would be transcribed precisely upon the sand by the piece of wood. The Yogi stretched out his hand, and the wooden piece immediately copied upon the sand the most complicated and twisted figures that Jacolliot drew. When the Frenchman stopped writing, the piece of wood also came to a standstill. Read Words in His Mind. The fakir stood at a distance against a 
            wall, while the justice held the paper and pencil in such a way that the Indian could not possibly see what he was writing. Finally, the Indian asked Jacolliot to think of some words in Sanskrit, whereupon the piece of wood instantly traced n the sand the very words that were in the justice's mind. The fakir next stretched out his hand toward a huge bronze vase, filled with water, and weighing several hundred pounds. In five minutes the vase began to move, approaching the fakir with a slow, regular motion. When the distance between the vase and the paper had been considerably diminished, the vase began to emit loud, metallic sounds, as if struck with an iron rod. Occasionally, the noise would resemble the roar of a fire. At Jacolliot's request, the fakir made the vase stop, move, and stop again. Then, Jacolliot demanded that the metal tones should sound again at the end of ten seconds, and the phenomenon was repeated 
            at the exact moment, which he noted by his own watch. He asked that the sounds should keep time to the tune of a music box, which he wound up for the purpose. This requirement, too, was fulfilled. Buried For Three Months. Other demonstrations of the Yoga, even more startling and seemingly more impossible, have been recorded. Sir Claude Wade, in company with several English army officers, witnessed a demonstration at Lahore, India, that even more fully demonstrated the power of the fakir to suspend life in his own body. This fakir was buried quite naturally in a grave dug for the purpose, and the earth was piled in upon him. Sir Claude took every precaution against the body being disturbed, keeping a guard about the grave constantly. At the expiration of three months, the time specified for the end of the demonstration, he superintended the disinterment of the man, who, when the earth had been removed, walked from the 
            grave alive and well. During the interim, he had been hermetically sealed, and had had nothing to eat or drink, thus proving beyond the question of a doubt, his ability to suspend breathing and animation at will. Other Demonstrations. Other familiar demonstrations of the Yogi are the throwing of a rope into the air, the demonstrator climbing up to an invisible height, finally vanishing completely; the appearance and disappearance of the operator at will before his audience; the ability to withstand the application of hot irons and sword thrusts with seeming indifference, and the control that enables him to pose for hours at a time in an apparently cramped condition without the movement of a muscle.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1908-12-06/ed-1/seq-18/#words=yoga+Yoga+Swami+Vedanta+VIVEKANANDA+VEDANTA+SWAMI+swami+Vedantic
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            The larger part of the mental energy of the majority of people in this country is needlessly wasted by the constant rush of their daily lives, which is merely the result of a lack of self-control. The secret revealed by Karma Yoga teaches how to avoid this waste and also the nervous disorders which are the outcome. "Then comes Bhakti Yoga. I find not only your women but also the men, the business and professional men, much in need of this teaching. It is for those of an emotional nature. It is the path of devotion and love. It teaches how to fulfill the purpose of life both here and in the hereafter. "The third is Raja Yoga, the path of concentration and meditation. This field covers the whole psychic plane and describes the processes by which the psychic powers are developed, such as thought reading, clairvoyance, clairaudience, the evolving of finer perceptions, the going out of the body, the curing of disease 
            through mental power. Everything taught in such kindred treatments as mental healing, Christian Science, the Emmanuel movement has been taught as one element of a great whole for generation after generation by the believers and followers of the Vedanta. "Displayed by Jesus of Nazareth and which are used today by the so-called new sects have been an open book for years to the Yogis or wise men of India. Christian Science, the new Emmanuel, can give us nothing new. But we do not overemphasize peculiar cult; we do not believe in the constant obsession of the mind by the thought of disease, even though the healing of the disease is the ultimate reason for that obsession. "It is in Raja Yoga that the wonderful system of breathing is taught, whose effects are not unknown to the mental healers of the West, but it does not cease to warn its students that the attainment of any of these powers is not a sign of spirituality.
            "Jnana Yoga is the fourth method. It is the path of right knowledge and discrimination. It is for those who are of a philosophic nature. It explains the fundamental principles of spiritualism, tells us how the soul exists after death and under what conditions, describes how the earthbound are reincarnated, taking human form again and again. It expounded the law of correspondences ages before Swedenborg was born." The only other resident swami at the Vedanta society at present besides Swami Paramananda is Swami Abhedananda, who delivers a special course of lectures during the winter and holds the Yoga classes for members only.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
             <id>
            https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1909-04-11/ed-1/seq-12/#words=HINDOO+Yogi+Hindu+yoga
             </id>
             <rel>1</rel>
             <time>No timeline found</time>
             <text>
             A PAGE HOW YOUNG GIRLS STUDY THE FOR HINDOO METHOD OF REST AND RELAXATION THAT there is a great deal of good in the old Hindu philosophy of rest and relaxation is a truth that has again been demonstrated by recent happenings. One of these is the fact that many young girls, girls as young as 10 or 12 years of age, find it necessary to rest from school work or mental and physical exertion of any kind, temporarily, and take a rest cure, just as the jaded society woman withdraws from her social activities to recuperate, and during the retirement they are taught the value of absolute relaxation. The other is that, simultaneously with the scientific study of rest and relaxation by the young girl of today, the Yogi treatment and philosophy are brought into prominence by the leaders in the Emmanuel movement who rely upon this old Hindu method for restoring the mind and body to a natural and healthful condition. Yogi breathing,
            Yogi physical exercises and Yogi philosophy of relaxation are made a feature of the practical side of the Emmanuel treatment of certain cases, and this form of treatment is proved to be so beneficial in restoring wasted mental and physical force that the method is now being applied to young persons, the idea being that the sooner a girl learns how to rest and relax scientifically the stronger will be her vitality and the better will be her ability to withstand the strain that modern life puts upon the individual. It is not because girls are breaking down earlier or are showing a loss of nervous force at a younger age than formerly that they are being taught how to take care of themselves after the oriental fashion, but because parents and guardians see that it is important to them to learn as early as possible the value of this quaint and simple philosophy which has been practiced centuries upon centuries and has brought
            about excellent results. The difficulty experienced by a grown person in learning to relax properly and to rest perfectly is multiplied by that person's years. It follows quite naturally, then, that the earlier one begins studying this science the easier it comes to one and the greater are its advantages all during life. Besides the beneficial effects derived from the practice of Hindu philosophy and physical exercises the idea of the science can not fail to appeal to the young girl. The principle of the treatment is simple to understand and the rules are easy to follow, while the results are almost always immediate enough to be encouraging and to stimulate interest in the cult. One of the hardest things to do is to relax completely. Some persons think they are letting go of their muscles, but in reality they are not. Instead, the grip of their muscles is tense and it is almost impossible for them to relax even after a 
            series of mental and physical treatment. Relaxing is partly mental, so that youthful minds are easier to grasp this idea than grown persons. AMONG the best relaxing exercises are those which start with the body standing and letting go of each muscle and joint separately. First the arms are outstretched in front and the fingers are permitted to drop, to fall of themselves, and when they are perfectly limp and inactive then the relaxing should be continued to the forearm, then to the upper arm, letting the whole arm drop loosely at the side and not only remain motionless but possess the sensation of utter relaxation. These exercises in letting go of the tension of the muscles should be continued to the feet, then the legs, the pupil lifting and dropping each one in turn; then to the shoulders and the head by letting the latter fall loosely as it will either in front or to one side and the whole pupil relax the body "slumping"
            forward. Even the waist and the hips can be relaxed, although the loosening of the tension will be less noticeable. Now, after the various muscles have been taught what perfect relaxation means and this is only the beginning of the treatment—lie down on a couch or a bed that is not too soft and let go of the entire body, supplementing the physical relaxation with a mental attention to these muscles and members of the body. The Hindu maintains that the mind must be fixed on the muscle relaxation in order to get the best results and to make the "letting go" thorough and complete, especially when one is learning the first principles of relaxing. Resting like this once or twice during the day will restore one quickly to normal condition, and a few minutes devoted to perfect relaxation are worth an hour or more of sleep of the ordinary kind. It sounds more or less absurd to one who does not understand the art and science of 
            relaxation and perfect rest to say that one's energy and vitality can be restored without having the pupil lie down. The method to pursue in this quick restoration process is to think of oneself in their active position; that is, with the head up, shoulders back and chest expanded slightly. The arms should be allowed to drop loosely at the sides. While in this position the body on the balls of the feet, lifting the heels gradually and throwing them back to the floor. the weight forward, with the body still held erect and not tilted forward. As the heels rise the arms should be lifted straight out at the sides and upward until they pass above the horizontal line. Breathe deeply as the arms ascend, then hold the position for a minute or so and gradually let the heels drop down and the arms fall limply at the sides, not forgetting to exhale slowly and evenly as the original position is resumed. PROPER breathing has quite as
             much to do with the success of the relaxing and the muscle exercises as the movements themselves. One can fall into what approaches a mesmerized state just by breathing in the oriental fashion and continuing the action for a few minutes. While lying flat on your back raise the right hand to the nostrils, and with the finger or the thumb close one side tightly, making it necessary to breathe through the other. Rhythmical breathing is essential to perfect repose. With the hand at the nostrils alternate by inhaling through the right side and exhaling through the left, then reversing the order by closing the other side. Instead of expanding the chest first as you breathe try abdominal breathing for the rest cure by continuing the reclining position and alternating the nostrils as inhalers and exhalers. Then begin by taking a deep breath from deep down in the abdominal region, gradually inflating the other parts of the chest
            and lungs as the breathing is continued on up to the very tops of the lungs. In this way the abdomen, chest, and even the upper section of the lungs or the collarbone are raised and expanded with the air. Hold it a few seconds, then exhale by first drawing in the abdomen, then dropping the lower part of the chest and finally allowing the upper part to fall as much as possible breathing is essential to perfect repose. With the hand at the nostrils alternate by inhaling through the right side and exhaling through the left, then reversing the order by closing the other side. Instead of expanding the chest first as you breathe, try abdominal breathing for the rest cure by continuing the reclining position and alternating the nostrils as inhalers and exhalers. Then begin by taking a deep breath from deep down in the abdominal region, gradually inflating the other parts of the chest and lungs as the breathing is continued on up 
            to the very tops of the lungs. In this way the abdomen, chest, and even the upper section of the lungs or the collarbone are raised and expanded with the air. Hold it a few seconds, then exhale by first drawing in the standing position, with the feet spread a little apart, heels almost touching, head up, shoulders back, chest expanded and the abdomen drawn in. This is the way to start. Then, if you want to begin with an easy exercise, stretch the arms forward in front, keeping them level with the shoulders, and with the palms of the hands pressed together gently, not rigidly, swing the arms back, keeping them on the same horizontal plane until they are as far back of the shoulders as they will go. At first you will not be able to touch the backs of the hands, but after a little practice this will come quite readily. Do this quickly backward and forward for 10 times and then see how much better the muscles of the back feel 
            and how much easier it is to stand erect.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016209/1961-09-12/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=yoga&amp;r=0.237,0.038,0.903,0.471,0
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            POsition Is Everything in Life to Yogi Practitioners By B.K. Tiwari. NEW DELHI (UPI)—Ancient Hindu saints, it is believed here, lived as long as 2000 years. They then went to heaven, traveled through hell, explored space and returned to earth to tell their people all about those regions. Their secret was "Yoga"—the Indian way of controlling mind and body.Rishis (saints) Brataharti, Markandeya, the Saptarishi brothers and Narad are some notable legendary figures who lived a world life for as much as 2000 years and then left for a heavenly abode at their will. "Yoga" is a comprehensive term which embodies a number of postures called "asans." These "asans" are dependent upon the physiology of the body and its muscular and nervous systems. The "Yoga" system has three divisions, Karma Yoga, Hatha Yoga and Gyan Yoga. Karma Yoga is practiced to achieve peace of mind while living in this world. Its best exposition is found in the Gita,
            the Hindus' holy bible. Hatha Yoga has preventive as well as curative qualities for all ailments, Hindus believe. Perfection in this Yoga system would make a man capable of living in any climatic conditions without any difficulty. Deep breathing and meditation are the essence of Yoga. Prime Minister Nehru and his daughter Indira practice part of Hatha Yoga. Nehru now no longer stands on his head. But he does deep breathing almost every day. Hatha Yoga is regarded as a prime Yoga effort which gradually comes to be the methodical approach to the attainment of the highest in the Yoga. Hatha Yoga accepts man for what he really is. It therefore does not neglect the physical aspect of a person's life. Yoga experts recommend Hatha Yoga for space flights among other things. Gyan Yoga is the highest form of Yoga. By achieving perfection in this branch, according to Hindus, a person can leave his body at will, travel as far as he likes and then re-enter his body.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86002403/1951-11-16/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=yoga
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            ¿Qué Es El Yoga? Yoga es una palabra sánscrita que significa literalmente unión, aunque también tiene las acepciones de “contemplación” y “concentración”. Por yoga se comprende el método que ha de seguir el hombre para llegar a la mística unión con Dios. Los indúistas reconocen varias clases de yoga: los yoga de sabiduría, donde se logra la liberación por medio de la comprensión, conocimientos y sabiduría adquiridos por el ejercicio de la razón pura. La Yoga-Raja, o yoga mental que consiste en el dominio de la mente y del cuerpo mediante la actuación de la voluntad, de acuerdo con ciertos métodos, como el de la respiración rítmica. La Yoga-Karma, o yoga de acción que consiste en la realización de buenas obras. La Yoga-Bhakti o devocional que consiste en el sincero anhelo de la unión amorosa con el infinito, es una yoga mística donde se pide a Dios amor y devoción pero se abstienen de pedir favores y merecedes personales como hacemos nosotros con nuestros santos. 
            Hay además el Hatha-yoga, que es muy susceptible de perversión pues suele conducir a la magia negra a los espíritus pusilánimes.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>
            https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82001257/1961-07-23/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=yoga&amp;r=-0.252,0.484,1.643,0.856,0
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            Con la Práctica del Yoga se Puede Vivir Muchos Años Más El Karma Yoga, el Hatha Yoga y el Gyan Yoga — Peligroso si se Experimenta Equivocadamente Los antiguos santos hindúes vivían hasta 2,000 años. Estaban en el cielo, recorrían los infiernos, rondaban por el espacio y regresaban a la tierra para contarle todo a la gente. Su secreto era el Yoga, la manera india de controlar la mente y el cuerpo. Los Rishis (santos) Bratahari, Markandeya Saptarishi y Narad son algunas de las figuras legendarias que vivieron una vida terrestre durante 2,000 años y luego la dejaron, por la celestia, por su propia voluntad. "Yoga" es un término amplio que comprende una cantidad de posturas llamadas “Asans.” Estas “Asans” dependen de la fisiología del cuerpo y su sistema muscular y nervioso. El sistema "Yoga" tiene tres divisiones, el Karma Yoga, el Hatha Yoga y el Gyan Yoga. El Karma Yoga se practica para lograr la paz de la mente en este mundo. Su mejor exposición se encuentra en el Gita, la biblia de los hindúes. El Hatha Yoga tiene cualidades curativas,
            así como preventivas, para todos los males. La perfección en este sistema yoga, haría a un hombre capaz de vivir en cualquier condición climática sin dificultad alguna. La respiración profunda y la meditación constituyen la esencia del yoga. El Primer Ministro de India, Jawaharlal Nehru, y su hija, Indira, practican parte del Hatha Yoga. Nehru no se pone cabeza abajo, pero hace aspiraciones profundas todos los días. Se considera el Hatha Yoga como un esfuerzo primario que, gradualmente, llega a reconocerse en el acercamiento a la perfección de la mente
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
             <id>
             https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88063294/1945-01-21/ed-1/?sp=55&amp;q=yoga&amp;r=0.002,0.715,1.183,0.616,0
            </id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <time>No timeline found</time>
            <text>
            Love Tangles Too, Too Solid Even for Yoga Mrs. Florence Street could not get her husband, Robert A. Street, wealthy radio executive, to take his meals regularly. Then, as if that were not enough, Mrs. Edith Street lived in despair because she could not account for a series of strange happenings. At least, according to Mrs. Street, when Robert Street got a notion to judge her mental equilibrium, he did it in a way that seemed to defy all reason. “Yoga,” he explained, is that mystic philosophy of the East, whose exponents rise to triumph in all kinds of weird feats, such as attitude making themselves invisible. Yogis, as the practitioners of Yoga are called, eat carrots, stand on their heads and squat. Learning that Robert had acquired his taste for these activities at the exquisite feet of Miss Barnes, his wife went into a New York court and charged as much. She said he’d told her that Yogi High Priestess Carman had given him “new life, new love, new hope and a complete new cycle”—by which he did not mean a bicycle. He meant a life cycle, 
            which is something you have over and over again, like the common cold. Her testimony won Mrs. Street a new separation and new alimony. Robert, meanwhile, had skipped out to Reno and won himself a full-dress divorce. At least, it was full-dress everywhere but in New York. There, the courts considered his wife’s suit the more formal, so his was fruitless. Mr. Street was dissatisfied, as a consequence, and it seems a fair surmise that Mrs. Street was a little dissatisfied, too. Whether or not she then proceeded to work off her Yoga-bred dissatisfaction by getting another woman's husband to do things he hadn’t done before is a question which Mrs. Edith Marko now has asked the New York courts to pass upon. If the answer is “Yes,” as Mrs. Marko believes, then she will win a separation from her Robert, plus $500 a week alimony and $5,000 for her lawyers. Mrs. Marko's description of Mrs. Street is scarcely that of a wife unable to hold a husband. She calls her, "A Jezebel, a Lorelei, full of guile, who sings songs of love, making foolish men mad with desire."
            Curiously enough, the incident which allegedly showed Mrs. Street in her new colors was precipitated not by Mrs. Marko but by Mr. Street, who all this time has been biding his time, dissatisfied. The detectives, who raided her Bucks County, Pa., retreat a while ago, were his detectives. And, as they walked into the house, they testified, down the stairs came the lady of the house and Mrs. Marko’s Robert, convivially wearing bathrobes. Mrs. Street and Mr. Marko, for their part, assert that they weren’t there to play, but to write a play. After kindly turning over his alleged findings to Mrs. Marko, so she could start suing, Mr. Street started suing again himself, in the New York courts this time. He asked for a divorce, and if not that an annulment, and if not THAT at least a separation.
            </text>
        </result>
    </results>
</topic>